<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Navy on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/navy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Navy on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 21:13:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/navy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pentagon UFO videos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_200a71f90a18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 21:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_200a71f90a18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;pentagon-ufo-videos&#34;&gt;Pentagon UFO Videos &lt;a href=&#34;#pentagon-ufo-videos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the widely publicized cockpit instrumentation display videos from US Navy fighter jets, often characterized as UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for the videos, referencing historical UFO photographs and events. It details the initial incident on November 14, 2004, involving Commander David Fravor of the USS &lt;em&gt;Nimitz&lt;/em&gt; Carrier Strike Group investigating radar indications of a possible target off the coast of southern California. The USS &lt;em&gt;Princeton&lt;/em&gt; had been tracking unusual aircraft for two weeks prior to the incident. Fravor&amp;rsquo;s account of encountering a white, oval object hovering above an ocean disturbance is highlighted, as well as the observations of other pilots. It also mentions Lieutenant Commander Chad Underwood, who recorded the &amp;ldquo;FLIR&amp;rdquo; video and coined the term &amp;ldquo;Tic Tac&amp;rdquo; to describe the object. The section also mentions the 2014-2015 incidents involving fighter pilots associated with the USS &lt;em&gt;Theodore Roosevelt&lt;/em&gt; carrier strike group operating off the East Coast of the United States, during which the GIMBAL and GOFAST videos were recorded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release-of-videos&#34;&gt;Release of Videos &lt;a href=&#34;#release-of-videos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the public release of the videos. &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; reported on the incidents and published the &amp;ldquo;FLIR&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;GIMBAL&amp;rdquo; videos in December 2017, while the &lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; published the &amp;ldquo;GOFAST&amp;rdquo; video. Christopher Mellon, former Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Intelligence, provided the videos to the press. Luis Elizondo, the director of the Advanced Aerospace Threat Identification Program, resigned from the Pentagon in October 2017 to protest government secrecy. In September 2019, the Pentagon confirmed the videos were made by naval aviators. On April 27, 2020, the Pentagon formally released the three videos. In February 2020, the United States Navy confirmed that intelligence briefings have been provided to members of Congress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2021-release&#34;&gt;2021 Release &lt;a href=&#34;#2021-release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the release of additional footage in 2021. In April 2021, the Pentagon confirmed the authenticity of a video taken by Navy personnel aboard USS &lt;em&gt;Russell&lt;/em&gt; in 2019, showing a triangular object. Mick West suggested the image was the result of an optical effect called a bokeh. The Pentagon also confirmed photographs of objects described as &amp;ldquo;sphere&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;acorn&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;metallic blimp&amp;rdquo;. In May 2021, a second video recorded by Navy personnel aboard the USS &lt;em&gt;Omaha&lt;/em&gt; on July 15, 2019, was confirmed and is under review by the UAP Task Force. The video purportedly shows a spherical object flying over the ocean. Mick West commented on the video, suggesting it could simply be a plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2023-release&#34;&gt;2023 Release &lt;a href=&#34;#2023-release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the release of additional videos in 2023. In early 2023, an object was filmed by two MQ-9 drones in South Asia, initially believed to be anomalous but later identified as a commuter aircraft. On May 31, 2023, Sean M. Kirkpatrick shared an infrared video recorded in the western United States in 2021, which AARO concluded to be commercial aircraft. On April 19, 2023, the Pentagon released another video featuring MQ-9 drone footage from the Middle East depicting an unidentified aerial phenomenon resembling a small &amp;ldquo;metallic orb&amp;rdquo;. Sean M. Kirkpatrick briefed a Senate Armed Services subcommittee on the video, but stated they are unable to fully identify anything from the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;potential-explanations&#34;&gt;Potential Explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#potential-explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores potential explanations for the aerial phenomena recorded in the videos. As of 2020, the Department of Defense characterizes the phenomena as &amp;ldquo;unidentified&amp;rdquo;. Skeptical explanations include instrument malfunction, human observational error, or common aircraft. Mick West cautioned that believers in &amp;ldquo;alien disclosure&amp;rdquo; are &amp;ldquo;encroaching on these real issues of UAPs&amp;rdquo;. Adam Frank speculated that the UFOs could be drones deployed by rivals like Russia and China. Thomas Bania speculated that they could be some form of electronic warfare fielded by China or Russia. The US Navy updated its reporting guidelines for unexplained aerial observations. Senator Marco Rubio expressed concern that the UFOs may be Chinese or Russian technology. Admiral Gary Roughead said that most assessments were inconclusive. Jeff Wise suggests advancements in electronic warfare could deceive sensors. In 2023, David Fravor testified under oath regarding the USS Nimitz sighting, stating that the technology was far superior to anything the US had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;june-2021-ufo-report&#34;&gt;June 2021 UFO Report &lt;a href=&#34;#june-2021-ufo-report&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the preliminary report on UAPs released by the US Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI) on June 25, 2021. The report came to no conclusion about what the UAPs were, citing a lack of sufficient data. Some UAPs appeared to exhibit unusual flight characteristics, including high velocity and maneuverability. The report indicated that the UAP recordings probably were of physical objects and proposed five possible categories of explanation: airborne clutter, natural atmospheric phenomena, US government or industry development technology, foreign craft, and an &amp;ldquo;Other&amp;rdquo; category. The report raised concerns about safety and security issues and indicated that investigation of the topic would continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;foi-request-by-the-black-vault&#34;&gt;FOI Request by The Black Vault &lt;a href=&#34;#foi-request-by-the-black-vault&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details a Freedom of Information request made by The Black Vault for the release of more video footage. The government confirmed it had more footage but refused to release it, citing concerns for national security. Gregory Cason stated that the release of this information would harm national security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In Popular Culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section notes the videos&amp;rsquo; appearance in the History Channel series &lt;em&gt;Unidentified: Inside America&amp;rsquo;s UFO Investigation&lt;/em&gt; and an interview with Fravor on &lt;em&gt;The Joe Rogan Experience&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See Also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics, including the Advanced Aerospace Threat Identification Program, Unidentified Aerial Phenomena Task Force, All-domain Anomaly Resolution Office, Navy UFO patents, and the film &lt;em&gt;The Phenomenon&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pentagon_UFO_videos&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pentagon_UFO_videos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pentagon UFO videos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_b8187019fdfb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 21:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_b8187019fdfb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;pentagon-ufo-videos&#34;&gt;Pentagon UFO videos &lt;a href=&#34;#pentagon-ufo-videos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pentagon UFO videos are visual recordings from United States Navy fighter jets, widely publicized as UFOs. These videos were recorded using forward-looking infrared (FLIR) targeting cameras from fighter jets based aboard the aircraft carriers USS &lt;em&gt;Nimitz&lt;/em&gt; and USS &lt;em&gt;Theodore Roosevelt&lt;/em&gt; in 2004, 2014, and 2015. Additional footage was taken by other Navy personnel in 2019. The videos, characterized as officially documenting UFOs, have received extensive media coverage since 2017. The Pentagon officially released the first three videos of unidentified aerial phenomena (UAP) in 2020 and confirmed the provenance of the leaked 2019 videos in 2021. Footage of UAPs was also released in 2023, sourced from MQ-9 military drones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publicity surrounding the videos has prompted explanations including drones or unidentified terrestrial aircraft, anomalous instrument readings, physical observational phenomena, human observational and interpretive error, and speculations of alien spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for the Pentagon UFO videos, referencing the broader history of UFO sightings and investigations. It mentions UFO photographs and links to other Wikipedia articles on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 14, 2004, Commander David Fravor of the USS &lt;em&gt;Nimitz&lt;/em&gt; Carrier Strike Group investigated radar indications of a possible target off the coast of southern California. Fravor reported seeing a white, oval object hovering above an ocean disturbance. A second wave of fighters, including Lieutenant Commander Chad Underwood, recorded the FLIR video, with Underwood coining the term &amp;ldquo;Tic Tac&amp;rdquo; to describe the infrared image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During 2014–2015, fighter pilots associated with the USS &lt;em&gt;Theodore Roosevelt&lt;/em&gt; carrier strike group recorded the GIMBAL and GOFAST videos while operating off the East Coast of the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release-of-videos&#34;&gt;Release of videos &lt;a href=&#34;#release-of-videos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the public release of the videos and the reactions that followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 16, 2017, &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; reported on the incidents and published two videos, &amp;ldquo;FLIR&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;GIMBAL.&amp;rdquo; The &lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; published a video titled &amp;ldquo;GOFAST.&amp;rdquo; The reports led to speculation by UFO investigators. Journalism professor Keith Kloor criticized the reporting as thinly-sourced and slanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The videos were initially provided to the press by Christopher Mellon, former Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Intelligence. Luis Elizondo, the director of the Advanced Aerospace Threat Identification Program, resigned from the Pentagon in October 2017 to protest government secrecy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In September 2019, the Pentagon confirmed that the released videos were made by naval aviators. On April 27, 2020, the Pentagon formally released the three videos. In February 2020, the United States Navy confirmed that intelligence briefings have been provided to members of Congress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2021-release&#34;&gt;2021 release &lt;a href=&#34;#2021-release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the release of additional videos and images in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April 2021, the Pentagon confirmed that video footage of an unidentified triangular object taken by Navy personnel aboard USS &lt;em&gt;Russell&lt;/em&gt; in 2019 was authentic. Mick West suggested the image was the result of an optical effect called a bokeh. The Pentagon also confirmed photographs of objects described as &amp;ldquo;sphere&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;acorn&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;metallic blimp&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May 2021, the Pentagon confirmed a second video recorded by Navy personnel aboard the USS &lt;em&gt;Omaha&lt;/em&gt; on July 15, 2019, showing a spherical object flying over the ocean. Mick West commented that the object was likely a plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2023-release&#34;&gt;2023 release &lt;a href=&#34;#2023-release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the release of additional footage in 2023, including analysis of the objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In early 2023, an object was filmed by two MQ-9 drones in South Asia. Initially believed to be anomalous, the object was later identified as a commuter aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 31, 2023, Sean M. Kirkpatrick shared an infrared video recorded in the western United States in 2021, which the AARO concluded to be commercial aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 19, 2023, the Pentagon released another video featuring MQ-9 drone footage from the Middle East depicting an unidentified aerial phenomenon. Sean M. Kirkpatrick briefed a Senate Armed Services subcommittee that it resembled a small &amp;ldquo;metallic orb&amp;rdquo; but said they are unable to fully identify anything from this video. Some skeptics suggested it might be a balloon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;potential-explanations&#34;&gt;Potential explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#potential-explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses potential explanations for the aerial phenomena recorded in the videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of 2020, the Department of Defense characterizes the phenomena as &amp;ldquo;unidentified.&amp;rdquo; Widespread media attention has led to various theories, including pseudoscientific explanations such as ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skeptical explanations include instrument malfunction, human observational illusion, or common aircraft. Mick West cautioned that believers in &amp;ldquo;alien disclosure&amp;rdquo; are encroaching on real issues and that the recorded UFOs might be commercial airplanes or balloons distorted by infrared glare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astrophysicist Adam Frank speculated that the UFOs could be drones deployed by rivals like Russia and China. Astronomer Thomas Bania speculated that they could be electronic warfare technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US Navy updated its guidelines for reporting unexplained aerial observations. A spokesman suggested that the increase in reported intrusions could be due to the rise in availability of unmanned aerial systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senator Marco Rubio expressed concern that the UFOs may be Chinese or Russian technology. Retired Admiral Gary Roughead said that most assessments were inconclusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam Dodd and security expert Jack Weinstein say that neither China nor Russia presently have the capability to produce aircraft with such extraordinary capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeff Wise suggested that advancements in electronic warfare techniques could deceive sensors, resulting in false velocity and position information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2023, David Fravor testified under oath that the technology they faced was far superior to anything they had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;june-2021-ufo-report&#34;&gt;June 2021 UFO report &lt;a href=&#34;#june-2021-ufo-report&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the US Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI) preliminary report on UAPs released on June 25, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report came to no conclusion about what the UAPs were, citing a lack of sufficient data. In a limited number of incidents, UAP appeared to exhibit unusual flight characteristics. Some of the UAPs appeared to move with no discernible means of propulsion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report indicated that, in most cases, the UAP recordings probably were of physical objects. The report proposed five possible categories of explanation: airborne clutter, natural atmospheric phenomena, US government or industry development technology, foreign craft, and an &amp;ldquo;Other&amp;rdquo; category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report raised concerns about safety and security issues and indicated that investigation of the topic would continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;foi-request-by-the-black-vault&#34;&gt;FOI request by The Black Vault &lt;a href=&#34;#foi-request-by-the-black-vault&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses a Freedom of Information request made by The Black Vault for the release of more video footage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April 2020, The Black Vault made a Freedom of Information request to the US Navy. The government confirmed it had more footage but refused to release it, citing concerns for national security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section notes the appearance of the videos in popular media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The videos were featured in the 2019 History Channel series &lt;em&gt;Unidentified: Inside America&amp;rsquo;s UFO Investigation&lt;/em&gt;. Episode 1361 of &lt;em&gt;The Joe Rogan Experience&lt;/em&gt; featured the videos and interviewed Fravor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/USS_Theodore_Roosevelt_UFO_incidents&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/USS_Theodore_Roosevelt_UFO_incidents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
