<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Police Procedural on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/police-procedural/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Police Procedural on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 03:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/police-procedural/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Nation</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_eed570f8ae8c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 03:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_eed570f8ae8c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-nation&#34;&gt;Alien Nation &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-nation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A science fiction police procedural television series that aired on Fox from 1989 to 1990. It&amp;rsquo;s based on the 1988 film &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series is set in the near future, beginning in 1990, after a flying saucer crashes in the Mojave Desert. The ship contains the Tenctonese, a race of extraterrestrials escaping slavery. They are accepted as immigrants to the US, and the series explores their integration into American society. Storylines often address themes of racism and bigotry, using the Newcomers as a stand-in for discriminated minorities. The series uses social commentary to illustrate what it means to be human and the often bizarre rituals we observe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detective Matthew &amp;ldquo;Matt&amp;rdquo; Sikes:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Gary Graham, a human detective partnered with George Francisco.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detective George Francisco:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Eric Pierpoint, a Newcomer detective partnered with Matthew Sikes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Susan Francisco:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Michele Scarabelli, George&amp;rsquo;s wife, a Newcomer advertising businesswoman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emily Francisco:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Lauren Woodland, George and Susan&amp;rsquo;s young daughter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buck Francisco:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Sean Six, George and Susan&amp;rsquo;s initially delinquent teenage son.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cathy Frankel:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Terri Treas, Matt&amp;rsquo;s Newcomer neighbor and on-off girlfriend, a bio-chemist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Albert Einstein:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Jeff Marcus, a timid Newcomer janitor working at the police department.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cpt. Bryon Grazer:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Ron Fassler, Matt and George&amp;rsquo;s human superior officer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beatrice Zepeda:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Jenny Gago, a human detective in Matt and George&amp;rsquo;s squad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Burns:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Jeff Doucette, a human photographer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sergeant Dobbs:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Lawrence Hilton-Jacobs, a human police officer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jill:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Molly Morgan, a human girl and Emily&amp;rsquo;s friend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uncle Moodri:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by James Greene, an eccentric but wise Newcomer and member of the Francisco family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenneth Johnson, responsible for other science-fiction television series, was approached for the television adaptation of the 1988 film &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt;. He initially had no interest in the project but was later inspired to create a series focusing on social commentary about the integration of a new minority group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;changes-from-the-film&#34;&gt;Changes from the film &lt;a href=&#34;#changes-from-the-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several changes were made from the original film. The human detective Matthew Sykes was played by James Caan in the film, but Gary Graham in the TV series. Detective George Francisco was played by Mandy Patinkin in the film, but Eric Pierpoint in the TV series. The TV series explores Newcomer culture more deeply than the film. Francisco&amp;rsquo;s family also differs, with a daughter, Emily, added to the TV series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cancellation&#34;&gt;Cancellation &lt;a href=&#34;#cancellation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series ran for one season on Fox. Despite building a strong fan base, the show was cancelled due to the network&amp;rsquo;s financial difficulties. The season ended on a cliffhanger, and popular demand led to the unproduced second season premiere being adapted as a novel and comic book. Years later, Fox produced five television films to continue the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series consists of 22 episodes, each dealing with the integration of the Newcomers into human society and the challenges they face. The episodes often involve police procedural elements, with Sikes and Francisco investigating crimes involving both humans and Newcomers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;television-films&#34;&gt;Television films &lt;a href=&#34;#television-films&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five television films continued the story after the series&amp;rsquo; cancellation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation: Dark Horizon&lt;/em&gt; (1994)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation: Body and Soul&lt;/em&gt; (1995)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation: Millennium&lt;/em&gt; (1996)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation: The Enemy Within&lt;/em&gt; (1996)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation: The Udara Legacy&lt;/em&gt; (1997)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;home-media&#34;&gt;Home media &lt;a href=&#34;#home-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complete series was released on DVD by 20th Century Fox in 2006. The five television films were later released as a collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;revival&#34;&gt;Revival &lt;a href=&#34;#revival&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2009, Syfy announced a new take on the series with Tim Minear writing. However, the series was later cancelled. In 2015, a remake was reported to be in the works with Art Marcum and Matt Holloway writing the script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Nation_(TV_series)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Nation_(TV_series)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
