<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Atlantis on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/atlantis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Atlantis on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 08:25:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/atlantis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien from L.A. (1988 Film)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_e9c1ca5b8272/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 08:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_e9c1ca5b8272/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-from-la-1988-film&#34;&gt;Alien from L.A. (1988 Film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-from-la-1988-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a description of the 1988 science fiction film &lt;em&gt;Alien from L.A.&lt;/em&gt; directed by Albert Pyun, based on the provided Wikipedia article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien from L.A.&lt;/em&gt; is a 1988 science fiction film directed by Albert Pyun, starring Kathy Ireland. The film centers on a young woman from Los Angeles who discovers an underground civilization in Atlantis. The film is loosely based on Jules Verne&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Journey to the Center of the Earth&lt;/em&gt;. It was also featured on &lt;em&gt;Mystery Science Theater 3000&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wanda Saknussemm, a social misfit from Los Angeles, learns of her archaeologist father&amp;rsquo;s death in North Africa. While sorting through his belongings, she discovers notes about Atlantis, an alien ship that crashed and sank into the Earth&amp;rsquo;s center. Wanda accidentally falls into a deep hole and awakens in the underground world of Atlantis. She encounters Gus, a miner, who helps her search for her father, whom she believes is still alive. The Atlanteans consider surface dwellers &amp;ldquo;aliens&amp;rdquo; and suspect Wanda and her father of planning an invasion. Wanda becomes a fugitive, pursued by &amp;ldquo;Government House&amp;rdquo; and the crime lord Mambino. She receives assistance from Charmin&amp;rsquo;, a rogue who falls in love with her. Eventually, Wanda is captured by General Rykov, who intends to kill her and her father. Gus helps them escape, and they return to the surface. The film concludes with Wanda rejecting her ex-boyfriend and reuniting with Charmin&amp;rsquo; on a beach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film stars:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kathy Ireland as Wanda Saknussemm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;William R. Moses as Guten &amp;ldquo;Gus&amp;rdquo; Edway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Richard Haines as Professor Arnold Saknussemm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don Michael Paul as Robbie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thom Mathews as &amp;ldquo;Charmin&#39;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Janie Du Plessis as General Rykov / Shank / Claims Officer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simon Poland as Consul Triton Crassus / The Mailman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linda Kerridge as Roryis Freki / Auntie Pearl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kristen Trucksess as Stacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lochner de Kock as Professor Ovid Galba / Paddy Mahoney&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep Roy as Mambino, The Boss of Bosses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Albert Pyun took on &lt;em&gt;Alien from L.A.&lt;/em&gt; after being approached by producers Yoram Globus and Menahem Golan during the troubled production of &lt;em&gt;Journey to the Center of the Earth&lt;/em&gt;. Pyun agreed to finish the film if he could also film &lt;em&gt;Alien from L.A.&lt;/em&gt; for under $1 million. Kathy Ireland was cast by Pyun after seeing a photo of her. Filming locations included Los Angeles, Redondo Beach, South Africa, and Namibia. The gold mines and dumps around South Africa were used for the underground setpieces. The sets were inspired by &amp;ldquo;future noir&amp;rdquo; films like &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Blade Runner&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien from L.A.&lt;/em&gt; was released on February 26, 1988. It was released on VHS in June 1995 and on DVD in June 2005. Vinegar Syndrome has released a Blu-ray edition with special features. A direct-to-video sequel, &lt;em&gt;Journey to the Center of the Earth&lt;/em&gt;, also directed by Albert Pyun and starring Kathy Ireland, was released in 1989.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe Bob Briggs called it a &amp;ldquo;pretty decent film&amp;rdquo;, awarding it two stars. Rebecca Harris of the &lt;em&gt;Abilene Reporter-News&lt;/em&gt; gave the film 2.5 stars out of 4. David Picking called it &amp;ldquo;a cheapo adventure movie without a single redeeming quality&amp;rdquo;. Rob Thomas of &lt;em&gt;The Capital Times&lt;/em&gt; said &amp;ldquo;Completely awful – you can&amp;rsquo;t believe they&amp;rsquo;re serious.&amp;rdquo; Daniel M. Kimmel of the &lt;em&gt;Worcester Telegram &amp;amp; Gazette&lt;/em&gt; gave the film one out of five stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_from_L.A&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_from_L.A&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
