<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pacific Northwest on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/pacific-northwest/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pacific Northwest on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 10:32:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/pacific-northwest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flight 105 UFO sighting</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f9095ed38662/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 10:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f9095ed38662/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;flight-105-ufo-sighting&#34;&gt;Flight 105 UFO Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#flight-105-ufo-sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the UFO sighting reported by the crew of United Airlines Flight 105 on July 4, 1947, over the Pacific Northwest. It connects the event to the broader context of the 1947 flying disc craze and provides background information, a description of the sighting, its aftermath, and eventual explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for the Flight 105 incident by referencing the Kenneth Arnold UFO sighting and the broader 1947 flying disc craze. It explains how Arnold&amp;rsquo;s report of objects flying near Mount Rainier led to the terms &amp;ldquo;flying saucers&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;flying discs&amp;rdquo; and sparked a wave of similar reports. The section establishes the Flight 105 sighting as part of this larger phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sighting&#34;&gt;Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the details of the Flight 105 UFO sighting. On July 4, 1947, United Airlines Flight 105, a Douglas DC-3, departed from Boise, Idaho, bound for Pendleton, Oregon. First Officer Ralph Stevens spotted unusual objects and alerted Captain E.J. Smith. Both men, along with stewardess Marty Morrow, observed four to five &amp;ldquo;flat and circular&amp;rdquo; objects. The objects were larger than aircraft and flew in formation for approximately 10 to 15 minutes (about 45 miles). The crew radioed the tower in Ontario, Oregon, and another United flight, but neither could confirm the sighting. The passengers did not see the objects. The objects eventually sped away or disintegrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aftermath&#34;&gt;Aftermath &lt;a href=&#34;#aftermath&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the immediate reactions and consequences of the Flight 105 sighting. News outlets widely reported the crew&amp;rsquo;s account. The report was considered credible due to the professional background of the witnesses. Captain Smith, Ralph Stevens, and Kenneth Arnold were photographed together &amp;ldquo;comparing notes.&amp;rdquo; Kenneth Arnold felt vindicated by the corroboration of his own sighting. Arnold and Smith were interviewed by the FBI and investigated the Maury Island hoax together. Another &amp;ldquo;disklike object&amp;rdquo; was sighted on Flight 105 later in July by a different pair of pilots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;explanation-and-legacy&#34;&gt;Explanation and Legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#explanation-and-legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explains the official explanation for the Flight 105 sighting and its lasting impact. Air Materiel Command concluded that the objects were likely &amp;ldquo;ordinary aircraft, balloons, birds, or pure illusion&amp;rdquo; due to the sighting occurring at sunset. The Air Force suggested the power of suggestion influenced observers during the craze. Despite the official explanation, the Flight 105 sighting has become part of UFO folklore and conspiracy theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flight_105_UFO_sighting&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flight_105_UFO_sighting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
