<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>South Africa on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/south-africa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in South Africa on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 18:20:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/south-africa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in South Africa</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_fa04a626f0cf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 18:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_fa04a626f0cf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-south-africa&#34;&gt;List of Alleged UFO Sightings in South Africa &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-south-africa&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article documents reported sightings of Unidentified Flying Objects (UFOs) in South Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1914-phantom-monoplanes&#34;&gt;1914 Phantom Monoplanes &lt;a href=&#34;#1914-phantom-monoplanes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details a series of sightings from August to September 1914, where numerous South Africans reported seeing a nighttime monoplane. These sightings occurred during the lead-up to the South West Africa campaign of World War I, leading to speculation that it was a German spy plane. However, the origin of the plane remained unknown, leading some to consider mass hysteria as a possible explanation. Key locations include various parts of South Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1970s-sighting&#34;&gt;1970s Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#1970s-sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on an incident from June 26, 1971, involving Bennie Smit, a farm owner near Fort Beaufort in the Eastern Cape. Smit and local police reportedly fired shots at a fireball-like object that changed color. Rumors circulated about an army investigation, though no records were found. The incident gained international attention, and local businesses capitalized on the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1990s-sightings&#34;&gt;1990s Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#1990s-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers several UFO sightings during the 1990s:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 7, 1991:&lt;/strong&gt; A family in Baviaanspoort, Pretoria, reported a triangular craft with red and white lights. Similar sightings occurred in nearby Eersterust.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 18, 1993:&lt;/strong&gt; Residents of Sasolburg observed lights moving from Vereeniging, describing a craft that could change color and shape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September–October 1994:&lt;/strong&gt; A farmer in Warrenton claimed to see a &amp;lsquo;mothership&amp;rsquo; with a distinctive engine sound.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March–April 1995:&lt;/strong&gt; A UFO flap occurred across South Africa, with reports including a hovering object at De Brug, a spacecraft blocking a road near Coligny, and disruptions to vehicles and watches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 28, 1996:&lt;/strong&gt; Police Sgt. Nico Stander in Pretoria videotaped lights in the sky, leading to a chase involving police and a helicopter near Cullinan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 1997:&lt;/strong&gt; Andreas Mathios claimed to film a cylindrical light above Trichardt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 8, 2000:&lt;/strong&gt; Police inspector Kriel reported observing an orange, oval-shaped light on the N3 freeway near Warden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;21st-century&#34;&gt;21st Century &lt;a href=&#34;#21st-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details UFO sightings in the 2000s and beyond:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June 27, 2004:&lt;/strong&gt; Roshnie Naidu in Durban reported observing and videotaping a bright, colorful light changing shape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2009:&lt;/strong&gt; Multiple people witnessed orange-red objects traveling between Middelburg and Witbank.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 21–22, 2010:&lt;/strong&gt; Residents of Booysens, Pretoria, reported seeing a triangle of bright lights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May–October 2011:&lt;/strong&gt; Numerous reports of silent, orange lights over Tierpoort and Krugersdorp, with additional sightings near Harrismith.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 2015:&lt;/strong&gt; Residents in Pietermaritzburg and Clarendon reported seeing orange orbs, and a green light was reported over Long Street in Cape Town.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 12, 2016:&lt;/strong&gt; The captain and co-pilot of a Boeing 737 cargo aircraft reported seeing a glowing green object near Jeffreys Bay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crash-claims-and-hoaxes&#34;&gt;Crash Claims and Hoaxes &lt;a href=&#34;#crash-claims-and-hoaxes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section addresses claims of alien spacecraft being shot down by South African aircraft in 1989 and 1995, which were later determined to be hoaxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the main &amp;ldquo;List of reported UFO sightings&amp;rdquo; article on Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes &lt;a href=&#34;#notes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains footnotes and references to support the information presented in the article, citing various news reports, books, and other sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external websites related to UFO research in South Africa, including scans of Cynthia Hind&amp;rsquo;s UFO Afrinews and the UfoRSA website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_South_Africa&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_South_Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
