<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Satire on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/satire/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Satire on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/satire/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Autopsy  Fact or Fiction (1995 film)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_f41f4fadf611/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_f41f4fadf611/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-autopsy-fact-or-fiction-1995-film&#34;&gt;Alien Autopsy: Fact or Fiction (1995 film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-autopsy-fact-or-fiction-1995-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry discusses the 1995 pseudo-documentary &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy: Fact or Fiction&lt;/em&gt;, which featured footage purporting to show an alien autopsy conducted after the Roswell incident. The footage, released by British entrepreneur Ray Santilli, was broadcast on television networks worldwide, including Fox television, hosted by Jonathan Frakes, and Channel 4 in the UK. Despite its popularity, the program was thoroughly debunked, with the footage revealed to have been shot on a set in London using plaster casts filled with offal and other materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the production of the hoaxed footage. In 2006, Ray Santilli and Gary Shoefield admitted to creating the 1995 footage in a documentary presented by Eamonn Holmes. They simulated an autopsy on a fabricated alien, constructed by artist and sculptor John Humphreys in a London flat. Humphreys created two dummy alien bodies filled with raspberry jam, sheep brains, and chicken entrails. Alien artifacts were also fabricated. Santilli and Shoefield also admitted to hiring a homeless man in Los Angeles to play the role of the original cameraman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines how &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; was received and referenced in media. &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt; satirized the footage, and Fox later aired a special debunking it. A fictionalized version of the creation of the footage was retold in the comedy film &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; (2006).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including books, news articles, and documentaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of additional resources for readers interested in learning more about the topic, including articles from &lt;em&gt;Skeptical Inquirer&lt;/em&gt; and books about the Roswell incident and alien autopsy film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external resources, including Ray Santilli&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;My Story&amp;rdquo; on VJ Enterprises, his IMDb page, and a YouTube link to &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy: Fact or Fiction?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Autopsy_(1995_film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Autopsy_(1995_film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
