<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docufiction on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/docufiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docufiction on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 00:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/docufiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Worlds</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_46ef1ab96feb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 00:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_46ef1ab96feb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-worlds&#34;&gt;Alien Worlds &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-worlds&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Worlds&lt;/em&gt; is a 2020 British sci-fi nature docufiction miniseries that blends science fiction with real scientific principles to imagine what alien life might be like on exoplanets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Genre:&lt;/strong&gt; Docufiction, Science fiction, Speculative evolution
&lt;strong&gt;Country of origin:&lt;/strong&gt; United Kingdom
&lt;strong&gt;Original language:&lt;/strong&gt; English
&lt;strong&gt;Number of seasons:&lt;/strong&gt; 1
&lt;strong&gt;Number of episodes:&lt;/strong&gt; 4
&lt;strong&gt;Production company:&lt;/strong&gt; Wall to Wall Media
&lt;strong&gt;Original release:&lt;/strong&gt; December 2, 2020
&lt;strong&gt;Network:&lt;/strong&gt; Netflix&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series is narrated by Sophie Okonedo and uses CGI to depict hypothetical alien lifeforms and ecosystems based on the laws of life on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a summary of each of the four episodes of the &lt;em&gt;Alien Worlds&lt;/em&gt; miniseries, including the title, original release date, and a brief description of the exoplanet featured and the scientific concepts explored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Episode 1: &amp;ldquo;Atlas&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; (December 2, 2020) - Atlas is a planet larger than Earth with higher gravity and a thicker atmosphere, leading to an airborne ecosystem. Astronomer Didier Queloz discusses exoplanet discoveries. The episode explores the handicap principle in insects and falconry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Episode 2: &amp;ldquo;Janus&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; (December 2, 2020) - Janus orbits a red dwarf star and is tidally locked, resulting in a hemisphere of perpetual daylight, a hemisphere of perpetual night, and a twilight zone. Life has adapted to these conditions. The episode examines life in the Danakil Depression with exobiologist Kennda Lynch, polymorphism in leafcutter ants, scorpion venom, snottites, and bioluminescence in fireflies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Episode 3: &amp;ldquo;Eden&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; (December 2, 2020) - Eden is a planet in a binary star system with an oxygen-rich atmosphere. A parasitic fungus affects grazing creatures, which are then preyed upon by predators. Ecologist Thomas Crowther discusses mycelial networks in the Rothiemurchus Forest in Scotland. The episode also discusses predation on reproductive strategies, cooperation between humans (Hadza hunters in Tanzania) and honeyguide birds, and the mayfly life cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Episode 4: &amp;ldquo;Terra&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; (December 2, 2020) - Terra features an advanced alien civilization terraforming and colonizing another planet. The episode features Noor Power Station and RASSOR, a robot being developed by NASA. Astrophysicist Adam Frank talks about Area 51 and the possibility of extraterrestrial civilizations. Astronaut Michael Foale discusses a collision on the &lt;em&gt;Mir&lt;/em&gt; space station and space radiation. Astrobiologist Doug Vakoch talks about the Arecibo message and communication with extraterrestrial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the critical and popular response to &lt;em&gt;Alien Worlds&lt;/em&gt;. It mentions that the series was in Netflix&amp;rsquo;s top 10 shows in the UK after its release. Sheena Scott of &lt;em&gt;Forbes&lt;/em&gt; and Emma Stefansky of &lt;em&gt;Thrillist&lt;/em&gt; both noted that the most interesting parts of the series were the non-fiction segments about Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists other similar docufiction and speculative evolution works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Planet&lt;/em&gt; (2005)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Natural History of an Alien&lt;/em&gt; (1998)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Extraterrestrial&lt;/em&gt; (2005)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of the sources cited in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external resources related to &lt;em&gt;Alien Worlds&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Worlds&lt;/em&gt; at IMDb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Worlds&lt;/em&gt; on Netflix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Exploring &amp;lsquo;Alien Worlds&amp;rsquo; on Netflix&amp;rdquo; from the SETI Institute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Worlds_(TV_series)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Worlds_(TV_series)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien Planet (2005 TV series)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e77076cc2caf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 06:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e77076cc2caf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-planet-2005-tv-series&#34;&gt;Alien Planet (2005 TV series) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-planet-2005-tv-series&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2005 docufiction TV special created for the Discovery Channel, based on Wayne Barlowe&amp;rsquo;s 1990 book &lt;em&gt;Expedition&lt;/em&gt;. It explores the imagined extraterrestrial life of the fictional planet Darwin IV in the style of a nature documentary. It features scientists and science fiction figures discussing Darwin IV as if it had actually been discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Von Braun&lt;/em&gt; interstellar spacecraft travels to Darwin IV, 6.5 light-years away. It deploys the &lt;em&gt;Darwin Reconnaissance Orbiter&lt;/em&gt; to find landing sites for probes. The first probe, &lt;em&gt;Balboa&lt;/em&gt;, explodes during entry. Backup probes &lt;em&gt;Leonardo da Vinci&lt;/em&gt; (Leo) and &lt;em&gt;Isaac Newton&lt;/em&gt; (Ike) land successfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The robotic probes, called Horus Probes, are equipped with inflatable balloons, solar receptors, computers, sensors, and smaller robots. They have limited AI and are programmed with different personalities. Ike is cautious, while Leo is a risk-taker. They are equipped with a holographic message for any sentient life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The probes encounter various lifeforms, including Arrowtongues, Gyrosprinters, Trunk Suckers, Daggerwrists, and Unths. Ike studies plant life, while Leo goes after big game. A massive storm hits, and Ike launches weather balloons. Leo finds Bladderhorns and attempts to present the holographic message, but is interrupted. Ike encounters Grovebacks, Littoralopes, Skewers, Beach Quills, and Prongheads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leo briefly re-establishes contact with &lt;em&gt;Von Braun&lt;/em&gt; until a mysterious creature interferes. Ike is ordered to search for Leo. Ike finds a sea that is Amoebic in nature and encounters giant Sea Striders. Ike finds Leo&amp;rsquo;s last known location, where a Skewer is killed by a spear. Ike finds Leo and the sapient Eosapiens. Ike presents the holographic message to the Eosapiens, but one of them destroys the camera disk, and the Eosapiens attack Ike. The wrecked camera disk records the Eosapiens carrying Ike away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commentary from Michio Kaku, Stephen Hawking, Jack Horner, James B. Garvin, and George Lucas is interspersed throughout the special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Planet&lt;/em&gt; is based on &lt;em&gt;Expedition&lt;/em&gt; (1990) by Wayne Barlowe. Barlowe served as one of the executive producers. Scientists and other figures were assembled to comment on the life on Darwin IV. The documentary gives the appearance of the featured scientists having designed Darwin IV and its animals, most of what is shown of the actual planet and its life follows what is described in &lt;em&gt;Expedition&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike &lt;em&gt;Expedition&lt;/em&gt;, which is set in the mid-24th century, &lt;em&gt;Alien Planet&lt;/em&gt; is set in the near future, and the planet is explored using sophisticated probes. The technology featured is more advanced than present-day technology, but is based on current trends and informed speculation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dwayne A. Day of &lt;em&gt;The Space Review&lt;/em&gt; gave the special a positive review. Some criticism was leveled at the strangeness of the creatures showcased. Day stated that the animals are bizarre and frequently border on the implausible. A review in &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; stated that a few too many of the creatures seem like cartoonish monsters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lists related speculative evolution, similar documentaries, and topics related to astrobiology and xenology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citations for reviews and articles related to the production and reception of &lt;em&gt;Alien Planet&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links to the IMDb page, archived Discovery Channel page, and the Internet Archive page for &lt;em&gt;Alien Planet&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Planet&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Planet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
