<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Predators on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/predators/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Predators on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 02:39:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/predators/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien vs. Predator (2004 film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_80778c3082c7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 02:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_80778c3082c7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-vs-predator-2004-film&#34;&gt;Alien vs. Predator (2004 film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-vs-predator-2004-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2004 science fiction action horror film directed by Paul W. S. Anderson, &lt;em&gt;Alien vs. Predator&lt;/em&gt; brings together the titular creatures from the &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Predator&lt;/em&gt; franchises. The story draws inspiration from a 1989 comic book and incorporates elements of Aztec mythology and the writings of Erich von Däniken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Antarctica, a Predator ship melts a hole in the ice, revealing a buried pyramid. Charles Weyland assembles a team to investigate. The team discovers evidence of an ancient civilization and a sacrificial chamber. Three Predators arrive and descend into the pyramid, where they encounter the humans and awakened Xenomorphs. Battles ensue, and Lex Woods and Sebastian De Rosa learn about the Predators&amp;rsquo; history on Earth through hieroglyphs. They discover that the Predators have been visiting Earth for millennia, teaching humans to build pyramids and using them for rite of passage rituals involving Xenomorphs. Lex and Sebastian ally with a Predator named Scar to prevent the Xenomorphs from escaping. Scar destroys the pyramid, but the Xenomorph Queen attacks. Lex and Scar defeat the Queen, and an elder Predator gifts Lex a spear. A Predalien chestburster erupts from Scar&amp;rsquo;s body on the Predator spaceship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanaa Lathan stars as Alexa &amp;ldquo;Lex&amp;rdquo; Woods, an experienced guide. Raoul Bova plays Professor Sebastian De Rosa, an Italian archaeologist. Lance Henriksen portrays Charles Bishop Weyland, the head of Weyland Corporation. Ewen Bremner is Dr. Graeme Miller, the main scientist. Colin Salmon plays Maxwell Stafford, Weyland&amp;rsquo;s assistant. Tommy Flanagan is Mark Verheiden, a member of the armed escort. Tom Woodruff Jr. plays the Alien/Grid, and Ian Whyte plays the Predator/Scar and other Predators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fifth-alien-film-and-sequel&#34;&gt;Fifth &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; film and sequel &lt;a href=&#34;#fifth-alien-film-and-sequel&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James Cameron had been working on a fifth &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; film, and Ridley Scott had a concept to explore the origins of the alien creatures. However, upon learning of &lt;em&gt;Alien vs. Predator&lt;/em&gt;, Cameron ceased work, believing it would damage the franchise. Ridley Scott also expressed disinterest in the &lt;em&gt;Alien vs. Predator&lt;/em&gt; films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;development&#34;&gt;Development &lt;a href=&#34;#development&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept originated from the &lt;em&gt;Aliens versus Predator&lt;/em&gt; comic book. Screenwriter Peter Briggs created a spec screenplay in 1990–1991. The project was delayed due to &lt;em&gt;Alien Resurrection&lt;/em&gt;. Paul W. S. Anderson pitched John Davis a story adapting the Machiko Noguchi series. Anderson began working on the film after completing the script for &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil: Apocalypse&lt;/em&gt;, with Shane Salerno co-writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;story-and-setting&#34;&gt;Story and setting &lt;a href=&#34;#story-and-setting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenced by Erich von Däniken and Aztec mythology, Anderson depicted Predators teaching humans to build pyramids and being treated as gods. The Predators would use Earth for rite of passage rituals every 100 years, hunting Aliens. If overwhelmed, the Predators would use self-destruct weapons. H. P. Lovecraft&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;At the Mountains of Madness&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Aliens vs. Predator&lt;/em&gt; comic series influenced the story. The film is set on Bouvet Island in Antarctica.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;casting&#34;&gt;Casting &lt;a href=&#34;#casting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lance Henriksen was the first actor cast, maintaining continuity with the &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; series. He plays Charles Bishop Weyland, tying into the Weyland-Yutani Corporation. Sanaa Lathan was cast as Alexa Woods. Arnold Schwarzenegger was considered for a cameo as Major Alan &amp;ldquo;Dutch&amp;rdquo; Schaeffer from &lt;em&gt;Predator&lt;/em&gt;. Sigourney Weaver declined to participate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;filming-and-set-designs&#34;&gt;Filming and set designs &lt;a href=&#34;#filming-and-set-designs&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Production began in 2003 at Barrandov Studios in Prague. Richard Bridgland designed sets, props, and vehicles. 25 to 30 life-sized sets were constructed, including interiors of the pyramid. The pyramid&amp;rsquo;s designs were influenced by Egyptian, Cambodian, and Aztec civilizations. Miniatures were used to enhance realism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;visual-effects-and-creatures&#34;&gt;Visual effects and creatures &lt;a href=&#34;#visual-effects-and-creatures&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amalgamated Dynamics, Inc. (ADI) designed costumes, miniatures, and effects. The Predators&amp;rsquo; wrist blades were extended, and a larger mechanical plasma caster was created. Each Predator was given a unique mask. A hydraulic Alien puppet was created for faster movements. CGI use was minimized. The Alien queen was filmed using practical, puppet, and computer-generated versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;Music &lt;a href=&#34;#music&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harald Kloser composed the film&amp;rsquo;s score, recorded in London. The score album was released on iTunes and CD, receiving mixed reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;home-media&#34;&gt;Home media &lt;a href=&#34;#home-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien vs. Predator&lt;/em&gt; was released on VHS, DVD, and PSP UMD Movies. The DVD included audio commentaries, a &amp;ldquo;Making of&amp;rdquo; featurette, and deleted scenes. An &amp;ldquo;Extreme Edition&amp;rdquo; and an &amp;ldquo;Unrated Edition&amp;rdquo; were also released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;box-office&#34;&gt;Box office &lt;a href=&#34;#box-office&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien vs. Predator&lt;/em&gt; grossed $177.4 million worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;critical-response&#34;&gt;Critical response &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-response&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received generally negative reviews. Rotten Tomatoes reported 21% positive reviews, with the consensus being &amp;ldquo;Gore without scares and cardboard cut-out characters make this clash of the monsters a dull sit.&amp;rdquo; Metacritic gave the film a score of 29 out of 100, indicating &amp;ldquo;generally unfavorable&amp;rdquo; reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-media&#34;&gt;Other media &lt;a href=&#34;#other-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sequel&#34;&gt;Sequel &lt;a href=&#34;#sequel&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aliens vs. Predator: Requiem&lt;/em&gt; was released in December 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-film&#34;&gt;Related film &lt;a href=&#34;#related-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Predator&lt;/em&gt; (2018) featured Lex Wood&amp;rsquo;s Xenomorph-bone spear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-video-games&#34;&gt;Related video games &lt;a href=&#34;#related-video-games&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several video games were released, including &lt;em&gt;Alien vs. Predator&lt;/em&gt; (mobile) and &lt;em&gt;Aliens vs. Pinball&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_vs._Predator_(film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_vs._Predator_(film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
