<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Berlitz on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/berlitz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Berlitz on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 19:29:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/berlitz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Roswell Incident (1980 book)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_35f31e4c5c9f/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 19:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_35f31e4c5c9f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-roswell-incident-1980-book&#34;&gt;The Roswell Incident (1980 book) &lt;a href=&#34;#the-roswell-incident-1980-book&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This entry details the 1980 book &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt; by Charles Berlitz and William Moore, which popularized stories about the Roswell incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for the Roswell incident, focusing on the events of 1947 and the renewed interest in the story in the late 1970s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;events-of-1947&#34;&gt;Events of 1947 &lt;a href=&#34;#events-of-1947&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This subsection outlines the initial reports of unusual debris recovered near Roswell Army Air Field in July 1947, amidst a broader wave of &amp;ldquo;flying disc&amp;rdquo; sightings. It mentions Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting, the initial press release by Roswell Army Air Field, and the Army&amp;rsquo;s subsequent retraction, claiming the object was a weather balloon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;roswell-revisited&#34;&gt;Roswell revisited &lt;a href=&#34;#roswell-revisited&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This subsection highlights the resurgence of interest in the Roswell story in 1978, sparked by an interview with retired lieutenant colonel Jesse Marcel, who claimed the debris he retrieved was of extraterrestrial origin. Stanton Friedman, a ufologist, is also mentioned in this context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;authors&#34;&gt;Authors &lt;a href=&#34;#authors&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides background information on the authors of the book, Charles Berlitz and William Moore. It notes Berlitz&amp;rsquo;s previous success with &lt;em&gt;The Bermuda Triangle&lt;/em&gt;, a book that popularized the Bermuda Triangle mystery. It also mentions their collaboration on &lt;em&gt;The Philadelphia Experiment: Project Invisibility&lt;/em&gt;, which promoted the Philadelphia Experiment conspiracy theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents &lt;a href=&#34;#contents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the book&amp;rsquo;s central argument: that an extraterrestrial craft crashed near Roswell while observing nuclear weapons activity, and that the US government engaged in a cover-up. It mentions accounts of debris described as &amp;ldquo;nothing made on this earth&amp;rdquo; and includes testimonies from Bill Brazel, Floyd Proctor, and Walt Whitman Jr. It also introduces the idea that the debris shown in photos with Marcel was substituted as part of a cover-up. The section also notes that the authors claimed to have interviewed over 90 witnesses, but only a fraction of their testimonies appear in the book. The incarceration of Mac Brazel is also mentioned. The section also notes that the book elevated Marcel&amp;rsquo;s narrative above that of Cavitt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-bodies&#34;&gt;Alien bodies &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-bodies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the book&amp;rsquo;s introduction of the &amp;ldquo;Barnett Legend,&amp;rdquo; involving Grady &amp;ldquo;Barney&amp;rdquo; Barnett and archaeology students encountering wreckage and &amp;ldquo;alien bodies&amp;rdquo; on the Plains of San Agustin, far from the initial Roswell crash site. It also mentions the conflation of the Roswell incident with the Aztec, New Mexico, UFO incident, a hoax promoted by Frank Scully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the critical reception of &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt;, noting that some critics deemed it &amp;ldquo;a collection of wild hearsay&amp;rdquo; and questioned the authenticity of the Majestic 12 documents, pointing fingers at Moore. It also notes that the book did not achieve the commercial success its authors anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aftermath&#34;&gt;Aftermath &lt;a href=&#34;#aftermath&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section mentions Moore&amp;rsquo;s later admission at a MUFON conference in 1989 that he had engaged in &amp;ldquo;disinformation&amp;rdquo; activities against Paul Bennewitz on behalf of the Air Force Office of Special Investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modern-views&#34;&gt;Modern views &lt;a href=&#34;#modern-views&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section briefly mentions the 1993 inquiry by the General Accounting Office in response to US congressman Steven Schiff, and the subsequent 1994 Air Force report concluding that the recovered material was likely debris from Project Mogul, a military surveillance program using high-altitude balloons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Roswell_Incident_(1980_book)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Roswell_Incident_(1980_book)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
