<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adaptation on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/adaptation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Adaptation on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 22:46:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/adaptation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Nation Comic Books</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f43d477afc2e/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 22:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f43d477afc2e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-nation-comic-books&#34;&gt;Alien Nation Comic Books &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-nation-comic-books&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the comic book adaptations and spin-offs based on the &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt; franchise, which originated with the 1988 film. DC Comics initially published a single-issue adaptation of the film, followed by a series of spin-off titles by Malibu Comics under their Adventure Comics imprint from 1990 to 1992.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publications&#34;&gt;Publications &lt;a href=&#34;#publications&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a table listing all the &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt; comic book titles, their creators, publisher, number of issues, publication dates, and additional notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alien Nation (DC Comics):&lt;/strong&gt; A one-shot comic written by Martin Pasko with art by Jerry Bingham, adapting the original film written by Rockne S. O&amp;rsquo;Bannon. It was released in December 1988.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alien Nation: The Spartans:&lt;/strong&gt; A 4-issue mini-series published by Adventure Comics (Malibu Comics imprint) from July to November 1990. It was written by Bill Spangler with art by James Tucker and was also released as a trade paperback. The story involves Ruth Lawrence of the Newcomer Advocacy League investigating the disappearance of Art Deco, the brother of Newcomer Harvey Wallbanger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alien Nation: A Breed Apart:&lt;/strong&gt; A 4-issue mini-series published by Adventure Comics (Malibu Comics imprint) from November 1990 to March 1991. It was written by Steve Jones with art by Stan Timmons and Jimmy Palmiotti. The story follows LAPD detectives Wayne Hadenfelt and Log B&amp;rsquo;Omen as they investigate a home invasion that appears to be a gangland assassination. The mini-series ended on an unresolved cliffhanger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alien Nation: The Skin Trade:&lt;/strong&gt; A 4-issue mini-series published by Adventure Comics (Malibu Comics imprint) from March to June 1991. It was written by Lowell Cunningham with art by Leonard Kirk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ape Nation:&lt;/strong&gt; A 4-issue mini-series published by Adventure Comics (Malibu Comics imprint) from February to June 1991. It was written by Charles Marshall with art by M.C. Wyman. This series is a crossover with &lt;em&gt;Planet of the Apes&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alien Nation: The Firstcomers:&lt;/strong&gt; A 4-issue mini-series published by Adventure Comics (Malibu Comics imprint) from May to August 1991. It was written by Martin Powell with art by Tim Eldred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alien Nation: The Public Enemy:&lt;/strong&gt; A 4-issue mini-series published by Adventure Comics (Malibu Comics imprint) from December 1991 to March 1991. It was written by Lowell Cunningham with art by Sandy Carruthers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alien Nation Television Special: The Lost Episode:&lt;/strong&gt; A one-shot comic published by Malibu Graphics in 1992. It was written by Bill Spangler with art by Terry Pallot. The comic is based on &amp;ldquo;Soul Train,&amp;rdquo; a script from the unproduced second season of the &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt; TV series, written by Diane Frolov and Andrew Schneider. The premise and elements of this script were later used in the &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation: Dark Horizon&lt;/em&gt; TV movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a link to the &amp;ldquo;List of comics based on films&amp;rdquo; Wikipedia page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the references used in the article, including &amp;ldquo;Batman Unmasked: Analyzing a Cultural Icon&amp;rdquo; by Will Brooker (2001).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides an external link to &amp;ldquo;Welcome Back to the Planet of the Apes,&amp;rdquo; an article from &lt;em&gt;Comics Scene&lt;/em&gt; #13 (1990) about the Adventure Comics run on &lt;em&gt;Planet of the Apes&lt;/em&gt;, including &lt;em&gt;Ape Nation&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Nation_(comics)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Nation_(comics)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
