<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hearings on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/hearings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hearings on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 13:17:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/hearings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2022 United States Congress hearings on UFOs</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cacc9618f5eb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 13:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cacc9618f5eb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;2022-united-states-congressional-hearings-on-unexplained-aerial-phenomena&#34;&gt;2022 United States Congressional Hearings on Unexplained Aerial Phenomena &lt;a href=&#34;#2022-united-states-congressional-hearings-on-unexplained-aerial-phenomena&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the United States congressional hearings held on May 17, 2022, by the House Intelligence Subcommittee on Counterterrorism, Counterintelligence, and Counterproliferation to discuss military reports of Unexplained Aerial Phenomena (UAPs). It was the first public congressional hearing on UFO sightings in the US in over 50 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides the historical context leading up to the 2022 hearings. It mentions the last public congressional hearing on UAPs in 1969, initiated by then-congressman Gerald Ford in 1966. Project Blue Book, a U.S. Air Force program investigating UFOs, was disbanded in 1969. The section also notes the 2017 reports of Pentagon investigations into UAPs and the 2020 COVID-19 relief bill that mandated a report on UAPs from US intelligence agencies. The unclassified report released in June 2021 is highlighted, noting its conclusion that 144 incidents defied explanation and called for further investigation. Finally, the establishment of the Airborne Object Identification and Management Synchronization Group (AOIMSG) in November 2021 and the provisions in the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022 and the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2022, for a permanent agency to investigate UAPs are mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hearings&#34;&gt;Hearings &lt;a href=&#34;#hearings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the events of the May 17, 2022, congressional hearings. Rep. André Carson, chairman of the subcommittee, opened the hearing, expressing concerns about national security threats posed by UAPs and criticizing the Pentagon&amp;rsquo;s lack of updates and leadership for the AOIMSG. Testimony was given by Under Secretary of Defense for Intelligence and Security Ronald S. Moultrie and Deputy Director of Naval Intelligence Scott Bray. Bray stated that reported sightings had grown to about 400 since the previous year&amp;rsquo;s report and dismissed extraterrestrial origins. He also noted no collisions had been reported. The section mentions that other countries have similar reports and communicate with U.S. intelligence agencies. Moultrie emphasized the need for cooperation with the Federal Aviation Administration and other government agencies. Declassified images and footage of UFOs were shown, including a video of a &amp;ldquo;spherical object&amp;rdquo; and triangular objects seen through night-vision goggles. Concerns about potential Russian or Chinese hypersonic weapons programs were raised by lawmakers like Rick Crawford. The standardization of civilian reporting was discussed. The public portion of the hearing was followed by a private classified session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reactions&#34;&gt;Reactions &lt;a href=&#34;#reactions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the reactions to the congressional hearings. Rep. Tim Burchett criticized the Pentagon&amp;rsquo;s transparency and dismissiveness of extraterrestrial explanations. UFO skeptic Robert Sheaffer derided the footage shown at the hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external resources related to the hearings, including the event page on Congress.gov, the hearing on C-SPAN, and a YouTube video of the hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2022_United_States_Congress_hearings_on_UFOs&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2022_United_States_Congress_hearings_on_UFOs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
