<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Astronauts on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/astronauts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Astronauts on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 18:53:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/astronauts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in outer space</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8bf289ccb939/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 18:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8bf289ccb939/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-sightings-in-outer-space&#34;&gt;UFO Sightings in Outer Space &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-sightings-in-outer-space&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses reported sightings of Unidentified Flying Objects (UFOs) by astronauts while in space. These sightings are often cited by ufologists as potential evidence of extraterrestrial life. However, the article also presents counterarguments and explanations for these sightings, often attributing them to misidentified objects, debris, or other natural phenomena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;incidents&#34;&gt;Incidents &lt;a href=&#34;#incidents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details specific instances where astronauts have reported seeing unusual objects during space missions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gemini 4:&lt;/strong&gt; Pilot Jim McDivitt reported seeing a &amp;ldquo;white cylindrical shape with a white pole&amp;rdquo; and took pictures. McDivitt believes it was man-made debris, while James Oberg suggests it was the Titan II second stage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gemini 7:&lt;/strong&gt; Astronauts mentioned a &amp;ldquo;bogey&amp;rdquo; in a transcript, which some ufologists interpreted as a UFO. James Oberg argues it was booster debris. Astronaut Frank Borman confirmed it was not a UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apollo 11:&lt;/strong&gt; Stories circulated about Neil Armstrong witnessing UFOs during the Apollo 11 mission. Armstrong claimed he saw two blue pale glowing orbs. Explanations suggest these could have been jettisoned components. Science fiction writer Otto Binder perpetuated a hoax about this event. Buzz Aldrin clarified that he observed a light alongside the crew.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;International Space Station (2005):&lt;/strong&gt; Astronaut Leroy Chiao reported seeing lights in a formation during a spacewalk. Initially promoted as a possible UFO sighting, Chiao later identified the lights as fishing boats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;International Space Station (2013):&lt;/strong&gt; Astronaut Christopher Cassidy reportedly saw a UFO near the Progress 52 cargo ship. Russian flight controllers identified it as an antenna cover from the Zvezda service module.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;International Space Station (2020):&lt;/strong&gt; Cosmonaut Ivan Vagner posted a video on Twitter featuring UFOs on a time-lapse of the Aurora Australis, dubbing them &amp;ldquo;space guests.&amp;rdquo; He later clarified that they seemed to be satellites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to related Wikipedia articles, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of reported UFO sightings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;STS-48 (specifically mentioning ice particles)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited within the article, including news articles, scientific papers, and websites. Key references include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NBC News article debunking myths about Neil Armstrong&amp;rsquo;s UFO sightings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Oberg&amp;rsquo;s analysis of astronaut UFO sightings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Popular Mechanics article discussing NASA&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; videos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huffington Post article about astronaut Leroy Chiao&amp;rsquo;s UFO sighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fox News report on NASA identifying a UFO as an antenna cover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CTV News report on Cosmonaut Ivan Vagner&amp;rsquo;s video of apparent UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of additional resources for readers interested in learning more about UFO sightings in outer space. These include books, articles, and online resources. Key entries include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Franklin E. Roach&amp;rsquo;s chapter on visual observations made by U.S. astronauts in the Condon Report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James R. Hansen&amp;rsquo;s biography of Neil Armstrong, which discusses the Apollo 11 UFO incidents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Oberg&amp;rsquo;s article &amp;ldquo;Astronauts and UFOs: The whole story.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;em&gt;The Demon-Haunted World: Science as a Candle in the Dark&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external websites related to UFO sightings and NASA&amp;rsquo;s perspective on the topic. Key links include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NASA&amp;rsquo;s Solar System Exploration Research Virtual Institute page on Buzz Aldrin&amp;rsquo;s UFO sighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NASA&amp;rsquo;s Solar System Exploration Research Virtual Institute page on the Apollo 11 UFO sighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Oberg&amp;rsquo;s website with frequently asked questions about astronauts and UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NASA News Topics article titled &amp;ldquo;UFO No longer unidentified.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufos-template&#34;&gt;UFOs Template &lt;a href=&#34;#ufos-template&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a template linking to various UFO-related topics on Wikipedia, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ufology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claimed sightings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Types of UFOs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Types of alleged extraterrestrial beings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Studies and timeline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hypotheses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conspiracy theories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Involvement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Culture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skepticism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Government &amp;amp; Law&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_outer_space&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_outer_space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
