<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hypothetical Planets on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/hypothetical-planets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hypothetical Planets on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 17:45:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/hypothetical-planets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Planetary objects proposed in religion, astrology, ufology and pseudoscience</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_2684e1d7f984/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_2684e1d7f984/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;non-scientific-hypothetical-objects&#34;&gt;Non-scientific hypothetical objects &lt;a href=&#34;#non-scientific-hypothetical-objects&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses planetary objects proposed in religion, astrology, ufology, and pseudoscience that lack scientific evidence. It distinguishes these from scientifically accepted hypothetical astronomical objects and fictional planets in science fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;kolob&#34;&gt;Kolob &lt;a href=&#34;#kolob&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kolob is a star or planet described in the Book of Abraham, a sacred text in the Latter Day Saint movement. While the Book of Abraham refers to Kolob as a &amp;ldquo;star,&amp;rdquo; it also refers to planets as stars, leading Latter Day Saints to commonly view Kolob as a planet. It is described as the heavenly body closest to the throne of God and is said to have &amp;ldquo;signified&amp;rdquo; the first creation according to Joseph Smith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lilith&#34;&gt;Lilith &lt;a href=&#34;#lilith&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lilith is a fictitious, invisible moon of Earth proposed in 1918 by astrologer Walter Gorn Old (Sepharial). Sepharial claimed Lilith was the same second moon that scientist Georg Waltemath claimed to have discovered twenty years earlier, but which was never confirmed. Sepharial claimed to be the first to observe Waltemath&amp;rsquo;s moon crossing the Sun. The scientific community had already discredited Waltemath&amp;rsquo;s proposed moon. While fringe groups believe in Lilith&amp;rsquo;s existence, astrologers now generally use the name for the position of the Moon&amp;rsquo;s apogee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-modern-astrology&#34;&gt;In modern astrology &lt;a href=&#34;#in-modern-astrology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In modern astrology, &amp;ldquo;Lilith&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Black Moon Lilith&amp;rdquo; refers to a point on the horoscope representing the Moon&amp;rsquo;s apogee. This point is sometimes defined as the second focus of the ellipse described by the Moon&amp;rsquo;s orbit. It takes approximately 8 years and 10 months for this point to complete a circuit through the zodiac, tracking the apsidal precession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;planets-proposed-by-l-ron-hubbard&#34;&gt;Planets proposed by L. Ron Hubbard &lt;a href=&#34;#planets-proposed-by-l-ron-hubbard&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L. Ron Hubbard, the founder of Scientology, proposed a Galactic Confederacy as part of his cosmology. This confederacy consisted of 26 stars and 76 planets, including Earth, then known as &amp;ldquo;Teegeeack.&amp;rdquo; Helatrobus is another planet mentioned in Scientology doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ummo&#34;&gt;Ummo &lt;a href=&#34;#ummo&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ummo is a hypothetical planet believed to be located in the Constellation Virgo. A series of claims describe aliens from Ummo communicating with people on Earth through detailed documents and letters. The Ummo affair gained attention in France and Spain during the 1960s. Ummoism refers to groups interested in studying the ideas presented in the Ummo letters. José Luis Jordán Peña has claimed responsibility for writing the letters and instigating Ummoism, leading many to believe Ummo is a hoax. Jacques Vallée compared the Ummo documents to Borges&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;Tlön, Uqbar, Orbis Tertius.&amp;rdquo; Mike Dash notes that Ummoism began on February 6, 1966, in Madrid, when Jordán Peña claimed to have seen a circular object with a symbol resembling the alchemical sign for Uranus. Fernando Sesma Manzano, a contactee, became involved after receiving documents purportedly from the Ummites. Jean-Pierre Petit claims to have detected signs of superior intelligence in the Ummite writings and that they have inspired his research in cosmology and magnetohydrodynamics. Antonio Ribera compiled 403 Ummo words in 1978, and Jean Pollion listed over a thousand words in 2002.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two theories have been formulated by analysts of Ummite letters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jean Pollion considers each letter (sound or phoneme) in words transcribed in typewritten form to be signifying, calling these sounds &amp;ldquo;soncepts&amp;rdquo; and considering the language to be &amp;ldquo;ideophonemic.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The second theory considers that differences in spelling are of little significance and are due to differences in the understanding of foreign sounds by the typist(s), or to difficulties in alphabetic transcription, considering that language is made up of word-objects and not of &amp;ldquo;soncepts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 1300 pages of letters have been registered, with references to 3850 pages in a 1988 letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dash notes that the photographic evidence was suspect, and the letters, while sophisticated, could have originated on Earth. Jerome Clark notes that Jacques Vallée argued that the scientific content of the Ummo letters was knowledgeable but unremarkable, comparing the scientific references to a well-researched science fiction novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The controversy over an &amp;ldquo;error&amp;rdquo; in the distance from Wolf 424 arose from the first letter, referenced D21 (May 1966), which states that the distance used by terrestrial astronomers is different from the real distance in decadimensional space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;planets-proposed-by-zecharia-sitchin&#34;&gt;Planets proposed by Zecharia Sitchin &lt;a href=&#34;#planets-proposed-by-zecharia-sitchin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zecharia Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s work has gained attention among ufologists, ancient astronaut theorists, and conspiracy theorists. He claimed to have found evidence in Sumerian texts that the human race was visited/created by extraterrestrials from a distant planet in the Solar System. He interpreted the Babylonian creation myth, the &lt;em&gt;Enuma Elish&lt;/em&gt;, by replacing the names of gods with hypothetical planets. Academics consider his work pseudoscience and pseudohistory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s theory proposes the planets Tiamat and Nibiru. Tiamat supposedly existed between Mars and Jupiter, and its orbit was disrupted by the arrival of Nibiru. The collision of Tiamat with one of Nibiru&amp;rsquo;s moons supposedly formed the asteroid belt and Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitchin claimed the Babylonians associated Nibiru with the god Marduk. He hypothesized it as a planet in a highly elliptic orbit around the Sun, with a perihelion passage some 3,600 years ago and an orbital period of about 3,450 years. He also claimed it was the home of the Anunnaki, a technologically advanced alien race who visited Earth in search of gold and created humanity by genetically crossing themselves with primates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Websites such as ZetaTalk have claimed that Nibiru or &amp;ldquo;Planet X&amp;rdquo; is a brown dwarf within our planetary system, soon to pass close to Earth. Sitchin disagreed that it is a star, with the timing and parameters of passage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitchin also postulated that Pluto began life as Gaga, a satellite of Saturn, which was flung into orbit beyond Neptune due to Nibiru&amp;rsquo;s passing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;serpo&#34;&gt;Serpo &lt;a href=&#34;#serpo&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project Serpo is an alleged top-secret exchange program between the United States government and an alien planet called Serpo in the Zeta Reticuli star system. Details of the alleged exchange program have appeared in UFO conspiracy stories, including an incident in 1983 involving Richard C. Doty and Linda Moulton Howe, and emails sent to a UFO discussion group run by Victor Martinez in 2005. Some versions state that Serpo is the nickname of the extrasolar planet, while others claim it is a mispronunciation of Serponia or Seinu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first mention of Project Serpo was in a UFO email list maintained by Victor Martinez. According to the story, an alien survived a crash near Roswell in the late 1940s and was repatriated, leading to a relationship between the American government and the people of its home world in the Zeta Reticuli system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story claims that twelve American military personnel visited the planet between 1965 and 1978 and that all have since died from radiation levels from the two suns. Another version claims that eight team members returned, one died en route, one died on the planet, and two decided to remain on Serpo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Criticism of Project Serpo stems from the lack of veracity of Richard Doty, who has been involved in other UFO-related activities and is considered a discredited source. There is no physical evidence supporting the project&amp;rsquo;s existence. Tim Swartz of &lt;em&gt;Mysteries Magazine&lt;/em&gt; expressed that the details of Project Serpo have varied considerably with different accounts. It has been alleged that the entire series of posts were designed to be viral marketing for a new book by Doty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill Ryan, a proponent of publicizing the Project Serpo claims, stepped down from his role as webmaster for the Serpo material but maintains his belief that an extraterrestrial exchange program did occur, although the Serpo releases contained disinformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planetary_objects_proposed_in_religion,_astrology,_ufology_and_pseudoscience&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planetary_objects_proposed_in_religion,_astrology,_ufology_and_pseudoscience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
