<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Air Force on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/air-force/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Air Force on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 12:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/air-force/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Big Sur UFO</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_76b62dd0f587/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 12:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_76b62dd0f587/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-big-sur-ufo&#34;&gt;The Big Sur UFO &lt;a href=&#34;#the-big-sur-ufo&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details a reported UFO incident that allegedly occurred during a 1964 Air Force mission near Big Sur, California. The Air Force team was stationed on a mountaintop to film Atlas missile tests from Vandenberg Air Force Base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;air-force-deployment-to-anderson-peak&#34;&gt;Air Force deployment to Anderson Peak &lt;a href=&#34;#air-force-deployment-to-anderson-peak&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From August to November 1964, the U.S. Air Force deployed personnel to the Los Padres National Forest in California. They used a special telescope borrowed from Boston University to photograph missile launches from Vandenberg Air Force Base. Lt. Robert Jacobs was the commander for the Big Sur location, managed by the 1369th Photo Squadron. The team successfully filmed nine launches, including one of an Atlas missile called &amp;ldquo;Buzzing Bee,&amp;rdquo; capturing footage of a re-entry vehicle deploying decoy warheads. This technology was highly classified and designed to protect American nuclear weapons from Soviet interception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fringe-claims-of-extra-terrestrials&#34;&gt;Fringe claims of extra-terrestrials &lt;a href=&#34;#fringe-claims-of-extra-terrestrials&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1982, Robert Jacobs wrote about the incident in the tabloid &lt;em&gt;National Enquirer&lt;/em&gt;, claiming he had been part of a cover-up and was now breaking his silence. He described film footage of an unidentified object next to a warhead and a senior official&amp;rsquo;s reaction. Jacobs claimed he was instructed to never discuss the film. Major Florenz Mansmann reportedly confirmed Jacobs&amp;rsquo; account in a 1987 letter. Robert Hastings, a UFO author, further popularized the story in 2007. In 2021, Jacobs participated in a press conference to discuss his interpretation of the incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;decoy-warheads-explanation&#34;&gt;Decoy warheads explanation &lt;a href=&#34;#decoy-warheads-explanation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kingston A. George, the project engineer during the incident, disputed Jacob&amp;rsquo;s claims of extraterrestrial interference in the &lt;em&gt;Skeptical Inquirer&lt;/em&gt;. George stated that he, too, had seen footage he wasn&amp;rsquo;t cleared to see and was instructed not to speak of it. However, George claims he knew the true purpose of the test: filming the deployment of decoy warheads and chaff to confuse enemy air defenses. He attributed the lights Jacobs reported to the explosive deployment of decoys and chaff, not a UFO energy beam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including articles from Military.com, Skeptical Inquirer, National Enquirer, and MUFON UFO Journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the &amp;ldquo;Malmstrom UFO incident&amp;rdquo; Wikipedia page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Sur_UFO&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Sur_UFO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chiles-Whitted UFO encounter</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_d56305523c82/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 06:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_d56305523c82/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chiles-whitted-ufo-encounter&#34;&gt;Chiles-Whitted UFO encounter &lt;a href=&#34;#chiles-whitted-ufo-encounter&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chiles-Whitted UFO encounter occurred on July 24, 1948, at approximately 2:45 AM near Montgomery, Alabama. Two commercial pilots, Clarence S. Chiles and John B. Whitted, reported seeing a &amp;ldquo;glowing object&amp;rdquo; fly past their plane. The object appeared to ascend into a cloud and disappear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-incident&#34;&gt;The incident &lt;a href=&#34;#the-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the morning of July 24, 1948, Clarence Chiles and John Whitted were flying a Douglas DC-3 passenger plane for Eastern Air Lines near Montgomery, Alabama, at an altitude of about 5,000 feet. Chiles noticed a red glow above and ahead of the aircraft. The object quickly approached their plane, and both pilots observed it passing by the right side at high speed. They said it then ascended into the clouds with a burst of flame. The pilots estimated they observed the object for ten to fifteen seconds. They described it as a wingless aircraft, approximately 100 feet long and 25–30 feet in diameter, with two rows of bright windows and flames coming from its tail. One passenger, C.L. McKelvie, reported seeing a bright streak of light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;investigation-and-explanation&#34;&gt;Investigation and explanation &lt;a href=&#34;#investigation-and-explanation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After landing in Atlanta, Georgia, Chiles and Whitted reported their sighting to the United States Air Force (USAF). They were interviewed by Project Sign personnel, the Air Force&amp;rsquo;s initial UFO investigation group. The pilots disagreed on some details; Chiles described a lighted cockpit, a long boom on the object&amp;rsquo;s nose, and a transparent center section, while Whitted did not see a cockpit or boom and described rectangular windows instead of a transparent section. Neither pilot heard any sound, and the plane was not affected by turbulence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USAF Captain Edward Ruppelt noted the report significantly impacted the Air Technical Intelligence Center (ATIC). Project Sign created a trajectory map indicating the object would have passed over Macon, Georgia. An Air Force crew chief at Robins Air Force Base near Macon reported seeing a bright light moving at high speed on the same night, seemingly corroborating the Chiles-Whitted sighting. Project Sign personnel drafted an &amp;ldquo;Estimate of the Situation,&amp;rdquo; concluding that UFOs were interplanetary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Air Force Chief of Staff Hoyt S. Vandenberg rejected the Estimate of the Situation in October 1948, citing insufficient evidence. J. Allen Hynek, an astronomer and consultant to Project Sign, suggested the pilots had seen a bright meteor. He noted that the flaming tail and sudden disappearance aligned with meteor behavior and that many bright meteors were observed that night. He speculated that the pilots&amp;rsquo; perception of windows and a cockpit could be a subjective impression caused by the meteor&amp;rsquo;s trail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astronomer Donald Menzel pointed out that the sighting occurred during a period of increased meteor activity, specifically the Aquarid streams. He noted reports of numerous meteors in the Southeast on July 24. Menzel argued that the pilots misinterpreted an unusually bright meteor, its body glowing intensely and emitting flaming gases. He cited a similar experience of another pilot in 1959 who recognized a fiery object as a meteor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFO skeptic Philip Klass supported the meteor explanation, criticizing Project Sign&amp;rsquo;s initial conclusion. While ufologist James E. McDonald interviewed Chiles and Whitted in the 1960s and disagreed with the meteor explanation, the USAF, based on the analysis of Hynek, Menzel, and others, officially attributed the Chiles-Whitted incident to a fireball-type meteor in 1959.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chiles-Whitted_UFO_encounter&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chiles-Whitted_UFO_encounter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
