<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Comic on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/comic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Comic on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 03:42:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/comic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Nation</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ecb551d0af0a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 03:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ecb551d0af0a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-nation&#34;&gt;Alien Nation &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-nation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt; is an American science fiction media franchise created by Rockne S. O&amp;rsquo;Bannon, known for &lt;em&gt;Farscape&lt;/em&gt;. The franchise, owned by 20th Century Studios, encompasses film, television, novels, and comics centered around alien refugees living on Earth. It blends science fiction with elements of drama, police procedural, and buddy cop genres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting&#34;&gt;Setting &lt;a href=&#34;#setting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The franchise is set in the near future in the United States, specifically starting in 1991. A flying saucer crashes in the Mojave Desert, revealing the Tenctonese, an extraterrestrial race referred to as &amp;ldquo;Newcomers.&amp;rdquo; These aliens are escaping slavery from a cruel Overseer race. The Tenctonese resemble humans but possess anatomical differences and enhanced physical and intellectual capabilities due to selective breeding. The core concept revolves around the Newcomers&amp;rsquo; integration into American society, exploring themes of multiculturalism and acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;film&#34;&gt;Film &lt;a href=&#34;#film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The franchise began with the 1988 film &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt;, released by 20th Century Fox. The film depicts the integration of the Tenctonese refugees, or Newcomers, into human society in Los Angeles. It combines science fiction and police drama elements. The film stars Mandy Patinkin as Sam &amp;ldquo;George&amp;rdquo; Francisco, a Newcomer detective in the Los Angeles Police Department, and James Caan as Matthew Sykes, his initially reluctant human partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;television&#34;&gt;Television &lt;a href=&#34;#television&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1989, Fox adapted the film into a television series, also called &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt;. The series follows the same premise as the film, focusing on the Newcomers&amp;rsquo; integration after their ship crashes on Earth. Eric Pierpoint stars as George Francisco, and Gary Graham as Matthew Sikes. The series explores themes of racism and the treatment of minority ethnic groups. The series ran for one season of 21 episodes and a pilot episode, ending in 1990. Fox abruptly cancelled the series after the season. Beginning in 1994, the network continued the story in five TV movies, which brought back the entire cast. The installments include &lt;em&gt;Dark Horizon&lt;/em&gt; (1994), &lt;em&gt;Body and Soul&lt;/em&gt; (1995), &lt;em&gt;Millennium&lt;/em&gt; (1996), &lt;em&gt;The Enemy Within&lt;/em&gt; (1996), and &lt;em&gt;The Udara Legacy&lt;/em&gt; (1997).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;novels&#34;&gt;Novels &lt;a href=&#34;#novels&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pocket Books, a division of Simon &amp;amp; Schuster, published a novel series connected to the franchise starting in 1993. Judith and Garfield Reeves-Stevens, known for their work in &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;, wrote a novel entitled &lt;em&gt;Day of Descent&lt;/em&gt;. Some novels served as prequels to the movie sequels, such as K.W. Jeter&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Cross of Blood&lt;/em&gt;, a tie-in to the &lt;em&gt;Dark Horizon&lt;/em&gt; film, and Peter David&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Body and Soul&lt;/em&gt;, which became one of the sequels of the same name. The novels regularly addressed racism and discrimination with extraterrestrial themes. K. W. Jeter and Barry B. Longyear were regular contributors to the series with novels like, &lt;em&gt;The Change&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Slag Like Me&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comics&#34;&gt;Comics &lt;a href=&#34;#comics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 1990 to 1992, Malibu Comics published several comics adapting the &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt; storyline. Among the first released titles were &lt;em&gt;The Spartans&lt;/em&gt;, created with the help of author Bill Spangler and illustrator James Tucker, and &lt;em&gt;A Breed Apart&lt;/em&gt;, authored by Steve Jones. Other titles included &lt;em&gt;Public Enemy&lt;/em&gt;, authored by Sandy Carruthers and illustrated by Lowell Cunningham, and a crossover series with the &lt;em&gt;Planet of the Apes&lt;/em&gt; franchise titled &lt;em&gt;Ape Nation&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;Ape Nation&lt;/em&gt; series included four different adventures called &lt;em&gt;Plans&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Pasts&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Pawns&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Pains&lt;/em&gt; along with a collector&amp;rsquo;s edition. Other contributors to the series included illustrators Terry Pallott and Leonard Kirk to titles like, &lt;em&gt;The Skin Trade&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;remake&#34;&gt;Remake &lt;a href=&#34;#remake&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On March 25, 2015, Fox announced a remake with Art Marcum and Matt Holloway writing. On September 9, 2016, &lt;em&gt;Deadline&lt;/em&gt; reported that Jeff Nichols would write and direct the film. On January 25, 2021, it was announced that Jeff Nichols would remake the film as a ten-part television series. On June 21, 2024, it was reported Nichols was developing an original sci-fi feature film for Paramount instead of an Alien Nation project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Nation&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Nation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flying saucer</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1b2fc7b45b2e/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1b2fc7b45b2e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;purported-disk-shaped-aircraft&#34;&gt;Purported disk-shaped aircraft &lt;a href=&#34;#purported-disk-shaped-aircraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article focuses on the &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;flying disc&amp;rdquo; as a specific type of unidentified flying object (UFO). It clarifies that the term, popularized in 1947, is distinct from the more general terms UFO or UAP (unidentified anomalous phenomena). The article includes a photograph of an alleged flying saucer taken over Passaic, New Jersey, in 1952.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;precursors&#34;&gt;Precursors &lt;a href=&#34;#precursors&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the historical roots of the flying saucer concept, predating the 1947 coining of the term. It mentions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mysterious lights in the sky interpreted as spiritual phenomena in antiquity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;19th-century newspaper reports of massive airships with lights and humming engines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John Martin&amp;rsquo;s 1878 report in the &lt;em&gt;Denison Daily News&lt;/em&gt; describing an object resembling a saucer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mystery airship sightings in America during 1896 and 1897.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Foo fighters&amp;rdquo; reported by Allied pilots during World War II.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The appearance of flying discs in science fiction, citing Jean de La Hire&amp;rsquo;s 1908 novel &lt;em&gt;La Roue fulgurante&lt;/em&gt; and &amp;ldquo;The Shaver Mystery&amp;rdquo; stories in &lt;em&gt;Amazing Stories&lt;/em&gt; magazine by Richard Sharpe Shaver and Raymond A. Palmer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fantasy artwork in pulp magazines depicting flying discs, with specific mention of Frank R. Paul&amp;rsquo;s cover for the November 1929 issue of &lt;em&gt;Science Wonder Stories&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;origins&#34;&gt;Origins &lt;a href=&#34;#origins&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the origin of the modern flying saucer concept, tracing it back to the Kenneth Arnold UFO sighting in 1947. Key points include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting of nine unusual airborne objects near Yakima, Washington, on June 24, 1947.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Newspaper reports describing the objects as &amp;ldquo;saucer-like.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arnold&amp;rsquo;s description of their movement as &amp;ldquo;like a saucer skipping across the water.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The coining of the terms &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;flying disk&amp;rdquo; by headline writers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The subsequent wave of flying saucer reports across the United States.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donald S. Whitehead&amp;rsquo;s sighting of a fast-moving object resembling a meteor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The United Airlines crew sighting on July 4 of nine disc-like objects over Idaho.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initial public speculation about the objects being experimental aircraft or Soviet weapons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The spread of the stories to other countries, influenced by local political and social concerns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Twin Falls saucer hoax, where teenagers fabricated a crashed disc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Roswell UFO incident, involving the recovery of a &amp;ldquo;flying disc&amp;rdquo; by the Army Air Force.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The establishment of Project SAUCER (later Project Sign) by the Air Force to investigate the reports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;development&#34;&gt;Development &lt;a href=&#34;#development&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the evolution of the flying saucer concept and its association with extraterrestrial life. Key points include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The association of flying saucers with extraterrestrial life by the 1950s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US Air Force&amp;rsquo;s investigation into the possibility of an alien origin after the Clarence Chiles and John Whitted sighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s belief that the objects were of extraterrestrial origin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meade Layne&amp;rsquo;s speculation that they came from an alternate dimension.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The influence of pulp science fiction on beliefs about flying saucers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ray Palmer&amp;rsquo;s transition from publishing the Shaver Mystery to organizing UFO investigations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fred Crisman&amp;rsquo;s letters about encounters with underground beings and the Maury Island incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The emergence of the &amp;ldquo;men in black&amp;rdquo; trope, popularized by Gray Barker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The launch of &lt;em&gt;Fate&lt;/em&gt; magazine by Palmer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The development of a flying saucer movement influenced by science, occult practices, pop culture, existing religions, and earlier myths.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The emergence of contactees such as George Van Tassel, George Adamski, and Truman Bethurum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The construction of the Integratron by Van Tassel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The founding of the Aetherius Society by George King.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The incorporation of flying saucers into existing religions, such as the Nation of Islam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speculation about ancient astronauts piloting UFOs, with mention of Robert Dione and Erich von Däniken.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The development of ufology as a parallel social movement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The publication of &lt;em&gt;Behind the Flying Saucers&lt;/em&gt; by Frank Scully and &lt;em&gt;The Flying Saucers Are Real&lt;/em&gt; by Donald Keyhoe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Life&lt;/em&gt; magazine article &amp;ldquo;Have We Visitors From Space?&amp;rdquo; and the subsequent wave of sightings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The formation of UFO investigation groups such as the Civilian Investigating Group for Aerial Phenomena by Leonard H. Stringfield and the International Flying Saucer Bureau by Albert K. Bender.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The spread of reports to other countries and the emergence of local groups and ufologists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The emergence of UFO photography as a subgenre of documentary photography, with mention of the McMinnville photographs, the Passaic UFO photographs, and the photographs of George Adamski.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The identification of some alleged flying saucer photographs as hoaxes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walther Johannes Riedel&amp;rsquo;s analysis of George Adamski&amp;rsquo;s UFO photos, revealing them to be faked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gradual supplanting of &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; by &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; and later &amp;ldquo;UAP.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description &lt;a href=&#34;#description&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;identification&#34;&gt;Identification &lt;a href=&#34;#identification&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the identification of flying saucer and UFO reports with known phenomena. Key points include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The identification of the majority of reports with known phenomena by experts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;British government investigations finding that most reports were misidentifications or hoaxes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common explanations for saucer sightings, including the planet Venus, weather phenomena, balloons, and airborne trash.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US Navy and General Mills&amp;rsquo; launch of Skyhook spy balloons, which were often mistaken for flying saucers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The death of Kentucky Air National Guard pilot Thomas Mantell while pursuing an object later identified as a Skyhook balloon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psychological studies on why people believed in flying saucers, with mention of Georges Heuyer&amp;rsquo;s view of the phenomenon as a shared delusion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michel Monnerie&amp;rsquo;s psychosocial UFO hypothesis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reported-sightings&#34;&gt;Reported sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#reported-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the characteristics of reported flying saucers based on eyewitness accounts. Key points include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lack of consistency in reports, with astronomer Donald Howard Menzel noting that &amp;ldquo;no two reports describe exactly the same kind of UFO.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Variations in shape, size, color, movement, and sound.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The typical setting of sightings at night, around sunset or sunrise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The usual description of distant saucers in flight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The association of a saucer&amp;rsquo;s crew with extraterrestrial life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gradual standardization of the &amp;ldquo;grey alien&amp;rdquo; as the most reported type of pilot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The consistent description and depiction of flying saucers as ahead of contemporary technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The reflection of popular social and cultural expectations in claimed observations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The shift in emphasis from speed in early reports to hovering in later reports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fictional-portrayals&#34;&gt;Fictional portrayals &lt;a href=&#34;#fictional-portrayals&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the portrayal of flying saucers in popular media. Key points include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A change in motion from high-speed maneuvers in early portrayals to slowly hovering discs in later media.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Examples of films and television series depicting flying saucers, such as &lt;em&gt;The Flying Saucer&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Bruce Gentry – Daredevil of the Skies&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Day the Earth Stood Still&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Invaders&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Fire in the Sky&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;popular-culture&#34;&gt;Popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the cultural impact of flying saucers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The association of flying discs with a cultural conception of aliens that reflects the social and political anxieties of the 20th century.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The representation of concerns about atomic warfare, the Cold War, loss of bodily integrity, xenophobia, government secrecy, and the question of whether humanity is alone in the universe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The influence of reports from witnesses on popular media, which led to greater interest in flying saucers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The adaptation of Donald Keyhoe&amp;rsquo;s UFO books for the screenplay of &lt;em&gt;Earth vs. the Flying Saucers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of a disc, often domed or emitting a beam of light, as visual shorthand for aliens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The addition of the flying saucer emoji to Unicode in 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The re-interpretation of premodern art by ufologists to support pseudohistorical claims of ancient alien interactions with humanity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The explanation of purported portrayals of ancient UFOs as artifacts of the cultures producing them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;literature&#34;&gt;Literature &lt;a href=&#34;#literature&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the appearance of flying saucers in literature. Key points include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The appearance of precursors to modern flying saucers in science fiction literature, including The Shaver Mystery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The emergence of a genre that treated fantastical stories as either true or plausibly true.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of sensationalist advertisements to promote saucer books.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The leveraging of cultural interest in flying saucers in advertisements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The appearance of aliens and flying discs in 1950s science fiction comics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The comic book anthology &lt;em&gt;UFO Flying Saucers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;film-and-television&#34;&gt;Film and television &lt;a href=&#34;#film-and-television&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flying_saucer&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flying_saucer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dover Demon</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_670cdf070164/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 16:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_670cdf070164/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;dover-demon&#34;&gt;Dover Demon &lt;a href=&#34;#dover-demon&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dover Demon is a creature reportedly sighted in Dover, Massachusetts, in April 1977.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sightings&#34;&gt;Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the reported sightings of the Dover Demon in April 1977. William &amp;ldquo;Bill&amp;rdquo; Bartlett, John Baxter, and Abby Brabham, all teenagers at the time, independently reported seeing a strange creature. Bartlett described it as about 4 feet tall with glowing orange eyes and no nose or mouth, with a watermelon-shaped head. Baxter reported a similar sighting on Miller Hill Road, and Brabham claimed to have seen the creature the following night on Springdale Avenue. The teenagers drew sketches of the creature, with Bartlett swearing on a stack of Bibles to the accuracy of his drawing. The locations of the sightings, when plotted on a map, formed a straight line over 2 miles. The sightings became public in May, and a local investigator noted similarities to the creatures in the Kelly–Hopkinsville encounter. The Mutual UFO Network also investigated the sightings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;possible-explanations&#34;&gt;Possible explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#possible-explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores potential explanations for the Dover Demon sightings. One suggestion is that the creature was a foal or a moose calf. Skeptic Joe Nickell proposes that the creature was likely a snowy owl, citing its size and plumage, which could reflect yellow headlights. The &amp;ldquo;long spindly arms&amp;rdquo; could be the partially opened wings of the owl. Police suggested the sightings were a school vacation hoax. Ben Radford suggests the sightings may have been influenced by the release of &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt; in 1977.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the Dover Demon&amp;rsquo;s appearances in popular culture. It was featured in an episode of the American horror television series &lt;em&gt;Lost Tapes&lt;/em&gt; on Animal Planet in 2009. The Dover Demon appears as a character in the comic book series &lt;em&gt;Proof&lt;/em&gt;, where it can see into the future, and in &lt;em&gt;The Perhapanauts&lt;/em&gt;. It also made appearances in &lt;em&gt;The Pound: Ghouls Night Out&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Hack/Slash: Entry Wound&lt;/em&gt;. A Dover Demon appears in the webcomic &lt;em&gt;Gunnerkrigg Court&lt;/em&gt;. In the manga series &lt;em&gt;Dandadan&lt;/em&gt;, an alien known as Dover Demon takes the form of a bipedal crustacean-like alien.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dover_Demon&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dover_Demon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
