<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Photographs on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/photographs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Photographs on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 23:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/photographs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>McMinnville UFO photographs</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_95f5acf2867f/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 23:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_95f5acf2867f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;mcminnville-ufo-photographs&#34;&gt;McMinnville UFO Photographs &lt;a href=&#34;#mcminnville-ufo-photographs&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The McMinnville UFO photographs, taken in 1950 near McMinnville, Oregon, are among the most famous UFO photos ever taken. They have been subject to intense scrutiny, with some believing them to be genuine evidence of UFOs, while others consider them a hoax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alleged-origin&#34;&gt;Alleged Origin &lt;a href=&#34;#alleged-origin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The photos were taken on a farm just outside Sheridan, Oregon, about 13 miles southwest of McMinnville. On May 11, 1950, Evelyn Trent claimed to have seen a metallic, disk-shaped object while walking back to her farmhouse. She alerted her husband, Paul Trent, who also saw the object. Paul retrieved a camera and took two photos before the object sped away. Paul Trent&amp;rsquo;s father also claimed to have briefly viewed the object. There are slight discrepancies in the Trents&amp;rsquo; initial accounts of the sighting, with different versions appearing in the McMinnville &lt;em&gt;Telephone Register&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Oregonian&lt;/em&gt; newspaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-publicity&#34;&gt;Initial Publicity &lt;a href=&#34;#initial-publicity&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film from Paul Trent&amp;rsquo;s camera wasn&amp;rsquo;t immediately developed, as it wasn&amp;rsquo;t fully used until Mother&amp;rsquo;s Day family photos were taken. The Trents initially hesitated to publicize the photos, fearing trouble due to the object potentially being a secret military aircraft. However, they showed the photos to their banker, Frank Wortmann, who displayed them in his bank window in McMinnville. Reporter Bill Powell convinced Paul Trent to loan him the negatives. Powell found no evidence of tampering and published the story and photos in the McMinnville &lt;em&gt;Telephone-Register&lt;/em&gt; on June 8, 1950. The International News Service (INS) picked up the story, giving it national exposure. &lt;em&gt;Life&lt;/em&gt; magazine published cropped versions of the photos on June 26, 1950. The Trents never received their negatives back from &lt;em&gt;Life&lt;/em&gt; magazine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;condon-committee-investigation&#34;&gt;Condon Committee Investigation &lt;a href=&#34;#condon-committee-investigation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1967, the negatives were located in the files of United Press International (UPI), which had merged with INS. They were loaned to Dr. William K. Hartmann, an astronomer working for the Condon Committee, a government-funded UFO research project led by Edward Condon at the University of Colorado Boulder. Hartmann interviewed the Trents and was impressed by their sincerity and lack of attempts to profit from the photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hartmann&amp;rsquo;s analysis suggested the photos were consistent with an extraordinary flying object, based on geometric, psychological, and physical factors. He noted that the brightness of the object&amp;rsquo;s underside appeared lighter than an oil tank in the images, potentially due to atmospheric extinction and scattering, suggesting the object was distant. However, Hartmann also acknowledged the possibility of a hoax, noting the object&amp;rsquo;s position beneath wires and the potential for it to be a small model suspended by a thread. He also pointed out a discrepancy in the lighting, suggesting the photos might have been taken in the morning rather than the evening. After his investigation, Hartmann returned the negatives to UPI, who then informed the Trents. The Trents requested the negatives back from the &lt;em&gt;News-Register&lt;/em&gt; in 1970, but the editor, Philip Bladine, never contacted them after receiving them from UPI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;maccabee-analysis&#34;&gt;Maccabee Analysis &lt;a href=&#34;#maccabee-analysis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1975, Bruce Maccabee, an optical physicist and ufologist, found the negatives in the &lt;em&gt;News-Register&lt;/em&gt; files. He conducted his own study and concluded that the photos were not hoaxed and showed a real object in the sky. Maccabee&amp;rsquo;s analysis, based on densitometric measurements, supported the idea that the object was distant. He also analyzed the position of objects in the images and argued that the line-of-sight of the two images intersected behind the power lines, further suggesting it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a small model. Maccabee found no evidence of a thread or string suspending the object. He attributed shadows on the garage, which skeptics used to argue the photos were taken in the morning, to cloud conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hoax-explanation&#34;&gt;Hoax Explanation &lt;a href=&#34;#hoax-explanation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skeptics Philip J. Klass and Robert Sheaffer concluded in the 1980s that the photos were a hoax. Their primary argument was that shadows on a garage indicated the photos were taken in the morning, contradicting the Trents&amp;rsquo; claim of an evening sighting. They also noted the Trents&amp;rsquo; prior interest in UFOs. Klass and Sheaffer suggested the object was a small model hanging from power lines or a detached side-view mirror from a vehicle, noting its similarity to mirrors used on Ford vehicles. Klass found contradictions in the Trents&amp;rsquo; story and concluded they had hoaxed the event. William Hartmann withdrew his positive assessment after reviewing Sheaffer&amp;rsquo;s research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April 2013, researchers with IPACO posted studies arguing that the geometry of the photographs is most consistent with a small model with a hollow bottom hanging from a wire suspended from the power lines above. They claimed to have detected the presence of a thread above the object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aftermath&#34;&gt;Aftermath &lt;a href=&#34;#aftermath&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The McMinnville UFO photographs remain highly publicized. Skeptics maintain they are hoaxes, while ufologists argue they are credible evidence of UFOs. The Trents, described as unassuming farm folk, maintained the authenticity of their sighting until their deaths (Evelyn in 1997 and Paul in 1998). The interest in the photos led to the establishment of an annual &amp;ldquo;UFO Festival&amp;rdquo; in McMinnville, now the largest in the Pacific Northwest and the second-largest in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists other notable UFO photographs and incidents, including the Rhodes UFO photographs (1947), Mariana UFO film (Aug 1950), and Passaic UFO photographs (1952).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/McMinnville_UFO_photographs&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/McMinnville_UFO_photographs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
