<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Magazine on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/magazine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Magazine on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 07:20:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/magazine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Psychosocial UFO hypothesis</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a235c7fbdf9b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 07:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a235c7fbdf9b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;psychosocial-hypothesis-in-ufology&#34;&gt;Psychosocial Hypothesis in Ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#psychosocial-hypothesis-in-ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psychosocial hypothesis (PSH) in ufology suggests that some UFO reports are best explained by psychological or social factors rather than extraterrestrial origins. It contrasts with the extraterrestrial hypothesis (ETH) and is favored by UFO researchers in the UK and France. Proponents view UFOs as an interesting subject for study, even with skepticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;origin&#34;&gt;Origin &lt;a href=&#34;#origin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;psychosocial hypothesis&amp;rdquo; gained prominence in English UFO literature in 1984, influenced by French UFO controversies sparked by Michel Monnerie&amp;rsquo;s challenge to the ETH. &lt;em&gt;Magonia&lt;/em&gt; magazine played a key role in popularizing the term. Peter Rogerson&amp;rsquo;s adoption of the term marked a shift away from paranormal explanations towards normal psychological processes influenced by cultural myths and social conditioning. Writers associated with &lt;em&gt;Magonia&lt;/em&gt; had been exploring alternatives to the ETH since 1968, driven by the belief that it failed to account for high strangeness cases. Roger Sandell&amp;rsquo;s research on a 1905 Welsh UFO wave led him to conclude that UFO reports were part of a larger complex of ghost stories and religious visions. Peter Rogerson advocated for a search for historical antecedents of UFO rumors and the social factors driving UFO flaps and social panics, noting a relationship between UFO waves and times of radical social change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;science-fiction-aspects-of-the-ufo-mythos&#34;&gt;Science Fiction Aspects of the UFO Mythos &lt;a href=&#34;#science-fiction-aspects-of-the-ufo-mythos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bertrand Méheust&amp;rsquo;s study of science fiction parallels to UFO mythology revealed numerous similarities between UFO experience narratives and pre-1947 science fiction literature. These parallels include wondrous effects like invisible force-fields, teleportation, and engine-stopping rays, as well as humanoid motives for visiting Earth. Michel Monnerie integrated Meheust&amp;rsquo;s study into his historical critique of UFO mythology. Michel Meurger expanded Meheust&amp;rsquo;s thesis with a compendium of parallels. Jacques Vallee noted electromagnetic effects associated with UFOs in earlier fiction. Researchers have explored the cultural backstories to various alien types, including Grays, insectoids, and reptoids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-saucer-rumor&#34;&gt;The Saucer Rumor &lt;a href=&#34;#the-saucer-rumor&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psychosocial approach helped solve the mystery of why flying saucers are the dominant shape in UFO reports. Martin Kottmeyer discovered that the &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; label originated from a misinterpretation of Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s 1947 sighting. Arnold described the objects&amp;rsquo; motion as erratic, &amp;ldquo;like a saucer if you skip it across the water,&amp;rdquo; but the reporter misinterpreted this as describing the objects&amp;rsquo; shape. This mistake shaped the UFO phenomenon for decades, influencing film imagery, saucer photography, UFO illustration, contactee tales, and abduction experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flaps-of-flying-phantoms&#34;&gt;Flaps of Flying Phantoms &lt;a href=&#34;#flaps-of-flying-phantoms&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early researchers attempted to correlate UFO flaps with Mars&amp;rsquo; proximity, but these predictions failed. British researchers shifted focus to pre-1947 &amp;ldquo;waves,&amp;rdquo; examining social, religious, political, and scientific backgrounds. Nigel Watson researched a March–May 1909 panic involving German airships spying on Britain. Phantom airship flaps were cataloged in various locations, often accompanied by rumors of foreign spies. By the 1930s, phantom airships were replaced by phantom aeroplanes. Researchers have experimented with variations in these explanations, such as the 1905 Wales flap occurring during a time of rapid social change. Researchers generally reject explanations involving mass hysteria, preferring to discuss flaps as collective delusions maintained by rumor and gossip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-modern-myth-of-jung&#34;&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Modern Myth&lt;/em&gt; of Jung &lt;a href=&#34;#the-modern-myth-of-jung&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Gustav Jung&amp;rsquo;s essay &lt;em&gt;Flying Saucers: A Modern Myth of Things Seen in the Skies&lt;/em&gt; is considered a foundational work of the PSH. While some argue that Jung also considered the ETH, Jung himself refuted claims that he believed UFOs were physically real. He emphasized the psychological significance of the UFO phenomenon, regardless of its objective reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychosocial_UFO_hypothesis&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychosocial_UFO_hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jason Colavito</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_03177d2d1dcd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 07:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_03177d2d1dcd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;jason-colavito&#34;&gt;Jason Colavito &lt;a href=&#34;#jason-colavito&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason Colavito, born in 1981, is an American author and independent scholar known for his work debunking fringe theories, particularly those related to ancient history and extraterrestrials. He has written several books on these topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;biography&#34;&gt;Biography &lt;a href=&#34;#biography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colavito graduated summa cum laude from Ithaca College in 2003 with a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in anthropology and journalism. He attended Auburn High School before that. His work focuses on debunking alternative archaeology. His work has been cited in &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Huffington Post&lt;/em&gt;, and on the History Channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bibliography&#34;&gt;Bibliography &lt;a href=&#34;#bibliography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colavito&amp;rsquo;s writings have appeared in &lt;em&gt;The New Republic&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Slate&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Esquire Magazine&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Skeptic&lt;/em&gt; magazine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books (as author):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cult of Alien Gods: H. P. Lovecraft and Extraterrestrial Pop Culture&lt;/em&gt; (2005) explores the influence of H.P. Lovecraft&amp;rsquo;s Cthulhu Mythos on the works of Erich von Däniken and Graham Hancock, and its impact on extraterrestrial pop culture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Knowing Fear: Science, Knowledge, and the Development of the Horror Genre&lt;/em&gt; (2007) examines the history and science of the horror genre.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Critical Companion to Ancient Aliens Seasons 3 and 4: Unauthorized&lt;/em&gt; (2012)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Faking History: Essays on Aliens, Atlantis, Monsters, and More&lt;/em&gt; (2013)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unearthing the Truth: An Unauthorized Commentary on America Unearthed Season One&lt;/em&gt; (2013)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cthulhu in World Mythology&lt;/em&gt; (2014)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jason and the Argonauts Through the Ages&lt;/em&gt; (2014)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Mound Builder Myth: Fake History and the Hunt for a &amp;ldquo;Lost White Race&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; (2020) discusses the myth surrounding mound builders and its connection to ideas of a lost white race.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Legends of the Pyramids&lt;/em&gt; (2021)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jimmy: The Secret Life of James Dean&lt;/em&gt; (2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books (as editor):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Hideous Bit of Morbidity: An Anthology of Horror Criticism from the Enlightenment to World War I&lt;/em&gt; (2009)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unseen Horror: 15 Tales of Invisibility and the Macabre&lt;/em&gt; (2011)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Faust Book: And Other Early Stories of Dr. Faustus&lt;/em&gt; (2011)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moon Men!: A Lunar Anthology of Proto-Science Fiction, A.D. 200–1835&lt;/em&gt; (2012)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Theosophy on Ancient Astronauts&lt;/em&gt; (2012)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pyramidiots: Outrageous Theories about the Great Pyramid&lt;/em&gt; (2012)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Foundations of Atlantis, Ancient Astronauts and Other Alternative Pasts: 148 Documents Cited by Writers of Fringe History&lt;/em&gt; (2015)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books (as translator):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Orphic Argonautica&lt;/em&gt; (2011)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Xipéhux&lt;/em&gt; (2012)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the various sources cited throughout the article, including news articles, academic journals, and websites. These sources provide verification for the information presented about Jason Colavito&amp;rsquo;s life, work, and publications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Cult_of_Alien_Gods&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Cult_of_Alien_Gods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voronezh UFO incident</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_345e43d72a87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 07:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_345e43d72a87/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;voronezh-ufo-incident&#34;&gt;Voronezh UFO incident &lt;a href=&#34;#voronezh-ufo-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Voronezh UFO incident refers to an alleged UFO and extraterrestrial sighting reported by children in Voronezh, Soviet Union, on September 27, 1989. The area became a tourist attraction for UFO enthusiasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tass-reports&#34;&gt;TASS reports &lt;a href=&#34;#tass-reports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the account of the incident as reported by TASS. Children playing football in a park claimed to have witnessed a pink glow, followed by a red ball-shaped object. They further reported seeing a three-eyed alien and a robot exiting the object. The alien was said to have used a ray gun to make a boy disappear temporarily. A local police lieutenant claimed to have seen a flying object. TASS also reported that a correspondent spoke with youths who claimed to have seen a flying saucer, and Dr. Silanov of the Voronezh Geophysical Laboratory confirmed the landing location using &amp;ldquo;biolocation&amp;rdquo;. The reports were part of the government&amp;rsquo;s new &amp;ldquo;openness&amp;rdquo; policy. A reporter from Komsomolskaya Pravda claimed to have an interview with aliens. Sovietskaya Kultura, a Communist Party paper, defended its coverage of the children&amp;rsquo;s claims. Following the publicity, tours of Voronezh, &amp;ldquo;land of the aliens&amp;rdquo;, were offered. The description of the incident was similar to stories in the American magazine Saga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufologists&#34;&gt;Ufologists &lt;a href=&#34;#ufologists&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions A. Kuzovkin, a UFOlogist, who believed a scorched patch of ground near Moscow was caused by a UFO landing. However, TASS reported that firefighters attributed the scorched ground to an ignited haystack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;response&#34;&gt;Response &lt;a href=&#34;#response&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the official response to the alleged incident. The Soviet Scientific Commission launched an inquiry. Scientists, including members of the &amp;ldquo;Voronezh Amateur Section for the Study of Abnormal Phenomena,&amp;rdquo; investigated the site. Genrikh Silanov of the Voronezh Geophysical Lab later clarified that the extraterrestrial rock was a common form of hematite. Igor Sarotsev of the University of Voronezh stated that the presence of cesium was insignificant and could be attributed to the Chernobyl disaster. A French Press Agency report found no verifiable proof of a landing. Vladimir Posner sent a film crew to Voronezh but could only find the children as &amp;ldquo;witnesses&amp;rdquo;. The section concludes by citing a Time magazine article that viewed the state sponsorship of psychic and UFO claims as a new &amp;ldquo;opiate for the masses&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voronezh_UFO_incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voronezh_UFO_incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nash-Fortenberry UFO sighting</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f9288f9c7c4f/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 01:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f9288f9c7c4f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;nash-fortenberry-ufo-sighting&#34;&gt;Nash-Fortenberry UFO Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#nash-fortenberry-ufo-sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Nash-Fortenberry UFO sighting occurred on July 14, 1952, when two commercial pilots, William B. Nash and William H. Fortenberry, reported seeing eight UFOs in a tight echelon formation over Chesapeake Bay in Virginia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description &lt;a href=&#34;#description&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two commercial pilots, William B. Nash and William H. Fortenberry, reported observing eight UFOs flying in formation over Chesapeake Bay, Virginia. Ufologists highlight the pilots&amp;rsquo; observation allowed for measurements of the objects&amp;rsquo; motion and size relative to known landmarks. The sighting was reportedly corroborated by independent ground witnesses. Project Blue Book listed the case as an &amp;ldquo;unknown.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;explanations&#34;&gt;Explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donald Howard Menzel suggested the pilots might have seen distorted ground lights due to haze or fireflies trapped in the cockpit window. Steuart Campbell proposed the sighting was a mirage of Venus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A NICAP report by Thomas Thulien revisiting the Nash/Fortenberry sighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donald Howard Menzel&amp;rsquo;s book, &lt;em&gt;The World of Flying Saucers&lt;/em&gt;, where he offers naturalistic explanations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steuart Campbell&amp;rsquo;s book, &lt;em&gt;The UFO Mystery Solved&lt;/em&gt;, where he suggests the sighting was a mirage of Venus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further Reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists additional resources for further information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steuart Campbell&amp;rsquo;s book, &lt;em&gt;The UFO Mystery Solved&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James W. Moseley and Karl T. Pflock&amp;rsquo;s book, &lt;em&gt;Shockingly Close to the Truth: Confessions of a Grave-Robbing Ufologist&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External Links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Pilots&amp;rsquo; Tale&amp;rdquo; at Saturday Night Uforia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;We Flew Above Flying Saucers&amp;rdquo; by William B. Nash and William H. Fortenberry, published in &lt;em&gt;True&lt;/em&gt; magazine in 1967.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nash-Fortenberry_UFO_sighting&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nash-Fortenberry_UFO_sighting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
