<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cosmology on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/cosmology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cosmology on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 17:45:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/cosmology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Planetary objects proposed in religion, astrology, ufology and pseudoscience</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_485ff785184c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_485ff785184c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;planetary-objects-proposed-in-religion-astrology-ufology-and-pseudoscience&#34;&gt;Planetary Objects Proposed in Religion, Astrology, Ufology and Pseudoscience &lt;a href=&#34;#planetary-objects-proposed-in-religion-astrology-ufology-and-pseudoscience&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses planetary objects proposed outside of mainstream science, specifically within religion, astrology, ufology, and pseudoscience. These objects lack scientific evidence supporting their existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;kolob&#34;&gt;Kolob &lt;a href=&#34;#kolob&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kolob is a star or planet described in the Book of Abraham, a sacred text in the Latter Day Saint movement. It&amp;rsquo;s also mentioned in a Latter-day Saint hymn. While the Book of Abraham refers to it as a &amp;ldquo;star,&amp;rdquo; it&amp;rsquo;s commonly viewed as a planet by Latter Day Saints. Kolob is described as the heavenly body closest to the throne of God, and Joseph Smith claimed it &amp;ldquo;signified&amp;rdquo; the first creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lilith&#34;&gt;Lilith &lt;a href=&#34;#lilith&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lilith is a fictitious, invisible moon of Earth, proposed in 1918 by astrologer Walter Gorn Old (Sepharial). He claimed it had the same mass as Earth&amp;rsquo;s Moon. Sepharial associated it with the Lilith of Jewish legend and claimed it was the same second moon that scientist Georg Waltemath claimed to have discovered earlier. Sepharial claimed to have observed it crossing the Sun. The scientific community had already discredited Waltemath&amp;rsquo;s moon. Modern astrologers use the name Lilith to refer to the position of the Moon&amp;rsquo;s apogee. Black Moon Lilith is sometimes defined as the second focus of the ellipse described by the Moon&amp;rsquo;s orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-modern-astrology&#34;&gt;In Modern Astrology &lt;a href=&#34;#in-modern-astrology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contemporary astrology, &amp;ldquo;Lilith&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Black Moon Lilith&amp;rdquo; denotes a point on a horoscope corresponding to the Moon&amp;rsquo;s apogee. This point, considered the second focus of the Moon&amp;rsquo;s elliptical orbit (with Earth as the first), completes a zodiac circuit in approximately 8 years and 10 months, tracking apsidal precession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;planets-proposed-by-l-ron-hubbard&#34;&gt;Planets Proposed by L. Ron Hubbard &lt;a href=&#34;#planets-proposed-by-l-ron-hubbard&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L. Ron Hubbard, the founder of Scientology, proposed a Galactic Confederacy as part of his cosmology. This confederacy consisted of 26 stars and 76 planets, including Earth, then known as &amp;ldquo;Teegeeack.&amp;rdquo; Helatrobus is another planet mentioned in Scientology doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ummo&#34;&gt;Ummo &lt;a href=&#34;#ummo&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ummo is a hypothetical planet believed to be located in the Constellation Virgo. It is described in claims of communication between aliens from Ummo and people on Earth. This information was disseminated through detailed documents and letters sent to esoteric groups and UFO enthusiasts. The Ummo affair gained attention in France and Spain in the 1960s. Ummoism refers to groups interested in studying the ideas presented in the Ummo letters. José Luis Jordán Peña has claimed responsibility for writing the letters, leading many to believe Ummo is a hoax. Jacques Vallée compared the creators of the Ummo documents to the fictional creators of Borges&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;Tlön, Uqbar, Orbis Tertius.&amp;rdquo; Mike Dash notes that Ummoism began on February 6, 1966, in Madrid, when Jordán Peña claimed to have seen a UFO. Fernando Sesma Manzano, a contactee, became involved after receiving documents purportedly from the Ummites. Jean-Pierre Petit claims to have detected signs of superior intelligence in Ummite writings and that they have inspired his research in cosmology and magnetohydrodynamics. Antonio Ribera mentions 403 Ummo words in a 1978 compilation. Jean Pollion lists over a thousand words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;planets-proposed-by-zecharia-sitchin&#34;&gt;Planets Proposed by Zecharia Sitchin &lt;a href=&#34;#planets-proposed-by-zecharia-sitchin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zecharia Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s work has gained attention among ufologists, ancient astronaut theorists, and conspiracy theorists. He claimed to have found evidence in Sumerian texts that extraterrestrials from a distant planet in the Solar System visited/created the human race. His theory involves an astronomical interpretation of the Babylonian creation myth, the &lt;em&gt;Enuma Elish&lt;/em&gt;, where he replaced the names of gods with hypothetical planets. Academics consider his work pseudoscience and pseudohistory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s theory proposes the planets Tiamat and Nibiru. Tiamat supposedly existed between Mars and Jupiter. Its orbit was disrupted by the arrival of Nibiru, which caused Tiamat to collide with one of Nibiru&amp;rsquo;s moons. The debris formed the asteroid belt and Earth. Sitchin claims the Babylonians associated Nibiru with the god Marduk. He hypothesized it as a planet in a highly elliptic orbit around the Sun, with a perihelion passage some 3,600 years ago. He claimed it was the home of the Anunnaki, who visited Earth in search of gold and created humanity by genetically crossing themselves with primates. Websites such as ZetaTalk have claimed that Nibiru or &amp;ldquo;Planet X&amp;rdquo; is a brown dwarf soon to pass close to Earth. Sitchin disagreed it is a star. Sitchin also postulated that Pluto began life as Gaga, a satellite of Saturn which, due to perturbation caused by Nibiru&amp;rsquo;s passing, was flung into orbit beyond Neptune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;serpo&#34;&gt;Serpo &lt;a href=&#34;#serpo&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project Serpo is an alleged top-secret exchange program between the United States government and an alien planet called Serpo in the Zeta Reticuli star system. Details of the alleged exchange program have appeared in UFO conspiracy stories. In 1983, a man identifying himself as United States Air Force Sergeant Richard C. Doty contacted investigative journalist Linda Moulton Howe claiming to be able to supply her Air Force records of the exchange for her HBO documentary &lt;em&gt;The ET Factor&lt;/em&gt;, only to pull out without providing any evidence to substantiate his story. In 2005, a series of emails were sent to a UFO discussion group run by Victor Martinez claiming that the project was real. Some variations state that Serpo is the nickname of the extrasolar planet. The first mention of &amp;lsquo;Project Serpo&amp;rsquo; was in a UFO email list maintained by enthusiast Victor Martinez.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the most common version of the story, an alien survived a crash near Roswell in the later 1940s. This alien was detained but treated well by American military forces, contacted its home planet and eventually repatriated. This led to the establishment of a relationship between the American government and the people of its home world, said to be a planet of the binary star system Zeta Reticuli. Zeta Reticuli has a history in ufology, having been claimed as the home system of the Greys. Twelve American military personnel visited the planet between 1965 and 1978 and that all of the party have since died, from &amp;ldquo;after effects of high radiation levels from the two suns&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One criticism of Project Serpo stems from the lack of veracity of one of its alleged witnesses, Sergeant Richard Doty. Doty has been involved in other alleged UFO-related activities, and thus is a discredited source. Additionally, there is no physical evidence supporting the project&amp;rsquo;s existence. According to Tim Swartz of &lt;em&gt;Mysteries Magazine&lt;/em&gt;, Doty, who promised evidence to Moulton Howe before backing out, has been involved in circulating several other UFO conspiracy stories. Bill Ryan, a chief proponent of publicizing the Project Serpo claims, announced on 5 March 2007, that he was stepping down from his role as webmaster for the Serpo material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_Serpo&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_Serpo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
