<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UFO Sighting on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ufo-sighting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UFO Sighting on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 13:38:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ufo-sighting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2007 Alderney UFO sighting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_40bc71f5c743/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 13:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_40bc71f5c743/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;2007-alderney-ufo-sighting&#34;&gt;2007 Alderney UFO sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#2007-alderney-ufo-sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the reported UFO sighting that occurred on April 23, 2007, over Alderney in the Channel Islands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;accounts-of-the-sighting&#34;&gt;Accounts of the sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#accounts-of-the-sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces the event, mentioning that a pilot, Ray Bowyer, reported seeing unidentified flying objects. An air traffic controller confirmed that another pilot had reported a similar sighting. Passengers on Bowyer&amp;rsquo;s aircraft also reported seeing unusual lights. Possible explanations for the sighting, such as earthquake lights and sun dogs, are also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bowyers-accounts&#34;&gt;Bowyer&amp;rsquo;s accounts &lt;a href=&#34;#bowyers-accounts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the account of Ray Bowyer, the pilot who initially reported the sighting. It details his description of the object as a &amp;ldquo;cigar-shaped brilliant white light,&amp;rdquo; initially thought to be reflections from greenhouses. Bowyer&amp;rsquo;s estimates of the object&amp;rsquo;s size and distance evolved, eventually describing it as being the size of a Boeing 737, then later as large as five or six battleships or a reasonably large town. The section includes details from a recorded conversation between Bowyer and an air traffic controller, who reported only a faint radar contact. Bowyer&amp;rsquo;s actions, such as using binoculars to observe the light, and his report to the Civil Aviation Authority are also covered. The Ministry of Defence&amp;rsquo;s initial reluctance to investigate and subsequent release of information, including a statement from a second pilot, are mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-witness-accounts&#34;&gt;Other witness accounts &lt;a href=&#34;#other-witness-accounts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents accounts from other witnesses to the event. Passengers on Bowyer&amp;rsquo;s aircraft reported seeing the light, with one describing it as &amp;ldquo;sunlight-colored&amp;rdquo; and another as &amp;ldquo;an orange light … like an elongated oval.&amp;rdquo; Patrick Patterson, a pilot from Blue Islands, also reported seeing a similar object in the same general location. The section also mentions an interpretation that the sighting was an atmospheric phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;proposed-explanations&#34;&gt;Proposed explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#proposed-explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores potential explanations for the UFO sighting. Bowyer rejected the idea that he saw an alien vessel, but considered the possibility of earthquake lights related to the earthquake in south-eastern England that occurred shortly after the sighting. A local astronomer, Michael Maunder, suggested that the sighting could be attributed to sun dogs, an optical phenomenon caused by the refraction of light through ice crystals. He noted that the weather conditions were favorable for sun dogs and that the reported lights were approximately 22 degrees from the sun, consistent with the appearance of sun dogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2007_Alderney_UFO_sighting&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2007_Alderney_UFO_sighting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mariana UFO film</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_172fd0b0c15b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_172fd0b0c15b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;mariana-ufo-incident&#34;&gt;Mariana UFO Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#mariana-ufo-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mariana UFO incident occurred in August 1950 in Great Falls, Montana. It involves a sighting filmed by local baseball coach Nick Mariana, considered among the first motion picture footage of a UFO. The U.S. Air Force initially claimed the objects were reflections of two F-94 jet fighters, a claim they later retracted and then endorsed again. Multiple investigations have yielded inconclusive results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;incident&#34;&gt;Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On August 15, 1950, at 11:29 am, Nick Mariana and his secretary, Virginia Raunig, spotted two bright, silvery objects rotating while flying over Great Falls at an estimated speed of 200 to 400 miles per hour. Mariana filmed the objects for sixteen seconds using his 16 mm movie camera. The &lt;em&gt;Great Falls Tribune&lt;/em&gt; reported the sighting the next day, and Mariana showed the film to local groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;air-force-investigation&#34;&gt;Air Force Investigation &lt;a href=&#34;#air-force-investigation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the &lt;em&gt;Great Falls Tribune&lt;/em&gt; informed Wright-Patterson Air Force Base about the sighting, Captain John P. Brynildsen interviewed Mariana and Raunig at Malmstrom AFB. Brynildsen sent the film to Wright-Patterson AFB for analysis. The Air Force initially determined the objects were reflections from two F-94 jet fighters. However, controversy arose when Mariana claimed the first thirty-five frames of his film, which clearly showed the UFOs as rotating disks, were missing. The Air Force denied removing more than a single damaged frame. Edward J. Ruppelt, who later headed Project Blue Book, noted the initial lack of Air Force interest in the UFO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lawsuit&#34;&gt;Lawsuit &lt;a href=&#34;#lawsuit&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January 1951, Bob Considine, a writer and UFO skeptic, wrote an article for &lt;em&gt;Cosmopolitan&lt;/em&gt; debunking famous UFO sightings, including Mariana&amp;rsquo;s. Mariana filed a slander lawsuit against Considine, which was eventually dropped in September 1955.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;later-studies&#34;&gt;Later Studies &lt;a href=&#34;#later-studies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In July 1952, Ruppelt convinced Mariana to allow the Air Force to reanalyze the film. Analysts at Wright-Patterson AFB ruled out birds, balloons, meteors, and reflections from F-94 jets. Ruppelt concluded the film showed an unknown object. In January 1953, the Robertson Panel, convened by the Air Force and CIA, judged the objects to be reflections of aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;baker-analysis&#34;&gt;Baker Analysis &lt;a href=&#34;#baker-analysis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1954, Greene-Rouse Productions hired Robert M.L. Baker, Jr. of Douglas Aircraft to analyze Mariana&amp;rsquo;s film for a documentary. Baker concluded that the jet reflection explanation was strained. In 1968, Baker testified before a Congressional hearing on UFOs, stating that his analysis excluded most natural phenomena. In 1969, at an AAAS UFO panel, Baker presented a paper concluding the Mariana film was unidentifiable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;condon-report&#34;&gt;Condon Report &lt;a href=&#34;#condon-report&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1966, the U.S. government funded a study of the UFO phenomenon at the University of Colorado, chaired by Edward U. Condon. Roy Craig, a skeptical physicist, and David Saunders, a psychologist interested in the Mariana incident, reinvestigated the film. They disagreed on the film&amp;rsquo;s authenticity and the removal of frames. William Hartmann, an astronomer, analyzed the film and suggested airplanes remained the principal working hypothesis, though he acknowledged arguments against it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legacy&#34;&gt;Legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copies of Mariana&amp;rsquo;s film are in the US National Archives. The film is featured in documentaries and online, and continues to be debated. Great Falls, Montana, has had over 100 UFO sightings since Mariana&amp;rsquo;s incident. In 2008, the minor league baseball team in Great Falls was renamed the Great Falls Voyagers in honor of the incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mariana_UFO_incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mariana_UFO_incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Westall UFO</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_b24ace289f7f/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 01:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_b24ace289f7f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;westall-ufo&#34;&gt;Westall UFO &lt;a href=&#34;#westall-ufo&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Westall UFO incident refers to a reported UFO sighting that occurred on April 6, 1966, in Melbourne, Victoria, Australia. The event involved multiple witnesses, including students and a teacher from Westall High School. The incident has been commemorated through documentaries, reunions, and a UFO-themed playground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reports&#34;&gt;Reports &lt;a href=&#34;#reports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 6, 1966, students and a teacher at Westall High School (now Westall Secondary College) reported observing a round, white, grey, or silver object with a domed top. The object reportedly descended behind trees into the Grange, an open area south of the school. Some accounts mention the object being pursued by five unidentified aircraft. Shaun Matthews, who was on vacation at the Grange, described the object as having a slight purple hue and being about twice the size of a family car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Witness accounts varied, with some reporting the object taking off after landing, while others claimed it hovered. Students who went to the Grange after the sighting described a landing site with varying details, including a circle of grass described as burnt, &amp;ldquo;boiled,&amp;rdquo; or pressed down. The number of circles reported ranged from one to three. On April 9, 1966, air force personnel and UFO enthusiasts visited the field but found nothing of interest. The landowner subsequently burned the field to prevent further access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;explanations&#34;&gt;Explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Age&lt;/em&gt; newspaper initially suggested the object might have been a weather balloon released from Laverton. However, checks revealed that no commercial, private, or RAAF pilots reported anything unusual in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keith Basterfield proposed that a runaway balloon from the HIBAL high-altitude balloon project, used to monitor radiation levels after British nuclear tests at Maralinga, could be a likely explanation. He cited documents indicating a test balloon launched from Mildura may have drifted off course and landed near Westall High School. Basterfield noted that HIBAL balloons had a white silver appearance with a parachute and gas tube, consistent with witness descriptions. Reports also surfaced of &amp;ldquo;men in suits&amp;rdquo; cautioning witnesses against discussing the incident, suggesting a secret government exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brian Dunning suggested that a weather balloon could explain the initial sighting. He proposed that a nylon target drogue, towed by one plane for others to chase, could account for the second part of the event. Dunning also noted that over time, descriptions of the event have become mixed with fabricated details, making it difficult to discern accurate accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;media-coverage&#34;&gt;Media Coverage &lt;a href=&#34;#media-coverage&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentary &lt;em&gt;Westall &amp;lsquo;66&lt;/em&gt; focuses on the sighting, featuring interviews conducted by ufologist Shane Ryan. &lt;em&gt;Westall &amp;lsquo;66&lt;/em&gt; has been incorporated into the national history curriculum as a lesson on critical analysis of popular portrayals of historical events. &lt;em&gt;The Phenomenon&lt;/em&gt;, a documentary film directed and co-produced by ufologist James Fox, includes content related to the Westall UFO case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;local-culture&#34;&gt;Local Culture &lt;a href=&#34;#local-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A witness reunion was held at Westall Tennis Club Hall on April 8, 2006, to commemorate the 40th anniversary of the incident. The City of Kingston created Grange Reserve UFO Park at The Grange Reserve in Clayton South, featuring a silver UFO with red slides to reflect the 1966 Westall UFO Incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ariel School UFO incident&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Australian Ufology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bass Strait Triangle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disappearance of Frederick Valentich&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of UFO sightings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Westall_UFO&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Westall_UFO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finnish Air Force UFO sighting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_46310b08f1d3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 12:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_46310b08f1d3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;finnish-air-force-ufo-sighting&#34;&gt;Finnish Air Force UFO Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#finnish-air-force-ufo-sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Finnish Air Force UFO sighting, also known as &amp;ldquo;The seven balloons of Pori,&amp;rdquo; refers to a UFO observation that occurred on April 12, 1969, in Pori, Finland, during military training exercises. This event is notable as the only UFO observation acknowledged by the Finnish Air Force. The Air Force suggested the objects may have been foreign reconnaissance aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sighting&#34;&gt;Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a Fouga Magister jet training mission at Pori Airport on April 12, 1969, a Finnish Defence Forces flight controller instructed pilot-in-training Tarmo Tukeva to investigate seven airborne objects. These objects were floating at an altitude of approximately 1500-3000 meters above the airport. Tukeva described the objects as ball or disc-shaped but could not accurately determine his distance from them. He reported that the objects accelerated away from him &amp;ldquo;at great speed.&amp;rdquo; Radar images, the nature of which remains undetermined, were also reported 200 kilometers away in Vaasa. Jouko Kuronen, another pilot-in-training, stated that he overheard the radio communications between the flight controller and Tukeva and also observed the objects. According to the Finnish Armed Forces magazine &lt;em&gt;Ruotuväki&lt;/em&gt;, the reports from April 12 were similar to other cases occurring over bodies of water during ongoing military exercises, suggesting the possibility of &amp;ldquo;transnational spy planes or aircraft.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The references section lists the sources used to support the information presented in the article. These include articles from &lt;em&gt;Ilta-Sanomat&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Yle Uutiset&lt;/em&gt;, both Finnish news outlets. These articles provide further details and context regarding the UFO sighting and the Finnish Air Force&amp;rsquo;s acknowledgment of the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufos&#34;&gt;UFOs &lt;a href=&#34;#ufos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a comprehensive template of UFO-related topics, including ufology, claimed sightings, types of UFOs, alleged extraterrestrial beings, studies, hypotheses, conspiracy theories, alien involvement, culture, skepticism, government involvement, and related categories. It serves as a navigation tool to explore various aspects of the UFO phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Finnish_Air_Force_UFO_sighting&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Finnish_Air_Force_UFO_sighting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flight 105 UFO sighting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_f9095ed38662/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 10:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_f9095ed38662/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;flight-105-ufo-sighting&#34;&gt;Flight 105 UFO Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#flight-105-ufo-sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the UFO sighting reported by the crew of United Airlines Flight 105 on July 4, 1947, over the Pacific Northwest. It connects the event to the broader context of the 1947 flying disc craze and provides background information, a description of the sighting, its aftermath, and eventual explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for the Flight 105 incident by referencing the Kenneth Arnold UFO sighting and the broader 1947 flying disc craze. It explains how Arnold&amp;rsquo;s report of objects flying near Mount Rainier led to the terms &amp;ldquo;flying saucers&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;flying discs&amp;rdquo; and sparked a wave of similar reports. The section establishes the Flight 105 sighting as part of this larger phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sighting&#34;&gt;Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the details of the Flight 105 UFO sighting. On July 4, 1947, United Airlines Flight 105, a Douglas DC-3, departed from Boise, Idaho, bound for Pendleton, Oregon. First Officer Ralph Stevens spotted unusual objects and alerted Captain E.J. Smith. Both men, along with stewardess Marty Morrow, observed four to five &amp;ldquo;flat and circular&amp;rdquo; objects. The objects were larger than aircraft and flew in formation for approximately 10 to 15 minutes (about 45 miles). The crew radioed the tower in Ontario, Oregon, and another United flight, but neither could confirm the sighting. The passengers did not see the objects. The objects eventually sped away or disintegrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aftermath&#34;&gt;Aftermath &lt;a href=&#34;#aftermath&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the immediate reactions and consequences of the Flight 105 sighting. News outlets widely reported the crew&amp;rsquo;s account. The report was considered credible due to the professional background of the witnesses. Captain Smith, Ralph Stevens, and Kenneth Arnold were photographed together &amp;ldquo;comparing notes.&amp;rdquo; Kenneth Arnold felt vindicated by the corroboration of his own sighting. Arnold and Smith were interviewed by the FBI and investigated the Maury Island hoax together. Another &amp;ldquo;disklike object&amp;rdquo; was sighted on Flight 105 later in July by a different pair of pilots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;explanation-and-legacy&#34;&gt;Explanation and Legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#explanation-and-legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explains the official explanation for the Flight 105 sighting and its lasting impact. Air Materiel Command concluded that the objects were likely &amp;ldquo;ordinary aircraft, balloons, birds, or pure illusion&amp;rdquo; due to the sighting occurring at sunset. The Air Force suggested the power of suggestion influenced observers during the craze. Despite the official explanation, the Flight 105 sighting has become part of UFO folklore and conspiracy theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flight_105_UFO_sighting&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flight_105_UFO_sighting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jimmy Carter UFO incident</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_1669788c5cb0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_1669788c5cb0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;1969-incident-regarding-the-sighting-of-a-ufo&#34;&gt;1969 incident regarding the sighting of a UFO &lt;a href=&#34;#1969-incident-regarding-the-sighting-of-a-ufo&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the UFO sighting reported by Jimmy Carter in 1969, prior to his governorship and presidency. It covers the details of the sighting, the subsequent investigation, and its impact on Carter&amp;rsquo;s views on UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;sighting&#34;&gt;Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the details of the UFO sighting as reported by Jimmy Carter. In 1969, while preparing to give a speech at a Lions Club meeting in Leary, Georgia, Carter and several other witnesses observed a bright, white object in the western sky. The object reportedly moved closer, stopped near a stand of pine trees, and changed colors before receding into the distance. Carter described the object as self-illuminated and not solid. The sighting lasted approximately 10-12 minutes and was witnessed by about 10-12 people. The section also includes quotes from Carter recounting the event in later interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;date&#34;&gt;Date &lt;a href=&#34;#date&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the conflicting information regarding the exact date of the sighting. While Carter initially reported the sighting occurred in October 1969, Lions Club records suggest it took place on January 6, 1969, the date of Carter&amp;rsquo;s speech to the Leary Lions Club. The section presents evidence supporting the January date, including Carter&amp;rsquo;s role as district governor of the Lions Club (a term that ended in June 1969) and the disbandment of the Leary Lions Club before October 1969.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;object-and-investigation&#34;&gt;Object and investigation &lt;a href=&#34;#object-and-investigation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the investigation into the sighting and alternative explanations for the object. It mentions that many attendees of the Lions Club meeting did not recall the event or did not consider it significant. One guest, Fred Hart, remembered a &amp;ldquo;blue light&amp;rdquo; that he thought might have been a weather balloon. The section also notes that Carter, while considering the object a UFO (unidentified flying object), did not believe it was an alien spacecraft. Ufologist Robert Sheaffer proposed that the object was Venus, which was near its maximum brightness and in the correct location on January 6, 1969. Ufologist Allan Hendry agreed with the Venus assessment. The section also mentions a 2007 interview where Carter stated he was an amateur astronomer and knew what Venus looked like, suggesting it was not Venus. It also presents an explanation from Carl G. &amp;ldquo;Jere&amp;rdquo; Justus, who worked on Air Force projects involving the release of glowing chemical clouds. Justus suggests the sighting was a barium cloud released from Eglin AFB in Florida on January 6, 1969, at 7:35 pm EST.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;personal-impact&#34;&gt;Personal impact &lt;a href=&#34;#personal-impact&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the impact of the sighting on Carter&amp;rsquo;s views on UFOs. During his 1976 presidential campaign, Carter pledged to make all UFO-related information available to the public if elected. However, after becoming president, he distanced himself from this pledge, citing &amp;ldquo;defense implications.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;1970s-media-reports&#34;&gt;1970s media reports &lt;a href=&#34;#1970s-media-reports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists various media reports from the 1970s covering Carter&amp;rsquo;s UFO sighting. It mentions articles in the &lt;em&gt;Atlanta Constitution&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The National Enquirer&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Argosy UFO&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;UFO Investigator&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;. It also notes inaccuracies in some of these reports, such as incorrect dates and locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related Wikipedia articles, including &amp;ldquo;Jimmy Carter rabbit incident,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;List of reported UFO sightings,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;UFO sightings in the United States.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the citations and cited works used in the article. It includes links to Carter&amp;rsquo;s report to the International UFO Bureau, news articles, and books on UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external websites related to the Jimmy Carter UFO incident, including archives of presidential UFO reports, interviews, and YouTube videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jimmy_Carter_UFO_incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jimmy_Carter_UFO_incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
