<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hynek Scale on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/hynek-scale/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hynek Scale on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 01:36:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/hynek-scale/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Close encounter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_6e704c7ca402/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 01:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_6e704c7ca402/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;close-encounter&#34;&gt;Close Encounter &lt;a href=&#34;#close-encounter&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A close encounter, in ufology, is defined as an event where a person witnesses an unidentified flying object (UFO) at close range, reducing the likelihood of misidentification. The term and classification system were introduced by astronomer and UFO researcher J. Allen Hynek in his 1972 book, &lt;em&gt;The UFO Experience: A Scientific Inquiry&lt;/em&gt;. While others have expanded on Hynek&amp;rsquo;s original categories, these extensions haven&amp;rsquo;t gained widespread acceptance due to a perceived lack of scientific rigor. Sightings beyond 150 meters are generally classified as &lt;em&gt;daylight discs&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;nocturnal lights&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;radar/visual reports&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hyneks-scale&#34;&gt;Hynek&amp;rsquo;s Scale &lt;a href=&#34;#hyneks-scale&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. Allen Hynek created a six-level classification system for UFO sightings, arranged by proximity. The categories include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nocturnal Lights:&lt;/strong&gt; Unexplained lights observed in the night sky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daylight Discs:&lt;/strong&gt; UFOs seen during the day, typically disc-shaped or oval.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Radar-Visual:&lt;/strong&gt; UFO sightings confirmed by radar, intended to provide more concrete evidence, though atmospheric anomalies can sometimes explain radar propagation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Close Encounters of the First Kind (CE1):&lt;/strong&gt; Visual sightings of a UFO at close range (less than 150 meters), displaying appreciable angular extension and detail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Close Encounters of the Second Kind (CE2):&lt;/strong&gt; UFO events involving physical effects, such as interference with vehicles or electronics, animal reactions, physiological effects on witnesses, or physical traces like ground impressions or scorched vegetation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind (CE3):&lt;/strong&gt; UFO encounters where animated entities are present, including humanoids, robots, or humans seemingly associated with the UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bloecher-subtypes&#34;&gt;Bloecher Subtypes &lt;a href=&#34;#bloecher-subtypes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ted Bloecher proposed six subtypes for Close Encounters of the Third Kind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aboard:&lt;/strong&gt; An entity is observed only inside the UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Both:&lt;/strong&gt; An entity is observed both inside and outside the UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Close:&lt;/strong&gt; An entity is observed near a UFO, but not entering or exiting it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Direct:&lt;/strong&gt; An entity is observed without any UFOs being seen, but UFO activity has been reported in the area around the same time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Excluded:&lt;/strong&gt; An entity is observed, but no UFOs are seen, and no UFO activity has been reported in the area at that time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frequence:&lt;/strong&gt; No entity or UFOs are observed, but the subject experiences some form of &amp;ldquo;intelligent communication.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;extensions-of-hyneks-scale&#34;&gt;Extensions of Hynek&amp;rsquo;s Scale &lt;a href=&#34;#extensions-of-hyneks-scale&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following Hynek&amp;rsquo;s death in 1986, Jacques Vallee expanded the classification system by adding Close Encounters of the Fourth and Fifth Kinds, detailed in his 1990 book, &lt;em&gt;Confrontations: A Scientist&amp;rsquo;s Search for Alien Contact&lt;/em&gt;. These extensions were quickly adopted by the Mutual UFO Network (MUFON).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;close-encounters-of-the-fourth-kind-ce4&#34;&gt;Close Encounters of the Fourth Kind (CE4) &lt;a href=&#34;#close-encounters-of-the-fourth-kind-ce4&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A CE4 involves a human being abducted by a UFO or its occupants. Jacques Vallée suggested that the &amp;ldquo;fourth kind&amp;rdquo; should encompass cases where witnesses experience a transformation of their sense of reality, including non-abduction events with absurd, hallucinatory, or dreamlike elements associated with UFO encounters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;close-encounters-of-the-fifth-kind-ce5&#34;&gt;Close Encounters of the Fifth Kind (CE5) &lt;a href=&#34;#close-encounters-of-the-fifth-kind-ce5&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Vallee&amp;rsquo;s original definition, a CE5 occurs when an alien abductee experiences a physical effect from the encounter, such as injury or healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alternate interpretation, popularized by Steven M. Greer, defines CE5 as human-initiated contact with extraterrestrial life forms or advanced interstellar civilizations, involving direct communication between aliens and humans. This involves individuals or groups using specific protocols, primarily contact meditation and sounds or signals, to establish communication or interaction with extraterrestrial beings. This is also referred to as human-initiated close encounter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;close-encounters-of-the-sixth-kind-ce6&#34;&gt;Close Encounters of the Sixth Kind (CE6) &lt;a href=&#34;#close-encounters-of-the-sixth-kind-ce6&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This term describes a sexual encounter between a human and an extraterrestrial species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Close_encounter&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Close_encounter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
