<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Extraterrestrials on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/extraterrestrials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Extraterrestrials on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:08:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/extraterrestrials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>List of UFO religions</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_c138a4063c7d/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_c138a4063c7d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-religions&#34;&gt;UFO Religions &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-religions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFO religions are groups that incorporate beliefs about communication with extraterrestrial beings into their religious doctrines. These groups often interpret major religions as being based on supernatural beings from heaven. Communication methods include telepathy and astral projection. A common belief is that humanity can be saved through education provided by aliens, leading to societal improvement. Alien abduction experiences can also contribute to the formation of these religions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for understanding UFO religions. It highlights that these religions generally involve belief in communication with extraterrestrial beings, often through physical contact, telepathy, or astral projection. These groups typically believe that aliens will save humanity by teaching them a better way to live, sometimes by taking believers to a more positive location. UFO religions emphasize spiritual growth and the evolution of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. Gordon Melton is identified as considering the &amp;ldquo;I AM&amp;rdquo; Activity, founded by Guy Ballard, as the first UFO religion. However, Christopher Hugh Partridge views it as a theosophical religion rather than a UFO religion. Partridge emphasizes the belief within UFO religions that supreme beings originate from other planets or planes, not from Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Roswell incident of 1947 is identified as a key event in the history of UFO spirituality, marking the emergence of UFOs into public consciousness. UFO religion is placed within the context of theosophical esotericism and New Age thought, with many groups believing that extraterrestrial beings are heralds of a new era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Aetherius Society, founded by George King in 1955, is described as one of the first and most enduring UFO cults. Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate and the Order of the Solar Temple are mentioned as controversial groups combining UFO beliefs with contactee assertions. Scientology is also discussed as a UFO religion due to its Xenu cosmogony and space opera elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;list&#34;&gt;List &lt;a href=&#34;#list&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a table listing various UFO religions, their founders, and the year they were founded. The list includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aetherius Society:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by George King in 1955.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ashtar Galactic Command:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Thelma B. Terrill (&amp;ldquo;Tuella&amp;rdquo;) in 1977.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CEIRUS:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Jean Miguères in 1987.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chen Tao:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Hon-ming Chen in 1993.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christ Brotherhood:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Wallace C. Halsey in 1956.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cosmic Circle of Fellowship:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by William R. Ferguson in 1955.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fiat Lux:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Uriella in 1980.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freie Interessengemeinschaft für Grenz- und Geisteswissenschaften und Ufologiestudien:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Billy Meier in the 1970s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ground Crew Project:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Sheldon Nidle in the 1980s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Marshall Applewhite and Bonnie Nettles in the 1970s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;I AM&amp;rdquo; Activity:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Guy Ballard in the 1930s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industrial Church of the New World Comforter:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Allen Michael in 1973.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark-Age:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Charles Boyd Gentzel and Pauline Sharpe in 1962.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nation of Islam:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Wallace Fard Muhammad in 1930.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Néo-Phare:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Arnaud Mussy in 2001.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nuwaubian Nation:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Dwight York in the 1970s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Order of the Solar Temple:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Joseph Di Mambro and Luc Jouret in 1984.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raëlism:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Raël in 1974.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rational Culture:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Manoel Jacintho Coelho in the 1930s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sanctuary of Thought:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Truman Bethurum in the 1950s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Seekers:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Charles Laughead (aka &amp;ldquo;Dr. Armstrong&amp;rdquo;) or Dorothy Martin (aka &amp;ldquo;Marian Keech&amp;rdquo;) in 1953.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Siderella:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Jean-Paul Appel-Guéry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scientology:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by L. Ron Hubbard in 1952.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unarius:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Ernest Norman and Ruth Norman in 1954.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universe People:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Ivo A. Benda in 1997.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Urantia movement:&lt;/strong&gt; Authorship of &lt;em&gt;The Urantia Book&lt;/em&gt; is unknown and disputed. The book alleges it was written by celestial beings. Founded between 1924 and 1955.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vale do Amanhecer:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Neiva Chaves Zelaya in the 1960s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics and links for further exploration, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Religion portal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outer space portal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doomsday cult&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of new religious movements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of ufologists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of UFO organizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO_religions&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO_religions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO religion</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_0a1958d0044c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 04:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_0a1958d0044c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-religion&#34;&gt;UFO Religion &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-religion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A UFO religion is a religion where belief in extraterrestrial entities operating unidentified flying objects (UFOs) is a core element. Adherents typically believe these ETs are interested in humanity&amp;rsquo;s welfare and that humanity will eventually join an existing ET civilization. Some UFO religions incorporate ETs into a supernatural worldview, blurring the lines between aliens and angels. These religions draw inspiration from early science fiction, ufology, UFO sightings, and alien abduction stories. The Aetherius Society, founded by George King, is considered the first UFO religion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary &lt;a href=&#34;#summary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adherents believe that the arrival or rediscovery of alien civilizations, technologies, and spirituality will enable humans to overcome ecological, spiritual, and social problems. Issues like hatred, war, bigotry, and poverty are believed to be resolvable through superior alien technology and spiritual abilities. These belief systems are often millenarian in their outlook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFO religions developed in countries like the United States, Canada, France, the United Kingdom, and Japan, where technology is advanced enough to conceive of ETs and where religion is not suppressed. The term &amp;ldquo;flying saucers&amp;rdquo; and the popular notion of the UFO originated in 1947. The study of UFO religions by sociologists, historians, theologians, scholars of religious studies, and new religious movements began in the 1950s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notable-ufo-religions&#34;&gt;Notable UFO Religions &lt;a href=&#34;#notable-ufo-religions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFO religions generally involve belief in communication with extraterrestrial beings through physical contact, telepathy, and astral projection. These groups often believe that humanity will be saved by aliens who will educate humans on a better way to live or take believers to a more positive location. Extraterrestrial beings are often seen pleading with humanity to improve itself and move away from greed and violence. UFO religions emphasize spiritual growth and the evolution of humanity. A UFO religion can form before or after an individual claims to have experienced an alien abduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. Gordon Melton identifies the &amp;ldquo;I AM&amp;rdquo; Activity, founded by Guy Ballard, as the first UFO religion, although Christopher Hugh Partridge views it as a theosophical religion. Partridge notes that UFO religions believe the supreme being or &amp;ldquo;evolved entity&amp;rdquo; came from another plane or planet. The 1947 Roswell incident is a key point in time within UFO spirituality. James R. Lewis notes that Ufologists see it as the date of the &amp;ldquo;emergence of UFOs into the public consciousness.&amp;rdquo; Partridge places UFO religion within the context of theosophical esotericism and asserts that it began to be associated as &amp;ldquo;UFO religion&amp;rdquo; after the Roswell incident. He notes that most UFO religions still have many of the key points associated with Theosophy, such as belief in the same Spiritual Hierarchy, and he also draws parallels to New Age thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen Hunt describes the Aetherius Society, founded by George King in 1955, as &amp;ldquo;probably the first and certainly the most enduring UFO cult.&amp;rdquo; Hunt places the Aetherius Society and Raëlism among the &amp;ldquo;most renowned&amp;rdquo; of the &amp;ldquo;flying saucer cults.&amp;rdquo; Melodie Campbell and Stephen A. Kent place the Aetherius Society and Unarius as among the &amp;ldquo;oldest and most studied&amp;rdquo; of the flying saucer cults. They describe Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate and Order of the Solar Temple as the &amp;ldquo;most controversial groups combining UFO belief with variations of contactee assertions.&amp;rdquo; Gregory L. Reece classes Scientology as a &amp;ldquo;UFO group,&amp;rdquo; discussing elements of the Xenu cosmogony and Space opera in Scientology doctrine. He compares Scientology to the Aetherius Society and Ashtar Command. Victoria Nelson writes that &amp;ldquo;[t]he most prominent current UFO religion is probably the science fiction writer L. Ron Hubbard&amp;rsquo;s Church of Scientology.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_religion&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_religion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
