<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Extraterrestrials on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/extraterrestrials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Extraterrestrials on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:08:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/extraterrestrials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>List of UFO religions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_c138a4063c7d/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_c138a4063c7d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-religions&#34;&gt;UFO Religions &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-religions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFO religions are groups that incorporate beliefs about communication with extraterrestrial beings into their religious doctrines. These groups often interpret major religions as being based on supernatural beings from heaven. Communication methods include telepathy and astral projection. A common belief is that humanity can be saved through education provided by aliens, leading to societal improvement. Alien abduction experiences can also contribute to the formation of these religions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for understanding UFO religions. It highlights that these religions generally involve belief in communication with extraterrestrial beings, often through physical contact, telepathy, or astral projection. These groups typically believe that aliens will save humanity by teaching them a better way to live, sometimes by taking believers to a more positive location. UFO religions emphasize spiritual growth and the evolution of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. Gordon Melton is identified as considering the &amp;ldquo;I AM&amp;rdquo; Activity, founded by Guy Ballard, as the first UFO religion. However, Christopher Hugh Partridge views it as a theosophical religion rather than a UFO religion. Partridge emphasizes the belief within UFO religions that supreme beings originate from other planets or planes, not from Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Roswell incident of 1947 is identified as a key event in the history of UFO spirituality, marking the emergence of UFOs into public consciousness. UFO religion is placed within the context of theosophical esotericism and New Age thought, with many groups believing that extraterrestrial beings are heralds of a new era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Aetherius Society, founded by George King in 1955, is described as one of the first and most enduring UFO cults. Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate and the Order of the Solar Temple are mentioned as controversial groups combining UFO beliefs with contactee assertions. Scientology is also discussed as a UFO religion due to its Xenu cosmogony and space opera elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;list&#34;&gt;List &lt;a href=&#34;#list&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a table listing various UFO religions, their founders, and the year they were founded. The list includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aetherius Society:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by George King in 1955.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ashtar Galactic Command:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Thelma B. Terrill (&amp;ldquo;Tuella&amp;rdquo;) in 1977.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CEIRUS:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Jean Miguères in 1987.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chen Tao:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Hon-ming Chen in 1993.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christ Brotherhood:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Wallace C. Halsey in 1956.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cosmic Circle of Fellowship:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by William R. Ferguson in 1955.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fiat Lux:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Uriella in 1980.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freie Interessengemeinschaft für Grenz- und Geisteswissenschaften und Ufologiestudien:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Billy Meier in the 1970s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ground Crew Project:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Sheldon Nidle in the 1980s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Marshall Applewhite and Bonnie Nettles in the 1970s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;I AM&amp;rdquo; Activity:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Guy Ballard in the 1930s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industrial Church of the New World Comforter:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Allen Michael in 1973.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark-Age:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Charles Boyd Gentzel and Pauline Sharpe in 1962.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nation of Islam:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Wallace Fard Muhammad in 1930.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Néo-Phare:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Arnaud Mussy in 2001.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nuwaubian Nation:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Dwight York in the 1970s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Order of the Solar Temple:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Joseph Di Mambro and Luc Jouret in 1984.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raëlism:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Raël in 1974.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rational Culture:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Manoel Jacintho Coelho in the 1930s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sanctuary of Thought:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Truman Bethurum in the 1950s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Seekers:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Charles Laughead (aka &amp;ldquo;Dr. Armstrong&amp;rdquo;) or Dorothy Martin (aka &amp;ldquo;Marian Keech&amp;rdquo;) in 1953.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Siderella:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Jean-Paul Appel-Guéry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scientology:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by L. Ron Hubbard in 1952.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unarius:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Ernest Norman and Ruth Norman in 1954.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universe People:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Ivo A. Benda in 1997.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Urantia movement:&lt;/strong&gt; Authorship of &lt;em&gt;The Urantia Book&lt;/em&gt; is unknown and disputed. The book alleges it was written by celestial beings. Founded between 1924 and 1955.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vale do Amanhecer:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Neiva Chaves Zelaya in the 1960s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics and links for further exploration, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Religion portal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outer space portal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doomsday cult&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of new religious movements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of ufologists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of UFO organizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO_religions&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO_religions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grey alien</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_dfdbd7176430/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 06:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_dfdbd7176430/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;grey-aliens&#34;&gt;Grey Aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#grey-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grey aliens, also known as Zeta Reticulians, Roswell Greys, or simply Greys, are alleged extraterrestrial beings frequently featured in close encounter and alien abduction claims. They are typically depicted as small humanoids with grey skin, large heads, and black, almond-shaped eyes. The Barney and Betty Hill abduction case in 1961 is credited with popularizing the image of Grey aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description &lt;a href=&#34;#description&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the typical physical characteristics attributed to Grey aliens. They are described as diminutive humanoid beings with grey skin, lacking external human features like noses, ears, or sex organs. Their bodies are elongated with small chests, lacking muscular definition, and having disproportionately short legs. A key feature is their large heads relative to their bodies, devoid of hair, with small orifices for ears, nostrils, and mouths. Their eyes are large, opaque, black, and almond-shaped. They are often described as shorter than average adult humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;association-with-zeta-reticuli&#34;&gt;Association with Zeta Reticuli &lt;a href=&#34;#association-with-zeta-reticuli&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The connection between Grey aliens and the Zeta Reticuli star system stems from Marjorie Fish&amp;rsquo;s interpretation of a star map drawn by Betty Hill in 1969. Hill, under hypnosis, claimed the map showed the aliens&amp;rsquo; home system. Fish created a model based on Hill&amp;rsquo;s drawing and identified the stars as Zeta Reticuli, a binary star system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section traces the origins and evolution of the Grey alien archetype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;origins&#34;&gt;Origins &lt;a href=&#34;#origins&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Descriptions of beings resembling Grey aliens predate reported encounters. H.G. Wells described future humans with similar features in his 1893 article &amp;ldquo;The Man of the Year Million&amp;rdquo; and his 1895 novel &lt;em&gt;The Time Machine&lt;/em&gt;. In 1917, Aleister Crowley described an entity named Lam with a similar appearance. In 1933, Swedish novelist Gustav Sandgren, writing as Gabriel Linde, described aliens with grey clothes, bald heads, and large eyes in his science fiction novel &lt;em&gt;The Unknown Danger&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;barney-and-betty-hill-abduction&#34;&gt;Barney and Betty Hill abduction &lt;a href=&#34;#barney-and-betty-hill-abduction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Barney and Betty Hill abduction case in 1961 brought the Grey alien archetype to public attention in 1965. The Hills claimed they were abducted by grey-skinned humanoids and taken aboard a flying saucer. Martin Kottmeyer suggested Barney&amp;rsquo;s memories, revealed under hypnosis, may have been influenced by an episode of &lt;em&gt;The Outer Limits&lt;/em&gt; titled &amp;ldquo;The Bellero Shield,&amp;rdquo; which aired shortly before Barney&amp;rsquo;s first hypnotic session. Carl Sagan also suggested &lt;em&gt;Invaders from Mars&lt;/em&gt; as a potential inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;diffusion-into-folklore&#34;&gt;Diffusion into folklore &lt;a href=&#34;#diffusion-into-folklore&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the Hill&amp;rsquo;s encounter, Greys became a central figure in ufology and extraterrestrial folklore, particularly in the United States, where they account for 73% of reported alien encounters. The alleged crash-landing of a flying saucer in Roswell, New Mexico, in 1947, was later linked to Greys. In 1987, Whitley Strieber published &lt;em&gt;Communion&lt;/em&gt;, a book detailing his alleged encounters with Greys, which became a bestseller and was adapted into a film. In 1988, Jimmy Guieu introduced the term &amp;ldquo;les Petits-Gris&amp;rdquo; (little greys) to French audiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greys have become the subject of conspiracy theories, with some theorists believing they are part of government disinformation campaigns or mind-control experiments. Ray Santilli claimed to have obtained film footage of an autopsy of a &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; Grey recovered from Roswell, but later admitted it was a &amp;ldquo;reconstruction.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;analysis&#34;&gt;Analysis &lt;a href=&#34;#analysis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores various analyses and interpretations of the Grey alien phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-close-encounter-claims-and-ufology&#34;&gt;In close encounter claims and ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#in-close-encounter-claims-and-ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greys are frequently associated with alien abduction claims, accounting for a significant percentage of reported encounters in various countries. Abduction claims are often described as traumatic, similar to human abduction or sexual assault. The eyes of the Greys are often a focal point, with claims of inducing hallucinogenic states or emotions through staring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;psychocultural-expression-of-intelligence&#34;&gt;Psychocultural expression of intelligence &lt;a href=&#34;#psychocultural-expression-of-intelligence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neurologist Steven Novella suggests that Grey aliens are a product of the human imagination, with their features representing traits associated with intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-mother-hypothesis&#34;&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Mother Hypothesis&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#the-mother-hypothesis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frederick V. Malmstrom proposes that Greys are residual memories of early childhood development, reconstructing the face of a Grey through transformation of a mother&amp;rsquo;s face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;evolutionary-implausibility&#34;&gt;Evolutionary implausibility &lt;a href=&#34;#evolutionary-implausibility&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biologist Jack Cohen argues that the typical image of a Grey is too physiologically similar to a human to be a credible representation of an alien from a different environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-hypotheses&#34;&gt;Other hypotheses &lt;a href=&#34;#other-hypotheses&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interdimensional, cryptoterrestrial, and time-traveler hypotheses offer alternative explanations for the humanoid anatomy and behavior of these alleged beings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights the presence of Grey aliens in various forms of media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grey aliens have become a common depiction of extraterrestrials in fiction, replacing the earlier &amp;ldquo;little green men.&amp;rdquo; They have appeared in films and television shows such as &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Babylon 5&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Stargate&lt;/em&gt;. During the 1990s, plotlines linking Greys to conspiracy theories became prevalent, as seen in &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt;. Other examples include the &lt;em&gt;XCOM&lt;/em&gt; video game franchise, &lt;em&gt;Dark Skies&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;American Dad!&lt;/em&gt;. The film &lt;em&gt;Paul&lt;/em&gt; features a Grey alien who attributes the Greys&amp;rsquo; presence in pop culture to government manipulation. The film &lt;em&gt;Dark Skies&lt;/em&gt; features child abduction by Greys. Greys also appear in the TV series &lt;em&gt;Resident Alien&lt;/em&gt; and the game &lt;em&gt;Greyhill Incident&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grey_alien&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grey_alien&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrials in fiction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_86feb41cd744/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 03:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_86feb41cd744/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;fictional-depictions-of-extraterrestrial-life&#34;&gt;Fictional Depictions of Extraterrestrial Life &lt;a href=&#34;#fictional-depictions-of-extraterrestrial-life&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses extraterrestrials as they are portrayed in works of fiction, distinguishing them from alleged real-life encounters. It includes a link to a separate article listing alleged extraterrestrial beings. A banner at the top indicates that the article relies heavily on a limited number of sources and needs more citations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the historical evolution of extraterrestrial depictions in fiction, starting from antiquity and progressing through modern times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;antiquity&#34;&gt;Antiquity &lt;a href=&#34;#antiquity&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers early depictions of extraterrestrials, beginning with Lucian&amp;rsquo;s 2nd-century satire &lt;em&gt;True History&lt;/em&gt;, where the protagonist visits the Moon and finds it inhabited by warring factions. It emphasizes how early concepts of extraterrestrials were tied to the development of astronomy and the understanding of celestial objects as physical entities. Early depictions often portrayed aliens as human-like, as exemplified by Voltaire&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Micromégas&lt;/em&gt; and works by Johannes Kepler, Francis Godwin, and Cyrano de Bergerac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-20th-century&#34;&gt;Early 20th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#early-20th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the impact of Charles Darwin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;On the Origin of Species&lt;/em&gt; on alien depictions, leading to the creation of non-humanoid aliens in fiction. Camille Flammarion&amp;rsquo;s works are mentioned as early examples of genuinely alien lifeforms. The section also highlights H.G. Wells&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;The War of the Worlds&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The First Men in the Moon&lt;/em&gt; as influential works that explored the implications of evolution and alien civilizations. The rise of pulp magazines and their role in popularizing science fiction with various alien tropes are also discussed, including the common use of Martians, Venusians, and other Solar System inhabitants. Stanley G. Weinbaum&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;A Martian Odyssey&lt;/em&gt; is noted for its unique Martian ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;modern-times&#34;&gt;Modern Times &lt;a href=&#34;#modern-times&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the evolution of alien depictions in more recent times. It mentions &lt;em&gt;The Eternaut&lt;/em&gt; by Héctor Germán Oesterheld, an Argentine work that critiques imperialism and colonialism through an alien invasion of Buenos Aires. The Barney and Betty Hill incident is discussed as a pivotal event that popularized the &amp;ldquo;grey alien&amp;rdquo; archetype. The influence of TV and films, particularly &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt;, is highlighted, noting the trend towards human-like aliens due to budgetary constraints. The section concludes by mentioning the impact of computer-generated imagery (CGI) on creating more diverse and bizarre alien lifeforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;types&#34;&gt;Types &lt;a href=&#34;#types&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section categorizes the various ways extraterrestrials are portrayed in fiction. It discusses differences in intelligence levels, biological forms (humanoid, Earth-species-like, or bizarre), and attitudes towards humanity (hostile, friendly, or indifferent). It also mentions that some extraterrestrials in fiction originate from unexplored areas of Earth, such as the sea, sky, underground, or other dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See Also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related Wikipedia articles, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parasites in fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of fictional extraterrestrials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of films featuring extraterrestrials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of humanoid aliens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mars in fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First contact (science fiction)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including books, journal articles, and online resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bibliography&#34;&gt;Bibliography &lt;a href=&#34;#bibliography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists additional books related to the topic of extraterrestrials in fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further Reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of additional resources for readers interested in learning more about the topic, including books and articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External Links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a link to an external website with additional information on the use of aliens as metaphors in fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_life_in_popular_culture&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_life_in_popular_culture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO religion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_0a1958d0044c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 04:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_0a1958d0044c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-religion&#34;&gt;UFO Religion &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-religion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A UFO religion is a religion where belief in extraterrestrial entities operating unidentified flying objects (UFOs) is a core element. Adherents typically believe these ETs are interested in humanity&amp;rsquo;s welfare and that humanity will eventually join an existing ET civilization. Some UFO religions incorporate ETs into a supernatural worldview, blurring the lines between aliens and angels. These religions draw inspiration from early science fiction, ufology, UFO sightings, and alien abduction stories. The Aetherius Society, founded by George King, is considered the first UFO religion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary &lt;a href=&#34;#summary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adherents believe that the arrival or rediscovery of alien civilizations, technologies, and spirituality will enable humans to overcome ecological, spiritual, and social problems. Issues like hatred, war, bigotry, and poverty are believed to be resolvable through superior alien technology and spiritual abilities. These belief systems are often millenarian in their outlook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFO religions developed in countries like the United States, Canada, France, the United Kingdom, and Japan, where technology is advanced enough to conceive of ETs and where religion is not suppressed. The term &amp;ldquo;flying saucers&amp;rdquo; and the popular notion of the UFO originated in 1947. The study of UFO religions by sociologists, historians, theologians, scholars of religious studies, and new religious movements began in the 1950s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notable-ufo-religions&#34;&gt;Notable UFO Religions &lt;a href=&#34;#notable-ufo-religions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFO religions generally involve belief in communication with extraterrestrial beings through physical contact, telepathy, and astral projection. These groups often believe that humanity will be saved by aliens who will educate humans on a better way to live or take believers to a more positive location. Extraterrestrial beings are often seen pleading with humanity to improve itself and move away from greed and violence. UFO religions emphasize spiritual growth and the evolution of humanity. A UFO religion can form before or after an individual claims to have experienced an alien abduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. Gordon Melton identifies the &amp;ldquo;I AM&amp;rdquo; Activity, founded by Guy Ballard, as the first UFO religion, although Christopher Hugh Partridge views it as a theosophical religion. Partridge notes that UFO religions believe the supreme being or &amp;ldquo;evolved entity&amp;rdquo; came from another plane or planet. The 1947 Roswell incident is a key point in time within UFO spirituality. James R. Lewis notes that Ufologists see it as the date of the &amp;ldquo;emergence of UFOs into the public consciousness.&amp;rdquo; Partridge places UFO religion within the context of theosophical esotericism and asserts that it began to be associated as &amp;ldquo;UFO religion&amp;rdquo; after the Roswell incident. He notes that most UFO religions still have many of the key points associated with Theosophy, such as belief in the same Spiritual Hierarchy, and he also draws parallels to New Age thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen Hunt describes the Aetherius Society, founded by George King in 1955, as &amp;ldquo;probably the first and certainly the most enduring UFO cult.&amp;rdquo; Hunt places the Aetherius Society and Raëlism among the &amp;ldquo;most renowned&amp;rdquo; of the &amp;ldquo;flying saucer cults.&amp;rdquo; Melodie Campbell and Stephen A. Kent place the Aetherius Society and Unarius as among the &amp;ldquo;oldest and most studied&amp;rdquo; of the flying saucer cults. They describe Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate and Order of the Solar Temple as the &amp;ldquo;most controversial groups combining UFO belief with variations of contactee assertions.&amp;rdquo; Gregory L. Reece classes Scientology as a &amp;ldquo;UFO group,&amp;rdquo; discussing elements of the Xenu cosmogony and Space opera in Scientology doctrine. He compares Scientology to the Aetherius Society and Ashtar Command. Victoria Nelson writes that &amp;ldquo;[t]he most prominent current UFO religion is probably the science fiction writer L. Ron Hubbard&amp;rsquo;s Church of Scientology.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_religion&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_religion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Contact  A Serious Handbook for Locating and Communicating With Extraterrestrials</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_6f918de7ab48/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 18:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_6f918de7ab48/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;making-contact-a-serious-handbook-for-locating-and-communicating-with-extraterrestrials&#34;&gt;Making Contact: A Serious Handbook for Locating and Communicating With Extraterrestrials &lt;a href=&#34;#making-contact-a-serious-handbook-for-locating-and-communicating-with-extraterrestrials&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Making Contact: A Serious Handbook for Locating and Communicating With Extraterrestrials&lt;/em&gt; is a book published in 1998.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents &lt;a href=&#34;#contents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the book&amp;rsquo;s subject matter, which encompasses various aspects of close encounters with extraterrestrials. Bill Fawcett, the editor, is quoted stating his belief that the existence of extraterrestrials is &amp;ldquo;unquestionable.&amp;rdquo; The book delves into potential signs and symptoms of alien abduction, including burns, tinnitus, a metallic taste, and double vision. Specific locations, such as Area 51 and Mexico City, are identified as places where encounters are more likely to occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is currently empty, indicating a lack of documented critical or public response to the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited within the article. These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;Chicago Sun-Times&lt;/em&gt; article by Dolores and Roger Flaherty from July 26, 1998, discussing the book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;Daily Herald&lt;/em&gt; article by Hilary Shenfeld from September 22, 1997, which provides details about the book&amp;rsquo;s content and the author&amp;rsquo;s perspective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Making_Contact_(book)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Making_Contact_(book)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
