<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>China on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/china/</link>
    <description>Recent content in China on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 17:48:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/china/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in China</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_25387abed308/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 17:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_25387abed308/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-sightings-in-china&#34;&gt;UFO Sightings in China &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-sightings-in-china&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article documents alleged sightings of unidentified flying objects (UFOs) in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1994&#34;&gt;1994 &lt;a href=&#34;#1994&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on &amp;ldquo;The Meng Zhaoguo Incident,&amp;rdquo; a purported close encounter of the third kind that Meng Zhaoguo claimed to have experienced in Phoenix Mountain, Wuchang, Heilongjiang. In 1994, Meng reported seeing a white, shining object descend into the mountain. He claimed to have been harassed by entities, taken aboard their spacecraft, and forced to copulate. He also stated that he was shown images of Jupiter, which the entities claimed was their homeworld. The UFO Enthusiasts Club at Wuhan University examined his story and concluded that while the initial contact might have occurred, the subsequent events were likely untrue. Other UFO groups in China, however, believed his claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2010&#34;&gt;2010 &lt;a href=&#34;#2010&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details a UFO sighting that occurred on July 7 above Hangzhou Xiaoshan International Airport near Hangzhou. The airport was temporarily closed due to the sighting. An investigation found no radar images and determined that the purported images of the UFO were not taken near the airport. The investigation concluded that the object may have been an aircraft, possibly military.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the &amp;ldquo;List of reported UFO sightings&amp;rdquo; for broader context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including news articles and websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_China&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_China&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
