<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Varginha on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/varginha/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Varginha on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 10:39:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/varginha/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Varginha UFO incident</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_3cbfbc358e9c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_3cbfbc358e9c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;varginha-ufo-incident&#34;&gt;Varginha UFO Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#varginha-ufo-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Varginha UFO incident refers to a series of events in 1996 in Varginha, Brazil, where residents reported sightings of strange creatures and at least one unidentified flying object (UFO). These reports gained significant media attention. Claims associated with the incident include the alleged capture of extraterrestrial beings by Brazilian authorities, animal fatalities at a zoo, and a woman becoming pregnant by an extraterrestrial. The Brazilian Army investigated the incident and concluded that a city resident was mistaken for an alien creature and that military activity in the area was routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 20, 1996, three women reported seeing a creature with a large head, bipedal stance, &amp;ldquo;spots like veins&amp;rdquo; on its skin, bumps on its head, and red eyes. The creature, later called the &amp;ldquo;ET de Varginha,&amp;rdquo; appeared unsteady, leading the women to believe it was injured or sick. They fled and told their mother they had seen the &amp;ldquo;devil.&amp;rdquo; Rumors spread about UFO sightings in the days prior. Claims emerged of additional creatures being captured and observed at a hospital, military activity in the area, an unidentified animal in a local forest, the death of a police officer, and unexplained animal deaths at the local zoo. Ufologists linked these claims, including the allegation that one of the initial witnesses became pregnant by the creature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inquiry&#34;&gt;Inquiry &lt;a href=&#34;#inquiry&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An official inquiry by the Brazilian military in 2010 concluded that the women encountered a homeless, mentally unstable man nicknamed &amp;ldquo;Mudinho.&amp;rdquo; The Commander of the 24th Police Battalion Military presented photographs of Mudinho, whose physical characteristics matched the description of the creature. The inquiry suggested that Mudinho, being dirty and crouching by a wall due to heavy rains, was mistaken for a space creature. The head of the inquiry stated that military trucks and personnel were performing routine duties, such as firefighters responding to a call, Army trucks undergoing maintenance, and vehicles departing from the Escola de Sargentos das Armas (EsSA). Skeptic Brian Dunning criticized sensational media accounts and ufologists&amp;rsquo; claims, arguing that the incident was magnified into unassailable proof of alien visitation despite a lack of unusual events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tourism&#34;&gt;Tourism &lt;a href=&#34;#tourism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The claims surrounding the Varginha incident have significantly impacted tourism in the city. Grey alien dolls in football uniforms are sold at the incident&amp;rsquo;s location. Grey alien designs are used in advertising campaigns for the municipality. Bus stops were built in the form of spaceships, and a 20-meter tall water tower with a disc-shaped water reservoir, called the Nave Espacial de Varginha, was erected in the town center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;media&#34;&gt;Media &lt;a href=&#34;#media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several media productions have been inspired by the Varginha UFO incident:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;1996&lt;/em&gt;, a 2020 short film by Rodrigo Brandão, is a horror story in the style of &lt;em&gt;The Blair Witch Project&lt;/em&gt; about two teenagers who get lost in the woods near Varginha and encounter an extraterrestrial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Incidente em Varginha&lt;/em&gt; is a video game inspired by the events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moment of Contact&lt;/em&gt;, a 2022 documentary film by James Fox, investigates the incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;O.V.N.I L&amp;rsquo;affaire Varginha&lt;/em&gt;, a French comic book by Philippe Auger, tells the story of the incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article lists related topics, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFO sightings in Brazil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1986 Brazilian UFO incident&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operação Prato&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Varginha_UFO_incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Varginha_UFO_incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
