<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Extraterrestrial Encounters on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/extraterrestrial-encounters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Extraterrestrial Encounters on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 22:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/extraterrestrial-encounters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nordic aliens</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7c6654f96aa5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 22:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7c6654f96aa5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;nordic-aliens&#34;&gt;Nordic Aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#nordic-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In ufology, &amp;ldquo;Nordics,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Nordic aliens,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Tall Whites&amp;rdquo; are terms used to describe alleged humanoid extraterrestrials who purportedly resemble Nordic, Germanic, or Scandinavian humans. They are said to originate from the Pleiades star cluster and are often described by contactees as being taller than average humans (6-7 ft), with blond hair, blue eyes, and fair skin. Some reports also mention pale-blue/grey or pastel purple skin tones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Early stories of Nordic aliens may have been inspired by the 1951 film &lt;em&gt;The Day the Earth Stood Still&lt;/em&gt;. Within the ufology community, these aliens are often associated with spiritual growth, benevolence, and protection. They are described as concerned about Earth&amp;rsquo;s ecology and world peace, possessing telepathic abilities, and exhibiting paternal, watchful, affectionate, and youthful characteristics. While popular in the 1950s, claims of encounters with Nordic aliens have become less frequent, with the grey alien becoming more prominent in reported extraterrestrial encounters. David J. Skal, a cultural historian, and Stephanie Kelley-Romano, a professor at Bates College, are mentioned in relation to their perspectives on Nordic aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publications-by-those-claiming-to-have-been-contacted&#34;&gt;Publications by Those Claiming to Have Been Contacted &lt;a href=&#34;#publications-by-those-claiming-to-have-been-contacted&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several books detail alleged personal contact with Nordic aliens. These include &lt;em&gt;Flying Saucers Have Landed&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Inside the Space Ships&lt;/em&gt; by George Adamski, &lt;em&gt;From Outer Space to You&lt;/em&gt; by Howard Menger, &lt;em&gt;The Walton Experience&lt;/em&gt; by Travis Walton, and &lt;em&gt;Millennial Hospitality&lt;/em&gt; by Charles James Hall, which was adapted into the film &lt;em&gt;Walking with the Tall Whites&lt;/em&gt;. The UFO religion Universe People also publishes interactions with &amp;ldquo;Cosmic Friends.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See Also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists related topics and figures in ufology, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Space Brothers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Truman Bethurum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elizabeth Klarer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Billy Meier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linda Moulton Howe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of alleged extraterrestrial beings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star people (New Age)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arcturians (New Age)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFOs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFO religion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists the references used in the article, including books and articles by Debbora Battaglia, C. D. B. Bryan, Jerome Clark, Una McGovern, Stephanie Kelley-Romano, David Skal, Desmond Leslie, George Adamski, Howard Menger, Travis Walton, Charles James Hall, and links to external websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External Links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to Wikimedia Commons for media related to Nordic aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_aliens&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_aliens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
