<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Radio Play on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/radio-play/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Radio Play on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 10:06:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/radio-play/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First Contact (novelette)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_09c859882d14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 10:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_09c859882d14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-contact&#34;&gt;First Contact &lt;a href=&#34;#first-contact&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;First Contact&amp;rdquo; is a science fiction novelette written by Murray Leinster, published in &lt;em&gt;Astounding Science Fiction&lt;/em&gt; in May 1945. It received a retro Hugo Award for Best Novelette in 1996. The story is notable for its early depiction of a universal translator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story revolves around the crew of the exploration ship &lt;em&gt;Llanvabon&lt;/em&gt; encountering an alien vessel near the Crab Nebula. Both ships are technologically matched and represent their respective civilizations. The central conflict arises from the mutual fear that either ship could trace the other back to their home planet, leading to potential exploitation or destruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communication is established, revealing that the aliens are humanoid bipeds who perceive infrared light and communicate via microwaves. Despite the differences, the crews, particularly a young human named Tommy Dort and his alien counterpart &amp;ldquo;Buck,&amp;rdquo; develop a rapport. However, the underlying tension remains due to the strategic implications of revealing their home worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story reaches a climax when Tommy proposes a solution: a mutual exchange of crews and ships. Each crew would take the other&amp;rsquo;s ship back to their respective home planets after disabling all tracking equipment. This plan is complicated by the realization that the aliens have independently conceived the same strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story concludes with the successful exchange, each crew departing in the other&amp;rsquo;s ship. They remove any identifying information that could lead back to their home worlds. Both sides anticipate technological gains from the exchange and plan to meet again in the future. Tommy expresses optimism about future relations, based on his shared sense of humor with Buck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;radio-plays&#34;&gt;Radio Plays &lt;a href=&#34;#radio-plays&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;First Contact&amp;rdquo; was adapted into radio plays for &lt;em&gt;Dimension X&lt;/em&gt; on September 8, 1951, and for &lt;em&gt;X Minus One&lt;/em&gt; on October 6, 1955. The &lt;em&gt;X Minus One&lt;/em&gt; version was a condensed adaptation with an altered ending. The story was also performed on &lt;em&gt;Exploring Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt; on January 15, 1958.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;style&#34;&gt;Style &lt;a href=&#34;#style&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writing style of &amp;ldquo;First Contact&amp;rdquo; is considered representative of the Golden Age of science fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legal-action-against-paramount-pictures&#34;&gt;Legal Action Against Paramount Pictures &lt;a href=&#34;#legal-action-against-paramount-pictures&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2000, Murray Leinster&amp;rsquo;s estate filed a lawsuit against Paramount Pictures, alleging trademark infringement related to the film &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: First Contact&lt;/em&gt;. The estate claimed ownership of the term &amp;ldquo;First Contact&amp;rdquo; and argued that Paramount&amp;rsquo;s use of the phrase infringed on their trademark. The U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia ruled in favor of Paramount, granting summary judgment and dismissing the suit. The court determined that the term &amp;ldquo;First Contact&amp;rdquo; had become generic, describing a common science fiction trope, and lacked the necessary secondary meaning to be protected as a trademark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_Contact_(novelette)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_Contact_(novelette)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
