<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UFO Research on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ufo-research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UFO Research on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 18:55:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ufo-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Center for UFO Studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_1684f4ca8cd3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 18:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_1684f4ca8cd3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;center-for-ufo-studies-cufos&#34;&gt;Center for UFO Studies (CUFOS) &lt;a href=&#34;#center-for-ufo-studies-cufos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Center for UFO Studies (CUFOS) is a privately funded UFO research group. It is a nonprofit organization founded in 1973 by J. Allen Hynek, who was the chair of the Department of Astronomy at Northwestern University in Illinois at the time. The organization&amp;rsquo;s headquarters are located in Chicago, Illinois, United States. CUFOS&amp;rsquo;s website is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cufos.org&#34;&gt;www.cufos.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. Allen Hynek, the founder of CUFOS, was a scientific consultant for Project Blue Book, the United States Air Force&amp;rsquo;s official study of the UFO phenomenon from 1948 to 1969. Initially a skeptic, Hynek gradually became convinced that some UFO cases were not hoaxes or misidentifications and might represent something extraordinary, such as alien visitation. After the Air Force shut down Project Blue Book in 1969, Hynek founded CUFOS in 1973 to continue collecting and studying UFO reports. James W. Moseley described CUFOS as the first real attempt to establish a private research group genuinely dedicated to the scientific investigation and study of UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;operation&#34;&gt;Operation &lt;a href=&#34;#operation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CUFOS, which started in Evanston, Illinois, but is now based in Chicago, continues to be a small research organization emphasizing the scientific analysis of UFO cases. Its archives include files from defunct civilian research groups like the National Investigations Committee On Aerial Phenomena (NICAP). Following Hynek&amp;rsquo;s death in 1986, CUFOS was renamed the J. Allen Hynek Center for UFO Studies in his honor. Mark Rodeghier, an associate editor of the Journal of Scientific Exploration, has been the Director of CUFOS since 1986. Ufologists who have served on the CUFOS Board of Directors include Jerome Clark, Michael D. Swords, and Thomas E. Bullard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CUFOS maintains a library and archives of UFO-related materials, open for use by researchers and investigators. It also continues to compile and analyze reports of UFO incidents from around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to a list of UFO organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the references cited in the article, providing sources for the information presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources &lt;a href=&#34;#sources&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources used in the article, including books by Jerome Clark and James W. Moseley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the official website of the Center for UFO Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Center_for_UFO_Studies&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Center_for_UFO_Studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
