<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Albania on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/albania/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Albania on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 14:18:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/albania/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in Albania</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6fdd01abfa7c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6fdd01abfa7c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-albania&#34;&gt;List of alleged UFO sightings in Albania &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-albania&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article documents alleged UFO sightings in Albania, spanning from 1907 to 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1907&#34;&gt;1907 &lt;a href=&#34;#1907&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the earliest documented UFO encounter in Albania, recorded in the diary of Mihal Grameno, a journalist, writer, and activist. He recounts an incident during the years 1907–1908 while fighting alongside Çerçiz Topulli&amp;rsquo;s guerrilla group. Grameno describes a shiny object that hovered in the air before disappearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;8-july-1933&#34;&gt;8 July 1933 &lt;a href=&#34;#8-july-1933&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions a report addressed to the Prefecture of Milan regarding an unusual incident in Vlorë. It states that two airplanes changed direction in a way that was considered abnormal for the technology of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;18-july-1947&#34;&gt;18 July 1947 &lt;a href=&#34;#18-july-1947&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section references an FBI report that mentions UFOs, also referred to as &amp;ldquo;saucers,&amp;rdquo; being observed in various locations worldwide, including Albania.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;january-1963&#34;&gt;January 1963 &lt;a href=&#34;#january-1963&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes an incident in the village of Kallamishtëz in the Kurvelesh area, where residents reported seeing a bright object in the sky. The Albanian authorities attempted to explain the sighting as a new jet plane model used by the Albanian Air Force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1969&#34;&gt;1969 &lt;a href=&#34;#1969&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section recounts an experience of Ilir Malindi, a lawyer, in the Pirogoshi Canyon above Çorovodë. Malindi and others witnessed two luminous, circular objects that illuminated the canyon before rapidly disappearing into the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-august-1990&#34;&gt;1 August 1990 &lt;a href=&#34;#1-august-1990&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details an event experienced by Gëzim Dapi, an environmental engineer, while serving in the military in Shkodër. Dapi describes seeing a series of lights arranged in a diamond pattern moving at high speed with minimal noise. Other soldiers from different anti-aircraft units reported the same sighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;12-july-1993&#34;&gt;12 July 1993 &lt;a href=&#34;#12-july-1993&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes a sighting in Cërrik, Elbasan, where a glowing flying object appeared in the sky. Eyewitnesses reported sudden and quick movements of the object, which disappeared after approximately two hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-may-2006&#34;&gt;4 May 2006 &lt;a href=&#34;#4-may-2006&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section recounts the most famous case of UFO encounters in Albania, which occurred in the village of Roskovec. Residents, including an adult woman and two children, reported an unidentified object landing in their town. Evidence included three double-banded black circles in the asphalt. Witnesses described a sudden darkness, strong wind, and the object&amp;rsquo;s appearance as an oval disc with a gray color and a thin blue line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-march-2007&#34;&gt;6 March 2007 &lt;a href=&#34;#6-march-2007&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details a sighting reported by Coast Guard officer Admir Jemishaj and his commander in Seman, Fier. They observed an unmoving object in space that had a dazzling shine, changed colors, and had a disc-like shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;24-december-2008&#34;&gt;24 December 2008 &lt;a href=&#34;#24-december-2008&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes an encounter reported by four hunters from Elbasan. They claimed to have seen a flying disk in a village near Peqin. The hunters reported being blinded by a bright blue light and a vertical red light, which caused their vehicle&amp;rsquo;s engine to die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;21-july-2009&#34;&gt;21 July 2009 &lt;a href=&#34;#21-july-2009&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section recounts a sighting in Vlorë, where fishermen reported seeing an unidentified flying object shaped like a satellite in the area behind Karaburun. The object emitted a trail of smoke and was gray to white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-august-2010&#34;&gt;7 August 2010 &lt;a href=&#34;#7-august-2010&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details a sighting in Tirana, where a woman, Rezmie Lulo, and her family witnessed three strange, orange, spherical objects shining in the sky. The objects moved at immense speed, and the Albanian Army and Civil Aviation Authority did not provide official information about the objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to related articles, including &amp;ldquo;UFO sightings in Kosovo&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;List of reported UFO sightings.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including news articles, books, and YouTube videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Albania&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Albania&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
