<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Extraterrestrial Life in Fiction on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/extraterrestrial-life-in-fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Extraterrestrial Life in Fiction on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 03:36:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/extraterrestrial-life-in-fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrials in fiction</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_fb66d06449f7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 03:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_fb66d06449f7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;fictional-depictions-of-extraterrestrial-life&#34;&gt;Fictional Depictions of Extraterrestrial Life &lt;a href=&#34;#fictional-depictions-of-extraterrestrial-life&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article provides an overview of how extraterrestrial life is portrayed in fiction, distinguishing it from claims of actual alien encounters. It notes that the article relies heavily on a limited number of sources and encourages readers to contribute additional citations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section traces the evolution of extraterrestrial depictions in fiction from antiquity to modern times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;antiquity&#34;&gt;Antiquity &lt;a href=&#34;#antiquity&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This subsection begins with Lucian&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;True History&lt;/em&gt; (2nd century) as an early example of extraterrestrial encounters, featuring a visit to the Moon. It explains that early concepts of extraterrestrials were closely tied to the understanding of astronomy and the prevailing anthropocentric view, where aliens were essentially humans from other celestial bodies. Voltaire&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Micromégas&lt;/em&gt; (1752) and works by Johannes Kepler, Francis Godwin, and Cyrano de Bergerac are mentioned as examples where extraterrestrials differed from humans only in culture or size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-20th-century&#34;&gt;Early 20th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#early-20th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the impact of Charles Darwin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;On the Origin of Species&lt;/em&gt; (1859) on alien depictions, leading to more diverse and non-humanoid portrayals. Camille Flammarion&amp;rsquo;s works, H.G. Wells&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;The War of the Worlds&lt;/em&gt; (1898) and &lt;em&gt;The First Men in the Moon&lt;/em&gt; (1901), Stanley G. Weinbaum&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;A Martian Odyssey&lt;/em&gt; (1934), and Olaf Stapledon&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Star Maker&lt;/em&gt; (1937) are highlighted as examples of genuinely alien lifeforms. It also notes that many works still featured human-like aliens. &lt;em&gt;The War of the Worlds&lt;/em&gt; is analyzed for its use of Darwinian evolution, exploration of alien life implications, critique of British imperialism, and introduction of alien invasion tropes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-20th-century-1&#34;&gt;Early 20th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#early-20th-century-1&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the rise of pulp magazines and their influence on science fiction. It notes the prevalence of quasi-human aliens, monstrous invaders, and the inversion of the alien invasion trope with humans conquering alien worlds. The section also mentions the common setting of stories within the Solar System and the shift brought about by Stanley G. Weinbaum&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;A Martian Odyssey&lt;/em&gt;, which featured a unique Martian ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;modern-times&#34;&gt;Modern Times &lt;a href=&#34;#modern-times&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the evolution of alien depictions in modern times, starting with &lt;em&gt;The Eternaut&lt;/em&gt; by Héctor Germán Oesterheld, which critiques imperialism and colonialism through an alien invasion of Buenos Aires. The Barney and Betty Hill incident (1961) is mentioned as the origin of the &amp;ldquo;grey alien&amp;rdquo; archetype. The impact of TV and films, particularly &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt;, on popularizing extraterrestrial themes is discussed. The section concludes by noting the influence of computer-generated imagery (CGI) on creating more diverse and bizarre alien lifeforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;types&#34;&gt;Types &lt;a href=&#34;#types&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section categorizes the various ways extraterrestrials are portrayed in fiction, including their intelligence levels, biological forms, and attitudes towards humanity. It notes that aliens may be hostile invaders, friendly allies, or indifferent observers. The section also mentions that some extraterrestrials may originate from unexplored regions of Earth, such as the sea, sky, underground, or other dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See Also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of internal links to related Wikipedia articles, including &amp;ldquo;Parasites in fiction,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;List of fictional extraterrestrials,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;List of films featuring extraterrestrials,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;List of humanoid aliens,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Mars in fiction,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;First contact (science fiction).&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including books, journal articles, and online resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bibliography&#34;&gt;Bibliography &lt;a href=&#34;#bibliography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of books used as background material for the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further Reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of additional resources for readers interested in learning more about extraterrestrials in fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External Links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to an external website with additional information on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrials_in_fiction&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrials_in_fiction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
