<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jimmy Carter on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/jimmy-carter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jimmy Carter on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:14:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/jimmy-carter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jimmy Carter UFO incident</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1669788c5cb0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1669788c5cb0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;1969-incident-regarding-the-sighting-of-a-ufo&#34;&gt;1969 incident regarding the sighting of a UFO &lt;a href=&#34;#1969-incident-regarding-the-sighting-of-a-ufo&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the UFO sighting reported by Jimmy Carter in 1969, prior to his governorship and presidency. It covers the details of the sighting, the subsequent investigation, and its impact on Carter&amp;rsquo;s views on UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;sighting&#34;&gt;Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the details of the UFO sighting as reported by Jimmy Carter. In 1969, while preparing to give a speech at a Lions Club meeting in Leary, Georgia, Carter and several other witnesses observed a bright, white object in the western sky. The object reportedly moved closer, stopped near a stand of pine trees, and changed colors before receding into the distance. Carter described the object as self-illuminated and not solid. The sighting lasted approximately 10-12 minutes and was witnessed by about 10-12 people. The section also includes quotes from Carter recounting the event in later interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;date&#34;&gt;Date &lt;a href=&#34;#date&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the conflicting information regarding the exact date of the sighting. While Carter initially reported the sighting occurred in October 1969, Lions Club records suggest it took place on January 6, 1969, the date of Carter&amp;rsquo;s speech to the Leary Lions Club. The section presents evidence supporting the January date, including Carter&amp;rsquo;s role as district governor of the Lions Club (a term that ended in June 1969) and the disbandment of the Leary Lions Club before October 1969.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;object-and-investigation&#34;&gt;Object and investigation &lt;a href=&#34;#object-and-investigation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the investigation into the sighting and alternative explanations for the object. It mentions that many attendees of the Lions Club meeting did not recall the event or did not consider it significant. One guest, Fred Hart, remembered a &amp;ldquo;blue light&amp;rdquo; that he thought might have been a weather balloon. The section also notes that Carter, while considering the object a UFO (unidentified flying object), did not believe it was an alien spacecraft. Ufologist Robert Sheaffer proposed that the object was Venus, which was near its maximum brightness and in the correct location on January 6, 1969. Ufologist Allan Hendry agreed with the Venus assessment. The section also mentions a 2007 interview where Carter stated he was an amateur astronomer and knew what Venus looked like, suggesting it was not Venus. It also presents an explanation from Carl G. &amp;ldquo;Jere&amp;rdquo; Justus, who worked on Air Force projects involving the release of glowing chemical clouds. Justus suggests the sighting was a barium cloud released from Eglin AFB in Florida on January 6, 1969, at 7:35 pm EST.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;personal-impact&#34;&gt;Personal impact &lt;a href=&#34;#personal-impact&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the impact of the sighting on Carter&amp;rsquo;s views on UFOs. During his 1976 presidential campaign, Carter pledged to make all UFO-related information available to the public if elected. However, after becoming president, he distanced himself from this pledge, citing &amp;ldquo;defense implications.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;1970s-media-reports&#34;&gt;1970s media reports &lt;a href=&#34;#1970s-media-reports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists various media reports from the 1970s covering Carter&amp;rsquo;s UFO sighting. It mentions articles in the &lt;em&gt;Atlanta Constitution&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The National Enquirer&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Argosy UFO&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;UFO Investigator&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;. It also notes inaccuracies in some of these reports, such as incorrect dates and locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related Wikipedia articles, including &amp;ldquo;Jimmy Carter rabbit incident,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;List of reported UFO sightings,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;UFO sightings in the United States.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the citations and cited works used in the article. It includes links to Carter&amp;rsquo;s report to the International UFO Bureau, news articles, and books on UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external websites related to the Jimmy Carter UFO incident, including archives of presidential UFO reports, interviews, and YouTube videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jimmy_Carter_UFO_incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jimmy_Carter_UFO_incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
