<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Calvine Sighting on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/calvine-sighting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Calvine Sighting on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 03:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/calvine-sighting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Calvine UFO photograph</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_3fb0a06114df/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 03:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_3fb0a06114df/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;calvine-ufo-photograph&#34;&gt;Calvine UFO photograph &lt;a href=&#34;#calvine-ufo-photograph&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Calvine UFO photograph, also known as the Calvine Sighting, refers to a reported UFO sighting near Calvine, Perthshire, Scotland, in August 1990. Two men reported witnessing a diamond-shaped craft while walking on the moors. They took photographs of the object as it hovered silently before ascending vertically and disappearing. The &lt;em&gt;Daily Record&lt;/em&gt; newspaper received the story and the original prints and negatives, which were then passed to the Ministry of Defence (MOD). The original materials disappeared, and the story was never published. Investigative journalist David Clarke has led efforts to locate the witnesses. The case gained public interest over the years, with partial documentation released by The National Archives in 2009. An original photograph was discovered by Clarke and published in the &lt;em&gt;Daily Mail&lt;/em&gt; in 2022, leading to significant media coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-background&#34;&gt;Historical background &lt;a href=&#34;#historical-background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for the Calvine sighting within the broader history of UFO photography. It mentions Nick Pope, a former Ministry of Defence desk officer, who included the Calvine sighting in his 1996 book, &lt;em&gt;Open Skies, Closed Minds&lt;/em&gt;. Pope described the sighting as intriguing and noted that the MOD&amp;rsquo;s analysis concluded the photos were likely genuine. The object was described as a solid craft, at least the size of a Harrier or Hawk fighter jet. Sean Kirkpatrick, former director of the All-domain Anomaly Resolution Office, has suggested the image is a reflection and may have been doctored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release-of-mod-files&#34;&gt;Release of MOD files &lt;a href=&#34;#release-of-mod-files&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details how the Calvine case gained more public attention after 2008 when the National Archives began releasing MOD UFO reports. David Clarke supervised the release and publication of these files. Among the released documents were materials related to the Calvine sighting, including a government briefing and handwritten summary. Two poor-quality photocopies of images were also included. These files revealed that DI55, a branch of the Directorate of Scientific and Technical Intelligence (DSTI), investigated the images along with a RAF photo analyst agency. Clarke later explored the Calvine incident in his book, &lt;em&gt;The UFO Files&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2015-channel-5-documentary&#34;&gt;2015 Channel 5 documentary &lt;a href=&#34;#2015-channel-5-documentary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The release of information from the National Archives, along with publicity from Clarke and Pope, led to increasing public interest in the case. In 2015, the incident was featured in the Channel 5 documentary series &lt;em&gt;Conspiracy&lt;/em&gt;. The episode, titled &amp;ldquo;Alien Cover-Up&amp;rdquo;, included interviews with Clarke and Pope and featured a reconstruction of the sighting. A graphic artist recreated the Calvine photograph for the program, which was later mistaken by some for a genuine image. Pope has speculated on potential links to the alleged Aurora project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;discovery-of-the-calvine-photograph&#34;&gt;Discovery of the Calvine photograph &lt;a href=&#34;#discovery-of-the-calvine-photograph&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the renewed investigation led by David Clarke in 2018 to locate the missing photographs and witnesses. Clarke&amp;rsquo;s interest was sparked by a Defence Intelligence Officer&amp;rsquo;s claim that the witnesses had photographed a classified U.S. black project platform. Clarke and his team interviewed former MOD staff and conducted public searches. In 2020, Scottish UFOlogist Straiph Wilson launched a search for the hill walkers. Clarke eventually tracked down retired RAF Press Officer Craig Lindsay, who had kept the original photograph for over 32 years. Lindsay donated the print and other items to Sheffield Hallam University&amp;rsquo;s Special Collection. Andrew Robinson, a photographic specialist, produced high-resolution digital copies and conducted an in-depth analysis, concluding that the photograph is genuine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-search-for-kevin-russell&#34;&gt;The search for Kevin Russell &lt;a href=&#34;#the-search-for-kevin-russell&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the search for a person named Kevin Russell, whose name was written on the back of the original Calvine photograph. The name was believed to be that of one of the witnesses. Despite contacting over 400 people with that name, Clarke&amp;rsquo;s team was unable to identify the witness. A person named Kevin Russell who worked at a hotel in Pitlochry was identified, but he denied any knowledge of the UFO. Nick Pope acknowledges being aware of the name Kevin Russell but declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-program-documentary-2024&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Program&lt;/em&gt; documentary (2024) &lt;a href=&#34;#the-program-documentary-2024&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the documentary &lt;em&gt;The Program&lt;/em&gt; by James Fox, released in December 2024, which features the Calvine UFO case. Fox interviewed David Clarke and Robinson in Sheffield and Lindsay in Scotland. The film explores the U.S. congressional effort to uncover government knowledge about UFOs and UAPs and includes an in-depth review of the Calvine case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Calvine_UFO&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Calvine_UFO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
