<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shag Harbour on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/shag-harbour/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shag Harbour on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 16:13:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/shag-harbour/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shag Harbour UFO incident</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_70419b0fb526/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 16:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_70419b0fb526/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;shag-harbour-ufo-incident&#34;&gt;Shag Harbour UFO Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#shag-harbour-ufo-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shag Harbour UFO incident refers to the reported crash of a large, unidentified object into the waters near Shag Harbour, Nova Scotia, on October 4, 1967. The incident was investigated by Canadian civilian and military agencies, as well as the U.S. Condon Committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pre-incident-aerial-phenomenon&#34;&gt;Pre-incident Aerial Phenomenon &lt;a href=&#34;#pre-incident-aerial-phenomenon&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details several aerial phenomena reported before the Shag Harbour incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;air-canada-flight-305&#34;&gt;Air Canada flight 305 &lt;a href=&#34;#air-canada-flight-305&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Air Canada Flight 305, en route from Halifax to Toronto, experienced a sighting. First Officer Robert Ralph pointed out a strange object to Captain Pierre Charbonneau. The object was described as a brilliantly lit, rectangular shape with trailing lights, flying parallel to the aircraft. The pilots reported two silent explosions near the object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;yellow-object&#34;&gt;Yellow object &lt;a href=&#34;#yellow-object&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darrel Dorey, along with his sister Kaykay and mother, witnessed a large object maneuvering in the southwestern horizon from their porch in Mahone Bay. Dorey wrote to the RCAF Greenwood Base Commander to inquire about the object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mv-nickerson-of-sambro-nova-scotia&#34;&gt;MV &lt;em&gt;Nickerson&lt;/em&gt; of Sambro, Nova Scotia &lt;a href=&#34;#mv-nickerson-of-sambro-nova-scotia&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain Leo Howard Mersey of the MV &lt;em&gt;Nickerson&lt;/em&gt; observed four bright objects in a rectangular formation on his Decca radar and visually in the northeastern sky, approximately 28 kilometers from his vessel. The entire crew of nearly twenty fishermen witnessed the event. Mersey reported the sighting to the rescue coordination center and the harbor master in Halifax, and later filed a report with the Lunenburg RCMP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;halifax-harbour-sightings&#34;&gt;Halifax Harbour sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#halifax-harbour-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Chronicle-Herald&lt;/em&gt; and local radio stations reported numerous sightings of a glowing object around Halifax at approximately 10:00 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-events&#34;&gt;Initial events &lt;a href=&#34;#initial-events&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On October 4, 1967, at approximately 11:20 pm Atlantic Daylight Time, reports surfaced of an object crashing into the waters of Shag Harbour. At least eleven witnesses observed a low-flying, lit object heading towards the harbor, accompanied by whistling and whooshing sounds, followed by a loud bang. Laurie Wickens and four friends, driving on Highway 3, witnessed a large object descending into the water. They observed the object floating offshore and contacted the RCMP detachment in Barrington Passage, reporting a possible plane or airliner crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;search-and-rescue-efforts&#34;&gt;Search and rescue efforts &lt;a href=&#34;#search-and-rescue-efforts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the initial report, two RCMP officers arrived at the scene. The RCMP contacted the Rescue Coordination Centre (RCC) in Halifax to report the incident and inquire about missing aircraft. The object, still displaying lights, began to sink and disappeared from view before any rescue attempt could be initiated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rescue mission was assembled, with local fishing boats and a Canadian Coast Guard cutter dispatched to the crash site. No survivors, bodies, or debris were recovered. The next morning, RCC Halifax confirmed that no aircraft were missing. Despite this, the search continued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RCC Halifax sent a telex to the &amp;ldquo;Air Desk&amp;rdquo; at air force headquarters in Ottawa, classifying the incident as a &amp;ldquo;UFO Report.&amp;rdquo; The Air Desk then sent a telex to navy headquarters, recommending an underwater search. Fleet Diving Unit Atlantic was tasked with carrying out the search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two days after the incident, navy divers from Fleet Diving Unit Atlantic searched the seafloor off Shag Harbour for three days. The final report indicated that no trace of an object was found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;documents&#34;&gt;Documents &lt;a href=&#34;#documents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Department of National Defence files at the national Library and Archives contain a summary of the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;press-coverage&#34;&gt;Press coverage &lt;a href=&#34;#press-coverage&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shag Harbour incident received extensive coverage in the &lt;em&gt;Halifax Chronicle-Herald&lt;/em&gt;. A headline story on October 7, titled &amp;ldquo;Could Be Something Concrete in Shag Harbour UFO – RCAF,&amp;rdquo; detailed witness accounts, the air force&amp;rsquo;s search and rescue efforts, and the navy&amp;rsquo;s underwater search. Squadron Leader Bain, head of the air force&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Air Desk,&amp;rdquo; expressed the air force&amp;rsquo;s strong interest in the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another article on October 9, titled &amp;ldquo;UFO Search Called Off,&amp;rdquo; reported the navy&amp;rsquo;s conclusion of the underwater search, stating that no trace of the object was found. The Canadian Press also carried the story of the search being called off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shag_Harbour_UFO_incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shag_Harbour_UFO_incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
