<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sitcom on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/sitcom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sitcom on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:31:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/sitcom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Parents Are Aliens</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_54e389674a99/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_54e389674a99/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-parents-are-aliens&#34;&gt;My Parents Are Aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#my-parents-are-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My Parents Are Aliens&lt;/em&gt; is a British children&amp;rsquo;s television sitcom created by Andy Watts and produced by Yorkshire Television/Granada Yorkshire. It aired on ITV from November 8, 1999, to December 18, 2006, spanning eight series. The show requires additional citations for verification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show centers on the lives of orphaned siblings Mel, Josh, and Lucy Barker, who are fostered by Brian and Sophie Johnson. The children discover that their new parents are aliens from the planet Valux who crash-landed on Earth. The house they live in is a morphed form of their spaceship. Brian and Sophie have limited knowledge of Earth customs, and the children help them navigate human life while keeping their alien identities secret. The show&amp;rsquo;s humor is surreal and subversive, appealing to both children and older viewers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series consists of 106 episodes across eight series. Series 1 has 6 episodes, Series 2 has 10 episodes, Series 3 has 10 episodes, Series 4 has 13 episodes, Series 5 has 13 episodes, Series 6 has 20 episodes, Series 7 has 20 episodes, and Series 8 has 14 episodes. The episodes aired between November 8, 1999, and December 18, 2006.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;characters&#34;&gt;Characters &lt;a href=&#34;#characters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;parents&#34;&gt;Parents &lt;a href=&#34;#parents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brian Johnson (Tony Gardner):&lt;/strong&gt; A Valuxian alien and the cause of the crash-landing. He is childlike, amoral, and ignorant of Earth culture but an excellent scientist. He has an allergy to ice cream that causes him to grow moose antlers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sophie Johnson (Barbara Durkin/Carla Mendonça):&lt;/strong&gt; Brian&amp;rsquo;s wife, also a Valuxian alien. She has more common sense than Brian but is still clueless. She can only morph when eating ice cream. Carla Mendonça replaced Barbara Durkin in the role after Sophie morphs into a new shape at the beginning of the third series and is unable to return to her previous form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;series-17-the-barkers&#34;&gt;Series 1–7: The Barkers &lt;a href=&#34;#series-17-the-barkers&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Melanie ‘Mel’ Barker (Danielle McCormack):&lt;/strong&gt; The oldest Barker sibling, a sarcastic teenager with a protective nature. She eventually moves to Canada on an exchange program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joshua ‘Josh’ Barker (Alex Kew):&lt;/strong&gt; The middle sibling, a devious and scheming boy who constantly invents scams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lucia ‘Lucy’ Barker (Charlotte Francis):&lt;/strong&gt; The youngest and most intelligent Barker, excelling in Maths and Science.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C.J. (Olisa Odele):&lt;/strong&gt; An orphan adopted into the family after discovering Brian and Sophie are aliens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harriet ‘Harry’ Barker (Stephanie Fearon):&lt;/strong&gt; Adopted after Mel leaves, similar to Mel in personality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-characters&#34;&gt;Other characters &lt;a href=&#34;#other-characters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pete Walker (Patrick Niknejad):&lt;/strong&gt; One of Josh&amp;rsquo;s friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frankie Perkins (Jordan Maxwell):&lt;/strong&gt; Another of Josh&amp;rsquo;s friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wendy Richardson (Isabella Melling):&lt;/strong&gt; Lucy&amp;rsquo;s friend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Terence ‘Trent’ Clements (Keith Warwick):&lt;/strong&gt; Mel&amp;rsquo;s friend and eventual boyfriend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr Graham Whiteside (Dan O&amp;rsquo;Brien):&lt;/strong&gt; A grumpy teacher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mrs Alison Hardman (Beatrice Kelley):&lt;/strong&gt; Another of Josh&amp;rsquo;s and Lucy&amp;rsquo;s teachers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poppy Manning (Kirsha Southward):&lt;/strong&gt; A rival to Josh and Lucy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tania Thomas (Zoe Thorne/Emily Fleeshman/Sasha Tilley):&lt;/strong&gt; The object of Josh&amp;rsquo;s affections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mikey (Chris Cornwell):&lt;/strong&gt; One of Josh&amp;rsquo;s friends in the first series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave Locket (Julian Triandafyllou):&lt;/strong&gt; A popular boy in school.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andy ‘the Freak’ (Danny Robinson):&lt;/strong&gt; A geeky boy in love with Mel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scott Taylor (Marco Williamson):&lt;/strong&gt; A popular boy who Mel had a date with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;series-8-the-bennetts&#34;&gt;Series 8: The Bennetts &lt;a href=&#34;#series-8-the-bennetts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jacqueline ‘Jaq’ Bennett (Jessica Woods):&lt;/strong&gt; The oldest of the new foster children.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dan Bennett (Daniel Feltham):&lt;/strong&gt; Becky&amp;rsquo;s twin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Becky Bennett (Katie Pearson):&lt;/strong&gt; Dan&amp;rsquo;s twin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eddie Bennett (Jake Young):&lt;/strong&gt; The youngest member of the family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show was filmed in Studio 4 at The Leeds Studios. A laugh track was added from series 4 onwards. The last episode of series 7 featured the original cast and concluded ongoing plots. Series 8 introduced a new family, the Bennetts, after Brian and Sophie&amp;rsquo;s memories were erased. ITV closed its in-house children&amp;rsquo;s production unit, ending the show after series 8. Nickelodeon purchased the rights to make an American version, but the pilot never entered production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;broadcast&#34;&gt;Broadcast &lt;a href=&#34;#broadcast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Series 1 to 7 was repeated regularly on CITV from the channel&amp;rsquo;s launch in 2006 up until late 2017, while series 8 repeats were discontinued by early 2010. Entertainment Rights Distribution handled worldwide distribution rights to the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;home-media&#34;&gt;Home media &lt;a href=&#34;#home-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A VHS release containing all six Series One episodes was released in 2000 by Video Collection International and Granada Media. A single-release DVD containing two episodes from Series 2 and four from Series 3 titled &lt;em&gt;The Best Of&lt;/em&gt; was released in 2006 by Right Entertainment/Universal Pictures Video UK. Right/Universal also released Series 1 and 2 in a box-set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;awards-and-nominations&#34;&gt;Awards and nominations &lt;a href=&#34;#awards-and-nominations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show won a Royal Television Society Award for Best Children&amp;rsquo;s Drama in 2000 and 2006. It was nominated for a Children&amp;rsquo;s BAFTA Award for Best Drama in 2001, 2003, and 2004. It also won Best Children&amp;rsquo;s Program at the Banff Television Festival and Best Children&amp;rsquo;s Fiction in 2002.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Parents_Are_Aliens&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Parents_Are_Aliens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
