<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ariel School on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ariel-school/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ariel School on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 14:04:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ariel-school/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ariel School UFO incident</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f6835b840705/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 14:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f6835b840705/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;1994-sighting-in-zimbabwe&#34;&gt;1994 Sighting in Zimbabwe &lt;a href=&#34;#1994-sighting-in-zimbabwe&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On September 16, 1994, a UFO sighting occurred outside Ruwa, Zimbabwe, witnessed by 62 pupils aged six to twelve at Ariel School. The children reported seeing silver crafts descend from the sky and land in a nearby field. Some claimed to have encountered creatures dressed in black who communicated a telepathic message with an environmental theme, causing fear and distress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortean writer Jerome Clark called it the &amp;ldquo;most remarkable close encounter of the third kind of the 1990s.&amp;rdquo; Skeptics have suggested mass hysteria as a possible explanation. Some children maintain the truthfulness of their accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruwa is described as a small agricultural center 22 kilometers southeast of Harare. Ariel School was a private school, primarily attended by children from wealthy white families in Harare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two days before the Ariel School incident, numerous UFO sightings were reported throughout southern Africa, including reports of a bright fireball in the sky at night. This led to a wave of UFO mania in Zimbabwe. Brian Dunning suggests the fireball was the re-entry of the Zenit-2 rocket from the Cosmos 2290 satellite launch. Local UFO researcher Cynthia Hind recorded other alien sightings during this period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;incident&#34;&gt;Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sightings at Ariel School occurred at 10 a.m. on September 16, 1994, during mid-morning break. The faculty was in a meeting at the time. The incident lasted about fifteen minutes. The children reported the event to their teachers, but were dismissed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After telling their parents, many parents came to the school the next day to discuss the incident with the faculty. The sighting was reported on ZBC Radio, where Cynthia Hind learned about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BBC correspondent Tim Leach visited the school on September 19 to film interviews with pupils and staff. Hind visited the school on September 20, interviewing children and asking them to draw what they had seen. She reported that the children told her the same story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November, Harvard University professor of psychiatry John Mack visited the school to interview witnesses. Mack had investigated UFO sightings and the alien abduction phenomenon throughout the 1990s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to interviews by Hind, Leach, and Mack, 62 children reported seeing at least one UFO. Silver objects, usually described as discs, appeared in the sky and descended to a field near the school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between one and four creatures with big eyes and dressed in black exited a craft and approached the children. Some children ran, but others stayed and watched. Mack&amp;rsquo;s interviews suggest the creatures telepathically communicated an environmental message to the children before returning to the craft and flying away. Dunning notes that the telepathic message aspect was primarily in Mack&amp;rsquo;s reports, although Hind reported it later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children described being warned about impending events and the importance of avoiding pollution. One child said they were told the world would end because of a lack of care for the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The children insisted they had not seen a plane. Hind noted that the children&amp;rsquo;s different cultural backgrounds led to varying interpretations, with some believing they had seen tikoloshes from Shona and Ndebele folklore rather than extraterrestrials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;aftermath&#34;&gt;Aftermath &lt;a href=&#34;#aftermath&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ariel School UFO incident became a famous UFO case in Africa. A June 2021 episode of the BBC&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Witness History&lt;/em&gt; described it as &amp;ldquo;one of the most significant events in UFO history.&amp;rdquo; Ufologists continue to cite the case as evidence of extraterrestrial visits to Earth. Skeptics have suggested mass hysteria or a prank as explanations. Gideon Reid proposed a hypothesis involving confusion with touring puppet shows promoting AIDS awareness. Another argument suggests the children misidentified a dust devil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hind interviewed the children in groups, potentially leading to cross-contamination of their stories. Dunning says that Mack, interviewed the children two months after the alleged sighting and as a known environmentalist, &amp;ldquo;prompted and suggested&amp;rdquo; the telepathic communication angle, which was not present in Hind&amp;rsquo;s previous report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several witnesses maintain the truthfulness of their accounts. In 2014, a witness told the &lt;em&gt;Mail &amp;amp; Guardian&lt;/em&gt; that she fears the creatures will return and that she can sense when they are back in the atmosphere. In 2016, witness Emily Trim exhibited paintings described as a &amp;ldquo;manifestation of the messages she received&amp;rdquo; from the beings. In June 2021, Barstool Sports writer Zah, a former Ariel School pupil, recounted seeing a bright light and aliens exiting it. Other witnesses were interviewed for the 2020 documentary &lt;em&gt;The Phenomenon&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 2023 Netflix documentary &amp;ldquo;Encounters&amp;rdquo;, a former student named Dallyn claimed that he was behind this incident. He claimed that he purposefully told his classmates and other students that a &amp;ldquo;shiny rock&amp;rdquo; in the distance was a UFO. According to his own statement in the documentary, he never thought this would work, and was surprised about the mass hysteria. Dallyn&amp;rsquo;s claims in the documentary directly contradict claims made on camera 15 years prior to the documentary, describing the UFO as having a light that would &amp;ldquo;flash a different color in the sky.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of reported UFO sightings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Westall UFO, a similar UFO sighting by school students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ariel_School_UFO_incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ariel_School_UFO_incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
