<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alien Autopsy on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/alien-autopsy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alien Autopsy on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/alien-autopsy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Autopsy (1995 television film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f41f4fadf611/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f41f4fadf611/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-autopsy-1995-television-film&#34;&gt;Alien Autopsy (1995 television film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-autopsy-1995-television-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the 1995 pseudo-documentary &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy: Fact or Fiction&lt;/em&gt;, which featured footage purporting to show an alien autopsy conducted after the Roswell incident. The article distinguishes the original footage from the 2006 feature film &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt;, which is based on the events surrounding the creation of the hoax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section details the production of the &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; footage. It highlights Ray Santilli and Gary Shoefield&amp;rsquo;s admission in the 2006 documentary &lt;em&gt;Eamonn Investigates: Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; that they created the 1995 footage. The section describes how they filmed a simulated autopsy on a fabricated alien in a set constructed in a London living room. Artist and sculptor John Humphreys constructed two dummy alien bodies filled with raspberry jam, sheep brains, chicken entrails, and knuckle joints. Humphreys also played the role of the chief examiner. The section also mentions the creation of alien artifacts and the recruitment of a homeless man to play the role of the cameraman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section explores how &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; was received and satirized in the media. It mentions &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt; referencing the footage and later satirizing it in the episode &amp;ldquo;Jose Chung&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;From Outer Space&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. It also notes Fox airing a special debunking the footage and the release of the comedy film &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; (2006), which fictionalized the creation of the footage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including books, news articles, and documentaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of additional resources for readers interested in learning more about the &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; film and the surrounding controversy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external resources, including Ray Santilli&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;My Story&amp;rdquo; on VJ Enterprises, his IMDb page, and a YouTube link to &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy: Fact or Fiction?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Autopsy_(1995_film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Autopsy_(1995_film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
