<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alien Autopsy on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/alien-autopsy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alien Autopsy on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 07:31:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/alien-autopsy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Autopsy (2006 film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ebe39ea3023e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 07:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ebe39ea3023e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-autopsy-2006-film&#34;&gt;Alien Autopsy (2006 film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-autopsy-2006-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2006 British comedy film directed by Jonny Campbell and written by William Davies, &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; is a fictionalized account of the events surrounding the infamous &amp;ldquo;alien autopsy&amp;rdquo; film promoted by Ray Santilli. The film stars Ant &amp;amp; Dec as Santilli and Gary Shoefield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ray Santilli and Gary Shoefield recount their story to a documentary maker. In 1995, they travel to the United States to find Elvis memorabilia. They encounter Harvey, a former US Army cameraman, who offers them a film from 1947 depicting the autopsy of an alien from the Roswell UFO crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After returning to England, Ray and Gary discover the film has degraded. To avoid repercussions from their investor, Laszlo Voros, they decide to recreate the autopsy film. They use a mannequin and meat products to create a replica alien and film it in Gary&amp;rsquo;s sister&amp;rsquo;s living room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They sell the film, earning a large sum of money. Voros demands a larger share of the profits but is killed in a mysterious accident. Ray and Gary travel to Argentina to promote the film, where they are followed by reporter Amber Fuentes. They produce a fake interview with a homeless man posing as Harvey to maintain Harvey&amp;rsquo;s anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ray and Gary attempt to restore the original 1947 footage, but after viewing the results, they decide to bury the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film stars Declan Donnelly as Ray Santilli and Anthony McPartlin as Gary Shoefield. Bill Pullman plays Morgan Banner, the documentary maker. Götz Otto portrays Laszlo Voros, and Harry Dean Stanton plays Harvey. Other cast members include Morwenna Banks, Omid Djalili, Jimmy Carr, and Jonathan Frakes as himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received mainly positive reviews, earning a 75% approval rating on Rotten Tomatoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;releases&#34;&gt;Releases &lt;a href=&#34;#releases&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film was released as a Region 2 DVD by Warner Home Video on July 3, 2006. In America, it was released as a Region 1 DVD by Warner Home Video on September 21, 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;soundtrack&#34;&gt;Soundtrack &lt;a href=&#34;#soundtrack&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film&amp;rsquo;s soundtrack includes songs by Supergrass, Pete Moore, The Beloved, Stakka Bo, The Monkees, Stereo MC&amp;rsquo;s, Tom Jones, Nouvelle Vague, Son of Dork, and Babylon Zoo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Autopsy_(2006_film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Autopsy_(2006_film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
