<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alien Invasion on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/alien-invasion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alien Invasion on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 21:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/alien-invasion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Apocalypse (2005 film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_4b816dc128cd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 21:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_4b816dc128cd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-apocalypse-2005-film&#34;&gt;Alien Apocalypse (2005 film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-apocalypse-2005-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry describes the 2005 American science fiction TV film &lt;em&gt;Alien Apocalypse&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents the film&amp;rsquo;s promotional poster and basic information in a table format. Key details include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writer and Director:&lt;/strong&gt; Josh Becker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starring:&lt;/strong&gt; Bruce Campbell, Renee O&amp;rsquo;Connor, Remington Franklin, Michael Cory Davis, and Peter Jason&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theme Music Composer:&lt;/strong&gt; Joseph LoDuca&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Country of Origin:&lt;/strong&gt; United States&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language:&lt;/strong&gt; English&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Production:&lt;/strong&gt; Jeff Franklin and Bob Perkis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cinematography:&lt;/strong&gt; David Worth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor:&lt;/strong&gt; Shawn Paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Production Company:&lt;/strong&gt; Syfy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Release:&lt;/strong&gt; March 26, 2005&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network:&lt;/strong&gt; Sci Fi Channel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It establishes the film as a Sci Fi Channel original movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot summary details the events of the film:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Astronaut Dr. Ivan Hood (Bruce Campbell) and his companion Kelly return to Earth after a 40-year space mission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They discover Earth has been conquered by giant termite-like aliens who used EMP bombs to disable the planet 20 years prior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Humans are enslaved and forced to work in camps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dr. Hood and Kelly are captured near the ruins of Portland, Oregon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They plan an escape after learning of a surviving President.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kelly is recaptured, and Dr. Hood seeks out the President, eventually finding him a broken man.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dr. Hood rallies escaped slaves to attack the alien camp and rescue Kelly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The attack is successful with the help of the President&amp;rsquo;s forces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dr. Hood becomes known as &amp;ldquo;The Great Exterminator&amp;rdquo; and continues to fight the aliens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the actors and the characters they portray in the film:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bruce Campbell as Dr. Ivan Hood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renee O&amp;rsquo;Connor as Lieutenant Kelly Lanaman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remington Franklin as Alex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michael Cory Davis as Captain Chuck Burkes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peter Jason as President Demsky&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vladimir Kolev as Bob &amp;ldquo;Fisherman Bob&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Valentin Giasbeily as Tyler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Velizar Binev as Manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dimiter Kuzov as Bounty Hunter 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Krum Iapulov as Bounty Hunter 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jonas Talkington as Bounty Hunter 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zlatko Zlatkov as Bounty Hunter 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chavdar Simeonov as Alien Leader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anton Trendafilov as Jeff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rosi Chernogova as Bizzy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Todor Nikolov as Bill &amp;ldquo;Mountain Man Bill&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asen Blatechki as Crazy Man&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides information about the film&amp;rsquo;s production:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The film was shot in Bulgaria.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many of the actors were Bulgarian and spoke little English, requiring extensive dubbing in post-production.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It includes an image of Josh Becker directing the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the critical reception of the film:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Apocalypse&lt;/em&gt; received mixed reviews from critics and audiences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Nusair of &lt;em&gt;Reel Film Reviews&lt;/em&gt; noted that the film doesn&amp;rsquo;t take itself seriously, especially by the end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists other films with similar themes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Planet of the Apes&lt;/em&gt; (1968)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Battlefield Earth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Apocalypse&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external sources used in the article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DVD Talk review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reel Film Reviews article&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external websites related to the film:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Apocalypse&lt;/em&gt; at IMDb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Making of &lt;em&gt;Alien Apocalypse&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Josh Becker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The shooting script for &lt;em&gt;Alien Apocalypse&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A navigation template for films directed by Josh Becker is also included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Apocalypse&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Apocalypse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrials in fiction</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_fb66d06449f7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 03:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_fb66d06449f7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;fictional-depictions-of-extraterrestrial-life&#34;&gt;Fictional Depictions of Extraterrestrial Life &lt;a href=&#34;#fictional-depictions-of-extraterrestrial-life&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses extraterrestrials as they appear in works of fiction, distinguishing them from alleged real-life encounters. It notes that the article relies heavily on a limited number of sources and encourages expansion with additional citations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrials-in-fiction&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrials in Fiction &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrials-in-fiction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a general overview, defining an extraterrestrial (or alien) as a lifeform originating outside Earth. It highlights the prevalence of extraterrestrials as a theme in science fiction, with examples ranging from ancient works like Lucian of Samosata&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;True History&lt;/em&gt; to modern depictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the historical evolution of extraterrestrial depictions in fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;antiquity&#34;&gt;Antiquity &lt;a href=&#34;#antiquity&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection traces the earliest portrayals of extraterrestrials, starting with Lucian&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;True History&lt;/em&gt;, which features a voyage to the Moon and a war between lunar and solar inhabitants. It explains how early concepts of aliens were tied to the development of astronomy and the initial tendency to imagine them as human-like. Voltaire&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Micromégas&lt;/em&gt; and works by Johannes Kepler, Francis Godwin, and Cyrano de Bergerac are mentioned as examples where extraterrestrials differed from humans only in culture or size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The impact of Charles Darwin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;On the Origin of Species&lt;/em&gt; is discussed, noting how it revolutionized alien depictions by inspiring authors to imagine non-humanoid lifeforms based on evolutionary principles. Camille Flammarion&amp;rsquo;s works and H.G. Wells&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;The War of the Worlds&lt;/em&gt; are cited as early examples of genuinely alien lifeforms. The section also acknowledges that many works of the era still featured human-like aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The War of the Worlds&lt;/em&gt; is further analyzed for its exploration of Darwinian evolution, its depiction of Martians as apex predators, and its critique of British imperialism. It also introduced the tropes of alien invasion and extraterrestrials as monsters. Wells&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;The First Men in the Moon&lt;/em&gt; is mentioned as an early attempt to detail an alien civilization, drawing parallels to ant colonies. Jules Verne&amp;rsquo;s contributions to science fiction and space exploration are also noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-20th-century&#34;&gt;Early 20th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#early-20th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the influence of pulp magazines on science fiction, highlighting the prevalence of quasi-human aliens, monstrous invaders, and the trope of human conquest of alien worlds. It mentions Ralph Milne Farley&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Radio Man&lt;/em&gt; as an example. The section notes that most aliens in pulp magazines originated from planets or moons within the Solar System. Stanley G. Weinbaum&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;A Martian Odyssey&lt;/em&gt; is recognized for its unique Martian ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modern-times&#34;&gt;Modern Times &lt;a href=&#34;#modern-times&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines the evolution of alien depictions in more recent times. &lt;em&gt;The Eternaut&lt;/em&gt; by Héctor Germán Oesterheld is highlighted as a pioneering work of alien invasion set in Buenos Aires, serving as a critique of imperialism and the military dictatorship in Argentina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Barney and Betty Hill incident is discussed as the first recorded claim of alien abduction, leading to the &amp;ldquo;grey alien&amp;rdquo; archetype. Steven Spielberg&amp;rsquo;s films &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial&lt;/em&gt; are mentioned as influential works that popularized the grey alien image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The impact of television and film on alien portrayals is explored, noting the trend towards human-like aliens due to budget constraints, particularly in the &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt; franchise. &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; are mentioned as franchises that sustained public interest in outer space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The section concludes by discussing the influence of computer-generated imagery (CGI) on alien depictions, allowing for more bizarre and imaginative lifeforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;types&#34;&gt;Types &lt;a href=&#34;#types&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section categorizes the various ways extraterrestrials are portrayed in fiction. It discusses variations in intelligence, biological aspects (humanoid, Earth-species-like, or weird), and attitudes towards humanity (hostile, friendly, or indifferent). It also mentions the possibility of extraterrestrials originating from unexplored areas of Earth, such as the sea, sky, underground, or other dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See Also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related Wikipedia articles, including &amp;ldquo;Parasites in fiction,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;List of fictional extraterrestrials,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;List of films featuring extraterrestrials,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;List of humanoid aliens,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Mars in fiction,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;First contact (science fiction).&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including books, journal articles, and online resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bibliography&#34;&gt;Bibliography &lt;a href=&#34;#bibliography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of books used as sources for the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further Reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of additional resources for readers interested in learning more about extraterrestrials in fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External Links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to an external website with additional information on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrials_in_fiction&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrials_in_fiction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien invasion</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_c423562fffa8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 23:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_c423562fffa8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-invasion&#34;&gt;Alien Invasion &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-invasion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alien invasion, also known as space invasion, is a prevalent theme in science fiction stories and films. It involves extraterrestrial lifeforms invading Earth with various motives, such as exterminating or enslaving humanity, harvesting humans for food, stealing resources, or destroying the planet. This theme is a subgenre of invasion literature, popularized by H.G. Wells&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;The War of the Worlds&lt;/em&gt;, and is a type of first contact science fiction. Experts consider an actual alien invasion unlikely due to the immense costs involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;origins&#34;&gt;Origins &lt;a href=&#34;#origins&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the origins of the alien invasion theme in fiction. H.G. Wells&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;The War of the Worlds&lt;/em&gt; (1898) is considered the seminal alien invasion story, establishing themes like first contact and interplanetary war. However, earlier stories exist, such as Robert Potter&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Germ Growers&lt;/em&gt; (1892), which features a covert alien invasion. The section also mentions Wells&amp;rsquo; proposed guerrilla war scenario in &lt;em&gt;The War of the Worlds&lt;/em&gt;. Garrett P. Serviss&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;Edison&amp;rsquo;s Conquest of Mars&lt;/em&gt;, an unauthorized sequel to &lt;em&gt;The War of the Worlds&lt;/em&gt;, depicts Thomas Edison leading a counterattack on Mars. The reprinting of &lt;em&gt;The War of the Worlds&lt;/em&gt; in the United States in 1927 coincided with the Golden Age of Science Fiction. John W. Campbell and other science fiction writers, including Isaac Asimov, Arthur C. Clarke, Clifford D. Simak, and Robert A. Heinlein, further developed the theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;variations&#34;&gt;Variations &lt;a href=&#34;#variations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores different variations of the alien invasion theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-infiltration&#34;&gt;Alien Infiltration &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-infiltration&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This variation involves invaders taking human form and infiltrating society, even taking control of command positions. Their goal may be to take over the world or prepare for a full-scale invasion. This theme reflects Cold War fears of communist infiltration. The Reptilian conspiracy theory is mentioned as a real-world belief in covert alien infiltration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;beneficial-alien-invasion&#34;&gt;Beneficial Alien Invasion &lt;a href=&#34;#beneficial-alien-invasion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This variation presents aliens colonizing Earth to &amp;ldquo;civilize&amp;rdquo; humanity or secretly aiding humans to prevent self-destruction. Henry Slesar&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Delegate from Venus&lt;/em&gt; is mentioned. Examples include Klaatu and Gort in &lt;em&gt;The Day the Earth Stood Still&lt;/em&gt;, Gene Roddenberry&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Questor Tapes&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt; episode &amp;ldquo;Assignment: Earth&amp;rdquo;, Arthur C. Clarke&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Childhood&amp;rsquo;s End&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Crest of the Stars&lt;/em&gt;, the film &lt;em&gt;Arrival&lt;/em&gt;, and David Brin&amp;rsquo;s Uplift Universe series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;invasion-by-humans&#34;&gt;Invasion by Humans &lt;a href=&#34;#invasion-by-humans&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This variation reverses the roles, with humans invading or attacking extraterrestrial lifeforms. Examples include the short story &lt;em&gt;Sentry&lt;/em&gt;, the video game &lt;em&gt;Phantasy Star II&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Martian Chronicles&lt;/em&gt; by Ray Bradbury, the Imperium of Man in the &lt;em&gt;Warhammer 40,000&lt;/em&gt; universe, &lt;em&gt;Invaders from Earth&lt;/em&gt; by Robert Silverberg, &lt;em&gt;Ender&amp;rsquo;s Game&lt;/em&gt; by Orson Scott Card, and the movies &lt;em&gt;Battle for Terra&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Planet 51&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Avatar&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;feasibility&#34;&gt;Feasibility &lt;a href=&#34;#feasibility&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the feasibility of an actual alien invasion. Seth Shostak of the SETI Institute believes it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely due to resource availability and the likelihood of initial contact being through robots. David Morrison of NASA-Ames Research Center suggests first contact would be via radio communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics, including interplanetary contamination, potential cultural impact of extraterrestrial contact, space colonization, UFO religion, &lt;em&gt;The Kraken Wakes&lt;/em&gt;, list of films featuring space stations, and the Wow! signal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the references used in the article, providing sources for the information presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_invasion&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_invasion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cowboys &amp; Aliens (2011 film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_31a87c5e29e6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 23:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_31a87c5e29e6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;cowboys--aliens-2011-film&#34;&gt;Cowboys &amp;amp; Aliens (2011 film) &lt;a href=&#34;#cowboys--aliens-2011-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article provides a detailed overview of the 2011 American science fiction Western film &lt;em&gt;Cowboys &amp;amp; Aliens&lt;/em&gt;, directed by Jon Favreau. It covers various aspects of the film, including its plot, cast, production, themes, marketing, release, reception, and home media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot unfolds in 1873 New Mexico Territory, where an amnesiac outlaw named Jake Lonergan, portrayed by Daniel Craig, awakens with a mysterious metal bracelet attached to his wrist. He finds himself in the town of Absolution, which is soon attacked by aliens. The aliens abduct several townspeople, including Sheriff Taggart and Percy Dolarhyde. Lonergan&amp;rsquo;s bracelet activates, transforming into a weapon that he uses to shoot down an alien ship. A posse, including Colonel Woodrow Dolarhyde (Harrison Ford) and a mysterious woman named Ella Swenson (Olivia Wilde), forms to track the aliens. Lonergan&amp;rsquo;s memories gradually return, revealing his past abduction and the death of his lover, Alice. Ella reveals herself to be an alien from another race, who came to Earth to help resist the invaders. The group plans an attack on the aliens&amp;rsquo; mothership, resulting in a final confrontation where Ella sacrifices herself to destroy the ship and save Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film features a prominent cast:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daniel Craig&lt;/strong&gt; as Jake Lonergan, an amnesiac outlaw.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harrison Ford&lt;/strong&gt; as Woodrow Dolarhyde, a powerful cattleman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Olivia Wilde&lt;/strong&gt; as Ella Swenson, an alien traveler.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam Rockwell&lt;/strong&gt; as Doc, a doctor and saloon owner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adam Beach&lt;/strong&gt; as Nat Colorado, Dolarhyde&amp;rsquo;s Apache right-hand man.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Dano&lt;/strong&gt; as Percy Dolarhyde, Woodrow&amp;rsquo;s son.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Noah Ringer&lt;/strong&gt; as Emmett Taggart, Taggart&amp;rsquo;s grandson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keith Carradine&lt;/strong&gt; as Sheriff John Taggart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clancy Brown&lt;/strong&gt; as Meacham, Absolution&amp;rsquo;s preacher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The production section details the film&amp;rsquo;s development, casting, writing, filming, design, and visual effects. The project began in 1997, with Universal Pictures and DreamWorks Pictures acquiring film rights to a concept by Scott Mitchell Rosenberg. Jon Favreau joined as director in 2009, and Daniel Craig and Harrison Ford were cast in the lead roles. Filming took place in New Mexico and California in 2010. The film was shot in the anamorphic format on 35mm film to achieve a classic movie feel. Industrial Light &amp;amp; Magic (ILM) created the visual effects, with Legacy Effects producing practical puppet aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes &lt;a href=&#34;#themes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film explores themes of redemption, unity against a common enemy, and the clash between low-tech and high-tech cultures. Jon Favreau aimed for a plausible approach to how 19th-century humans could confront technologically superior extraterrestrial beings. The film also draws parallels between the alien invasion and the historical conflicts between European settlers and Native Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;marketing&#34;&gt;Marketing &lt;a href=&#34;#marketing&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The marketing section discusses the challenges of promoting a film with an &amp;ldquo;inherently comic&amp;rdquo; title and premise. The studio aimed to convey the film&amp;rsquo;s serious tone and adventure elements through trailers and presentations at events like San Diego Comic-Con.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cowboys &amp;amp; Aliens&lt;/em&gt; premiered at San Diego Comic-Con in July 2011 and was released theatrically in the United States and Canada on July 29, 2011. Paramount Pictures released the film in IMAX theaters internationally, and Reliance Entertainment released it in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reception section covers the film&amp;rsquo;s box office performance and critical response. &lt;em&gt;Cowboys &amp;amp; Aliens&lt;/em&gt; underperformed at the box office, earning $174.8 million worldwide on a $163 million budget. Critics praised the acting and special effects but criticized the screenplay and tone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;home-media&#34;&gt;Home Media &lt;a href=&#34;#home-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film was released on DVD and Blu-ray Disc on December 6, 2011, including an extended version, behind-the-scenes featurettes, and commentary with Jon Favreau. In 2024, Kino Lorber released a 4K Blu-ray of the theatrical cut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;infringement-lawsuit&#34;&gt;Infringement Lawsuit &lt;a href=&#34;#infringement-lawsuit&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steven John Busti filed a lawsuit against Universal, DreamWorks, Platinum Studios, and Scott Mitchell Rosenberg, claiming copyright infringement. Busti claimed he wrote a preview for his story &lt;em&gt;Cowboys and Aliens&lt;/em&gt; in 1994, which was published in the April 1995 issue of &lt;em&gt;Bizarre Fantasy #1&lt;/em&gt;. The lawsuit was dismissed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-legend&#34;&gt;Historical Legend &lt;a href=&#34;#historical-legend&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The capsized steamboat that appears in the film is presumed to be the &lt;em&gt;Iron Mountain&lt;/em&gt; which, according to legend, steamed out of Vicksburg towing two barges. Two hours later, another boat found the barges adrift. The ship was not found until later, having apparently been refloated by flood waters and carried through a break in a levee, and grounded in a cotton field at Omega Landing, near Tallulah, Louisiana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cowboys_%26_Aliens&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cowboys_%26_Aliens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
