<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Swamp Gas on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/swamp-gas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Swamp Gas on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 05:55:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/swamp-gas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Michigan &#34;swamp gas&#34; UFO reports</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_b0db806a2564/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 05:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_b0db806a2564/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;1966-us-ufo-sightings-michigan-swamp-gas-ufo-reports&#34;&gt;1966 US UFO Sightings: Michigan &amp;ldquo;Swamp Gas&amp;rdquo; UFO Reports &lt;a href=&#34;#1966-us-ufo-sightings-michigan-swamp-gas-ufo-reports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the mass sightings of unidentified flying objects (UFOs) that occurred in Michigan during March 1966, specifically on March 20 and 21. These events became known as the &amp;ldquo;Michigan &amp;lsquo;swamp gas&amp;rsquo; UFO reports&amp;rdquo; due to the Air Force&amp;rsquo;s controversial explanation for the sightings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;march-1966-ufo-flap&#34;&gt;March 1966 UFO Flap &lt;a href=&#34;#march-1966-ufo-flap&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides an overview of the broader context of the Michigan UFO sightings, noting that the Dexter and Hillsdale mass sightings occurred amidst a wave of UFO reports throughout southern Michigan. A map illustrates the locations of reported sightings, including Lima, Milan, Dexter, Hillsdale, and Holland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;initial-reports&#34;&gt;Initial Reports &lt;a href=&#34;#initial-reports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the initial UFO sightings that preceded the Dexter and Hillsdale incidents. It mentions reports from Washtenaw County residents, sheriffs, and police beginning around 3:50 a.m. on March 14, describing lights moving at high speeds over Lima Township. Sightings were also reported from Monroe, Livingston, Ypsilanti, Dexter, and Sylvania. Sheriff Deputies Buford Bushroe and John Foster, along with personnel at Selfridge Air Force Base, confirmed the sightings. Deputy David Fitzpatrick captured photographs of lights over Milan on March 16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dexter-mass-sighting&#34;&gt;Dexter Mass Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#dexter-mass-sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the events of March 20, 1966, when Frank Mannor, his wife, and son Ronald reported seeing a red &amp;ldquo;falling star&amp;rdquo; that hovered over a marshy area near their farmhouse northwest of Dexter. Mannor contacted law enforcement, and Deputy Sheriff Stanley McFadden and his partner David Fitzpatrick investigated. The Mannors described the object as football-shaped with a &amp;lsquo;waffled&amp;rsquo; texture, blinking lights, and antennae. Dexter patrolman Robert Hunawil and Dexter Chief of Police Robert Taylor were also witnesses. Approximately 60 people, including law enforcement, neighbors, and the Mannor family, reportedly witnessed the UFO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hillsdale-mass-sighting&#34;&gt;Hillsdale Mass Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#hillsdale-mass-sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the mass sighting that occurred around 9 p.m. on March 21 at Hillsdale College. Approximately 87 residents of the MacIntyre Residence Hall observed flashing lights hovering over the Arboretum. William Van Horn, Hillsdale County civil defense director, investigated and observed the lights through binoculars. Hillsdale police officers Harold Hess and Jerry Wise also witnessed the object and reported radio damage after the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;continued-reports&#34;&gt;Continued Reports &lt;a href=&#34;#continued-reports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section notes that reports of flying objects, strange sounds, and unexplained lights continued in Dexter and Hillsdale on March 22. On March 23, a teen from Monroe claimed to have taken photos of a UFO. Robert Nichols and his wife reported an object flying across a highway near Holland on March 24. Sightings were also reported over Macomb and Oakland counties, as well as Bad Axe, Flint, and Ann Arbor, on March 29.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;national-attention&#34;&gt;National Attention &lt;a href=&#34;#national-attention&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the national media coverage of the Dexter sightings, noting that papers nationwide reported on the events on March 21. Wire services distributed a drawing of the reported object by a police officer. Various speculations were covered, including a theory that the UFO was filling up on swamp water to recharge its batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hynek-press-conference&#34;&gt;Hynek Press Conference &lt;a href=&#34;#hynek-press-conference&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the involvement of J. Allen Hynek, an Air Force UFO expert, who was dispatched to investigate the Dexter and Hillsdale sightings. On March 25, Hynek held a press conference where he attributed the sightings to &amp;ldquo;marsh gas,&amp;rdquo; an explanation that was met with skepticism and derision. He dismissed the Fitzpatrick photograph as being of the moon and Venus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reactions&#34;&gt;Reactions &lt;a href=&#34;#reactions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the reactions to Hynek&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;swamp gas&amp;rdquo; explanation. Congressman Gerald R. Ford called for a Congressional investigation into the sightings. Life Magazine and CBS Reports covered the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;congressional-hearing&#34;&gt;Congressional Hearing &lt;a href=&#34;#congressional-hearing&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses Hynek&amp;rsquo;s testimony before the House Armed Services Committee on April 6, alongside Air Force Secretary Harold Brown and Bluebook chief Major Hector Quintanilla. Hynek broke with the Air Force&amp;rsquo;s stance and suggested that some aspects of UFOs merited serious study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aftermath-and-legacy&#34;&gt;Aftermath and Legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#aftermath-and-legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines the long-term impact of the Michigan UFO sightings. The sightings were listed as a top-ten story for 1966 in Michigan. Alan Hynek, who popularized the swamp gas hypothesis, later argued that the topic merited serious study. The phrase &amp;ldquo;swamp gas&amp;rdquo; became associated with skepticism of government conclusions. The incident has been referenced in popular culture, including &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Men in Black&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michigan_%22swamp_gas%22_UFO_reports&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michigan_%22swamp_gas%22_UFO_reports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
