<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Astrobiology on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/astrobiology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Astrobiology on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 22:47:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/astrobiology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial liquid water</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_77e58d4d298b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 22:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_77e58d4d298b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-liquid-water&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial Liquid Water &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-liquid-water&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extraterrestrial liquid water refers to water in its liquid state that occurs naturally outside of Earth. Its presence is considered a key prerequisite for life as we know it, making it a central focus in the search for extraterrestrial life. While many celestial bodies in the Solar System have a hydrosphere, Earth is the only one known to have stable bodies of liquid water on its surface. Confirmation of liquid water relies on absorption spectroscopy and geochemistry, which are effective for detecting water vapor and ice. However, detecting liquid water, especially subsurface water, is more challenging. Scientists use habitable zone theory, gravitational and tidal theory, planetary differentiation models, and radiometry to assess the potential for liquid water. Volcanic activity, fluvial features, and the presence of antifreeze agents also provide indirect evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;significance&#34;&gt;Significance &lt;a href=&#34;#significance&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Water is essential for the biochemistry of all known life forms. While lifeforms on Earth have adapted to varying levels of water scarcity, no known lifeform can survive entirely without it. Water is a simple molecule, consisting of oxygen and hydrogen, found throughout the solar system. However, it is only useful for life in its liquid state, which is less common than water vapor or ice. Because the first life forms on Earth originated in liquid water, the search for extraterrestrial liquid water is closely linked to the search for extraterrestrial life. Liquid water&amp;rsquo;s unique properties, such as becoming less dense when solidifying, are also beneficial for life, as they allow aquatic ecosystems to survive in cold environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;liquid-water-in-the-solar-system&#34;&gt;Liquid Water in the Solar System &lt;a href=&#34;#liquid-water-in-the-solar-system&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of December 2015, the confirmed liquid water outside Earth in the Solar System is estimated to be 25-50 times the volume of Earth&amp;rsquo;s water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mars&#34;&gt;Mars &lt;a href=&#34;#mars&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mars ocean theory suggests that nearly a third of the surface of Mars was once covered by water. Today, water on Mars exists primarily as ice and underground, with a small amount present as vapor in the atmosphere. Liquid water may occur transiently under specific conditions. The low atmospheric pressure and temperature prevent large bodies of standing liquid water from existing. Recurring slope lineae are thought to be caused by flows of brine. In July 2018, scientists from the Italian Space Agency detected a subglacial lake 1.5 kilometers below the southern polar ice cap, providing the first evidence of a stable body of liquid water on Mars. The water is thought to remain liquid due to the presence of magnesium and calcium perchlorates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;europa&#34;&gt;Europa &lt;a href=&#34;#europa&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists generally agree that a layer of liquid water exists beneath the surface of Europa, a moon of Jupiter. Heat from tidal flexing allows the subsurface ocean to remain liquid. The outer crust of solid ice is estimated to be 10-30 km thick, while the liquid ocean underneath may be about 100 km deep, resulting in a volume slightly more than twice that of Earth&amp;rsquo;s oceans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;enceladus&#34;&gt;Enceladus &lt;a href=&#34;#enceladus&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enceladus, a moon of Saturn, has geysers of water, confirmed by the &lt;em&gt;Cassini&lt;/em&gt; spacecraft. Gravimetric data confirmed a subsurface ocean. Evidence suggests the subsurface ocean is global in nature. The geysers also contain small amounts of salt, nitrogen, carbon dioxide, and volatile hydrocarbons. The melting of the ocean water and the geysers appear to be driven by tidal flux from Saturn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mimas&#34;&gt;Mimas &lt;a href=&#34;#mimas&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mimas, another moon of Saturn, was found by &lt;em&gt;Cassini&lt;/em&gt; to have a &amp;ldquo;rocking&amp;rdquo; motion whose amplitude could only be explained by a large subsurface ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ganymede&#34;&gt;Ganymede &lt;a href=&#34;#ganymede&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A subsurface saline ocean is theorized to exist on Ganymede, a moon of Jupiter, following observation by the Hubble Space Telescope in 2015. Patterns in auroral belts and rocking of the magnetic field suggest the presence of an ocean. It is estimated to be 100 km deep with the surface lying below a crust of 150 km of ice. The precise quantity of liquid water on Ganymede is highly uncertain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ceres&#34;&gt;Ceres &lt;a href=&#34;#ceres&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ceres appears to be differentiated into a rocky core and icy mantle, and may have a remnant internal ocean of liquid water under the layer of ice. The surface is probably a mixture of water ice and hydrated minerals. Emissions of water vapor have been detected from several regions of Ceres. Ceres also features a mountain called Ahuna Mons that is thought to be a cryovolcanic dome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ice-giants&#34;&gt;Ice Giants &lt;a href=&#34;#ice-giants&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ice giant planets Uranus and Neptune are thought to have a supercritical water ocean beneath their clouds, which accounts for about two-thirds of their total mass, most likely surrounding small rocky cores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pluto&#34;&gt;Pluto &lt;a href=&#34;#pluto&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June 2020, astronomers reported evidence that the dwarf planet Pluto may have had a subsurface ocean, and consequently may have been habitable, when it was first formed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;indicators-methods-of-detection-and-confirmation&#34;&gt;Indicators, Methods of Detection and Confirmation &lt;a href=&#34;#indicators-methods-of-detection-and-confirmation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most known extrasolar planetary systems appear to have very different compositions to the Solar System.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;spectroscopy&#34;&gt;Spectroscopy &lt;a href=&#34;#spectroscopy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liquid water has a distinct absorption spectroscopy signature compared to other states of water due to the state of its hydrogen bonds. Despite the confirmation of extraterrestrial water vapor and ice, the spectral signature of liquid water is yet to be confirmed outside of Earth. Seasonal flows on warm Martian slopes, though strongly suggestive of briny liquid water, have yet to indicate this in spectroscopic analysis. Water vapor has been confirmed in numerous objects via spectroscopy, though it does not by itself confirm the presence of liquid water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;magnetic-fields&#34;&gt;Magnetic Fields &lt;a href=&#34;#magnetic-fields&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Jovian moons Ganymede and Europa, the existence of a sub-ice ocean is inferred from the measurements of the magnetic field of Jupiter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;geological-indicators&#34;&gt;Geological Indicators &lt;a href=&#34;#geological-indicators&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas Gold posited that many Solar System bodies could potentially hold groundwater below the surface. Liquid water may exist in the Martian subsurface. Research suggests that in the past there was liquid water flowing on the surface, creating large areas similar to Earth&amp;rsquo;s oceans. &amp;ldquo;Chaos terrain&amp;rdquo;, a common feature on Europa&amp;rsquo;s surface, is interpreted as regions where the subsurface ocean has melted through the icy crust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;volcanic-observation&#34;&gt;Volcanic Observation &lt;a href=&#34;#volcanic-observation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geysers have been found on Enceladus, a moon of Saturn, and Europa, moon of Jupiter. These contain water vapour and could be indicators of liquid water deeper down. In June 2009, researchers noticed that Enceladus wobbled in a certain way as it orbited Saturn, indicating that the moon&amp;rsquo;s icy crust didn&amp;rsquo;t extend all the way to its core — instead, it rested on a global ocean. On 3 April 2014, NASA reported that evidence for a large underground ocean of liquid water on Enceladus had been found by the &lt;em&gt;Cassini&lt;/em&gt; spacecraft. Emissions of water vapor have been detected from several regions of the dwarf planet Ceres, combined with evidence of ongoing cryovalcanic activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gravitational-evidence&#34;&gt;Gravitational Evidence &lt;a href=&#34;#gravitational-evidence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists used gravitational measurements from the &lt;em&gt;Cassini&lt;/em&gt; spacecraft to confirm a water ocean under the crust of Enceladus. Such tidal models have been used as theories for water layers in other Solar System moons. Anomalies in the orbital libration of Saturn&amp;rsquo;s moon Mimas combined with models of tidal mechanics led scientists in 2022 to propose that it harbours an internal ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ground-penetrating-radio&#34;&gt;Ground Penetrating Radio &lt;a href=&#34;#ground-penetrating-radio&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists have detected liquid water using radio signals. The radio detection and ranging (RADAR) instrument of the &lt;em&gt;Cassini&lt;/em&gt; probe was used to detect the existence of a layer of liquid water and ammonia beneath the surface of Saturn&amp;rsquo;s moon Titan. Ground penetrating radar and dielectric permittivity data from the MARSIS instrument on Mars Express indicates a 20-kilometer-wide stable body of briny liquid water in the Planum Australe region of planet Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;density-calculation&#34;&gt;Density Calculation &lt;a href=&#34;#density-calculation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planetary scientists can use calculations of density to determine the composition of planets and their potential to possess liquid water. Models of Saturn&amp;rsquo;s moon Titan density indicate the presence of a subsurface ocean layer. Similar density estimations are strong indicators of an subsurface ocean on Enceladus. GJ 1214 b was the second exoplanet to have an established mass and radius less than those of the giant Solar System planets. Its low density indicated that it is likely a mix of rock and water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;models-of-radioactive-decay&#34;&gt;Models of Radioactive Decay &lt;a href=&#34;#models-of-radioactive-decay&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Models of heat retention and heating via radioactive decay in smaller icy Solar System bodies suggest that Rhea, Titania, Oberon, Triton, Pluto, Eris, Sedna, and Orcus may have oceans underneath solid icy crusts approximately 100 km thick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;internal-differentiation-models&#34;&gt;Internal Differentiation Models &lt;a href=&#34;#internal-differentiation-models&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Models of Solar System objects indicate the presence of liquid water in their internal differentiation. Some models of the dwarf planet Ceres indicate the possibility of a wet interior layer. A global layer of liquid water thick enough to decouple the crust from the mantle is thought to be present on Titan, Europa and, with less certainty, Callisto, Ganymede and Triton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;habitable-zone&#34;&gt;Habitable Zone &lt;a href=&#34;#habitable-zone&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A planet&amp;rsquo;s orbit in the circumstellar habitable zone is a popular method used to predict its potential for surface water at its surface. Habitable zone theory has put forward several extrasolar candidates for liquid water. The Gliese 581 planetary system contains multiple planets that may be candidates for surface water, including Gliese 581c, Gliese 581d, and Gliese 581e. Gliese 667 C has three of them are in the habitable zone including Gliese 667 Cc is estimated to have surface temperatures similar to Earth and a strong chance of liquid water. Kepler-22b one of the first 54 candidates found by the Kepler telescope and reported is 2.4 times the size of the Earth, with an estimated temperature of 22 °C. It is described as having the potential for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_liquid_water&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_liquid_water&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial intelligence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_acb86ff7a2fd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 13:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_acb86ff7a2fd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial Intelligence &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extraterrestrial intelligence (ETI) refers to the hypothetical existence of intelligent life beyond Earth. While no verifiable evidence of ETI has been found, the possibility has been debated since ancient times and gained traction with the Copernican Revolution. It remains a significant topic in science, science fiction, and popular culture. An alternative term, &amp;ldquo;Extraterrestrial Technological Instantiations,&amp;rdquo; avoids potentially ambiguous terms like &amp;ldquo;civilizations&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;species.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intelligence&#34;&gt;Intelligence &lt;a href=&#34;#intelligence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section defines intelligence in the context of ETI, linking it to human-like cognitive abilities, sapience, and the term &amp;ldquo;sophoncy&amp;rdquo; (wisdom), coined by Karen Anderson and popularized by Poul Anderson. It clarifies the distinction between intelligence/sapience and sentience/consciousness, noting that the latter terms are broader and include non-sapient life forms. The concept of &amp;ldquo;extraterrestrial civilization&amp;rdquo; is introduced as a potential outcome of intelligent extraterrestrial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;probability&#34;&gt;Probability &lt;a href=&#34;#probability&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Copernican principle, which suggests humans are not privileged observers, supports the idea that intelligent life could exist elsewhere in the vast universe. Stephen Hawking is mentioned as one of many scientists who believe the scale of the universe makes ETI probable. However, Fermi&amp;rsquo;s Paradox highlights the contradiction between this probability and the lack of observed contact. The section acknowledges the absence of confirmed extraterrestrial life. It also introduces the Kardashev scale as a method for measuring a civilization&amp;rsquo;s technological advancement based on energy use and the Drake equation as a probabilistic framework for estimating the number of communicative extraterrestrial civilizations in the Milky Way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34;&gt;Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence &lt;a href=&#34;#search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the ongoing search for ETI, noting the lack of significant results despite decades of effort. Active SETI, which involves sending messages to potential extraterrestrial civilizations, is described, including examples like radio signals and the Pioneer plaque. Communication with Extraterrestrial Intelligence (CETI) is defined as the branch of SETI focused on composing and deciphering messages. The Arecibo message, created by Frank Drake and Carl Sagan, is mentioned as a key CETI experiment. The U.S. government&amp;rsquo;s stance, reflecting expert consensus, is that the chances of contact are extremely small. The possibility of first contact being with extraterrestrial artificial intelligence is also raised. The Wow! signal is presented as the best candidate for an extraterrestrial radio signal, but its uniqueness makes definitive attribution impossible. The section also mentions a possible detection of artificial signals by China&amp;rsquo;s FAST telescope in 2022, followed by skepticism from Dan Werthimer, who attributed the signals to terrestrial radio interference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;potential-cultural-impact-of-extraterrestrial-contact&#34;&gt;Potential Cultural Impact of Extraterrestrial Contact &lt;a href=&#34;#potential-cultural-impact-of-extraterrestrial-contact&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the potential consequences of contact with ETI, emphasizing the wide range of possible outcomes depending on factors like technological advancement, benevolence, and mutual understanding. It mentions the possibility of contact with civilizations that have transcended biology and exist within advanced computers. The section draws parallels between ETI contact and historical encounters between vastly different human cultures, citing the Columbian Exchange as an example where the receiving civilization often suffers. It concludes by acknowledging the speculative nature of these predictions due to the lack of actual contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufology&#34;&gt;UFOlogy &lt;a href=&#34;#ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extraterrestrial hypothesis, which posits that some UFOs are vehicles from other worlds, is introduced. The concept of ETI as an explanation for UFOs is contrasted with EDI (extradimensional intelligence), a distinction made by J. Allen Hynek. The section also mentions a 2023 House hearing examining the executive branch&amp;rsquo;s handling of UFO reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-culture&#34;&gt;In Culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section briefly notes the recurring presence of ETI themes in popular culture, particularly since the advent of spaceflight. It mentions New Mexico&amp;rsquo;s declaration of February 14th as Extraterrestrial Culture Day in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_intelligence&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial intelligence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_d19b9c3cea60/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 13:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_d19b9c3cea60/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial Intelligence &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extraterrestrial intelligence (ETI) refers to hypothetical intelligent life beyond Earth. It emphasizes that no such life has been verifiably observed. The concept&amp;rsquo;s modern form arose with the Copernican Revolution, which positioned Earth as one of many planets. The possibility of inhabited worlds beyond Earth is a major question in science, science fiction, and popular culture. An alternative term, &amp;ldquo;Extraterrestrial Technological Instantiations&amp;rdquo; (ETI), avoids potentially ambiguous terms like &amp;ldquo;civilizations&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;species.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intelligence&#34;&gt;Intelligence &lt;a href=&#34;#intelligence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section defines intelligence in the context of extraterrestrial life, linking it to human-like cognitive abilities. It introduces &amp;ldquo;sapience&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sophoncy&amp;rdquo; as related terms. Karen and Poul Anderson are credited with coining the term sophoncy. The section clarifies that &amp;ldquo;sentience&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;consciousness&amp;rdquo; are broader terms that don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily imply intelligence or sapience. The term &amp;ldquo;extraterrestrial civilization&amp;rdquo; is presented as a specific case of extraterrestrial intelligence, representing the potential long-term result of intelligent extraterrestrial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;probability&#34;&gt;Probability &lt;a href=&#34;#probability&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the likelihood of extraterrestrial intelligence. It mentions the Copernican principle, suggesting humans aren&amp;rsquo;t privileged observers. Stephen Hawking is noted as one of many scientists who believe the universe&amp;rsquo;s scale makes extraterrestrial life probable. Fermi&amp;rsquo;s Paradox is introduced, highlighting the contradiction between high probability estimates and the lack of evidence. The section reiterates the absence of observed extraterrestrial life. The Kardashev scale, a method for measuring a civilization&amp;rsquo;s technological advancement based on energy use, is mentioned. The Drake equation, a probabilistic framework for estimating the number of communicative extraterrestrial civilizations in the Milky Way, is also noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34;&gt;Search for extraterrestrial intelligence &lt;a href=&#34;#search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the search for ETI, noting the lack of significant results despite decades of effort. It defines Active SETI as the attempt to send messages to potential extraterrestrial civilizations, usually via radio signals, and mentions the Pioneer plaque as a physical example. Communication with Extraterrestrial Intelligence (CETI) is described as focusing on composing and deciphering messages. Frank Drake and Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s Arecibo message is cited as a well-known CETI experiment. It mentions that multiple independent organizations and individuals are engaged in CETI research. The U.S. government&amp;rsquo;s stance, reflecting expert consensus, is that the chances of contact are extremely small. The possibility of first contact being with extraterrestrial artificial intelligence is raised. The Wow! signal is mentioned as the best candidate for an extraterrestrial radio signal, but its uniqueness makes attribution difficult. The section concludes with the report of possible artificial signals detected by China&amp;rsquo;s FAST telescope in June 2022, followed by the caution from Dan Werthimer that these signals are likely radio interference from Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;potential-cultural-impact-of-extraterrestrial-contact&#34;&gt;Potential cultural impact of extraterrestrial contact &lt;a href=&#34;#potential-cultural-impact-of-extraterrestrial-contact&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the potential consequences of contact with extraterrestrial intelligence. It notes that the impact could vary based on the extraterrestrial civilization&amp;rsquo;s technological advancement, intentions, and mutual comprehension with humanity. It mentions the possibility of contact with a civilization that has transcended biology and exists within advanced computers. The medium of contact (e.g., electromagnetic radiation, physical interaction) could also influence the results. The section draws parallels between extraterrestrial contact and historical encounters between vastly different human cultures, citing the Columbian Exchange as an example. It notes that such encounters have often led to the destruction of the less advanced civilization, raising the possibility of a similar outcome for humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufology&#34;&gt;UFOlogy &lt;a href=&#34;#ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section connects extraterrestrial intelligence to UFOs. The extraterrestrial hypothesis, which posits that some UFOs are vehicles from extraterrestrial beings, is introduced. The section contrasts ETI with EDI (extradimensional intelligence) as explanations for UFOs, referencing J. Allen Hynek. It mentions a 2023 House hearing examining the executive branch&amp;rsquo;s handling of UFO reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-culture&#34;&gt;In culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section briefly mentions the cultural impact of theories about intelligent life, particularly in popular culture since the advent of spaceflight. It notes that New Mexico declared February 14th as Extraterrestrial Culture Day in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_intelligence&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication with extraterrestrial intelligence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_2e93b1dd3f75/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 13:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_2e93b1dd3f75/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;communication-with-extraterrestrial-intelligence-ceti&#34;&gt;Communication with Extraterrestrial Intelligence (CETI) &lt;a href=&#34;#communication-with-extraterrestrial-intelligence-ceti&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CETI is a branch of SETI (Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence) that focuses on composing and deciphering interstellar messages that could theoretically be understood by another technological civilization. A well-known CETI experiment is the 1974 Arecibo message composed by Frank Drake. The abbreviations CETI and SETI are generic and do not refer to any particular organization like the SETI Institute. CETI research focuses on mathematical languages, pictorial systems (like the Arecibo message), algorithmic communication systems (ACETI), and computational approaches to detecting and deciphering &amp;ldquo;natural&amp;rdquo; language communication. Research also addresses how to overcome problems of decipherment in interplanetary communication, similar to the challenges posed by undeciphered writing systems in human communication like Linear A. In 2015, scientists including Douglas Vakoch, David Grinspoon, Seth Shostak, and David Brin discussed active SETI and the potential risks of transmitting messages to extraterrestrials. A statement signed by many in the SETI community emphasized the need for a global discussion before sending any messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 19th century, speculation about inhabitants of other planets was common, with many believing intelligent beings lived on the Moon, Mars, and/or Venus. Before radio, proposals for signaling extraterrestrials included Carl Friedrich Gauss&amp;rsquo;s 1820 suggestion to draw a giant Pythagorean triangle on the Siberian tundra and Joseph Johann Littrow&amp;rsquo;s 1819 idea to use the Sahara as a &amp;ldquo;blackboard&amp;rdquo; with trenches filled with water and kerosene to create signals. Astronomers like Franz von Paula Gruithuisen also looked for signs of life, claiming to see cities and agriculture on the Moon and evidence of life on Venus. By the late 1800s, Mars became the focus after Giovanni Schiaparelli reported &amp;ldquo;canali&amp;rdquo; (channels) on Mars, which were mistranslated as &amp;ldquo;canals,&amp;rdquo; sparking enthusiasm about Martian life. Inventor Charles Cros sought funding for a giant mirror to signal Martians, while Nikola Tesla believed his inventions could be used for interplanetary communication and claimed to have observed extraterrestrial radio signals. The Guzman Prize was created, offering 100,000 francs to the first person to establish interplanetary communication, excluding Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;mathematical-and-scientific-languages&#34;&gt;Mathematical and Scientific Languages &lt;a href=&#34;#mathematical-and-scientific-languages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers artificial languages designed for interstellar communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lincos-lingua-cosmica&#34;&gt;Lincos (Lingua cosmica) &lt;a href=&#34;#lincos-lingua-cosmica&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hans Freudenthal&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Lincos: Design of a Language for Cosmic Intercourse&lt;/em&gt; (1960) expands upon Astraglossa to create a general-purpose language derived from basic mathematics and logic symbols. A dictionary resembling Lincos was featured in Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s novel &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; and its film adaptation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;astraglossa&#34;&gt;Astraglossa &lt;a href=&#34;#astraglossa&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lancelot Hogben&amp;rsquo;s 1963 essay &amp;ldquo;Astraglossa&amp;rdquo; describes a system for combining numbers and operators in a series of short and long pulses, where short pulses represent numbers and trains of long pulses represent symbols for addition, subtraction, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;carl-sagan&#34;&gt;Carl Sagan &lt;a href=&#34;#carl-sagan&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s 1985 science fiction novel &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; explores how a message might be constructed for communication with an alien civilization, using prime numbers as a starting point, followed by universal principles and facts of mathematics and science. Sagan also edited a nonfiction book on the subject, and an updated collection of articles was published in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-language-based-on-the-fundamental-facts-of-science&#34;&gt;A Language Based on the Fundamental Facts of Science &lt;a href=&#34;#a-language-based-on-the-fundamental-facts-of-science&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Devito and Richard Oehrle&amp;rsquo;s 1992 paper, &lt;em&gt;A language based on the fundamental facts of science&lt;/em&gt;, describes a language similar in syntax to Astraglossa and Lincos, but which builds its vocabulary around known physical properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;busch-general-purpose-binary-language-used-in-lone-signal-transmissions&#34;&gt;Busch General-Purpose Binary Language Used in Lone Signal Transmissions &lt;a href=&#34;#busch-general-purpose-binary-language-used-in-lone-signal-transmissions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2010, Michael W. Busch created a general-purpose binary language later used in the Lone Signal project to transmit crowdsourced messages to extraterrestrial intelligence (METI). This was followed by an attempt to extend the syntax used in the Lone Signal hailing message to communicate in a way that, while neither mathematical nor strictly logical, was nonetheless understandable given the prior definition of terms and concepts in the Lone Signal hailing message. The Lone Signal project sent messages to Gliese 526 (HD 119850) in the constellation Boötes, with the message sent on July 10, 2013, and expected to arrive in 2031.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;pictorial-messages&#34;&gt;Pictorial Messages &lt;a href=&#34;#pictorial-messages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictorial communication systems describe fundamental mathematical or physical concepts via simplified diagrams sent as bitmaps. These messages assume the recipient has similar visual capabilities and can understand basic mathematics and geometry. A critique is that they presume a shared understanding of shapes, which may not be the case with a species with substantially different vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pioneer-probes&#34;&gt;Pioneer Probes &lt;a href=&#34;#pioneer-probes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two etched plaques, known as the Pioneer plaques, were included aboard the Pioneer 10 and Pioneer 11 spacecraft when they launched in 1972 and 1973. The plaques depict the location of the Solar System within the galaxy and the Earth within the Solar System, as well as the form of the human body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;voyager-probes&#34;&gt;Voyager Probes &lt;a href=&#34;#voyager-probes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Launched in 1977, the Voyager probes carried two golden records that were inscribed with diagrams similar to the Pioneer plaques, depicting the human form, the Solar System, and its location. Also included were recordings of images and sounds from Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;arecibo-message&#34;&gt;Arecibo Message &lt;a href=&#34;#arecibo-message&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Arecibo message, transmitted in 1974, was a 1,679-pixel bitmap that, when properly arranged into 73 rows and 23 columns, shows the numbers one through ten; the atomic numbers of hydrogen, carbon, nitrogen, oxygen, and phosphorus; the formulas for the sugars and bases that make up the nucleotides of DNA; the number of nucleotides in the human genome; the double helix structure of DNA; a simple illustration of a human being and its height; the human population of Earth; a diagram of the Solar System; and an illustration of the Arecibo telescope with its diameter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cosmic-call-messages&#34;&gt;Cosmic Call Messages &lt;a href=&#34;#cosmic-call-messages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Cosmic Call&lt;/em&gt; messages consisted of digital sections – &amp;ldquo;Rosetta Stone&amp;rdquo;, a copy of the Arecibo Message, the Bilingual Image Glossary, and the Braastad message – as well as text, audio, video, and other image files submitted for transmission by people around the world. The &amp;ldquo;Rosetta Stone&amp;rdquo; was composed by Stéphane Dumas and Yvan Dutil, and represents a multi-page bitmap that builds a vocabulary of symbols representing numbers and mathematical operations. These messages were transmitted in 1999 and 2003 from Evpatoria Planetary Radar in Russia under the scientific guidance of Alexander L. Zaitsev. Richard Braastad coordinated the overall project. Star systems to which the messages were sent include 16 Cyg A, 15 Sge, HD 178428, Gl 777, Hip 4872, HD 245409, 55 Cnc, HD 10307, and 47 UMa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;multi-modal-messages&#34;&gt;Multi-Modal Messages &lt;a href=&#34;#multi-modal-messages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;teen-age-message&#34;&gt;Teen-Age Message &lt;a href=&#34;#teen-age-message&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Teen-Age Message&lt;/em&gt;, composed by Russian scientists (Zaitsev, Gindilis, Pshenichner, Filippova) and teens, was transmitted from the 70-m dish of Evpatoria Deep Space Center in Ukraine to six star systems resembling that of the Sun on August 29 and September 3 and 4, 2001. The message consists of three parts: a coherent-sounding radio signal with slow Doppler wavelength tuning, analog information representing musical melodies performed on the theremin, and Arecibo-like binary digital information. Star systems to which the message was sent are HD 197076, 47 UMa, 37 Gem, HD 126053, HD 76151, and HD 193664.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cosmic-call-2-cosmic-call-2003-message&#34;&gt;Cosmic Call 2 (Cosmic Call 2003) Message &lt;a href=&#34;#cosmic-call-2-cosmic-call-2003-message&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cosmic Call-2 message contained text, images, video, music, the Dutil/Dumas message, a copy of the 1974 Arecibo message, BIG = Bilingual Image Glossary, the AI program &lt;em&gt;Ella&lt;/em&gt;, and the Braastad message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;algorithmic-messages&#34;&gt;Algorithmic Messages &lt;a href=&#34;#algorithmic-messages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Algorithmic communication systems describe a small set of mathematic and logic symbols that form the basis for a rudimentary programming language that the recipient can run on a virtual machine. Advantages include localized communication, forward error correction, and the ability to embed proxy agents within the message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cosmicos&#34;&gt;CosmicOS &lt;a href=&#34;#cosmicos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CosmicOS&lt;/em&gt;, designed by Paul Fitzpatrick at MIT, describes a virtual machine that is derived from lambda calculus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;logic-gate-matrices&#34;&gt;Logic Gate Matrices &lt;a href=&#34;#logic-gate-matrices&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Logic Gate Matrices&lt;/em&gt; (LGM), developed by Brian McConnell, describes a universal virtual machine that is constructed by connecting coordinates in an n-dimensional space via mathematics and logic operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;natural-language-messages&#34;&gt;Natural Language Messages &lt;a href=&#34;#natural-language-messages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research focuses on receiving a signal or message that is either not directed at us (eavesdropping) or one that is in its natural communicative form. Methods are being developed to detect if a signal has structure indicative of an intelligent source, categorize the type of structure detected, and then decipher its content. This structure modeling focuses on the search for generic human and inter-species language universals to devise computational methods by which language may be discriminated from non-language, and core structural syntactic elements of unknown languages may be detected. If a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communication_with_Extraterrestrial_Intelligence&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communication_with_Extraterrestrial_Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History of the extraterrestrial life debate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_a9b9b3e228d3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 20:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_a9b9b3e228d3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;historical-views-about-extraterrestrial-life&#34;&gt;Historical Views about Extraterrestrial Life &lt;a href=&#34;#historical-views-about-extraterrestrial-life&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article explores the historical debate surrounding the existence of extraterrestrial life, tracing its evolution from ancient philosophical speculations to modern scientific inquiry. It highlights key figures, pivotal moments, and shifting perspectives that have shaped our understanding of this enduring question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ancient-greece&#34;&gt;Ancient Greece &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-greece&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section delves into the earliest recorded discussions about extraterrestrial life, focusing on Ancient Greece. It contrasts the views of atomists, who believed in the possibility of multiple worlds with life, and Aristotelians, who argued for the uniqueness of Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt; The section highlights the shift from mythological explanations of celestial objects to philosophical inquiries about the nature of the universe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important People:&lt;/strong&gt; Thales of Miletus, Anaximander, Pythagoras, Aristarchus of Samos, Plato, Aristotle, Leucippus, Democritus, Epicurus, Lucretius, Alexander the Great.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Locations:&lt;/strong&gt; Ancient Greece, Alexandria, Baghdad, Roman Empire, Byzantine Empire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Major Events:&lt;/strong&gt; The development of geometry, the proposal of heliocentric and geocentric models, the spread of Greek ideas through the Macedonian Empire and the Islamic Golden Age, and the eventual return of this knowledge to Europe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;christianity&#34;&gt;Christianity &lt;a href=&#34;#christianity&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines the influence of Christianity on the debate about extraterrestrial life during the Middle Ages. It discusses how the concept of multiple worlds was largely viewed as heretical, with a few exceptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt; The section focuses on the conflict between religious doctrine and the idea of extraterrestrial life, particularly concerning the uniqueness of creation and the role of Christ&amp;rsquo;s redemption.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important People:&lt;/strong&gt; Origen, Augustine of Hippo, Thomas Aquinas, William Vorilong, John.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Major Events:&lt;/strong&gt; The rise of Christianity, the Condemnation of 1277, and the discussions surrounding the implications of extraterrestrial life for Christian theology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;copernican-revolution&#34;&gt;Copernican Revolution &lt;a href=&#34;#copernican-revolution&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores how the Copernican Revolution, which shifted the Earth from the center of the universe, significantly impacted the plausibility of extraterrestrial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt; The section highlights the transition from a geocentric to a heliocentric worldview and the scientific advancements that supported this shift.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important People:&lt;/strong&gt; Nicolaus Copernicus, Tycho Brahe, Johannes Kepler, Galileo Galilei, Isaac Newton, Giordano Bruno.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Major Events:&lt;/strong&gt; The publication of &lt;em&gt;De revolutionibus orbium coelestium&lt;/em&gt;, Kepler&amp;rsquo;s discovery of elliptical orbits, Galileo&amp;rsquo;s telescopic observations, and Newton&amp;rsquo;s formulation of the laws of motion and universal gravitation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modern-times&#34;&gt;Modern Times &lt;a href=&#34;#modern-times&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the modern scientific approach to the question of extraterrestrial life, encompassing fields like biology, chemistry, biochemistry, physics, and planetary science, all under the umbrella of astrobiology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt; The section emphasizes the vastness and age of the universe, the abundance of elements necessary for life, and the universality of physical laws, which together suggest that life on other worlds is plausible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Major Events:&lt;/strong&gt; The development of astrobiology as a multidisciplinary field, and the ongoing search for extraterrestrial life through scientific exploration and research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_the_extraterrestrial_life_debate&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_the_extraterrestrial_life_debate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial sample curation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_97f8be919529/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 06:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_97f8be919529/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-sample-curation&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial Sample Curation &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-sample-curation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the specialized facilities and procedures required for handling and preserving samples returned from space, with a focus on planetary protection and sample integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section emphasizes the importance of bringing extraterrestrial materials to Earth for in-depth scientific analysis due to the limitations of spacecraft instruments. It highlights the need for specialized biocontainment facilities that also function as cleanrooms to prevent contamination of the samples and protect Earth from potential biohazards. The section differentiates between non-restricted samples (e.g., from the Moon, asteroids) and restricted samples (from potentially habitable bodies like Mars), which require more stringent containment measures. It mentions the Biosafety Levels (BSL) required for each type of sample, with restricted samples needing BSL-4 facilities. A key challenge is the need to both contain the samples and allow researchers to analyze them without compromising their integrity or Earth&amp;rsquo;s safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;non-restricted-materials&#34;&gt;Non-restricted Materials &lt;a href=&#34;#non-restricted-materials&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the curation of samples from celestial bodies not considered to pose a biohazard risk, such as the Moon, asteroids, and comets. It mentions that as of 2019, only JAXA (Japan) and NASA (United States) operate BSL-3 laboratories dedicated to curating these samples. The Extraterrestrial Sample Curation Center at JAXA is highlighted for its ability to handle samples without atmospheric exposure. The Vernadsky Institute of Geochemistry and Analytical Chemistry at the Russian Academy of Sciences is mentioned as the location where Luna Soviet mission samples are studied and stored. The &lt;em&gt;OSIRIS-REx&lt;/em&gt; mission&amp;rsquo;s sample return to Earth is also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;restricted-materials&#34;&gt;Restricted Materials &lt;a href=&#34;#restricted-materials&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section addresses the handling of samples from planets or moons suspected of harboring past or present life, which are classified as Category V bodies. It emphasizes that these samples require BSL-4 facilities, but existing BSL-4 labs are not adequate for both sample preservation and Earth protection. Two proposed facilities are discussed: the European Sample Curation Facility (ESCF) in Vienna and NASA&amp;rsquo;s Mars Sample-Return Receiving Facility (MSRRF). The MSRRF had multiple designs submitted in 2009, and its construction is estimated to take 7-10 years, with an additional 2 years for staff training. A mobile BSL-4 facility for preliminary biohazard analysis at the landing site is also being considered. The section outlines stringent containment requirements, including filtering particles as small as 0.01 μm to prevent the release of potential biohazards, including gene transfer agents (GTAs) and ultramicrobacteria. The section also notes that some advocate for robotic systems within BSL-4 facilities to minimize human contamination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_sample_curation&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_sample_curation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
