<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 11:46:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives on the alien abduction phenomenon</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_c0a6e9617f65/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 11:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_c0a6e9617f65/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;perspectives-on-the-alien-abduction-phenomenon&#34;&gt;Perspectives on the Alien Abduction Phenomenon &lt;a href=&#34;#perspectives-on-the-alien-abduction-phenomenon&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This explores various explanations for claims of alien abduction and examination by otherworldly beings. Perspectives range from complete disbelief to the acceptance of these claims as objective reality. Some researchers, like Harvard psychiatrist John E. Mack, acknowledge an &amp;ldquo;authentic mystery&amp;rdquo; surrounding the phenomenon, urging consideration of all associated aspects, including missing time, UFO sightings, and occurrences in children. The mainstream scientific view leans towards a psychosocial explanation rooted in human psychology, neurology, and culture, while others, including conspiracy theorists and ufologists, believe in literal extraterrestrial abductions. Authors like Jacques Vallée and John E. Mack suggest the need to re-evaluate our understanding of reality to comprehend the phenomenon fully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-hypothesis&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial Hypothesis &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-hypothesis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents the idea that alien abduction is a real phenomenon where extraterrestrial beings abduct humans for study or experimentation. The elusiveness of these beings is attributed to their advanced technology. The hypothesis lacks widespread support among mainstream scientists due to the absence of physical evidence and the contradictory nature of abduction accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;literary-perspectives&#34;&gt;Literary Perspectives &lt;a href=&#34;#literary-perspectives&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the appeal of alien abduction accounts from a literary standpoint. Terry Matheson suggests that these tales are captivating due to their depiction of human powerlessness. The section contrasts the temporary fear experienced from ghost stories with the inescapable nature of alien abductions, which the abduction myth suggests cannot be avoided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;skeptical-perspectives&#34;&gt;Skeptical Perspectives &lt;a href=&#34;#skeptical-perspectives&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines skeptical explanations for alien abduction reports, focusing on psychological processes rather than extraterrestrial beings. Skeptics critically examine claims for evidence of hoaxes or influence from popular culture. Brian Dunning notes psychological explanations such as hallucination, temporary schizophrenia, epileptic seizures, and parasomnia (including hypnagogic states, night terrors, and sleep paralysis). Sleep paralysis, often accompanied by hallucinations, is presented as a potential explanation, although individuals experiencing it do not typically interpret it as alien encounters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hoax&#34;&gt;Hoax &lt;a href=&#34;#hoax&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section addresses the possibility of alien abduction claims being hoaxes, motivated by financial gain or attention. While some skeptics believe abductees are lying, it is acknowledged that most abductees genuinely believe in their experiences, making simple fabrication an insufficient explanation for the majority of claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;psychopathology&#34;&gt;Psychopathology &lt;a href=&#34;#psychopathology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the view, once common but now largely unsupported by scientists, that those claiming alien abduction are mentally ill. Studies have found that alleged abductees are generally no more likely to suffer from psychopathologies than the general population. However, abductees often score higher in tests measuring hypnotic suggestibility, absorption, magical ideation, and dissociative experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;false-memory-hypothesis&#34;&gt;False Memory Hypothesis &lt;a href=&#34;#false-memory-hypothesis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents the false memory hypothesis, a widely accepted theory in the scientific community, which explains how psychologically healthy individuals may develop and maintain a belief in alien abduction through psychological processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sleep-paralysis&#34;&gt;Sleep Paralysis &lt;a href=&#34;#sleep-paralysis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details how sleep paralysis, often accompanied by feelings of chest pressure and hypnopompic hallucinations (such as flying, lights, presences, and figures), can contribute to abduction experiences. Cultural beliefs strongly influence the content of these hallucinations. Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s comparison of alien abduction experiences to historical tales of demon abduction is highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;lucid-dreams&#34;&gt;Lucid Dreams &lt;a href=&#34;#lucid-dreams&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the connection between lucid dreams and alien abduction experiences. Research from the Phase Research Center suggests that experiences of close encounters with UFOs and extraterrestrials can be products of the human mind during lucid dreaming. A 2021 study found that a significant percentage of volunteers could emulate alien encounters via lucid dreams, with some experiencing sleep paralysis and fear similar to &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; abduction stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;hypnosis&#34;&gt;Hypnosis &lt;a href=&#34;#hypnosis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the use of hypnosis in recovering memories of &amp;ldquo;missing time&amp;rdquo; in abduction cases, starting with the Betty and Barney Hill abduction. It notes that individuals interested in UFOs may seek therapists with similar beliefs, potentially leading to the creation of false memories under hypnosis due to increased suggestibility. Thomas Bullard notes that hypnotized subjects are more likely to confabulate or be open to memory implantation. Budd Hopkins&amp;rsquo; counterargument, citing the Hill case, is also presented. Skeptics Robert Sheaffer and Phillip J. Klass suggest that individual abduction researchers influence the characteristics of narratives retrieved during hypnotic recall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;cultural-impact&#34;&gt;Cultural Impact &lt;a href=&#34;#cultural-impact&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines the influence of cultural factors on abduction claims. Skeptics argue that variations in abduction details across cultures support a psycho-social hypothesis. The section notes that abduction accounts may be influenced by science fiction, citing the resemblance between the Betty and Barney Hill case and media they had recently consumed. It also mentions how abduction claims have changed over time to align with scientific discoveries about the solar system. Robert Sheaffer highlights differences in the types of aliens reported in different countries and similarities between aliens in early science fiction films and abduction reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;maintenance-of-abduction-memories&#34;&gt;Maintenance of Abduction Memories &lt;a href=&#34;#maintenance-of-abduction-memories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses how abductees maintain their beliefs, even when faced with disbelief. Many seek support groups where they find validation from others with similar experiences, reinforcing the accuracy of their abduction memories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;drug-induced-hallucinations&#34;&gt;Drug-Induced Hallucinations &lt;a href=&#34;#drug-induced-hallucinations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the possibility that some alleged abductions are drug-induced hallucinations. It mentions Terence McKenna&amp;rsquo;s experiences with &amp;ldquo;Machine Elves&amp;rdquo; while using DMT and Rick Strassman&amp;rsquo;s research at the University of New Mexico, which found that a significant percentage of volunteers injected with high doses of DMT had experiences similar to purported alien abductions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;parallels-with-other-phenomena&#34;&gt;Parallels with Other Phenomena &lt;a href=&#34;#parallels-with-other-phenomena&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section draws parallels between the abduction phenomenon and other unusual events, such as witchcraft claims. Robert Sheaffer notes similarities in imagery, uncovered memories, and sex, suggesting a common underlying psychopathology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section also notes Gwen Dean&amp;rsquo;s presentation of 44 parallels between alien abduction and satanic ritual abuse (SRA) at a 1992 MIT conference. Both phenomena emerged in the late 1970s and early 1980s, often use hypnosis, and feature similar elements such as familial involvement, generational occurrences, examination tables/altars, focus on genitals/sexuality/breeding, altered states of consciousness, and &amp;ldquo;missing time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abductors-as-demonic-manifestations&#34;&gt;Abductors as Demonic Manifestations &lt;a href=&#34;#abductors-as-demonic-manifestations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents the view that abduction experiences share similarities with pre-20th century accounts of demonic manifestations. Writers have noted numerous similarities. Fr. Seraphim Rose, an Orthodox monk, dedicates a chapter in his book &lt;em&gt;Orthodoxy and the Religion of the Future&lt;/em&gt; to UFOs and abductions, concluding that they are manifestations of the demonic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perspectives_on_the_abduction_phenomenon&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perspectives_on_the_abduction_phenomenon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ufology</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7a24e854d947/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7a24e854d947/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufology&#34;&gt;Ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology is the investigation of unidentified flying objects (UFOs) by individuals who believe they may have extraordinary origins, often extraterrestrial. While governments, private groups, and fringe science have investigated UFOs, ufology is generally considered pseudoscience by skeptics and science educators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;etymology&#34;&gt;Etymology &lt;a href=&#34;#etymology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;ufology&amp;rdquo; is a neologism derived from &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; and the suffix &amp;ldquo;-logy.&amp;rdquo; Edward J. Ruppelt is credited with coining the term UFO. Early uses of &amp;ldquo;ufology&amp;rdquo; appeared in a 1957 &lt;em&gt;Fantastic Universe&lt;/em&gt; article and a 1958 presentation for The Planetary Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-background&#34;&gt;Historical Background &lt;a href=&#34;#historical-background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology&amp;rsquo;s roots can be traced to several historical phenomena:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mystery Airships (late 1890s):&lt;/strong&gt; Unexplained aerial objects reported during this period.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foo Fighters (World War II):&lt;/strong&gt; Reports from Allied airmen of unusual objects during flight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ghost Fliers (1930s):&lt;/strong&gt; Sightings in Europe and North America.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ghost Rockets (1946):&lt;/strong&gt; Sightings in Scandinavia, particularly Sweden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenneth Arnold Sighting (1947):&lt;/strong&gt; Arnold&amp;rsquo;s report of &amp;ldquo;flying saucers&amp;rdquo; popularized the concept.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increased media attention to UFOs after World War II coincided with the Cold War and concerns about Soviet aircraft. Official government involvement in ufology in the United States ended in the late 1960s after the Condon Committee report and the termination of Project Blue Book. Other countries, such as the United Kingdom, Canada, Denmark, Italy, and Sweden, also ended government-sponsored UFO activities. France is an exception, maintaining the GEIPAN program. In September 2023, NASA appointed Mark McInerney as the Director of U.A.P. to study such occurrences scientifically and transparently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;as-a-field&#34;&gt;As a Field &lt;a href=&#34;#as-a-field&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;status-as-a-pseudoscience&#34;&gt;Status as a Pseudoscience &lt;a href=&#34;#status-as-a-pseudoscience&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology is not recognized as a scientific field by academia and is generally considered a pseudoscience. Pseudoscience lacks adherence to the scientific method, supporting evidence, plausibility, or falsifiability. Social factors contribute to this status, including mistrust between ufology, the sciences, and government investigative bodies. Poor science communication regarding the extraterrestrial intelligence (ETI) hypothesis also hinders public understanding and academic inquiry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-interest&#34;&gt;Current Interest &lt;a href=&#34;#current-interest&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interest in ufology persists. In 2021, Avi Loeb launched The Galileo Project to collect scientific evidence of extraterrestrial technology. The University of Würzburg in Germany is developing sensors to detect and analyze aerial objects. A 2021 Gallup poll indicated increased belief among Americans that some UFOs are extraterrestrial spacecraft. In 2022, NASA announced a study to investigate UAP. In 2023, the RAND Corporation published a study reviewing 101,151 public reports of UAP sightings in the United States from 1998 to 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;methodological-issues&#34;&gt;Methodological Issues &lt;a href=&#34;#methodological-issues&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific UFO research faces challenges due to the unpredictable nature of the phenomena, lack of reproducibility, and absence of tangible physicality. Most UFO sightings have mundane explanations, limiting the interpretive power of extraordinary events. Carl Sagan noted that reliable cases are uninteresting, and interesting cases are unreliable. J. Allen Hynek and Jacques Vallée developed descriptive systems for characterizing UFO sightings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;phenomena-linked-to-ufology&#34;&gt;Phenomena Linked to Ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#phenomena-linked-to-ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain phenomena are of interest to some ufologists:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crop circles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cattle mutilations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anomalous materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alien abductions and implants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ufologists promote UFO conspiracy theories, such as the Roswell Incident and Majestic 12 documents. Robert Sheaffer has accused ufology of a &amp;ldquo;credulity explosion,&amp;rdquo; while James E. McDonald identified &amp;ldquo;cultism&amp;rdquo; as negatively impacting ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-posadism&#34;&gt;In Posadism &lt;a href=&#34;#in-posadism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the Cold War, ufology was synthesized with the ideas of Posadism, a Trotskyist movement in South America. Juan Posadas, the main theorist, believed humanity should appeal to extraterrestrials to intervene and collaborate in suppressing poverty and creating a socialist system on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;governmental-and-private-ufology-studies&#34;&gt;Governmental and Private Ufology Studies &lt;a href=&#34;#governmental-and-private-ufology-studies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting in the 1940s, governmental agencies and private groups sponsored investigations, studies, and conferences related to ufology. These studies include Project Sign, Project Magnet, Project Blue Book, the Robertson Panel, and the Condon Committee in the United States; the Flying Saucer Working Party and Project Condign in Britain; GEIPAN in France; and Project Hessdalen in Norway. Private studies include those by the RAND Corporation, Harvey Rutledge of the University of Missouri, and the National Press Club&amp;rsquo;s Disclosure Project. The United Nations sponsored meetings and hearings concerning UFO sightings from 1977 to 1979. In August 2020, the United States Department of Defense established the Unidentified Aerial Phenomena Task Force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufo-organizations-and-events&#34;&gt;UFO Organizations and Events &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-organizations-and-events&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerous private organizations worldwide are dedicated to the study and discussion of ufology. Skeptic organizations also exist, emphasizing the pseudoscientific nature of ufology. During World UFO Day (July 2), ufologists raise public awareness of ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ufology&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ufology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for extraterrestrial intelligence</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1448d6266380/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1448d6266380/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence-seti&#34;&gt;Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence (SETI) &lt;a href=&#34;#search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence-seti&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The search for extraterrestrial intelligence (SETI) encompasses various scientific projects aimed at detecting signals or evidence of intelligent life beyond Earth. These efforts involve monitoring electromagnetic radiation, searching for optical signals, and investigating potential extraterrestrial artifacts. Some initiatives, like NASA&amp;rsquo;s Golden Record, have also attempted to send messages to hypothetical alien civilizations. Despite decades of searching, no confirmed evidence of alien intelligence has been found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the historical progression of SETI efforts, from early speculations to modern scientific projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-work&#34;&gt;Early Work &lt;a href=&#34;#early-work&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early searches for extraterrestrial intelligence within the Solar System are highlighted. Nikola Tesla suggested using his wireless electrical transmission system to contact beings on Mars in 1896. In 1899, he thought he detected a signal from Mars at his Colorado Springs experimental station. Guglielmo Marconi, Lord Kelvin, and David Peck Todd also believed radio could be used to contact Martians in the early 1900s. In 1924, during a close opposition of Mars, the United States observed a &amp;ldquo;National Radio Silence Day&amp;rdquo; to listen for Martian signals, with William F. Friedman assigned to translate any potential messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-ozma-and-early-radio-astronomy&#34;&gt;Project Ozma and Early Radio Astronomy &lt;a href=&#34;#project-ozma-and-early-radio-astronomy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possibility of searching the microwave spectrum was first pointed out in a 1959 paper by Philip Morrison and Giuseppe Cocconi. In 1960, Frank Drake performed the first modern SETI experiment, Project Ozma, at Green Bank, West Virginia, examining the stars Tau Ceti and Epsilon Eridani. Soviet scientists also took a strong interest in SETI during the 1960s. Iosif Shklovsky wrote the book &lt;em&gt;Universe, Life, Intelligence&lt;/em&gt; (1962), which was expanded upon by Carl Sagan as &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Life in the Universe&lt;/em&gt; (1966). John D. Kraus&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Big Ear&amp;rdquo; radio telescope at Ohio State University began the world&amp;rsquo;s first continuous SETI program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-cyclops-and-the-wow-signal&#34;&gt;Project Cyclops and the Wow! Signal &lt;a href=&#34;#project-cyclops-and-the-wow-signal&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1971, NASA funded a SETI study that proposed the construction of an Earth-based radio telescope array with 1,500 dishes known as Project Cyclops. The project was not built, but the report formed the basis of much SETI work that followed. The Ohio State SETI program gained fame on August 15, 1977, when Jerry Ehman witnessed a strong signal, the Wow! signal, which is considered by some to be the best candidate for a radio signal from an extraterrestrial source ever discovered. In May 2023, a test extraterrestrial signal was transmitted to radio telescopes on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sentinel-meta-and-beta&#34;&gt;Sentinel, META, and BETA &lt;a href=&#34;#sentinel-meta-and-beta&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1980, Carl Sagan, Bruce Murray, and Louis Friedman founded the U.S. Planetary Society, partly as a vehicle for SETI studies. In the early 1980s, Harvard University physicist Paul Horowitz proposed the design of a spectrum analyzer specifically intended to search for SETI transmissions. This work led to &amp;ldquo;Suitcase SETI&amp;rdquo; in 1981, followed by Project META in 1985, and Project BETA in 1995. On March 23, 1999, the 26-meter radio telescope on which Sentinel, META and BETA were based was blown over by strong winds and seriously damaged, forcing the BETA project to cease operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mop-and-project-phoenix&#34;&gt;MOP and Project Phoenix &lt;a href=&#34;#mop-and-project-phoenix&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1978, the NASA SETI program was heavily criticized by Senator William Proxmire, and funding for SETI research was removed from the NASA budget by Congress in 1981. In 1992, the U.S. government funded an operational SETI program, in the form of the NASA Microwave Observing Program (MOP). MOP was canceled one year after its start. In 1995, the SETI Institute resurrected the MOP program under the name of Project Phoenix, under the direction of Jill Tarter. From 1995 through March 2004, Phoenix conducted observations at the Parkes radio telescope in Australia, the National Radio Astronomy Observatory in Green Bank, West Virginia, and the Arecibo Observatory in Puerto Rico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ongoing-radio-searches&#34;&gt;Ongoing Radio Searches &lt;a href=&#34;#ongoing-radio-searches&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the current state of radio-based SETI projects and the rationale behind focusing on radio frequencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many radio frequencies penetrate Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere well, leading to the development of radio telescopes. Human endeavors emit considerable electromagnetic radiation, which could be recognizable as artificial signals. Earth has been sending radio waves into space for over 100 years, reaching over 1,000 stars. Many international radio telescopes are currently being used for radio SETI searches, including the Low Frequency Array (LOFAR) in Europe, the Murchison Widefield Array (MWA) in Australia, and the Lovell Telescope in the United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;allen-telescope-array&#34;&gt;Allen Telescope Array &lt;a href=&#34;#allen-telescope-array&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SETI Institute collaborated with the Radio Astronomy Laboratory at the Berkeley SETI Research Center to develop the Allen Telescope Array (ATA). The array has 42 operational dishes at the Hat Creek Radio Observatory in rural northern California. The SETI Institute&amp;rsquo;s Center for SETI Research (CSR) uses ATA in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence, observing 12 hours a day, 7 days a week. Berkeley astronomers used the ATA to pursue several science topics until 2011, when the collaboration between the University of California, Berkeley and the SETI Institute was terminated. In 2012, the ATA was revitalized with a donation by Franklin Antonio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;serendip&#34;&gt;SERENDIP &lt;a href=&#34;#serendip&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SERENDIP (Search for Extraterrestrial Radio Emissions from Nearby Developed Intelligent Populations) is a SETI program launched in 1979 by the Berkeley SETI Research Center. SERENDIP analyzes deep space radio telescope data that it obtains while other astronomers are using the telescopes. The most recently deployed SERENDIP spectrometer, SERENDIP VI, was installed at both the Arecibo Telescope and the Green Bank Telescope in 2014–2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;breakthrough-listen&#34;&gt;Breakthrough Listen &lt;a href=&#34;#breakthrough-listen&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Breakthrough Listen&lt;/em&gt; is a ten-year initiative with $100 million funding begun in July 2015 to actively search for intelligent extraterrestrial communications in the universe. The science program for Breakthrough Listen is based at Berkeley SETI Research Center. The project is observing for thousands of hours every year on two major radio telescopes, the Green Bank Observatory in West Virginia, and the Parkes Observatory in Australia. Frank Drake was one of the scientists on the project&amp;rsquo;s advisory committee. In October 2019, Breakthrough Listen started a collaboration with scientists from the TESS team to look for signs of advanced extraterrestrial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fast&#34;&gt;FAST &lt;a href=&#34;#fast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China&amp;rsquo;s 500 meter Aperture Spherical Telescope (FAST) lists &lt;em&gt;detecting interstellar communication signals&lt;/em&gt; as part of its science mission. FAST is the first radio observatory built with SETI as a core scientific goal. On 14 June 2022, astronomers, working with China&amp;rsquo;s FAST telescope, reported the possibility of having detected artificial signals, but cautioned that further studies were required to determine if a natural radio interference may be the source. Dan Werthimer noted, &amp;ldquo;These signals are from radio interference; they are due to radio pollution from earthlings, not from E.T.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ucla&#34;&gt;UCLA &lt;a href=&#34;#ucla&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2016, University of California Los Angeles (UCLA) undergraduate and graduate students have been participating in radio searches for technosignatures with the Green Bank Telescope. Targets include the Kepler field, TRAPPIST-1, and solar-type stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;community-seti-projects&#34;&gt;Community SETI Projects &lt;a href=&#34;#community-seti-projects&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights SETI projects that rely on the contributions of volunteers and the general public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;setihome&#34;&gt;SETI@home &lt;a href=&#34;#setihome&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SETI@home project used volunteer computing to analyze signals acquired by the SERENDIP project. The SETI@home project was launched by the Berkeley SETI Research Center at the University of California, Berkeley, in May 1999. The project is run by director David P. Anderson and chief scientist Dan Werthimer. On March 31, 2020, the project stopped sending out new work to SETI@home users, bringing this particular SETI effort to an indefinite hiatus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;seti-net&#34;&gt;SETI Net &lt;a href=&#34;#seti-net&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SETI Network was the only fully operational private search system. SETI Net started operation in the early 1980s as a way to learn about the science of the search, and developed several software packages for the amateur SETI community. SETI Net went dark and was decommissioned on 2021-12-04.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-seti-league-and-project-argus&#34;&gt;The SETI League and Project Argus &lt;a href=&#34;#the-seti-league-and-project-argus&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1994 in response to the United States Congress cancellation of the NASA SETI program, The SETI League, Incorporated is a membership-supported nonprofit organization. This grass-roots alliance of amateur and professional radio astronomers is headed by executive director emeritus H. Paul Shuch. The organization concentrates on coordinating a global network of small, amateur-built radio telescopes under Project Argus, an all-sky survey seeking to achieve real-time coverage of the entire sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;optical-experiments&#34;&gt;Optical Experiments &lt;a href=&#34;#optical-experiments&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the search for extraterrestrial intelligence using optical wavelengths, such as lasers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some SETI researchers have considered the possibility that alien civilizations might be using powerful lasers for interstellar communications at optical wavelengths. There are two problems with optical SETI: lasers are highly &amp;ldquo;monochromatic&amp;rdquo;, and lasers are highly directional&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SETI&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SETI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien language</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_523ba4ab15e4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 12:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_523ba4ab15e4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-language&#34;&gt;Alien Language &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-language&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the hypothetical concept of alien languages, exploring the challenges and possibilities of understanding and communicating with extraterrestrial beings. It delves into the field of study dedicated to these hypothetical languages, the opinions of linguists on the matter, and examples of how the topic has been approached in science fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hypothetical-non-earth-language&#34;&gt;Hypothetical Non-Earth Language &lt;a href=&#34;#hypothetical-non-earth-language&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces the concept of alien languages as a hypothetical subject due to the lack of confirmed contact with extraterrestrial life. It mentions the various names for the study of these languages, including exolinguistics, xenolinguistics, and astrolinguistics. The section also references the book &lt;em&gt;Xenolinguistics: Towards a Science of Extraterrestrial Language&lt;/em&gt;, edited by Douglas Vakoch and Jeffrey Punske, which features contributions from prominent linguists like Noam Chomsky. It also mentions that the topic of alien languages has been included in linguistics and language studies courses, such as at Bowling Green State University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#heading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents Noam Chomsky&amp;rsquo;s view that humans might not be able to naturally learn an alien language due to the constraints of a genetically predetermined universal grammar. He suggests that understanding an alien language would require a scientific approach, similar to research in physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#heading-1&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights Keren Rice&amp;rsquo;s more optimistic perspective, suggesting that basic communication between humans and aliens should be possible if fundamental aspects of language, such as time, space, and participants, are not radically different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;heading-2&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#heading-2&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses Jessica Coon&amp;rsquo;s involvement as a linguistic consultant for the film &lt;em&gt;Arrival&lt;/em&gt;. While acknowledging the artistic license taken with the alien language in the film, she notes that the film accurately portrays the approach human linguists would take in attempting to decipher an alien language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;heading-3&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#heading-3&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions Laurance Doyle&amp;rsquo;s suggestion of using Zipf&amp;rsquo;s law to detect alien language within the search for extraterrestrial intelligence (SETI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;heading-4&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#heading-4&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents Solomon W. Golomb&amp;rsquo;s argument that any civilization capable of interstellar communication must possess an innate understanding that information retains its meaning regardless of the speaker. He posits that this shared understanding would facilitate the learning of extraterrestrial languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;heading-5&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#heading-5&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section includes a quote from Ian Roberts, a professor of linguistics at the University of Cambridge, who emphasizes the unique open-endedness of human language. Roberts is also mentioned as being on the Advisory Council of Messaging Extraterrestrial Intelligence (METI), an organization that sends messages into space in hopes of receiving a reply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alien language in science fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Animal language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Astrolinguistics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communication with extraterrestrial intelligence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interspecies communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, providing credibility and allowing readers to further explore the topics discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_language&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Close encounter</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6e704c7ca402/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 01:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6e704c7ca402/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;close-encounter&#34;&gt;Close Encounter &lt;a href=&#34;#close-encounter&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A close encounter, in ufology, is defined as an event where a person witnesses an unidentified flying object (UFO) at close range, reducing the likelihood of misidentification. The term and classification system were introduced by astronomer and UFO researcher J. Allen Hynek in his 1972 book, &lt;em&gt;The UFO Experience: A Scientific Inquiry&lt;/em&gt;. While others have expanded on Hynek&amp;rsquo;s original categories, these extensions haven&amp;rsquo;t gained widespread acceptance due to a perceived lack of scientific rigor. Sightings beyond 150 meters are generally classified as &lt;em&gt;daylight discs&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;nocturnal lights&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;radar/visual reports&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hyneks-scale&#34;&gt;Hynek&amp;rsquo;s Scale &lt;a href=&#34;#hyneks-scale&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. Allen Hynek created a six-level classification system for UFO sightings, arranged by proximity. The categories include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nocturnal Lights:&lt;/strong&gt; Unexplained lights observed in the night sky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daylight Discs:&lt;/strong&gt; UFOs seen during the day, typically disc-shaped or oval.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Radar-Visual:&lt;/strong&gt; UFO sightings confirmed by radar, intended to provide more concrete evidence, though atmospheric anomalies can sometimes explain radar propagation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Close Encounters of the First Kind (CE1):&lt;/strong&gt; Visual sightings of a UFO at close range (less than 150 meters), displaying appreciable angular extension and detail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Close Encounters of the Second Kind (CE2):&lt;/strong&gt; UFO events involving physical effects, such as interference with vehicles or electronics, animal reactions, physiological effects on witnesses, or physical traces like ground impressions or scorched vegetation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind (CE3):&lt;/strong&gt; UFO encounters where animated entities are present, including humanoids, robots, or humans seemingly associated with the UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bloecher-subtypes&#34;&gt;Bloecher Subtypes &lt;a href=&#34;#bloecher-subtypes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ted Bloecher proposed six subtypes for Close Encounters of the Third Kind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aboard:&lt;/strong&gt; An entity is observed only inside the UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Both:&lt;/strong&gt; An entity is observed both inside and outside the UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Close:&lt;/strong&gt; An entity is observed near a UFO, but not entering or exiting it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Direct:&lt;/strong&gt; An entity is observed without any UFOs being seen, but UFO activity has been reported in the area around the same time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Excluded:&lt;/strong&gt; An entity is observed, but no UFOs are seen, and no UFO activity has been reported in the area at that time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frequence:&lt;/strong&gt; No entity or UFOs are observed, but the subject experiences some form of &amp;ldquo;intelligent communication.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;extensions-of-hyneks-scale&#34;&gt;Extensions of Hynek&amp;rsquo;s Scale &lt;a href=&#34;#extensions-of-hyneks-scale&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following Hynek&amp;rsquo;s death in 1986, Jacques Vallee expanded the classification system by adding Close Encounters of the Fourth and Fifth Kinds, detailed in his 1990 book, &lt;em&gt;Confrontations: A Scientist&amp;rsquo;s Search for Alien Contact&lt;/em&gt;. These extensions were quickly adopted by the Mutual UFO Network (MUFON).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;close-encounters-of-the-fourth-kind-ce4&#34;&gt;Close Encounters of the Fourth Kind (CE4) &lt;a href=&#34;#close-encounters-of-the-fourth-kind-ce4&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A CE4 involves a human being abducted by a UFO or its occupants. Jacques Vallée suggested that the &amp;ldquo;fourth kind&amp;rdquo; should encompass cases where witnesses experience a transformation of their sense of reality, including non-abduction events with absurd, hallucinatory, or dreamlike elements associated with UFO encounters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;close-encounters-of-the-fifth-kind-ce5&#34;&gt;Close Encounters of the Fifth Kind (CE5) &lt;a href=&#34;#close-encounters-of-the-fifth-kind-ce5&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Vallee&amp;rsquo;s original definition, a CE5 occurs when an alien abductee experiences a physical effect from the encounter, such as injury or healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alternate interpretation, popularized by Steven M. Greer, defines CE5 as human-initiated contact with extraterrestrial life forms or advanced interstellar civilizations, involving direct communication between aliens and humans. This involves individuals or groups using specific protocols, primarily contact meditation and sounds or signals, to establish communication or interaction with extraterrestrial beings. This is also referred to as human-initiated close encounter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;close-encounters-of-the-sixth-kind-ce6&#34;&gt;Close Encounters of the Sixth Kind (CE6) &lt;a href=&#34;#close-encounters-of-the-sixth-kind-ce6&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This term describes a sexual encounter between a human and an extraterrestrial species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Close_encounter&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Close_encounter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flying saucer</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e1a122e1217a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e1a122e1217a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;purported-disk-shaped-aircraft&#34;&gt;Purported disk-shaped aircraft &lt;a href=&#34;#purported-disk-shaped-aircraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the history, description, and cultural impact of &amp;ldquo;flying saucers,&amp;rdquo; a term popularized in the late 1940s to describe disc-shaped unidentified flying objects (UFOs). It distinguishes flying saucers from the broader category of UFOs/UAPs and explores their evolution in popular culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section traces the origins and development of the flying saucer phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;precursors&#34;&gt;Precursors &lt;a href=&#34;#precursors&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explores earlier reports of unusual aerial phenomena that predate the term &amp;ldquo;flying saucer.&amp;rdquo; These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mysterious lights in the sky interpreted as spiritual phenomena in antiquity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;19th-century newspaper reports of massive airships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 1878 &lt;em&gt;Denison Daily News&lt;/em&gt; article describing an object resembling a saucer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Foo fighters&amp;rdquo; reported by Allied pilots during World War II.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Science fiction stories featuring disc-shaped aircraft, such as Jean de La Hire&amp;rsquo;s 1908 novel &lt;em&gt;La Roue fulgurante&lt;/em&gt; and &amp;ldquo;The Shaver Mystery&amp;rdquo; stories in &lt;em&gt;Amazing Stories&lt;/em&gt; magazine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fantasy artwork in pulp magazines depicting flying discs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;origins&#34;&gt;Origins &lt;a href=&#34;#origins&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection details the event that is credited with popularizing the term &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Kenneth Arnold UFO sighting on June 24, 1947, in Washington State.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arnold&amp;rsquo;s description of the objects&amp;rsquo; motion as &amp;ldquo;like a saucer skipping across the water.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The media&amp;rsquo;s coining of the terms &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;flying disc.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The subsequent wave of reported sightings across the United States, including the Flight 105 UFO sighting and the Roswell incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early speculation about the objects&amp;rsquo; origins, including secret military technology and Soviet aircraft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;development&#34;&gt;Development &lt;a href=&#34;#development&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers the evolution of the flying saucer concept and its association with extraterrestrial life:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The increasing association of flying saucers with extraterrestrial life in the 1950s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s speculation about an extraterrestrial origin for the objects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The emergence of unusual theories, such as Meade Layne&amp;rsquo;s speculation about alternate dimensions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The influence of pulp science fiction on beliefs about flying saucers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The rise of the &amp;ldquo;contactee&amp;rdquo; movement, with individuals like George Van Tassel and George Adamski claiming to have ridden aboard saucers and received messages from aliens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The development of ufology as a parallel social movement, with figures like Frank Scully, Donald Keyhoe, and Leonard H. Stringfield publishing books and forming UFO investigation groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The emergence of UFO photography as a subgenre of documentary photography.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The eventual decline in popularity of the term &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; and its replacement by &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;UAP.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description &lt;a href=&#34;#description&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the characteristics and identification of flying saucers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;identification&#34;&gt;Identification &lt;a href=&#34;#identification&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the identification of reported flying saucers with known phenomena:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experts have identified the majority of UFO reports as misidentifications or hoaxes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common explanations for saucer sightings include the planet Venus, weather phenomena, balloons, and airborne trash.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US Navy&amp;rsquo;s Skyhook spy balloon project, which led to numerous misidentified sightings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psychological studies of why people believe in flying saucers, including Georges Heuyer&amp;rsquo;s view of the phenomenon as a shared delusion and Michel Monnerie&amp;rsquo;s psychosocial UFO hypothesis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reported-sightings&#34;&gt;Reported sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#reported-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection summarizes the characteristics of reported flying saucer sightings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eyewitness descriptions differ in reported appearance, movement, and purpose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Astronomer Donald Howard Menzel&amp;rsquo;s overview of flying saucers, noting the variety of shapes, sizes, colors, and movements reported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The increasing standardization of alien descriptions over time, with Grey aliens becoming the most reported type of pilot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The influence of popular social and cultural expectations on the details of claimed observations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fictional-portrayals&#34;&gt;Fictional portrayals &lt;a href=&#34;#fictional-portrayals&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the portrayal of flying saucers in popular media:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early portrayals emphasized high-speed maneuvers, while later media shifted to slowly hovering discs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Examples of films and television series that feature flying saucers, such as &lt;em&gt;The Flying Saucer&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Day the Earth Stood Still&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Invaders&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;popular-culture&#34;&gt;Popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the cultural impact of flying saucers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;literature&#34;&gt;Literature &lt;a href=&#34;#literature&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the appearance of flying saucers in literature:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Precursors to modern flying saucers appeared in science fiction literature, including The Shaver Mystery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The emergence of a genre that treated fantastical stories as either true or plausibly true.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of advertisements to leverage cultural interest in flying saucers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The appearance of aliens and flying discs in 1950s science fiction comics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;film-and-television&#34;&gt;Film and television &lt;a href=&#34;#film-and-television&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the portrayal of flying saucers in film and television:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many early portrayals of flying saucers linked them to the Cold War.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Examples of films that feature flying saucers, such as &lt;em&gt;The Thing from Another World&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Day the Earth Stood Still&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Earth vs. the Flying Saucers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The adaptation of the flying saucer phenomenon by other countries, such as Japan and India.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of flying saucers in other genres, such as science fiction and comedy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;architecture&#34;&gt;Architecture &lt;a href=&#34;#architecture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the use of flying saucer motifs in architecture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The flying saucer as a symbol of 1950s culture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of flying saucer motifs in Googie architecture and Atomic Age décor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notable flying saucer structures, such as Seattle&amp;rsquo;s Space Needle and Los Angeles International Airport&amp;rsquo;s Theme Building.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The influence of Googie architecture on the futuristic structures in the cartoon &lt;em&gt;The Jetsons&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of the flying saucer as an architectural motif by Frank Lloyd Wright.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Examples of novelty architecture shaped like flying saucers, such as the Kielce Bus Station in Poland and the Spodek arena in Katowice, Poland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;broader-pop-culture&#34;&gt;Broader pop culture &lt;a href=&#34;#broader-pop-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the broader cultural impact of flying saucers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flying saucers were a ubiquitous part of pop culture from 1947 into the mid-1970s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of flying disc motifs in toys and other novelties, such as the frisbee and flying saucer candy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The release of novelty songs about flying discs and alien invaders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The appearance of flying saucers in video games, typically as antagonists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flying_saucers&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flying_saucers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena Independent Study Team</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_47d13a747092/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 23:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_47d13a747092/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;nasa-unidentified-anomalous-phenomena-independent-study-team&#34;&gt;NASA Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena Independent Study Team &lt;a href=&#34;#nasa-unidentified-anomalous-phenomena-independent-study-team&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NASA Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena Independent Study Team (UAPIST) was a group of experts assembled by NASA to create a plan for analyzing unidentified anomalous phenomena (UAPs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;David Spergel, chair of NASA&amp;rsquo;s independent study on UAPs, answers a question during a public meeting of the team on May 31, 2023.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Agency overview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Formed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 24, 2022 (2022-05-24)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dissolved&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;September 14, 2023 (2023-09-14)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Agency executives&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;* David Spergel, chair * Daniel Evans, designated federal official&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Parent agency&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NASA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Website&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Official website&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scope-and-objectives&#34;&gt;Scope and objectives &lt;a href=&#34;#scope-and-objectives&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UAPIST was officially created by Karen St. Germain, the director of NASA&amp;rsquo;s Earth Science Division, as a subcommittee of the Earth Science Advisory Committee (ESAC) on May 24, 2022. NASA appointed astrophysicist David Spergel as the chair of the team, and Daniel Evans as the official responsible for the study. The team&amp;rsquo;s goal was to gather data from various sources (civilians, government, non-profits, companies) to analyze UAPs. NASA emphasized openness and transparency, stating that findings would be shared publicly. The study was separate from the Department of Defense&amp;rsquo;s UAP efforts, although NASA coordinated with the government. In July 2022, the Department of Defense replaced the Airborne Object Identification and Management Synchronization Group with the All-domain Anomaly Resolution Office (AARO). Further terms of reference were signed on May 18, 2023, extending the UAPIST and renaming it by changing &amp;ldquo;Aerial&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Anomalous&amp;rdquo;. Sean Kirkpatrick, director of the Defense Department&amp;rsquo;s AARO, spoke at the first public meeting on May 31, 2023, emphasizing the complementary nature of NASA and AARO&amp;rsquo;s efforts. NASA focused on unclassified data, while AARO included classified material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;uap-versus-ufo-terminology&#34;&gt;UAP versus UFO terminology &lt;a href=&#34;#uap-versus-ufo-terminology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term UAP emerged in the late 1960s, while &amp;ldquo;unidentified flying object&amp;rdquo; (UFO) dates back to 1947. UAP avoids the cultural associations with extraterrestrial life linked to UFOs. UFO has become associated with aliens, conspiracy theories, and religious movements. NASA updated the name of its independent study team at the start of 2023 from &amp;ldquo;unidentified aerial phenomena&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;unidentified anomalous phenomena&amp;rdquo; to be consistent with the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;team-members&#34;&gt;Team members &lt;a href=&#34;#team-members&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA announced the UAP study team members on October 21, 2022. The team included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Spergel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anamaria Berea (George Mason University)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Federica Bianco (University of Delaware)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paula Bontempi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reggie Brothers (AE Industrial Partners)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jen Buss (Potomac Institute for Policy Studies)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nadia Drake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mike Gold (Redwire)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Grinspoon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scott Kelly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matt Mountain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Warren Randolph (FAA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walter Scott (Maxar Technologies)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joshua Semeter (Boston University)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Karlin Toner (FAA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shelley Wright (University of California, San Diego)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg Eghigian noted that the NASA study team represents a significant shift, with many academics now supporting scholarly research into UFOs. He highlighted that NASA&amp;rsquo;s involvement and the scientifically informed questions being asked are unprecedented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;team-member-commentary&#34;&gt;Team member commentary &lt;a href=&#34;#team-member-commentary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the first public meeting on May 31, 2023, the NASA team addressed questions about UFOs. They emphasized collecting empirical data and improving UAP analysis. Spergel noted that many UAP events could be attributed to commercial aircraft, drones, balloons, weather, and ionospheric phenomena, but some events remain unexplained due to poor data quality. He cited fast radio bursts as an example of how anomalies can lead to novel physical phenomena. Regarding David Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims of a government coverup, Joshua Semeter stated that the NASA team is collaborating with the Defense Department&amp;rsquo;s AARO to determine the origin and nature of UAPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-report&#34;&gt;Final report &lt;a href=&#34;#final-report&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The independent study team&amp;rsquo;s final report was published on September 14, 2023, along with the announcement of a director of UAP research at NASA. The report found no evidence of extraterrestrial life. The report stated that the lack of reproducible data makes it difficult to draw conclusions about some UAP origins. It recommended a rigorous, evidence-based approach to studying UAPs, including data collection methods using artificial intelligence and citizen observers. NASA was deemed well-positioned to lead this study. According to its 2023 terms of reference, the team was dissolved upon the completion and submission of its final report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NASA%27s_UAP_independent_study_team&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NASA%27s_UAP_independent_study_team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication with extraterrestrial intelligence</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e2fe06a9ef48/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 13:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e2fe06a9ef48/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;communication-with-extraterrestrial-intelligence-ceti&#34;&gt;Communication with Extraterrestrial Intelligence (CETI) &lt;a href=&#34;#communication-with-extraterrestrial-intelligence-ceti&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CETI is a branch of SETI (Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence) that focuses on composing and deciphering interstellar messages that could theoretically be understood by another technological civilization. A well-known CETI experiment is the 1974 Arecibo message composed by Frank Drake. The abbreviations CETI and SETI are generic and do not refer to any particular organization like the SETI Institute. CETI research focuses on mathematical languages, pictorial systems (like the Arecibo message), algorithmic communication systems (ACETI), and computational approaches to detecting and deciphering &amp;ldquo;natural&amp;rdquo; language communication. The challenges of deciphering undeciphered writing systems in human communication, such as Linear A, are relevant to the problems of interplanetary communication. In 2015, scientists discussed active SETI and the potential risks of transmitting messages to extraterrestrials, leading to a statement advocating for a global discussion before any messages are sent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 19th century, speculation about inhabitants of other planets was common, with many believing in intelligent beings on the Moon, Mars, and Venus. Before radio, proposals for signaling extraterrestrials included Carl Friedrich Gauss&amp;rsquo;s idea of drawing a giant Pythagorean triangle on the Siberian tundra and Joseph Johann Littrow&amp;rsquo;s suggestion to use the Sahara as a &amp;ldquo;blackboard&amp;rdquo; with trenches filled with kerosene for burning signals. Astronomers like Franz von Paula Gruithuisen looked for signs of life on the Moon and Venus, though his claims were later refuted. Interest shifted to Mars after Giovanni Schiaparelli&amp;rsquo;s discovery of &amp;ldquo;canali&amp;rdquo; (mistranslated as &amp;ldquo;canals&amp;rdquo;), sparking enthusiasm about Martian life, which eventually proved illusory. Inventor Charles Cros sought funding for a giant mirror to signal Martians, while Nikola Tesla believed his inventions could be used for interplanetary communication, claiming to have observed extraterrestrial radio signals. The Guzman Prize was established to reward the first person to establish interplanetary communication, excluding Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;mathematical-and-scientific-languages&#34;&gt;Mathematical and Scientific Languages &lt;a href=&#34;#mathematical-and-scientific-languages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details attempts to create languages that could be universally understood based on mathematics and logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lincos-lingua-cosmica&#34;&gt;Lincos (Lingua cosmica) &lt;a href=&#34;#lincos-lingua-cosmica&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hans Freudenthal&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Lincos: Design of a Language for Cosmic Intercourse&lt;/em&gt; (1960) expands on Astraglossa to create a general-purpose language derived from basic mathematics and logic symbols. The Carl Sagan novel &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; and its film adaptation featured a dictionary resembling Lincos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;astraglossa&#34;&gt;Astraglossa &lt;a href=&#34;#astraglossa&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lancelot Hogben&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Astraglossa&amp;rdquo; (1963) describes a system for combining numbers and operators in a series of short and long pulses, where short pulses represent numbers and long pulses represent symbols for mathematical operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;carl-sagan&#34;&gt;Carl Sagan &lt;a href=&#34;#carl-sagan&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s 1985 science fiction novel &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; explores how a message might be constructed for communication with an alien civilization, using prime numbers, mathematics, and science. Sagan also edited a nonfiction book on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-language-based-on-the-fundamental-facts-of-science&#34;&gt;A Language Based on the Fundamental Facts of Science &lt;a href=&#34;#a-language-based-on-the-fundamental-facts-of-science&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Devito and Richard Oehrle&amp;rsquo;s 1992 paper describes a language similar to Astraglossa and Lincos, but builds its vocabulary around known physical properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;busch-general-purpose-binary-language-used-in-lone-signal-transmissions&#34;&gt;Busch General-Purpose Binary Language Used in Lone Signal Transmissions &lt;a href=&#34;#busch-general-purpose-binary-language-used-in-lone-signal-transmissions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2010, Michael W. Busch created a general-purpose binary language used in the Lone Signal project to transmit crowdsourced messages to extraterrestrial intelligence. The Lone Signal project transmitted messages to Gliese 526 in the constellation Boötes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;pictorial-messages&#34;&gt;Pictorial Messages &lt;a href=&#34;#pictorial-messages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictorial communication systems describe mathematical or physical concepts via simplified diagrams sent as bitmaps. These messages assume the recipient has similar visual capabilities and understands basic mathematics and geometry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pioneer-probes&#34;&gt;Pioneer Probes &lt;a href=&#34;#pioneer-probes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pioneer plaques were included aboard the Pioneer 10 and Pioneer 11 spacecraft, depicting the location of the Solar System within the galaxy, the Earth within the Solar System, and the human form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;voyager-probes&#34;&gt;Voyager Probes &lt;a href=&#34;#voyager-probes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Launched in 1977, the Voyager probes carried golden records inscribed with diagrams similar to the Pioneer plaques, depicting the human form, the Solar System, and its location, along with recordings of images and sounds from Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;arecibo-message&#34;&gt;Arecibo Message &lt;a href=&#34;#arecibo-message&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Arecibo message, transmitted in 1974, was a 1,679-pixel bitmap showing the numbers one through ten, atomic numbers of key elements, formulas for DNA nucleotides, the number of nucleotides in the human genome, the DNA double helix, a human figure and height, the human population, a diagram of the Solar System, and an illustration of the Arecibo telescope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cosmic-call-messages&#34;&gt;Cosmic Call Messages &lt;a href=&#34;#cosmic-call-messages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Cosmic Call&lt;/em&gt; messages consisted of digital sections, including a &amp;ldquo;Rosetta Stone&amp;rdquo; composed by Stéphane Dumas and Yvan Dutil, a copy of the Arecibo Message, the Bilingual Image Glossary, and the Braastad message, as well as text, audio, video, and other image files. These messages were transmitted in 1999 and 2003 from Evpatoria Planetary Radar in Russia under the scientific guidance of Alexander L. Zaitsev. Star systems targeted included 16 Cyg A, 15 Sge, HD 178428, Gl 777, Hip 4872, HD 245409, 55 Cnc, HD 10307, and 47 UMa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;multi-modal-messages&#34;&gt;Multi-Modal Messages &lt;a href=&#34;#multi-modal-messages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses messages that combine different forms of communication, such as sound, images, and text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;teen-age-message&#34;&gt;Teen-Age Message &lt;a href=&#34;#teen-age-message&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Teen-Age Message&lt;/em&gt;, composed by Russian scientists (Zaitsev, Gindilis, Pshenichner, Filippova) and teens, was transmitted from the 70-m dish of Evpatoria Deep Space Center in Ukraine to six star systems resembling the Sun on August 29 and September 3 and 4, 2001. The message consisted of a coherent-sounding radio signal, musical melodies performed on the theremin, and Arecibo-like binary digital information. Star systems targeted included 197076, 47 UMa, 37 Gem, 126053, 76151, and 193664.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cosmic-call-2-cosmic-call-2003-message&#34;&gt;Cosmic Call 2 (Cosmic Call 2003) Message &lt;a href=&#34;#cosmic-call-2-cosmic-call-2003-message&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Cosmic Call&lt;/em&gt;-2 message contained text, images, video, music, the Dutil/Dumas message, a copy of the 1974 Arecibo message, BIG = Bilingual Image Glossary, the AI program &lt;em&gt;Ella&lt;/em&gt;, and the Braastad message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;algorithmic-messages&#34;&gt;Algorithmic Messages &lt;a href=&#34;#algorithmic-messages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Algorithmic communication systems describe a small set of mathematic and logic symbols that form the basis for a rudimentary programming language that the recipient can run on a virtual machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cosmicos&#34;&gt;CosmicOS &lt;a href=&#34;#cosmicos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CosmicOS&lt;/em&gt;, designed by Paul Fitzpatrick at MIT, describes a virtual machine derived from lambda calculus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;logic-gate-matrices&#34;&gt;Logic Gate Matrices &lt;a href=&#34;#logic-gate-matrices&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Logic Gate Matrices&lt;/em&gt; (LGM), developed by Brian McConnell, describes a universal virtual machine constructed by connecting coordinates in an n-dimensional space via mathematics and logic operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;natural-language-messages&#34;&gt;Natural Language Messages &lt;a href=&#34;#natural-language-messages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research focuses on detecting and deciphering signals or messages that are either not directed at us (eavesdropping) or are in their natural communicative form. Methods are being developed to detect if a signal has structure indicative of an intelligent source, categorize the type of structure detected, and then decipher its content. This structure modeling focuses on the search for generic human and inter-species language universals to devise computational methods by which language may be discriminated from non-language, and core structural syntactic elements of unknown languages may be detected. John Elliott is a key researcher in this area. A key concept is that human languages conform to a Zipfian distribution, which may also apply to alien languages. Laurance Doyle explains that the slope of a line that represents individual tokens in a stream of tokens may indicate whether the stream contains linguistic or other structured content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;ceti-researchers&#34;&gt;CETI Researchers &lt;a href=&#34;#ceti-researchers&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists key individuals involved in CETI research:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frank Drake (SETI Institute):&lt;/strong&gt; SETI pioneer, composed the Arecibo message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr John Elliott:&lt;/strong&gt; Researches strategies for deciphering &amp;rsquo;natural&amp;rsquo; language messages, focusing on algorithms to detect intelligent-like structure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laurence Doyle (SETI Institute):&lt;/strong&gt; Studies animal communication and develops statistical measures of complexity in animal utterances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stephane Dumas:&lt;/strong&gt; Developed &lt;em&gt;Cosmic Call&lt;/em&gt; messages and techniques for generating noise-resistant 2-D symbols.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yvan Dutil:&lt;/strong&gt; Developed &lt;em&gt;Cosmic Call&lt;/em&gt; messages with Stephane Dumas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Fitzpatrick (MIT):&lt;/strong&gt; Developed &lt;em&gt;CosmicOS&lt;/em&gt; system based on lambda calculus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brian McConnell:&lt;/strong&gt; Developed a framework for algorithmic communication systems (ACETI).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marvin Minsky (MIT AI researcher):&lt;/strong&gt; Believed aliens may think similarly to humans, permitting communication, and proposed including algorithms in interstellar messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carl Sagan:&lt;/strong&gt; Co-authored the Arecibo message and was heavily involved in SETI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Douglas Vakoch (METI):&lt;/strong&gt; Editor of &lt;em&gt;Archaeology, Anthropology, and Interstellar Communication&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alexander Zaitsev (IRE, Russia):&lt;/strong&gt; Composed &lt;em&gt;Teen Age Message&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Bilingual Image Glossary&lt;/em&gt; and managed transmissions from Evpatoria Planetary Radar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Michael W&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communication_with_extraterrestrial_intelligence&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communication_with_extraterrestrial_intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien Oceans</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_d6ea56d495cd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 20:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_d6ea56d495cd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-oceans&#34;&gt;Alien Oceans &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-oceans&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2020 non-fiction book by Kevin Peter Hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;|          |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Oceans&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Oceans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
