<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Objects on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/objects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Objects on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 07:28:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/objects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in Canada</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_5b4d89bc641c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 07:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_5b4d89bc641c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-canada&#34;&gt;List of Alleged UFO Sightings in Canada &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-canada&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article presents a compilation of reported UFO sightings in Canada, spanning from the mid-20th century to recent years. It includes details of specific incidents, locations, and any investigations or cultural responses associated with these events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1951-gander-newfoundland&#34;&gt;1951, Gander, Newfoundland &lt;a href=&#34;#1951-gander-newfoundland&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details an incident on February 10, 1951, where a U.S. Navy aircraft flying from Gander, Newfoundland, to Iceland reported a near-collision with a large, orange, circular UFO. The UFO reportedly circled the American aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1960-clan-lake-northwest-territories&#34;&gt;1960, Clan Lake, Northwest Territories &lt;a href=&#34;#1960-clan-lake-northwest-territories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section recounts a report from June 18, 1960, where a prospector informed the Yellowknife RCMP detachment about a UFO sighting at Clan Lake, 30 miles north of Yellowknife. The prospector and his partner claimed to have seen a hovering object that hit the lake&amp;rsquo;s surface. The RCMP investigated but found nothing. Chris Rutkowski, a UFOlogist, is mentioned in connection with this incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1967-falcon-lake-manitoba&#34;&gt;1967, Falcon Lake, Manitoba &lt;a href=&#34;#1967-falcon-lake-manitoba&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the Falcon Lake Incident, where Stefan Michalak claimed to have been burned by a flying saucer on May 19, 1967, near Falcon Lake, Manitoba. The section mentions grid-like burn marks on Michalak&amp;rsquo;s chest and T-shirt. Ufologists consider this one of the most documented UFO stories in Canada. Two books about the incident are listed. Skeptic Aaron Sakulich suggests Michalak&amp;rsquo;s burns were likely caused by an accident related to alcohol consumption, and the story was fabricated to deter other prospectors. The Royal Canadian Mint released a commemorative coin depicting the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1967-shag-harbour-nova-scotia&#34;&gt;1967, Shag Harbour, Nova Scotia &lt;a href=&#34;#1967-shag-harbour-nova-scotia&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the Shag Harbour incident, involving the purported crash of a UFO in Shag Harbour, Nova Scotia, in October 1967. The Royal Canadian Mint also released a glow-in-the-dark coin depicting this sighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1969-prince-george-british-columbia&#34;&gt;1969, Prince George, British Columbia &lt;a href=&#34;#1969-prince-george-british-columbia&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details a sighting in Prince George, British Columbia, on January 1, 1969, where three unrelated witnesses reported a strange, round object radiating a yellow-orange light in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1974-langenburg-saskatchewan&#34;&gt;1974, Langenburg, Saskatchewan &lt;a href=&#34;#1974-langenburg-saskatchewan&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section recounts the experience of Edwin Fuhr, a farmer from Langenburg, Saskatchewan, who claimed to have seen five saucer-shaped objects hovering near a slough on September 1, 1974. An RCMP report confirmed the presence of five circles matching Fuhr&amp;rsquo;s description. The Royal Canadian Mint commemorated the event with a silver coin in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;19751976-southern-manitoba&#34;&gt;1975–1976, Southern Manitoba &lt;a href=&#34;#19751976-southern-manitoba&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions multiple sightings of a red glowing UFO in Southern Manitoba during 1975 and 1976. The UFO was nicknamed &amp;ldquo;Charlie Redstar.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1978-clarenville-newfoundland-and-labrador&#34;&gt;1978, Clarenville, Newfoundland and Labrador &lt;a href=&#34;#1978-clarenville-newfoundland-and-labrador&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes a UFO sighting in Clarenville, Newfoundland and Labrador, on October 26, 1978, witnessed by twelve individuals. Constable James Blackwood of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police also observed the object. The Royal Canadian Mint released a glow-in-the-dark coin depicting the sighting. A separate sighting in Clarenville in 2016 is also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1990-montreal-quebec&#34;&gt;1990, Montreal, Quebec &lt;a href=&#34;#1990-montreal-quebec&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details a sighting on November 7, 1990, in Montreal, Quebec, where witnesses reported a round, metallic object with lights forming a circle over the Bonaventure Hotel. The phenomenon lasted three hours. The sighting was commemorated on a Royal Canadian Mint coin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1997-trail-bc&#34;&gt;1997, Trail, BC &lt;a href=&#34;#1997-trail-bc&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes an event on July 1st in Trail, BC, where two women witnessed three small lights above them that quickly took off down the Columbia River.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2010-harbour-mille-newfoundland-and-labrador&#34;&gt;2010, Harbour Mille, Newfoundland and Labrador &lt;a href=&#34;#2010-harbour-mille-newfoundland-and-labrador&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section recounts multiple UFO sighting reports in Harbour Mille, Newfoundland and Labrador, on January 25, 2010. Initial reports of a missile launch were retracted, and the French Government denied any military activity. Gerry Byrne, a Member of Parliament, pressed the government for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2014-kensington-prince-edward-island&#34;&gt;2014, Kensington, Prince Edward Island &lt;a href=&#34;#2014-kensington-prince-edward-island&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details a sighting by John Sheppard in Kensington, Prince Edward Island, on June 4, 2014. Sheppard captured unusual lights on his cellphone. MUFON confirmed the sighting, and CBC covered the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2014-north-york-ontario&#34;&gt;2014, North York, Ontario &lt;a href=&#34;#2014-north-york-ontario&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes multiple UFO sighting reports in North York, Ontario, on July 26, 2014. Sarah Chun recorded videos of flashing lights. Toronto Police received several calls. Various explanations were offered, including quadcopters and Chinese lanterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;canadian-ufo-survey-results&#34;&gt;Canadian UFO Survey results &lt;a href=&#34;#canadian-ufo-survey-results&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the 2002 Canadian UFO Survey, noting that Toronto had the most sightings, followed by Vancouver and Terrace, B.C. It also mentions that the Canadian Federal Government directs UFO sightings to Chris Rutkowski of Ufology Research of Manitoba. A 2018 study by Ufology Research reported over 1,000 UFO sightings in Canada in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related links to people and projects associated with UFOs, including Dan Aykroyd, Stanton T. Friedman, Paul Hellyer, Peter Millman, lists of ufologists and reported UFO sightings, and Projects Magnet and Second Storey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, providing links to external websites and publications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Canada&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Canada&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
