<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SETI on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/seti/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SETI on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 04:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/seti/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Search for extraterrestrial intelligence</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1448d6266380/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1448d6266380/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence-seti&#34;&gt;Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence (SETI) &lt;a href=&#34;#search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence-seti&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The search for extraterrestrial intelligence (SETI) encompasses various scientific projects aimed at detecting signals or evidence of intelligent life beyond Earth. These efforts involve monitoring electromagnetic radiation, searching for optical signals, and investigating potential extraterrestrial artifacts. Some initiatives, like NASA&amp;rsquo;s Golden Record, have also attempted to send messages to hypothetical alien civilizations. Despite decades of searching, no confirmed evidence of alien intelligence has been found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the historical progression of SETI efforts, from early speculations to modern scientific projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-work&#34;&gt;Early Work &lt;a href=&#34;#early-work&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early searches for extraterrestrial intelligence within the Solar System are highlighted. Nikola Tesla suggested using his wireless electrical transmission system to contact beings on Mars in 1896. In 1899, he thought he detected a signal from Mars at his Colorado Springs experimental station. Guglielmo Marconi, Lord Kelvin, and David Peck Todd also believed radio could be used to contact Martians in the early 1900s. In 1924, during a close opposition of Mars, the United States observed a &amp;ldquo;National Radio Silence Day&amp;rdquo; to listen for Martian signals, with William F. Friedman assigned to translate any potential messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-ozma-and-early-radio-astronomy&#34;&gt;Project Ozma and Early Radio Astronomy &lt;a href=&#34;#project-ozma-and-early-radio-astronomy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possibility of searching the microwave spectrum was first pointed out in a 1959 paper by Philip Morrison and Giuseppe Cocconi. In 1960, Frank Drake performed the first modern SETI experiment, Project Ozma, at Green Bank, West Virginia, examining the stars Tau Ceti and Epsilon Eridani. Soviet scientists also took a strong interest in SETI during the 1960s. Iosif Shklovsky wrote the book &lt;em&gt;Universe, Life, Intelligence&lt;/em&gt; (1962), which was expanded upon by Carl Sagan as &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Life in the Universe&lt;/em&gt; (1966). John D. Kraus&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Big Ear&amp;rdquo; radio telescope at Ohio State University began the world&amp;rsquo;s first continuous SETI program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-cyclops-and-the-wow-signal&#34;&gt;Project Cyclops and the Wow! Signal &lt;a href=&#34;#project-cyclops-and-the-wow-signal&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1971, NASA funded a SETI study that proposed the construction of an Earth-based radio telescope array with 1,500 dishes known as Project Cyclops. The project was not built, but the report formed the basis of much SETI work that followed. The Ohio State SETI program gained fame on August 15, 1977, when Jerry Ehman witnessed a strong signal, the Wow! signal, which is considered by some to be the best candidate for a radio signal from an extraterrestrial source ever discovered. In May 2023, a test extraterrestrial signal was transmitted to radio telescopes on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sentinel-meta-and-beta&#34;&gt;Sentinel, META, and BETA &lt;a href=&#34;#sentinel-meta-and-beta&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1980, Carl Sagan, Bruce Murray, and Louis Friedman founded the U.S. Planetary Society, partly as a vehicle for SETI studies. In the early 1980s, Harvard University physicist Paul Horowitz proposed the design of a spectrum analyzer specifically intended to search for SETI transmissions. This work led to &amp;ldquo;Suitcase SETI&amp;rdquo; in 1981, followed by Project META in 1985, and Project BETA in 1995. On March 23, 1999, the 26-meter radio telescope on which Sentinel, META and BETA were based was blown over by strong winds and seriously damaged, forcing the BETA project to cease operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mop-and-project-phoenix&#34;&gt;MOP and Project Phoenix &lt;a href=&#34;#mop-and-project-phoenix&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1978, the NASA SETI program was heavily criticized by Senator William Proxmire, and funding for SETI research was removed from the NASA budget by Congress in 1981. In 1992, the U.S. government funded an operational SETI program, in the form of the NASA Microwave Observing Program (MOP). MOP was canceled one year after its start. In 1995, the SETI Institute resurrected the MOP program under the name of Project Phoenix, under the direction of Jill Tarter. From 1995 through March 2004, Phoenix conducted observations at the Parkes radio telescope in Australia, the National Radio Astronomy Observatory in Green Bank, West Virginia, and the Arecibo Observatory in Puerto Rico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ongoing-radio-searches&#34;&gt;Ongoing Radio Searches &lt;a href=&#34;#ongoing-radio-searches&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the current state of radio-based SETI projects and the rationale behind focusing on radio frequencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many radio frequencies penetrate Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere well, leading to the development of radio telescopes. Human endeavors emit considerable electromagnetic radiation, which could be recognizable as artificial signals. Earth has been sending radio waves into space for over 100 years, reaching over 1,000 stars. Many international radio telescopes are currently being used for radio SETI searches, including the Low Frequency Array (LOFAR) in Europe, the Murchison Widefield Array (MWA) in Australia, and the Lovell Telescope in the United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;allen-telescope-array&#34;&gt;Allen Telescope Array &lt;a href=&#34;#allen-telescope-array&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SETI Institute collaborated with the Radio Astronomy Laboratory at the Berkeley SETI Research Center to develop the Allen Telescope Array (ATA). The array has 42 operational dishes at the Hat Creek Radio Observatory in rural northern California. The SETI Institute&amp;rsquo;s Center for SETI Research (CSR) uses ATA in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence, observing 12 hours a day, 7 days a week. Berkeley astronomers used the ATA to pursue several science topics until 2011, when the collaboration between the University of California, Berkeley and the SETI Institute was terminated. In 2012, the ATA was revitalized with a donation by Franklin Antonio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;serendip&#34;&gt;SERENDIP &lt;a href=&#34;#serendip&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SERENDIP (Search for Extraterrestrial Radio Emissions from Nearby Developed Intelligent Populations) is a SETI program launched in 1979 by the Berkeley SETI Research Center. SERENDIP analyzes deep space radio telescope data that it obtains while other astronomers are using the telescopes. The most recently deployed SERENDIP spectrometer, SERENDIP VI, was installed at both the Arecibo Telescope and the Green Bank Telescope in 2014–2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;breakthrough-listen&#34;&gt;Breakthrough Listen &lt;a href=&#34;#breakthrough-listen&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Breakthrough Listen&lt;/em&gt; is a ten-year initiative with $100 million funding begun in July 2015 to actively search for intelligent extraterrestrial communications in the universe. The science program for Breakthrough Listen is based at Berkeley SETI Research Center. The project is observing for thousands of hours every year on two major radio telescopes, the Green Bank Observatory in West Virginia, and the Parkes Observatory in Australia. Frank Drake was one of the scientists on the project&amp;rsquo;s advisory committee. In October 2019, Breakthrough Listen started a collaboration with scientists from the TESS team to look for signs of advanced extraterrestrial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fast&#34;&gt;FAST &lt;a href=&#34;#fast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China&amp;rsquo;s 500 meter Aperture Spherical Telescope (FAST) lists &lt;em&gt;detecting interstellar communication signals&lt;/em&gt; as part of its science mission. FAST is the first radio observatory built with SETI as a core scientific goal. On 14 June 2022, astronomers, working with China&amp;rsquo;s FAST telescope, reported the possibility of having detected artificial signals, but cautioned that further studies were required to determine if a natural radio interference may be the source. Dan Werthimer noted, &amp;ldquo;These signals are from radio interference; they are due to radio pollution from earthlings, not from E.T.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ucla&#34;&gt;UCLA &lt;a href=&#34;#ucla&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2016, University of California Los Angeles (UCLA) undergraduate and graduate students have been participating in radio searches for technosignatures with the Green Bank Telescope. Targets include the Kepler field, TRAPPIST-1, and solar-type stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;community-seti-projects&#34;&gt;Community SETI Projects &lt;a href=&#34;#community-seti-projects&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights SETI projects that rely on the contributions of volunteers and the general public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;setihome&#34;&gt;SETI@home &lt;a href=&#34;#setihome&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SETI@home project used volunteer computing to analyze signals acquired by the SERENDIP project. The SETI@home project was launched by the Berkeley SETI Research Center at the University of California, Berkeley, in May 1999. The project is run by director David P. Anderson and chief scientist Dan Werthimer. On March 31, 2020, the project stopped sending out new work to SETI@home users, bringing this particular SETI effort to an indefinite hiatus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;seti-net&#34;&gt;SETI Net &lt;a href=&#34;#seti-net&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SETI Network was the only fully operational private search system. SETI Net started operation in the early 1980s as a way to learn about the science of the search, and developed several software packages for the amateur SETI community. SETI Net went dark and was decommissioned on 2021-12-04.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-seti-league-and-project-argus&#34;&gt;The SETI League and Project Argus &lt;a href=&#34;#the-seti-league-and-project-argus&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1994 in response to the United States Congress cancellation of the NASA SETI program, The SETI League, Incorporated is a membership-supported nonprofit organization. This grass-roots alliance of amateur and professional radio astronomers is headed by executive director emeritus H. Paul Shuch. The organization concentrates on coordinating a global network of small, amateur-built radio telescopes under Project Argus, an all-sky survey seeking to achieve real-time coverage of the entire sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;optical-experiments&#34;&gt;Optical Experiments &lt;a href=&#34;#optical-experiments&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the search for extraterrestrial intelligence using optical wavelengths, such as lasers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some SETI researchers have considered the possibility that alien civilizations might be using powerful lasers for interstellar communications at optical wavelengths. There are two problems with optical SETI: lasers are highly &amp;ldquo;monochromatic&amp;rdquo;, and lasers are highly directional&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SETI&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SETI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
