<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SETI on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/seti/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SETI on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 18:04:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/seti/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contact (1997 film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_d2406df786af/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 18:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_d2406df786af/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;contact-1997-film&#34;&gt;Contact (1997 film) &lt;a href=&#34;#contact-1997-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is a 1997 American science fiction drama film directed by Robert Zemeckis, based on Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s 1985 novel of the same name. The film stars Jodie Foster as Dr. Eleanor Arroway, a SETI scientist who discovers evidence of extraterrestrial life and is chosen to make first contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Ellie Arroway, driven by the childhood loss of her father and inspired by his encouragement of her amateur radio hobby, dedicates her life to SETI research at the Arecibo Observatory. Facing funding cuts led by President&amp;rsquo;s science advisor David Drumlin, she secures private funding from the reclusive billionaire S.R. Hadden to continue her work at the Very Large Array (VLA) in New Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four years later, Arroway discovers a signal from the star Vega containing a sequence of prime numbers. The discovery leads to a global effort to decode the message, which is complicated by Drumlin and the National Security Council&amp;rsquo;s attempts to control the facility. The signal is found to contain a video of Adolf Hitler&amp;rsquo;s opening address at the 1936 Summer Olympics, the first Earth transmission strong enough to reach Vega.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arroway&amp;rsquo;s team decodes the signal, revealing schematics for a complex machine designed to transport a single person. Multiple nations collaborate to fund the machine&amp;rsquo;s construction at the Kennedy Space Center in Cape Canaveral. An international panel is formed to select a candidate for the journey. Arroway is a leading contender, but her atheism, highlighted by panel member Palmer Joss, jeopardizes her selection. Drumlin is chosen, but a religious terrorist destroys the machine during testing, killing Drumlin and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hadden, now terminally ill and living on the Mir space station, informs Arroway of a second, secretly constructed machine in Hokkaido, Japan. Arroway is selected to use it. Equipped with recording devices, she enters the pod and travels through wormholes, observing alien structures and a celestial event. She finds herself on a beach resembling a childhood drawing of Pensacola, Florida, and encounters an alien taking the form of her deceased father, who explains that the aliens have been monitoring humanity&amp;rsquo;s radio emissions and have deemed them ready for first contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arroway awakens in the pod, which has only fallen a short distance into a safety net. Mission control insists that the experiment achieved nothing, and her recording devices show only static. A Congressional Committee, led by Michael Kitz, investigates the possibility of a hoax orchestrated by Hadden, who has since died. Arroway asks the committee to accept her testimony on faith, emphasizing the profound impact of her experience. Kitz and Rachel Constantine, a White House official, acknowledge that Arroway&amp;rsquo;s device recorded 18 hours of static. Arroway receives continued funding for SETI research at the VLA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film features a cast of notable actors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jodie Foster as Dr. Eleanor &amp;ldquo;Ellie&amp;rdquo; Ann Arroway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jena Malone as young Ellie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matthew McConaughey as Palmer Joss&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Morse as Theodore Arroway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tom Skerritt as Dr. David Drumlin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Woods as Michael Kitz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John Hurt as S. R. Hadden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;William Fichtner as Kent Clarke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Angela Bassett as Rachel Constantine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jake Busey as Joseph&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rob Lowe as Richard Rank&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geoffrey Blake as Fisher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Max Martini as Willie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steven Ford as Major John Russell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jay Leno as himself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Larry King as himself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ann Druyan as herself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;development&#34;&gt;Development &lt;a href=&#34;#development&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Sagan conceived &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; in 1979 with Lynda Obst and Peter Guber at Casablanca FilmWorks. Sagan and Ann Druyan completed the film treatment in 1980, aiming to depict a realistic first contact scenario. Kip Thorne consulted on wormhole travel. The character of Ellie Arroway was not directly inspired by Jill Tarter, though Foster met her for research. The name Ellie was inspired by Eleanor Roosevelt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project faced numerous rewrites and stalled development. Sagan rewrote &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; as a novel, published in 1985. Roland Joffé and George Miller were initially attached to direct but later departed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;filming&#34;&gt;Filming &lt;a href=&#34;#filming&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Zemeckis took over as director, securing artistic control. Filming began in September 1996 and concluded in February 1997. Key locations included the Very Large Array (VLA) in New Mexico, Warner Hollywood Studios, and Culver Studios. CNN news personalities were scripted into the film to enhance realism. Second unit filming took place at the Arecibo Observatory in Puerto Rico, Fiji, Saint John, US Virgin Islands, and Newfoundland, Canada. Technical consultants from the SETI Institute, Caltech, and a former White House staff member were involved. Sagan participated in the production until his death in December 1996, and the film is dedicated to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;visual-effects&#34;&gt;Visual effects &lt;a href=&#34;#visual-effects&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eight VFX companies, including Sony Pictures Imageworks, Weta Digital, and Industrial Light &amp;amp; Magic, collaborated on the visual effects. Weta Digital designed the wormhole sequence. Digital alterations were made to news footage of Bill Clinton. Digital color correction addressed continuity issues during location shooting. The opening scene is a five-minute CGI sequence depicting a zoom out from Earth to the distant universe. The mirror shot was created through three different plates and manipulated in CGI. The machine was designed by concept artist Steve Burg, reusing a design he created as a &amp;ldquo;time-displacement device&amp;rdquo; for an unused scene in &lt;em&gt;Terminator 2&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;Music &lt;a href=&#34;#music&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alan Silvestri composed and conducted the original score. A soundtrack album was released in August 1997.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes &lt;a href=&#34;#themes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; explores the cultural conflicts between religion and science, particularly concerning the existence of God. The film presents various viewpoints on faith and scientific evidence. It depicts intense public debate about the implications of alien contact, including questions about morality and the role of science. The film raises questions about the authenticity of Arroway&amp;rsquo;s journey, leaving room for doubt. The film suggests that science and religion can coexist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s release in July 1997 boosted interest in Sagan&amp;rsquo;s novel. The book appeared on &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; Best Seller list. The film premiered on July 1, 1997, and was released in the United States and Canada on July 11, 1997.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;critical-reception&#34;&gt;Critical reception &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received generally positive reviews. Critics praised its exploration of scientific and theological concepts but noted weaknesses in storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;awards&#34;&gt;Awards &lt;a href=&#34;#awards&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; won the Hugo Award for Best Dramatic Presentation and two Saturn Awards. It received nominations for an Academy Award for Best Sound and a Golden Globe Award for Best Lead Actress in a Motion Picture – Drama (Jodie Foster).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reactions&#34;&gt;Reactions &lt;a href=&#34;#reactions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bill-clinton&#34;&gt;Bill Clinton &lt;a href=&#34;#bill-clinton&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film used digitally altered footage of President Bill Clinton, leading to a protest from the White House.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cnn&#34;&gt;CNN &lt;a href=&#34;#cnn&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CNN chairman Tom Johnson expressed regret over allowing CNN staff to appear in the film, citing concerns about blurring the lines between news and entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nasa&#34;&gt;NASA &lt;a href=&#34;#nasa&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scene involving a cyanide pill caused controversy, with conflicting accounts from NASA advisor Gerald D. Griffin and Carl Sagan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;seti&#34;&gt;SETI &lt;a href=&#34;#seti&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SETI.org published a review of the film, highlighting its accuracy in depicting SETI research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lawsuits&#34;&gt;Lawsuits &lt;a href=&#34;#lawsuits&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Director George Miller unsuccessfully sued Warner Bros. over breach of contract policies. Francis Ford Coppola sued Warner Bros. and Sagan, claiming that Sagan&amp;rsquo;s novel was based on a story they had developed together. Coppola&amp;rsquo;s claim was dismissed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contact_(1997_American_film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contact_(1997_American_film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact (1985 novel)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_aadcaf1f76f6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 04:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_aadcaf1f76f6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;contact-1985-novel&#34;&gt;Contact (1985 novel) &lt;a href=&#34;#contact-1985-novel&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article provides information about Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s 1985 science fiction novel, &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt;. It distinguishes the novel from other works with the same title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot centers around Eleanor &amp;ldquo;Ellie&amp;rdquo; Arroway, a scientist with a strong aptitude for science and mathematics. Her father&amp;rsquo;s death deeply affects her, and she finds herself at odds with her stepfather. Ellie pursues a career in radio astronomy, eventually directing Project Argus, a SETI initiative in New Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project detects a signal from Vega, which is analyzed and found to contain a retransmission of Hitler&amp;rsquo;s 1936 Olympic speech. Later, a third message reveals plans for an advanced machine. Ellie works with Ken der Heer and Vaygay Lunacharsky to decipher the message. Religious leaders Billy Jo Rankin and Palmer Joss also become involved. The final piece of the message is discovered with the help of S.R. Hadden, revealing the primer needed to build the machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A race to build the machine ensues between the U.S. and the Soviet Union. An extremist bombing delays the project. Ellie learns Hadden has secretly built a third machine in Hokkaido, Japan. Ellie, Vaygay, Devi Sukhavati, Abonnema Eda, and Xi Qiaomu travel through wormholes to a station near the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;s center. There, they meet extraterrestrials who explain their motives and a project to alter the universe&amp;rsquo;s properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon returning to Earth, the travelers find their journey seemingly took no time at all. Their video recordings are erased, and officials suspect a hoax. Ellie finds evidence of her journey in the digits of pi, confirming the reality of her experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication-history&#34;&gt;Publication history &lt;a href=&#34;#publication-history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a child, Sagan was inspired by science fiction and fantasy. He preferred realistic stories that helped readers understand real science and history. In 1978, Sagan predicted that science fiction would make young people interested in extraterrestrial contact. Simon &amp;amp; Schuster gave Sagan a $2 million advance on the novel in 1981. Kip Thorne provided Sagan with ideas on wormholes. Eleanor Arroway was named after Eleanor Roosevelt and Voltaire. The character is based on Jill Tarter. The novel won the Locus Award for Best First Novel in 1986.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to related topics, including communication with extraterrestrial intelligence, the Fermi paradox, and &lt;em&gt;His Master&amp;rsquo;s Voice&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes &lt;a href=&#34;#notes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section clarifies two points related to the plot. The first note explains why a sequence of prime numbers is a predicted first message from alien intelligence. The second note updates the distance to Vega based on measurements from the Hipparcos satellite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including books and articles by Carl Sagan, Keay Davidson, and Jennifer Spence. It also includes links to online resources, such as Warner Bros.&amp;rsquo; website and Space.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources &lt;a href=&#34;#sources&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of sources used in the creation of the article, including books by Keay Davidson and Carl Sagan, as well as an archived webpage by Jennifer Spence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to Larry Klaes&amp;rsquo; in-depth analysis of the film and novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;carl-sagan-template&#34;&gt;Carl Sagan Template &lt;a href=&#34;#carl-sagan-template&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This template provides links to various aspects of Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s life and work, including his scientific career, books, media appearances, family, prizes, and related topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;locus-award-template&#34;&gt;Locus Award Template &lt;a href=&#34;#locus-award-template&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This template provides links to the winners of the Locus Award for Best First Novel from 1980 to 2024, as well as links to other Locus Awards categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;authority-control-databases&#34;&gt;Authority control databases &lt;a href=&#34;#authority-control-databases&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists links to various authority control databases, including VIAF, United States Library of Congress, Israel National Library, and MusicBrainz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contact_(novel)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contact_(novel)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potential cultural impact of extraterrestrial contact</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a5af699a6904/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 12:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a5af699a6904/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;cultural-impact-of-extraterrestrial-contact&#34;&gt;Cultural Impact of Extraterrestrial Contact &lt;a href=&#34;#cultural-impact-of-extraterrestrial-contact&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article explores the potential changes to human society, science, technology, religion, politics, and ecosystems that could result from contact with an extraterrestrial civilization. It emphasizes that the nature and magnitude of these changes would depend on factors such as the extraterrestrial civilization&amp;rsquo;s technological advancement, intentions (benevolent or malevolent), and the level of mutual understanding between the two species. The article also draws parallels to historical encounters between vastly different human cultures on Earth, such as the Columbian Exchange, and encounters between native and invasive species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section sets the stage by introducing the concept of the search for extraterrestrial intelligence (SETI) and its relationship to analyzing the implications of contact. It highlights that SETI focuses on locating intelligent life, while this article focuses on the potential consequences of such contact. It acknowledges that tragic consequences are largely speculative due to the absence of verified public contact to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34;&gt;Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence &lt;a href=&#34;#search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the efforts to detect extraterrestrial civilizations using radio telescopes. It mentions the challenge of identifying artificial signals against the background of natural radio waves. Key locations and projects mentioned include the Allen Telescope Array in Hat Creek, California, the Five hundred meter Aperture Spherical Telescope (FAST) in China, the now-demolished Arecibo Observatory in Puerto Rico, Project Cyclops commissioned by NASA, and Messaging to Extra-Terrestrial Intelligence (METI). The section also discusses the discovery of numerous extrasolar planets, including potentially habitable ones like Kepler-22b, and the renewed government interest in funding SETI programs, such as the European Space Agency&amp;rsquo;s COROT and NASA&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Kepler&lt;/em&gt; space observatory. Projects like A Message From Earth (AMFE) and SETILive are also mentioned, along with alternative search methods like SEVENDIP at the University of California, Berkeley. The section concludes by acknowledging that while several signals, such as the Wow! signal, have been detected, none have been confirmed as being of intelligent origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;impact-assessment&#34;&gt;Impact Assessment &lt;a href=&#34;#impact-assessment&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses methods for assessing the potential impact of extraterrestrial contact. It introduces the Rio scale, which provides a quantitative picture of the results of extraterrestrial contact based on factors such as the method of discovery, the information content of messages, and the nature of the extraterrestrial beings. The section also mentions a study by astronomer Steven J. Dick at the United States Naval Observatory, which analyzes events of similar significance in the history of science to predict the cultural impact of extraterrestrial contact. The study argues that the impact would be most strongly influenced by the information content of the message received and distinguishes between short-term and long-term impacts. The section also discusses the importance of physical distance between civilizations, with closer contact likely to be more disruptive. It also mentions a poll of United States and Chinese university students in 2000, which provides factor analysis of responses to questions about the participants&amp;rsquo; belief that extraterrestrial life exists in the Universe, that such life may be intelligent, and that humans will eventually make contact with it. The section concludes by mentioning a survey by psychologists Douglas Vakoch and Yuh-shiow Lee to assess people&amp;rsquo;s reactions to receiving a message from extraterrestrials, including their judgments about likelihood that extraterrestrials would be malevolent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;post-detection-protocols&#34;&gt;Post-Detection Protocols &lt;a href=&#34;#post-detection-protocols&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the protocols that have been developed to guide scientists and governments in the event of extraterrestrial contact. It emphasizes that these protocols are not legally binding and are likely to be ignored if contact occurs. The section mentions the &amp;ldquo;Declaration of Principles for Activities Following the Detection of Extraterrestrial Intelligence,&amp;rdquo; created by the SETI Permanent Committee of the International Academy of Astronautics (IAA) and endorsed by various international scientific unions. The Declaration of Principles contains broad provisions, including verification of the signal&amp;rsquo;s intelligent origin, communication with other signatories of the Declaration, informing national authorities, informing the astronomical community, making news of the discovery public, publishing all data, minimizing terrestrial use of the electromagnetic frequency bands, and not responding to the signal without international agreement. The section also mentions a separate &amp;ldquo;Proposed Agreement on the Sending of Communications to Extraterrestrial Intelligence,&amp;rdquo; which proposes an international commission to decide whether to send a message and determine its contents. The section concludes by noting that Paul Davies, a member of the SETI Post-Detection Taskgroup, believes that post-detection protocols are unlikely to be followed by astronomers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact-scenarios-and-considerations&#34;&gt;Contact Scenarios and Considerations &lt;a href=&#34;#contact-scenarios-and-considerations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores various models of interaction between extraterrestrial and human civilizations, ranging from beneficial collaborations to hostile subjugation. It highlights the importance of the extraterrestrial civilization&amp;rsquo;s level of aggressiveness, ethics, and biological compatibility with humans. The section also considers whether contact is via signals or physical probes, and the impact of mutual comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;friendly-civilizations&#34;&gt;Friendly Civilizations &lt;a href=&#34;#friendly-civilizations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses potential interactions with benevolent extraterrestrial civilizations. It mentions Albert Harrison, a professor emeritus of psychology at the University of California, Davis, who suggests that advanced civilizations might share knowledge such as a physical theory of everything, zero-point energy, or faster-than-light travel. The section also mentions Seth D. Baum, of the Global Catastrophic Risk Institute, who suggests that cooperative civilizations are more likely to aid humanity. In contrast, Paolo Musso, a member of the SETI Permanent Study Group of the International Academy of Astronautics (IAA) and the Pontifical Academy of Sciences, takes the view that extraterrestrial civilizations possess, like humans, a morality driven not entirely by altruism but for individual benefit as well, thus leaving open the possibility that at least &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; extraterrestrial civilizations are hostile. The section also discusses Allen Tough&amp;rsquo;s suggestions for how a friendly civilization might help humanity, including intervention to avert catastrophe, advice and action with consent, and forcible corrective action. The section concludes by noting that even with friendly contact, humans could suffer from a loss of identity and confidence, and that a friendly civilization may avoid contact altogether to allow natural development, known as the zoo hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hostile-civilizations&#34;&gt;Hostile Civilizations &lt;a href=&#34;#hostile-civilizations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the potential dangers of contact with aggressive extraterrestrial civilizations. It notes that while science fiction often depicts humans successfully repelling alien invasions, scientists generally believe that a technologically advanced civilization could easily destroy human civilization. The section mentions operations that are enormous on a human scale, such as destroying all major population centers on a planet, bombarding a planet with deadly neutron radiation, or even traveling to another planetary system in order to lay waste to it, may be important tools for a hostile civilization. The section also discusses the views of Carl Sagan, who believed that a civilization capable of interstellar travel would have transcended war, and Seth Shostak, who argues that limited resources would cultivate aggression. Ragbir Bhathal claims that an extremely advanced extraterrestrial civilization may have the motivation to colonize humanity in a similar manner to the European colonization of much of the rest of the world. The section also mentions David Brin, who states that while an extraterrestrial civilization may have an imperative to act for no benefit to itself, it would be naïve to suggest that such a trait would be prevalent throughout the galaxy. The section concludes by noting that humans may be an unsuitable food source for extraterrestrials due to biochemical differences, and that transmitting intentional signals may not increase the risk of invasion, as any civilization capable of interstellar travel could already detect Earth&amp;rsquo;s accidental radio leakage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;equally-advanced-and-more-advanced-civilizations&#34;&gt;Equally Advanced and More Advanced Civilizations &lt;a href=&#34;#equally-advanced-and-more-advanced-civilizations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines the implications of contact with civilizations of similar or greater technological advancement. It mentions Robert Freitas&amp;rsquo; speculation that the technological advancement and energy usage of a civilization, measured by its rating on the Kardashev scale, may play an important role in the result of extraterrestrial contact. The section also discusses Ben Finney&amp;rsquo;s comparison of the situation to the cargo cults of New Guinea, where indigenous people misunderstood European technology. The section concludes by noting that John Billingham suggests that a civilization which is far more technologically advanced than humanity is also likely to be culturally and ethically advanced, and would therefore be unlikely to conduct astroengineering projects that would harm human civilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;interstellar-groups-of-civilizations&#34;&gt;Interstellar Groups of Civilizations &lt;a href=&#34;#interstellar-groups-of-civilizations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the possibility of &amp;ldquo;galactic clubs,&amp;rdquo; groupings of civilizations from across the galaxy. It mentions Albert Harrison&amp;rsquo;s surmise that such clubs might exist, beginning as loose confederations and eventually developing into powerful unions. The section also discusses Sebastian von Hoerner&amp;rsquo;s suggestion that entry into a galactic club may be a way for humanity to handle the culture shock arising from contact with an advanced extraterrestrial civilization. The section concludes by noting that Michael A. G. Michaud suggests that an interstellar grouping of civilizations might take the form of an empire, which need not necessarily be a force for evil, but may provide for peace and security throughout its jurisdiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-artifacts&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial Artifacts &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-artifacts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the possibility of extraterrestrial civilizations communicating through artifacts or probes rather than radio. It notes that probes can hold sustained dialogues and perform surveillance, and that Allen Tough speculates that the enormous amount of energy required to achieve such speeds under currently proposed mechanisms means that robotic probes traveling at conventional speeds will still have an advantage for various applications. The section also mentions Robert Freitas&amp;rsquo; reasons why interstellar probes may be a preferred method of communication, including the ability to survey non-intelligent populations, store information for long timescales, and emit strong, unambiguous signals. The section concludes by noting that given the age of the Milky Way galaxy, an ancient extraterrestrial civilization may have existed and sent probes to the Solar System millions or even billions of years before the evolution of &lt;em&gt;Homo sapiens&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-implications-of-contact&#34;&gt;Further Implications of Contact &lt;a href=&#34;#further-implications-of-contact&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the potential theological, political, legal, scientific, technological, ethical, ecological, and biological-warfare impacts of extraterrestrial contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;theological&#34;&gt;Theological &lt;a href=&#34;#theological&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Potential_cultural_impact_of_extraterrestrial_contact&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Potential_cultural_impact_of_extraterrestrial_contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for extraterrestrial intelligence</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_119c6a59cbbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_119c6a59cbbd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence-seti&#34;&gt;Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence (SETI) &lt;a href=&#34;#search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence-seti&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The search for extraterrestrial intelligence (SETI) encompasses various scientific projects aimed at detecting signals or evidence of intelligent life beyond Earth. These efforts involve monitoring electromagnetic radiation, searching for optical signals, and investigating potential extraterrestrial artifacts. Some initiatives also involve sending messages to hypothetical alien civilizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the historical progression of SETI, from early speculations to modern scientific endeavors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-work&#34;&gt;Early Work &lt;a href=&#34;#early-work&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early searches for extraterrestrial intelligence within the Solar System are highlighted. Nikola Tesla suggested using his wireless electrical transmission system to contact beings on Mars in 1896. Guglielmo Marconi, Lord Kelvin, and David Peck Todd also believed radio could be used to contact Martians. In 1924, a &amp;ldquo;National Radio Silence Day&amp;rdquo; was promoted in the United States to listen for Martian signals during a close opposition of Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sentinel-meta-and-beta&#34;&gt;Sentinel, META, and BETA &lt;a href=&#34;#sentinel-meta-and-beta&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the development of spectrum analyzers for SETI. Harvard University physicist Paul Horowitz designed spectrum analyzers specifically for SETI transmissions. Project Sentinel, using a portable spectrum analyzer, began in 1983 at Oak Ridge Observatory. It was followed by Project META (Megachannel Extra-Terrestrial Assay) in 1985, which had a capacity of 8.4 million channels. META II was started in Argentina in 1990 to search the southern sky. The follow-on to META was named BETA (Billion-channel Extraterrestrial Assay), which commenced observation in 1995.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mop-and-project-phoenix&#34;&gt;MOP and Project Phoenix &lt;a href=&#34;#mop-and-project-phoenix&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the NASA Microwave Observing Program (MOP), which was canceled one year after its start due to opposition in the United States Congress. The SETI Institute resurrected the MOP program under the name of Project Phoenix in 1995, backed by private funding. Project Phoenix, directed by Jill Tarter, studied roughly 1,000 nearby Sun-like stars until approximately 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ongoing-radio-searches&#34;&gt;Ongoing Radio Searches &lt;a href=&#34;#ongoing-radio-searches&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on current radio SETI searches. Many radio frequencies penetrate Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere well, leading to the use of radio telescopes. Earth has been sending radio waves into space for over 100 years, reaching over 1,000 stars. Many international radio telescopes are currently being used for radio SETI searches, including the Low Frequency Array (LOFAR) in Europe, the Murchison Widefield Array (MWA) in Australia, and the Lovell Telescope in the United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;allen-telescope-array&#34;&gt;Allen Telescope Array &lt;a href=&#34;#allen-telescope-array&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SETI Institute collaborated with the Radio Astronomy Laboratory at the Berkeley SETI Research Center to develop the Allen Telescope Array (ATA). The array has 42 operational dishes at the Hat Creek Radio Observatory in rural northern California. The SETI Institute&amp;rsquo;s Center for SETI Research (CSR) uses ATA in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence, observing 12 hours a day, 7 days a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;serendip&#34;&gt;SERENDIP &lt;a href=&#34;#serendip&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SERENDIP (Search for Extraterrestrial Radio Emissions from Nearby Developed Intelligent Populations) is a SETI program launched in 1979 by the Berkeley SETI Research Center. SERENDIP analyzes deep space radio telescope data obtained while other astronomers are using the telescopes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;breakthrough-listen&#34;&gt;Breakthrough Listen &lt;a href=&#34;#breakthrough-listen&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Breakthrough Listen&lt;/em&gt; is a ten-year initiative with $100 million funding begun in July 2015 to actively search for intelligent extraterrestrial communications in the universe. The science program for Breakthrough Listen is based at Berkeley SETI Research Center. The project is observing for thousands of hours every year on two major radio telescopes, the Green Bank Observatory in West Virginia, and the Parkes Observatory in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fast&#34;&gt;FAST &lt;a href=&#34;#fast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China&amp;rsquo;s 500 meter Aperture Spherical Telescope (FAST) lists &lt;em&gt;detecting interstellar communication signals&lt;/em&gt; as part of its science mission. FAST is the first radio observatory built with SETI as a core scientific goal. In June 2022, astronomers working with FAST reported the possibility of having detected artificial signals, but cautioned that further studies were required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ucla&#34;&gt;UCLA &lt;a href=&#34;#ucla&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2016, University of California Los Angeles (UCLA) students have been participating in radio searches for technosignatures with the Green Bank Telescope. Targets include the Kepler field, TRAPPIST-1, and solar-type stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;community-seti-projects&#34;&gt;Community SETI Projects &lt;a href=&#34;#community-seti-projects&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights SETI projects that rely on community participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;setihome&#34;&gt;SETI@home &lt;a href=&#34;#setihome&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SETI@home project used volunteer computing to analyze signals acquired by the SERENDIP project. The project was launched by the Berkeley SETI Research Center at the University of California, Berkeley, in May 1999. On March 31, 2020, the project stopped sending out new work to SETI@home users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;seti-net&#34;&gt;SETI Net &lt;a href=&#34;#seti-net&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SETI Network was the only fully operational private search system. The SETI Net station consisted of off-the-shelf, consumer-grade electronics to minimize cost. SETI Net started operation in the early 1980s and was decommissioned on 2021-12-04.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-seti-league-and-project-argus&#34;&gt;The SETI League and Project Argus &lt;a href=&#34;#the-seti-league-and-project-argus&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1994 in response to the United States Congress cancellation of the NASA SETI program, The SETI League, Incorporated is a membership-supported nonprofit organization. The SETI League pioneered the conversion of backyard satellite TV dishes into research-grade radio telescopes. The organization concentrates on coordinating a global network of small, amateur-built radio telescopes under Project Argus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;optical-experiments&#34;&gt;Optical Experiments &lt;a href=&#34;#optical-experiments&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the possibility that alien civilizations might be using powerful lasers for interstellar communications at optical wavelengths. Several optical SETI experiments are now in progress. A Harvard-Smithsonian group designed a laser detector and mounted it on Harvard&amp;rsquo;s 155-centimeter optical telescope. The University of California, Berkeley, is also conducting optical SETI searches and collaborates with the NIROSETI program. The SETI Institute also runs a program called &amp;lsquo;Laser SETI&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quantum-communications&#34;&gt;Quantum Communications &lt;a href=&#34;#quantum-communications&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the possibility of using quantum communications for interstellar communication. A 2021 preprint described how one could search for quantum communication transmissions sent by ETI using existing telescope and receiver technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;search-for-extraterrestrial-artifacts&#34;&gt;Search for Extraterrestrial Artifacts &lt;a href=&#34;#search-for-extraterrestrial-artifacts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the possibility of using interstellar messenger probes in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence. In 1996, &amp;lsquo;Invitation to ETI&amp;rsquo; was established by Allen Tough, as a Web-based SETI experiment inviting spacefaring probes to establish contact with humanity. In 1979, Freitas and Valdes conducted a photographic search of the vicinity of the Earth-Moon triangular libration points L4 and L5, seeking possible orbiting extraterrestrial interstellar probes, but found nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;technosignatures&#34;&gt;Technosignatures &lt;a href=&#34;#technosignatures&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technosignatures, including all signs of technology, are a recent avenue in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence. Technosignatures may originate from various sources, from megastructures such as Dyson spheres to the atmospheric contamination created by an industrial civilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;advances-for-bio-and-technosignature-detection&#34;&gt;Advances for Bio and Technosignature Detection &lt;a href=&#34;#advances-for-bio-and-technosignature-detection&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights the development of an algorithm for signal reconstruction in zero-knowledge one-way communication channels. Another method called fractal messaging offers a framework for space-time scale-free communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fermi-paradox&#34;&gt;Fermi Paradox &lt;a href=&#34;#fermi-paradox&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section addresses the Fermi paradox, which questions why extraterrestrials have not visited Earth or why signals from extraterrestrials have not been heard. There are multiple explanations proposed for the Fermi paradox, ranging from analyses suggesting that intelligent life is rare to analyses suggesting that extraterrestrial civilizations may be common, but they would not communicate with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;difficulty-of-detection&#34;&gt;Difficulty of Detection &lt;a href=&#34;#difficulty-of-detection&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A significant problem is the vastness of space. For SERENDIP and most other SETI projects to detect a signal from an extraterrestrial civilization, the civilization would have to be beaming a powerful signal directly at us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;post-detection-disclosure-protocol&#34;&gt;Post-Detection Disclosure Protocol &lt;a href=&#34;#post-detection-disclosure-protocol&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The International Academy of Astronautics (IAA) has a long-standing SETI Permanent Study Group (SPSG), which addresses matters of SETI science, technology, and international policy. In October 2000 astronomers Iván Almár and Jill Tarter presented a paper which proposed a scale (modelled after the Torino scale) which is an ordinal scale between zero and ten that quantifies the impact of any public announcement regarding evidence of extraterrestrial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;active-seti&#34;&gt;Active SETI &lt;a href=&#34;#active-seti&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Active SETI, also known as messaging to extraterrestrial intelligence (METI), consists of sending signals into space in the hope that they will be detected by an alien intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;realized-interstellar-radio-message-projects&#34;&gt;Realized Interstellar Radio Message Projects &lt;a href=&#34;#realized-interstellar-radio-message-projects&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November 1974, an attempt was made at the Arecibo Observatory to send a message to other worlds. Known as the Arecibo Message, it was sent towards the globular cluster M13. Further IRMs Cosmic Call, Teen Age Message, Cosmic Call 2, and A Message From Earth were transmitted in 1999, 2001, 2003 and 2008 from the Evpatoria Planetary Radar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;debate&#34;&gt;Debate &lt;a href=&#34;#debate&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether or not to attempt to contact extraterrestrials has attracted significant academic debate. Physicist Stephen Hawking suggests that &amp;ldquo;alerting&amp;rdquo; extraterrestrial intelligences to our existence is foolhardy. Astronomer Jill Tarter disagrees with Hawking, arguing that aliens developed and long-lived enough to communicate and travel across interstellar distances would have evolved a cooperative and less violent intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;criticism&#34;&gt;Criticism &lt;a href=&#34;#criticism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critics claim that the existence of extraterrestrial intelligence has no good Popperian criteria for falsifiability. Supporters of the Rare Earth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Search_for_extraterrestrial_intelligence&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Search_for_extraterrestrial_intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for extraterrestrial intelligence</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1448d6266380/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1448d6266380/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence-seti&#34;&gt;Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence (SETI) &lt;a href=&#34;#search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence-seti&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The search for extraterrestrial intelligence (SETI) encompasses various scientific projects aimed at detecting signals or evidence of intelligent life beyond Earth. These efforts involve monitoring electromagnetic radiation, searching for optical signals, and investigating potential extraterrestrial artifacts. Some initiatives, like NASA&amp;rsquo;s Golden Record, have also attempted to send messages to hypothetical alien civilizations. Despite decades of searching, no confirmed evidence of alien intelligence has been found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the historical progression of SETI efforts, from early speculations to modern scientific projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-work&#34;&gt;Early Work &lt;a href=&#34;#early-work&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early searches for extraterrestrial intelligence within the Solar System are highlighted. Nikola Tesla suggested using his wireless electrical transmission system to contact beings on Mars in 1896. In 1899, he thought he detected a signal from Mars at his Colorado Springs experimental station. Guglielmo Marconi, Lord Kelvin, and David Peck Todd also believed radio could be used to contact Martians in the early 1900s. In 1924, during a close opposition of Mars, the United States observed a &amp;ldquo;National Radio Silence Day&amp;rdquo; to listen for Martian signals, with William F. Friedman assigned to translate any potential messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-ozma-and-early-radio-astronomy&#34;&gt;Project Ozma and Early Radio Astronomy &lt;a href=&#34;#project-ozma-and-early-radio-astronomy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possibility of searching the microwave spectrum was first pointed out in a 1959 paper by Philip Morrison and Giuseppe Cocconi. In 1960, Frank Drake performed the first modern SETI experiment, Project Ozma, at Green Bank, West Virginia, examining the stars Tau Ceti and Epsilon Eridani. Soviet scientists also took a strong interest in SETI during the 1960s. Iosif Shklovsky wrote the book &lt;em&gt;Universe, Life, Intelligence&lt;/em&gt; (1962), which was expanded upon by Carl Sagan as &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Life in the Universe&lt;/em&gt; (1966). John D. Kraus&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Big Ear&amp;rdquo; radio telescope at Ohio State University began the world&amp;rsquo;s first continuous SETI program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-cyclops-and-the-wow-signal&#34;&gt;Project Cyclops and the Wow! Signal &lt;a href=&#34;#project-cyclops-and-the-wow-signal&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1971, NASA funded a SETI study that proposed the construction of an Earth-based radio telescope array with 1,500 dishes known as Project Cyclops. The project was not built, but the report formed the basis of much SETI work that followed. The Ohio State SETI program gained fame on August 15, 1977, when Jerry Ehman witnessed a strong signal, the Wow! signal, which is considered by some to be the best candidate for a radio signal from an extraterrestrial source ever discovered. In May 2023, a test extraterrestrial signal was transmitted to radio telescopes on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sentinel-meta-and-beta&#34;&gt;Sentinel, META, and BETA &lt;a href=&#34;#sentinel-meta-and-beta&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1980, Carl Sagan, Bruce Murray, and Louis Friedman founded the U.S. Planetary Society, partly as a vehicle for SETI studies. In the early 1980s, Harvard University physicist Paul Horowitz proposed the design of a spectrum analyzer specifically intended to search for SETI transmissions. This work led to &amp;ldquo;Suitcase SETI&amp;rdquo; in 1981, followed by Project META in 1985, and Project BETA in 1995. On March 23, 1999, the 26-meter radio telescope on which Sentinel, META and BETA were based was blown over by strong winds and seriously damaged, forcing the BETA project to cease operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mop-and-project-phoenix&#34;&gt;MOP and Project Phoenix &lt;a href=&#34;#mop-and-project-phoenix&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1978, the NASA SETI program was heavily criticized by Senator William Proxmire, and funding for SETI research was removed from the NASA budget by Congress in 1981. In 1992, the U.S. government funded an operational SETI program, in the form of the NASA Microwave Observing Program (MOP). MOP was canceled one year after its start. In 1995, the SETI Institute resurrected the MOP program under the name of Project Phoenix, under the direction of Jill Tarter. From 1995 through March 2004, Phoenix conducted observations at the Parkes radio telescope in Australia, the National Radio Astronomy Observatory in Green Bank, West Virginia, and the Arecibo Observatory in Puerto Rico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ongoing-radio-searches&#34;&gt;Ongoing Radio Searches &lt;a href=&#34;#ongoing-radio-searches&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the current state of radio-based SETI projects and the rationale behind focusing on radio frequencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many radio frequencies penetrate Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere well, leading to the development of radio telescopes. Human endeavors emit considerable electromagnetic radiation, which could be recognizable as artificial signals. Earth has been sending radio waves into space for over 100 years, reaching over 1,000 stars. Many international radio telescopes are currently being used for radio SETI searches, including the Low Frequency Array (LOFAR) in Europe, the Murchison Widefield Array (MWA) in Australia, and the Lovell Telescope in the United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;allen-telescope-array&#34;&gt;Allen Telescope Array &lt;a href=&#34;#allen-telescope-array&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SETI Institute collaborated with the Radio Astronomy Laboratory at the Berkeley SETI Research Center to develop the Allen Telescope Array (ATA). The array has 42 operational dishes at the Hat Creek Radio Observatory in rural northern California. The SETI Institute&amp;rsquo;s Center for SETI Research (CSR) uses ATA in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence, observing 12 hours a day, 7 days a week. Berkeley astronomers used the ATA to pursue several science topics until 2011, when the collaboration between the University of California, Berkeley and the SETI Institute was terminated. In 2012, the ATA was revitalized with a donation by Franklin Antonio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;serendip&#34;&gt;SERENDIP &lt;a href=&#34;#serendip&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SERENDIP (Search for Extraterrestrial Radio Emissions from Nearby Developed Intelligent Populations) is a SETI program launched in 1979 by the Berkeley SETI Research Center. SERENDIP analyzes deep space radio telescope data that it obtains while other astronomers are using the telescopes. The most recently deployed SERENDIP spectrometer, SERENDIP VI, was installed at both the Arecibo Telescope and the Green Bank Telescope in 2014–2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;breakthrough-listen&#34;&gt;Breakthrough Listen &lt;a href=&#34;#breakthrough-listen&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Breakthrough Listen&lt;/em&gt; is a ten-year initiative with $100 million funding begun in July 2015 to actively search for intelligent extraterrestrial communications in the universe. The science program for Breakthrough Listen is based at Berkeley SETI Research Center. The project is observing for thousands of hours every year on two major radio telescopes, the Green Bank Observatory in West Virginia, and the Parkes Observatory in Australia. Frank Drake was one of the scientists on the project&amp;rsquo;s advisory committee. In October 2019, Breakthrough Listen started a collaboration with scientists from the TESS team to look for signs of advanced extraterrestrial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fast&#34;&gt;FAST &lt;a href=&#34;#fast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China&amp;rsquo;s 500 meter Aperture Spherical Telescope (FAST) lists &lt;em&gt;detecting interstellar communication signals&lt;/em&gt; as part of its science mission. FAST is the first radio observatory built with SETI as a core scientific goal. On 14 June 2022, astronomers, working with China&amp;rsquo;s FAST telescope, reported the possibility of having detected artificial signals, but cautioned that further studies were required to determine if a natural radio interference may be the source. Dan Werthimer noted, &amp;ldquo;These signals are from radio interference; they are due to radio pollution from earthlings, not from E.T.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ucla&#34;&gt;UCLA &lt;a href=&#34;#ucla&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2016, University of California Los Angeles (UCLA) undergraduate and graduate students have been participating in radio searches for technosignatures with the Green Bank Telescope. Targets include the Kepler field, TRAPPIST-1, and solar-type stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;community-seti-projects&#34;&gt;Community SETI Projects &lt;a href=&#34;#community-seti-projects&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights SETI projects that rely on the contributions of volunteers and the general public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;setihome&#34;&gt;SETI@home &lt;a href=&#34;#setihome&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SETI@home project used volunteer computing to analyze signals acquired by the SERENDIP project. The SETI@home project was launched by the Berkeley SETI Research Center at the University of California, Berkeley, in May 1999. The project is run by director David P. Anderson and chief scientist Dan Werthimer. On March 31, 2020, the project stopped sending out new work to SETI@home users, bringing this particular SETI effort to an indefinite hiatus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;seti-net&#34;&gt;SETI Net &lt;a href=&#34;#seti-net&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SETI Network was the only fully operational private search system. SETI Net started operation in the early 1980s as a way to learn about the science of the search, and developed several software packages for the amateur SETI community. SETI Net went dark and was decommissioned on 2021-12-04.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-seti-league-and-project-argus&#34;&gt;The SETI League and Project Argus &lt;a href=&#34;#the-seti-league-and-project-argus&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1994 in response to the United States Congress cancellation of the NASA SETI program, The SETI League, Incorporated is a membership-supported nonprofit organization. This grass-roots alliance of amateur and professional radio astronomers is headed by executive director emeritus H. Paul Shuch. The organization concentrates on coordinating a global network of small, amateur-built radio telescopes under Project Argus, an all-sky survey seeking to achieve real-time coverage of the entire sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;optical-experiments&#34;&gt;Optical Experiments &lt;a href=&#34;#optical-experiments&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the search for extraterrestrial intelligence using optical wavelengths, such as lasers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some SETI researchers have considered the possibility that alien civilizations might be using powerful lasers for interstellar communications at optical wavelengths. There are two problems with optical SETI: lasers are highly &amp;ldquo;monochromatic&amp;rdquo;, and lasers are highly directional&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SETI&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SETI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for extraterrestrial intelligence</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_66a1335bfda8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_66a1335bfda8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence-seti&#34;&gt;Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence (SETI) &lt;a href=&#34;#search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence-seti&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The search for extraterrestrial intelligence (SETI) encompasses various scientific projects aimed at detecting signals or evidence of intelligent life beyond Earth. These efforts involve monitoring electromagnetic radiation, searching for optical signals, and investigating potential extraterrestrial artifacts. While some initiatives focus on detection, others, like NASA&amp;rsquo;s Golden Record, attempt to send messages to hypothetical alien civilizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-work&#34;&gt;Early Work &lt;a href=&#34;#early-work&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early searches for extraterrestrial intelligence within the Solar System include Nikola Tesla&amp;rsquo;s suggestion in 1896 to use his wireless electrical transmission system to contact beings on Mars. In 1899, Tesla thought he detected a signal from Mars at his Colorado Springs experimental station. Guglielmo Marconi, Lord Kelvin, and David Peck Todd also believed radio could be used to contact Martians. In 1924, during a close opposition of Mars, a &amp;ldquo;National Radio Silence Day&amp;rdquo; was promoted in the United States, with a radio receiver lifted 3 kilometers above ground to listen for Martian messages, with William F. Friedman assigned to translate any potential Martian messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-ozma-and-early-radio-searches&#34;&gt;Project Ozma and Early Radio Searches &lt;a href=&#34;#project-ozma-and-early-radio-searches&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1959, Philip Morrison and Giuseppe Cocconi proposed searching the microwave spectrum for interstellar communications. In 1960, Frank Drake conducted the first modern SETI experiment, Project Ozma, at Green Bank, West Virginia, examining Tau Ceti and Epsilon Eridani near the 1.420 gigahertz marker frequency. Soviet scientists also showed strong interest in SETI during the 1960s, with Iosif Shklovsky co-authoring &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Life in the Universe&lt;/em&gt; with Carl Sagan. John D. Kraus began the Ohio State University SETI program, using the &amp;ldquo;Big Ear&amp;rdquo; radio telescope in Delaware, Ohio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-cyclops-and-the-wow-signal&#34;&gt;Project Cyclops and the Wow! Signal &lt;a href=&#34;#project-cyclops-and-the-wow-signal&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1971, NASA funded a SETI study that proposed Project Cyclops, an Earth-based radio telescope array with 1,500 dishes, but it was not built. The Ohio State SETI program gained fame on August 15, 1977, when Jerry Ehman witnessed the Wow! signal, a strong signal considered a candidate for an extraterrestrial source. In May 2023, a test extraterrestrial signal was transmitted to radio telescopes on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sentinel-meta-and-beta&#34;&gt;Sentinel, META, and BETA &lt;a href=&#34;#sentinel-meta-and-beta&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1980, Carl Sagan, Bruce Murray, and Louis Friedman founded the Planetary Society to support SETI studies. In the early 1980s, Harvard University physicist Paul Horowitz designed spectrum analyzers specifically for SETI, leading to &amp;ldquo;Suitcase SETI&amp;rdquo; in 1981 and Project META (Megachannel Extra-Terrestrial Assay) in 1985. META II was begun in Argentina in 1990. The follow-on project, BETA (Billion-channel Extraterrestrial Assay), commenced observation in 1995. In 1999, the 26-meter radio telescope used by these projects was damaged by strong winds, forcing BETA to cease operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mop-and-project-phoenix&#34;&gt;MOP and Project Phoenix &lt;a href=&#34;#mop-and-project-phoenix&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1978, the NASA SETI program faced criticism, but funding was restored in 1982 after Carl Sagan convinced Senator William Proxmire of its value. In 1992, the U.S. government funded the NASA Microwave Observing Program (MOP), but it was canceled one year after its start. In 1995, the SETI Institute resurrected the MOP program as Project Phoenix, directed by Jill Tarter, studying roughly 1,000 nearby Sun-like stars until approximately 2015, using radio telescopes in Australia, West Virginia, and Puerto Rico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ongoing-radio-searches&#34;&gt;Ongoing Radio Searches &lt;a href=&#34;#ongoing-radio-searches&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many radio frequencies penetrate Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere, leading to the use of radio telescopes for investigating the cosmos. Human communications emit electromagnetic radiation that could be recognized as artificial signals. Earth has been sending radio waves into space for over 100 years, reaching over 1,000 stars. Many international radio telescopes, including LOFAR in Europe, MWA in Australia, and the Lovell Telescope in the United Kingdom, are used for radio SETI searches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;allen-telescope-array&#34;&gt;Allen Telescope Array &lt;a href=&#34;#allen-telescope-array&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SETI Institute collaborated with the Radio Astronomy Laboratory at the Berkeley SETI Research Center to develop the Allen Telescope Array (ATA). The array currently has 42 operational dishes at the Hat Creek Radio Observatory in northern California. The full array is planned to consist of 350 or more radio dishes. The first portion of the array (ATA-42) became operational in October 2007. The SETI Institute&amp;rsquo;s Center for SETI Research (CSR) uses ATA in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence, observing 12 hours a day, 7 days a week. Berkeley astronomers used the ATA to pursue several science topics until 2011, when the collaboration between the University of California, Berkeley and the SETI Institute was terminated. In 2012, the ATA was revitalized with a donation by Franklin Antonio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;serendip&#34;&gt;SERENDIP &lt;a href=&#34;#serendip&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SERENDIP (Search for Extraterrestrial Radio Emissions from Nearby Developed Intelligent Populations) is a SETI program launched in 1979 by the Berkeley SETI Research Center. SERENDIP analyzes deep space radio telescope data obtained while other astronomers are using the telescopes. The most recently deployed SERENDIP spectrometer, SERENDIP VI, was installed at both the Arecibo Telescope and the Green Bank Telescope in 2014–2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;breakthrough-listen&#34;&gt;Breakthrough Listen &lt;a href=&#34;#breakthrough-listen&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Breakthrough Listen&lt;/em&gt; is a ten-year initiative with $100 million funding begun in July 2015 to actively search for intelligent extraterrestrial communications in the universe. The science program is based at Berkeley SETI Research Center. The project observes for thousands of hours every year on the Green Bank Observatory in West Virginia, and the Parkes Observatory in Australia. The Automated Planet Finder at Lick Observatory is searching for optical signals coming from laser transmissions. Some of the data are also analyzed by volunteers in the SETI@home volunteer computing network. Frank Drake was one of the scientists on the project&amp;rsquo;s advisory committee. In October 2019, Breakthrough Listen started a collaboration with scientists from the TESS team to look for signs of advanced extraterrestrial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fast&#34;&gt;FAST &lt;a href=&#34;#fast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China&amp;rsquo;s 500 meter Aperture Spherical Telescope (FAST) lists detecting interstellar communication signals as part of its science mission. FAST is the first radio observatory built with SETI as a core scientific goal. FAST consists of a fixed 500 m diameter spherical dish constructed in a natural depression sinkhole. In June 2022, astronomers working with FAST reported the possibility of having detected artificial signals, but cautioned that further studies were required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ucla&#34;&gt;UCLA &lt;a href=&#34;#ucla&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2016, University of California Los Angeles (UCLA) students have been participating in radio searches for technosignatures with the Green Bank Telescope. Targets include the Kepler field, TRAPPIST-1, and solar-type stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;community-seti-projects&#34;&gt;Community SETI Projects &lt;a href=&#34;#community-seti-projects&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;setihome&#34;&gt;SETI@home &lt;a href=&#34;#setihome&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SETI@home project used volunteer computing to analyze signals acquired by the SERENDIP project. It was launched by the Berkeley SETI Research Center at the University of California, Berkeley, in May 1999. Any individual could become involved with SETI research by downloading the BOINC software program and allowing the program to run as a background process. On March 31, 2020, the project stopped sending out new work to SETI@home users, bringing this particular SETI effort to an indefinite hiatus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;seti-net&#34;&gt;SETI Net &lt;a href=&#34;#seti-net&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SETI Network was the only fully operational private search system. The SETI Net station consisted of off-the-shelf, consumer-grade electronics. It had a 3-meter parabolic antenna that could be directed in azimuth and elevation. SETI Net started operation in the early 1980s and was decommissioned on 2021-12-04.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-seti-league-and-project-argus&#34;&gt;The SETI League and Project Argus &lt;a href=&#34;#the-seti-league-and-project-argus&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1994 in response to the United States Congress cancellation of the NASA SETI program, The SETI League, Incorporated is a membership-supported nonprofit organization. The SETI League pioneered the conversion of backyard satellite TV dishes into research-grade radio telescopes. The organization concentrates on coordinating a global network of small, amateur-built radio telescopes under Project Argus, an all-sky survey seeking to achieve real-time coverage of the entire sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;optical-experiments&#34;&gt;Optical Experiments &lt;a href=&#34;#optical-experiments&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some SETI researchers have considered the possibility that alien civilizations might be using powerful lasers for interstellar communications at optical wavelengths. There are two problems with optical SETI: lasers are highly &amp;ldquo;monochromatic&amp;rdquo; and lasers are highly directional. Several optical SETI experiments are now in progress. A Harvard-Smithsonian group designed a laser detector and mounted it on Harvard&amp;rsquo;s 155-centimeter optical telescope. The Harvard-Smithsonian group is now working with Princeton University to mount a similar detector system on Princeton&amp;rsquo;s 91-centimeter telescope. The Harvard-Smithsonian SETI group led by Professor Paul Horowitz built a dedicated all-sky optical survey system featuring a 1.8-meter telescope. The University of California, Berkeley, is also conducting optical SETI searches and collaborates with the NIROSETI program. The SETI Institute also runs a program called &amp;lsquo;Laser SETI&amp;rsquo; with an instrument composed of several&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Optical_SETI&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Optical_SETI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial intelligence</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_acb86ff7a2fd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 13:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_acb86ff7a2fd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial Intelligence &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extraterrestrial intelligence (ETI) refers to the hypothetical existence of intelligent life beyond Earth. While no verifiable evidence of ETI has been found, the possibility has been debated since ancient times and gained traction with the Copernican Revolution. It remains a significant topic in science, science fiction, and popular culture. An alternative term, &amp;ldquo;Extraterrestrial Technological Instantiations,&amp;rdquo; avoids potentially ambiguous terms like &amp;ldquo;civilizations&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;species.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intelligence&#34;&gt;Intelligence &lt;a href=&#34;#intelligence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section defines intelligence in the context of ETI, linking it to human-like cognitive abilities, sapience, and the term &amp;ldquo;sophoncy&amp;rdquo; (wisdom), coined by Karen Anderson and popularized by Poul Anderson. It clarifies the distinction between intelligence/sapience and sentience/consciousness, noting that the latter terms are broader and include non-sapient life forms. The concept of &amp;ldquo;extraterrestrial civilization&amp;rdquo; is introduced as a potential outcome of intelligent extraterrestrial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;probability&#34;&gt;Probability &lt;a href=&#34;#probability&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Copernican principle, which suggests humans are not privileged observers, supports the idea that intelligent life could exist elsewhere in the vast universe. Stephen Hawking is mentioned as one of many scientists who believe the scale of the universe makes ETI probable. However, Fermi&amp;rsquo;s Paradox highlights the contradiction between this probability and the lack of observed contact. The section acknowledges the absence of confirmed extraterrestrial life. It also introduces the Kardashev scale as a method for measuring a civilization&amp;rsquo;s technological advancement based on energy use and the Drake equation as a probabilistic framework for estimating the number of communicative extraterrestrial civilizations in the Milky Way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34;&gt;Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence &lt;a href=&#34;#search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the ongoing search for ETI, noting the lack of significant results despite decades of effort. Active SETI, which involves sending messages to potential extraterrestrial civilizations, is described, including examples like radio signals and the Pioneer plaque. Communication with Extraterrestrial Intelligence (CETI) is defined as the branch of SETI focused on composing and deciphering messages. The Arecibo message, created by Frank Drake and Carl Sagan, is mentioned as a key CETI experiment. The U.S. government&amp;rsquo;s stance, reflecting expert consensus, is that the chances of contact are extremely small. The possibility of first contact being with extraterrestrial artificial intelligence is also raised. The Wow! signal is presented as the best candidate for an extraterrestrial radio signal, but its uniqueness makes definitive attribution impossible. The section also mentions a possible detection of artificial signals by China&amp;rsquo;s FAST telescope in 2022, followed by skepticism from Dan Werthimer, who attributed the signals to terrestrial radio interference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;potential-cultural-impact-of-extraterrestrial-contact&#34;&gt;Potential Cultural Impact of Extraterrestrial Contact &lt;a href=&#34;#potential-cultural-impact-of-extraterrestrial-contact&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the potential consequences of contact with ETI, emphasizing the wide range of possible outcomes depending on factors like technological advancement, benevolence, and mutual understanding. It mentions the possibility of contact with civilizations that have transcended biology and exist within advanced computers. The section draws parallels between ETI contact and historical encounters between vastly different human cultures, citing the Columbian Exchange as an example where the receiving civilization often suffers. It concludes by acknowledging the speculative nature of these predictions due to the lack of actual contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufology&#34;&gt;UFOlogy &lt;a href=&#34;#ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extraterrestrial hypothesis, which posits that some UFOs are vehicles from other worlds, is introduced. The concept of ETI as an explanation for UFOs is contrasted with EDI (extradimensional intelligence), a distinction made by J. Allen Hynek. The section also mentions a 2023 House hearing examining the executive branch&amp;rsquo;s handling of UFO reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-culture&#34;&gt;In Culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section briefly notes the recurring presence of ETI themes in popular culture, particularly since the advent of spaceflight. It mentions New Mexico&amp;rsquo;s declaration of February 14th as Extraterrestrial Culture Day in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_intelligence&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial intelligence</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_d19b9c3cea60/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 13:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_d19b9c3cea60/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial Intelligence &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extraterrestrial intelligence (ETI) refers to hypothetical intelligent life beyond Earth. It emphasizes that no such life has been verifiably observed. The concept&amp;rsquo;s modern form arose with the Copernican Revolution, which positioned Earth as one of many planets. The possibility of inhabited worlds beyond Earth is a major question in science, science fiction, and popular culture. An alternative term, &amp;ldquo;Extraterrestrial Technological Instantiations&amp;rdquo; (ETI), avoids potentially ambiguous terms like &amp;ldquo;civilizations&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;species.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intelligence&#34;&gt;Intelligence &lt;a href=&#34;#intelligence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section defines intelligence in the context of extraterrestrial life, linking it to human-like cognitive abilities. It introduces &amp;ldquo;sapience&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sophoncy&amp;rdquo; as related terms. Karen and Poul Anderson are credited with coining the term sophoncy. The section clarifies that &amp;ldquo;sentience&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;consciousness&amp;rdquo; are broader terms that don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily imply intelligence or sapience. The term &amp;ldquo;extraterrestrial civilization&amp;rdquo; is presented as a specific case of extraterrestrial intelligence, representing the potential long-term result of intelligent extraterrestrial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;probability&#34;&gt;Probability &lt;a href=&#34;#probability&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the likelihood of extraterrestrial intelligence. It mentions the Copernican principle, suggesting humans aren&amp;rsquo;t privileged observers. Stephen Hawking is noted as one of many scientists who believe the universe&amp;rsquo;s scale makes extraterrestrial life probable. Fermi&amp;rsquo;s Paradox is introduced, highlighting the contradiction between high probability estimates and the lack of evidence. The section reiterates the absence of observed extraterrestrial life. The Kardashev scale, a method for measuring a civilization&amp;rsquo;s technological advancement based on energy use, is mentioned. The Drake equation, a probabilistic framework for estimating the number of communicative extraterrestrial civilizations in the Milky Way, is also noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34;&gt;Search for extraterrestrial intelligence &lt;a href=&#34;#search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the search for ETI, noting the lack of significant results despite decades of effort. It defines Active SETI as the attempt to send messages to potential extraterrestrial civilizations, usually via radio signals, and mentions the Pioneer plaque as a physical example. Communication with Extraterrestrial Intelligence (CETI) is described as focusing on composing and deciphering messages. Frank Drake and Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s Arecibo message is cited as a well-known CETI experiment. It mentions that multiple independent organizations and individuals are engaged in CETI research. The U.S. government&amp;rsquo;s stance, reflecting expert consensus, is that the chances of contact are extremely small. The possibility of first contact being with extraterrestrial artificial intelligence is raised. The Wow! signal is mentioned as the best candidate for an extraterrestrial radio signal, but its uniqueness makes attribution difficult. The section concludes with the report of possible artificial signals detected by China&amp;rsquo;s FAST telescope in June 2022, followed by the caution from Dan Werthimer that these signals are likely radio interference from Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;potential-cultural-impact-of-extraterrestrial-contact&#34;&gt;Potential cultural impact of extraterrestrial contact &lt;a href=&#34;#potential-cultural-impact-of-extraterrestrial-contact&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the potential consequences of contact with extraterrestrial intelligence. It notes that the impact could vary based on the extraterrestrial civilization&amp;rsquo;s technological advancement, intentions, and mutual comprehension with humanity. It mentions the possibility of contact with a civilization that has transcended biology and exists within advanced computers. The medium of contact (e.g., electromagnetic radiation, physical interaction) could also influence the results. The section draws parallels between extraterrestrial contact and historical encounters between vastly different human cultures, citing the Columbian Exchange as an example. It notes that such encounters have often led to the destruction of the less advanced civilization, raising the possibility of a similar outcome for humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufology&#34;&gt;UFOlogy &lt;a href=&#34;#ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section connects extraterrestrial intelligence to UFOs. The extraterrestrial hypothesis, which posits that some UFOs are vehicles from extraterrestrial beings, is introduced. The section contrasts ETI with EDI (extradimensional intelligence) as explanations for UFOs, referencing J. Allen Hynek. It mentions a 2023 House hearing examining the executive branch&amp;rsquo;s handling of UFO reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-culture&#34;&gt;In culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section briefly mentions the cultural impact of theories about intelligent life, particularly in popular culture since the advent of spaceflight. It notes that New Mexico declared February 14th as Extraterrestrial Culture Day in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_intelligence&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
