<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Extraterrestrial Influence on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/extraterrestrial-influence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Extraterrestrial Influence on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 08:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/extraterrestrial-influence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ancient astronauts</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_96b21753a786/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 08:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_96b21753a786/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ancient-astronauts&#34;&gt;Ancient Astronauts &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-astronauts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ancient astronauts, also known as ancient aliens, is a pseudoscientific belief that intelligent extraterrestrial beings visited Earth in ancient times and influenced human civilization. Proponents suggest that these aliens affected the development of cultures, technologies, religions, and even human biology. A common idea is that deities in many religions were actually extraterrestrials, and their advanced technologies were seen as divine powers by early humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This idea is rejected by academics and archaeologists, who consider it pseudoarchaeology and unscientific. Claims are often based on distorted or fabricated evidence. Some critics argue that ancient astronaut theories have racist implications, diminishing the achievements of indigenous cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notable proponents in the late 20th century include Robert Charroux, Jacques Bergier, Jean Sendy, Erich von Däniken, Alexander Kazantsev, Zecharia Sitchin, Robert K. G. Temple, Giorgio A. Tsoukalos, David Hatcher Childress, Peter Kolosimo, and Mauro Biglino.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various terms are used to describe claims about ancient astronauts, including ancient aliens, ancient ufonauts, ancient space pilots, paleocontact, astronaut- or alien gods, and paleo- or biblical-SETI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believers often claim that humans are descendants or creations of extraterrestrial intelligence that landed on Earth in the past. They suggest that human knowledge, religion, and culture originated from these ancient alien visitors, who acted as a &amp;ldquo;mother culture.&amp;rdquo; Proponents also claim that extraterrestrials built or helped humans build structures like the Egyptian pyramids and the Moai stone heads of Easter Island. Evidence is said to come from gaps in historical and archaeological records, as well as artifacts that are considered anachronistic and beyond the technical capabilities of ancient people. These &amp;ldquo;out-of-place artifacts&amp;rdquo; include artwork and legends reinterpreted to support extraterrestrial contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is featured in fringe media, such as the History Channel series &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;. The show mixes fact with fiction to promote theories of an alternate past, often incorporating white supremacist, nativist, imperialist, settler-colonial, and Christian Identity beliefs. Proponents portray themselves as an oppressed minority of academics challenging mainstream archaeology, despite lacking credentials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like past archaeological endeavors, the focus is on monumental structures, suggesting that indigenous people could not have built them without alien help. However, some indigenous voices argue that ancient alien theory supports their stories of extraterrestrial origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common theme is the portrayal of aliens as light-skinned or Aryan, as claimed by Erich von Däniken. Some proponents are associated with white supremacism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainstream archaeologists have largely ignored these claims, while popular science explainers and skeptics have criticized them. Carl Sagan noted that cases of apparent interest have reasonable alternative explanations, misreporting, or are hoaxes and distortions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34;&gt;History of Ancient Aliens Beliefs and Their Proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paleocontact narratives appeared in early science fiction of the late 19th and early 20th centuries, including &lt;em&gt;Edison&amp;rsquo;s Conquest of Mars&lt;/em&gt; (1898) and the works of H.P. Lovecraft. Harold T. Wilkins proposed the idea in earnest in 1954. It gained popularity in the 1960s due to the Space Race and Erich von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s works. Critics emerged in the 1970s, discrediting Von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s claims. By the early 1980s, support dwindled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;shklovskii-and-sagan&#34;&gt;Shklovskii and Sagan &lt;a href=&#34;#shklovskii-and-sagan&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Sagan co-authored &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Life in the Universe&lt;/em&gt; (1966) with Soviet astrophysicist Iosif Shklovsky. In &lt;em&gt;Broca&amp;rsquo;s Brain&lt;/em&gt; (1979), Sagan expressed disapproval of writers like von Däniken who treated speculations as valid evidence of extraterrestrial contact. Sagan noted that many legends, artifacts, and out-of-place artifacts cited in support of ancient astronaut hypotheses could be explained with conventional hypotheses. He reiterated that extraterrestrial visits were possible but unproven and improbable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;erich-von-däniken&#34;&gt;Erich von Däniken &lt;a href=&#34;#erich-von-d%c3%a4niken&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erich von Däniken became a leading proponent in the late 1960s and early 1970s with his book &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; (1968) and its sequels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Von Däniken argued that certain artifacts required more advanced technology than was available to ancient cultures. He claimed that these artifacts were constructed by extraterrestrial visitors or humans who learned from them. Examples include Stonehenge, Pumapunku, the Moai of Easter Island, the Great Pyramid of Giza, and the ancient Baghdad electric batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He wrote that ancient art and iconography depict air and space vehicles, intelligent non-human creatures, ancient astronauts, and advanced technology. He also stated that geographically separated cultures share artistic themes, implying a common origin. One example is his interpretation of the sarcophagus lid from the tomb of Pacal the Great in Palenque, which he saw as a seated astronaut, while Maya texts identify it as a portrait of the ruler with the World Tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Von Däniken interpreted the origins of many religions as reactions to encounters with an alien race, whose technology was seen as supernatural. He stated that religious traditions contain references to alien visitors, such as Ezekiel&amp;rsquo;s revelation, which he interpreted as a landing spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His hypotheses became popularized in the U.S. through the NBC-TV documentary &lt;em&gt;In Search of Ancient Astronauts&lt;/em&gt; and the film &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critics argue that von Däniken misrepresented data, made unfounded claims, and failed to validate his core claims. Christian creationists also criticized his work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the Nazca Lines, von Däniken stated that they resembled an airfield when seen from the air. Kenneth L. Feder argues that readers seeing the Nazca Lines in a book about aliens would be more likely to associate them with extraterrestrial origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1970, von Däniken admitted that the Nazca markings could have been laid out using a system of coordinates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;zecharia-sitchin&#34;&gt;Zecharia Sitchin &lt;a href=&#34;#zecharia-sitchin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zecharia Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Earth Chronicles&lt;/em&gt; series revolves around his interpretation of ancient Sumerian and Middle Eastern texts, megalithic sites, and artifacts. He hypothesized that the gods of Mesopotamia were astronauts from the planet Nibiru, which the Sumerians believed to be a remote &amp;ldquo;12th planet&amp;rdquo; associated with the god Marduk. According to Sitchin, Nibiru orbits the Sun on a 3,600-year elongated orbit. Modern astronomy has found no evidence to support these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitchin argued that Sumerian texts tell the story of 50 Anunnaki from Nibiru who came to Earth approximately 400,000 years ago to mine raw materials, especially gold. They genetically engineered laborers, creating &lt;em&gt;Homo sapiens sapiens&lt;/em&gt;: the &amp;ldquo;Adapa&amp;rdquo; or Adam of later mythology. Sitchin contended that the Anunnaki were active in human affairs until their culture was destroyed by global catastrophes caused by the end of the last ice age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His work has not received mainstream scholarly support and has been criticized by professionals. Semitic languages scholar Michael S. Heiser says that many of Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s translations are inconsistent with Mesopotamian cuneiform dictionaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alan F. Alford, author of &lt;em&gt;Gods of the New Millennium&lt;/em&gt;, initially adhered to Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s hypotheses but later found fault, stating that the gods personified the falling sky and that the descent of the gods was a poetic rendition of the cataclysm myth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;robert-temple&#34;&gt;Robert Temple &lt;a href=&#34;#robert-temple&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert K. G. Temple&amp;rsquo;s 1976 book, &lt;em&gt;The Sirius Mystery,&lt;/em&gt; argues that the Dogon people of northwestern Mali preserved an account of extraterrestrial visitation from around 5,000 years ago. He cites advanced astronomical knowledge, descriptions, and comparative belief systems with ancient civilizations. His work draws on the studies of cultural anthropologists Marcel Griaule and Germaine Dieterlen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His conclusions have been criticized by scientists, who point out discrepancies and suggest that the Dogon may have received their astronomical information recently from European sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ufo-religions&#34;&gt;UFO Religions &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-religions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various new religious movements, including some branches of Theosophy, Scientology, Raëlism, Aetherius Society, and Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate, believe in ancient and present-day contact with extraterrestrial intelligence. Many see ancient scriptures and recent revelations as connected with the action of aliens. Psychologists have found that UFO religions have similarities suggesting that members associate enchantment with science fiction memes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;claims-of-proponents&#34;&gt;Claims of Proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#claims-of-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientific consensus is that the ancient astronaut hypothesis is not impossible, but unjustified and unnecessary. The &amp;ldquo;mysteries&amp;rdquo; cited as evidence can be explained without invoking ancient astronauts. Since ancient astronauts are unnecessary, Occam&amp;rsquo;s razor should be applied and the hypothesis rejected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ancient-religious-texts&#34;&gt;Ancient Religious Texts &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-religious-texts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proponents cite ancient mythologies, suggesting that creation myths of gods descending from the heavens to create or instruct humanity are representations of alien visitors. They draw an analogy to cargo cults, where isolated cultures believed Western ships and cargo were sent from the gods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ancient Sumerian myth of &lt;em&gt;Enûma Eliš&lt;/em&gt; says humankind was created to serve gods called the &amp;ldquo;Annunaki.&amp;rdquo; Proponents believe that the Annunaki were aliens who came to Earth to mine gold and created the human race as slaves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;ramayana&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ramayana&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#ramayana&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Hindu mythology, the gods and their avatars travel in flying vehicles called Vimana. The &lt;em&gt;Ramayana&lt;/em&gt; mentions these flying objects, used by the Lankan king Ravana from Sri Lanka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples from the &lt;em&gt;Ramayana&lt;/em&gt; include descriptions of the Pushpak chariot, a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
