<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paranormal on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/paranormal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paranormal on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 19:42:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/paranormal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kelly–Hopkinsville encounter</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_12e4ff60c21c/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 19:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_12e4ff60c21c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;kellyhopkinsville-encounter&#34;&gt;Kelly–Hopkinsville Encounter &lt;a href=&#34;#kellyhopkinsville-encounter&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kelly–Hopkinsville encounter, also known as the Hopkinsville Goblins Case or Kelly Green Men Case, is a claimed close encounter with extraterrestrial beings that allegedly occurred near Kelly and Hopkinsville in Christian County, Kentucky, on August 21–22, 1955. Ufologists consider it a significant and well-documented UFO incident, while skeptics attribute the reports to misidentification of natural phenomena and &amp;ldquo;the effects of excitement.&amp;rdquo; The United States Air Force&amp;rsquo;s Project Blue Book classified the encounter as a hoax. Psychologists use the incident as an example of pseudoscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;claims&#34;&gt;Claims &lt;a href=&#34;#claims&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the evening of August 21, 1955, several adults and children reported to the Hopkinsville police that their farmhouse was under attack by small alien creatures from a spaceship. Elmer Sutton and Billy Ray Taylor claimed to have shot at the creatures, which repeatedly appeared at the doorway and windows. The &lt;em&gt;Kentucky New Era&lt;/em&gt; reported the number of creatures as &amp;ldquo;12 to 15.&amp;rdquo; Police officers, state troopers, deputy sheriffs, and military police from Fort Campbell investigated the Sutton farmhouse near Kelly, Kentucky, but found no evidence except for broken windows and holes in screens. The residents, including Glennie Lankford and her family, left the house the next day, claiming the creatures had returned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;press-coverage&#34;&gt;Press Coverage &lt;a href=&#34;#press-coverage&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The family&amp;rsquo;s claims received widespread local and national press coverage. Early articles did not initially describe the creatures as &amp;ldquo;little green men,&amp;rdquo; but the color was later added. Descriptions of the creatures varied, but common details included their small size (2 to 4 feet), large pointed ears, claw-like hands, glowing yellow eyes, and spindly legs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;explanations&#34;&gt;Explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychologists Rodney Schmaltz and Scott Lilienfeld use the incident as an example of pseudoscience to teach critical thinking. They suggest intoxication may have played a role in the sighting. Skeptic Joe Nickell proposes that the family misidentified great horned owls, which are nocturnal, have yellow eyes, and can be aggressive. Nickell also notes that meteor sightings occurred around the same time, which could explain Billy Ray Taylor&amp;rsquo;s claim of seeing a bright light in the sky. Brian Dunning also supports the great horned owl theory, noting the similarities in size and behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufologists&#34;&gt;UFOlogists &lt;a href=&#34;#ufologists&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;French UFOlogist Renaud Leclet suggests that the residents likely saw great horned owls. Jerome Clark describes the creatures as &amp;ldquo;floating&amp;rdquo; and the sound of bullets hitting them as &amp;ldquo;resembling bullets striking a metal bucket.&amp;rdquo; Clark mentions a luminous patch and a green light, which could be explained by foxfire. He also claims that police, Air Force officers, and civilian ufologists found no evidence of a hoax, but Brian Dunning disputes the involvement of Air Force investigators. Allan Hendry notes the case&amp;rsquo;s duration and the number of witnesses. Project Blue Book classified the case as a hoax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In Popular Culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kelly–Hopkinsville encounter has inspired several works of fiction. Steven Spielberg used the event as the basis for his unproduced horror film &lt;em&gt;Night Skies&lt;/em&gt;. The 1986 film &lt;em&gt;Critters&lt;/em&gt; is loosely based on the encounter. The Pokémon Sableye is believed to be inspired by the alleged goblins. The &amp;ldquo;hobkins&amp;rdquo; gremlins in the &lt;em&gt;Pathfinder Roleplaying Game&lt;/em&gt; are based on the goblins. The Annoyance Theater in Chicago created a musical called &amp;ldquo;It Came From Kentucky&amp;rdquo; based on the event. A 2020 episode of the television series &lt;em&gt;Project Blue Book&lt;/em&gt; focused on the encounter. The community of Kelly celebrates the event annually with the Little Green Men Days Festival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kelly%E2%80%93Hopkinsville_encounter&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kelly%E2%80%93Hopkinsville_encounter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aliens Exist</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_d7b98f0a4c06/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_d7b98f0a4c06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;aliens-exist&#34;&gt;Aliens Exist &lt;a href=&#34;#aliens-exist&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aliens Exist&amp;rdquo; is a song by the American rock band Blink-182, featured on their 1999 album &lt;em&gt;Enema of the State&lt;/em&gt;. The song, primarily written by guitarist Tom DeLonge with additional credit to bassist Mark Hoppus, is a lighthearted take on the existence of extraterrestrial life. It references UFO phenomena, including alleged CIA involvement and the Majestic 12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blink-182, originating from suburban San Diego, gained prominence in the late 1990s with their pop-punk sound. The band members included guitarist Tom DeLonge, bassist Mark Hoppus, and drummer Travis Barker. DeLonge&amp;rsquo;s fascination with extraterrestrials began in middle school and continued as he toured, reading books about paranormal activity. Barker recalls DeLonge constantly searching for UFOs. DeLonge used his first personal computer to research alien phenomena. He amassed a collection of UFO books and military interviews about UFO experiences. Hoppus found DeLonge&amp;rsquo;s beliefs amusing. DeLonge and Hoppus often debated the song&amp;rsquo;s subject matter, leaving each other messages on their equipment. Barker, then a touring musician, arranged the song&amp;rsquo;s tempo and structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;composition&#34;&gt;Composition &lt;a href=&#34;#composition&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The song is written in common time with a tempo of 216 beats per minute, in the key of B major. The lyrics, written by DeLonge, express youthful curiosity about the universe and attempt to convince listeners of the legitimacy of his claims. The lyrics suggest the CIA is suppressing information and reference the Majestic 12, a supposed group of scientists studying alien spacecraft in the 1940s. DeLonge explained the song&amp;rsquo;s perspective as that of someone who believes in aliens but is dismissed by others, directing his frustration towards the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release-and-reception&#34;&gt;Release and Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#release-and-reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aliens Exist&amp;rdquo; was initially previewed as part of an online medley and officially released on &lt;em&gt;Enema of the State&lt;/em&gt; in June 1999. It received positive reviews, with some critics praising its departure from typical pop-punk themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;live-performances&#34;&gt;Live Performances &lt;a href=&#34;#live-performances&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although not released as a single, the band performed the song on &lt;em&gt;The Tonight Show with Jay Leno&lt;/em&gt; in 2000. It was a regular part of their tour and live album, &lt;em&gt;The Mark, Tom and Travis Show&lt;/em&gt;. The band retired the song in 2002 but revived it on their 2019 tour, with Matt Skiba filling in for DeLonge. DeLonge also performed the song with Angels &amp;amp; Airwaves in 2019. Following DeLonge&amp;rsquo;s return to Blink-182, the band continued to perform the song on their 2023 world tour, incorporating tabloid imagery of DeLonge&amp;rsquo;s interest in aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legacy&#34;&gt;Legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The song has been re-examined in light of DeLonge&amp;rsquo;s continued pursuit of UFO research. It is remembered as a standout track from &lt;em&gt;Enema of the State&lt;/em&gt; and is considered part of American pop culture&amp;rsquo;s fascination with aliens. Blink-182 embraced this image, using alien imagery on merchandise and at concerts. DeLonge continued to explore alien themes in his band Angels &amp;amp; Airwaves. Machine Gun Kelly&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Concert for Aliens&amp;rdquo; was seen as reminiscent of DeLonge&amp;rsquo;s earlier work. DeLonge co-founded To the Stars, a company focused on aerospace, science, and entertainment, with former government and intelligence officials. In 2017, the company released leaked military footage of unidentified aerial phenomena, later confirmed by the Pentagon, which legitimized DeLonge&amp;rsquo;s research. This led to the Pentagon formally establishing interest in studying UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;personnel&#34;&gt;Personnel &lt;a href=&#34;#personnel&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Locations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signature Sound, Studio West (San Diego, California)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mad Hatter Studios, The Bomb Factory (Los Angeles, California)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conway Recording Studios (Hollywood, California)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Big Fish Studios (Encinitas, California)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blink-182:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mark Hoppus – bass guitar, vocals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tom DeLonge – guitars, vocals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travis Barker – drums, percussion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Production:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jerry Finn – production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tom Lord-Alge – mixing engineer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sean O&amp;rsquo;Dwyer – recording engineer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Darrel Harvey – assistant engineer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John Nelson – assistant engineer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert Read – assistant engineer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mike Fasano – drum technician&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brian Gardner – mastering engineer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aliens_Exist&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aliens_Exist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
