<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brazil on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/brazil/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Brazil on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 10:39:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/brazil/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Varginha UFO incident</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_3cbfbc358e9c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_3cbfbc358e9c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;varginha-ufo-incident&#34;&gt;Varginha UFO Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#varginha-ufo-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Varginha UFO incident refers to a series of events in 1996 in Varginha, Brazil, where residents reported sightings of strange creatures and at least one unidentified flying object (UFO). These reports gained significant media attention. Claims associated with the incident include the alleged capture of extraterrestrial beings by Brazilian authorities, animal fatalities at a zoo, and a woman becoming pregnant by an extraterrestrial. The Brazilian Army investigated the incident and concluded that a city resident was mistaken for an alien creature and that military activity in the area was routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 20, 1996, three women reported seeing a creature with a large head, bipedal stance, &amp;ldquo;spots like veins&amp;rdquo; on its skin, bumps on its head, and red eyes. The creature, later called the &amp;ldquo;ET de Varginha,&amp;rdquo; appeared unsteady, leading the women to believe it was injured or sick. They fled and told their mother they had seen the &amp;ldquo;devil.&amp;rdquo; Rumors spread about UFO sightings in the days prior. Claims emerged of additional creatures being captured and observed at a hospital, military activity in the area, an unidentified animal in a local forest, the death of a police officer, and unexplained animal deaths at the local zoo. Ufologists linked these claims, including the allegation that one of the initial witnesses became pregnant by the creature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inquiry&#34;&gt;Inquiry &lt;a href=&#34;#inquiry&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An official inquiry by the Brazilian military in 2010 concluded that the women encountered a homeless, mentally unstable man nicknamed &amp;ldquo;Mudinho.&amp;rdquo; The Commander of the 24th Police Battalion Military presented photographs of Mudinho, whose physical characteristics matched the description of the creature. The inquiry suggested that Mudinho, being dirty and crouching by a wall due to heavy rains, was mistaken for a space creature. The head of the inquiry stated that military trucks and personnel were performing routine duties, such as firefighters responding to a call, Army trucks undergoing maintenance, and vehicles departing from the Escola de Sargentos das Armas (EsSA). Skeptic Brian Dunning criticized sensational media accounts and ufologists&amp;rsquo; claims, arguing that the incident was magnified into unassailable proof of alien visitation despite a lack of unusual events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tourism&#34;&gt;Tourism &lt;a href=&#34;#tourism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The claims surrounding the Varginha incident have significantly impacted tourism in the city. Grey alien dolls in football uniforms are sold at the incident&amp;rsquo;s location. Grey alien designs are used in advertising campaigns for the municipality. Bus stops were built in the form of spaceships, and a 20-meter tall water tower with a disc-shaped water reservoir, called the Nave Espacial de Varginha, was erected in the town center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;media&#34;&gt;Media &lt;a href=&#34;#media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several media productions have been inspired by the Varginha UFO incident:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;1996&lt;/em&gt;, a 2020 short film by Rodrigo Brandão, is a horror story in the style of &lt;em&gt;The Blair Witch Project&lt;/em&gt; about two teenagers who get lost in the woods near Varginha and encounter an extraterrestrial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Incidente em Varginha&lt;/em&gt; is a video game inspired by the events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moment of Contact&lt;/em&gt;, a 2022 documentary film by James Fox, investigates the incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;O.V.N.I L&amp;rsquo;affaire Varginha&lt;/em&gt;, a French comic book by Philippe Auger, tells the story of the incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article lists related topics, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFO sightings in Brazil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1986 Brazilian UFO incident&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operação Prato&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Varginha_UFO_incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Varginha_UFO_incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in Brazil</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8b49f5067f22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8b49f5067f22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-brazil&#34;&gt;List of Alleged UFO Sightings in Brazil &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-brazil&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article catalogs reported UFO sightings in Brazil, spanning from 1947 to 2020. It presents a chronological list of incidents, including eyewitness accounts, investigations, and related controversies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1947&#34;&gt;1947 &lt;a href=&#34;#1947&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details an alleged encounter in Bauru, São Paulo, where topographer José Higgins and his laborers witnessed a lens-shaped object landing. Higgins reported communication with humanoid figures who emerged from the craft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1952&#34;&gt;1952 &lt;a href=&#34;#1952&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on a reported sighting near Barra da Tijuca by journalist Joao Martins and photographer Eduardo Keffel, who claimed to have photographed a flying disk. The photos were published in &lt;em&gt;O Cruzeiro&lt;/em&gt; magazine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1957&#34;&gt;1957 &lt;a href=&#34;#1957&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers several notable events:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Ubatuba incident, involving fragments of pure magnesium purportedly from a UFO that exploded over Ubatuba beach. Journalist Ibrahim Sued received the fragments and a letter describing the event. Ufologist James Harder believed the fragments to be of extraterrestrial origin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Antonio Villas Boas&amp;rsquo;s alleged abduction by extraterrestrials, one of the first widely publicized alien abduction stories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An incident at Itaipu Fort in Praia Grande, São Paulo, where sentinels suffered burns from a heat wave emanating from a descending UFO. The fort&amp;rsquo;s electricity went out during the event. The Brazilian Army, the United States Air Force (USAF), and the Brazilian Air Force investigated. Donald Keyhoe of the USAF offered his opinions on the case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1958&#34;&gt;1958 &lt;a href=&#34;#1958&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes a sighting by the crew of the Brazilian ship &lt;em&gt;Almirante Saldanha&lt;/em&gt; near Ilha de Trindade. Captain Viegas and others witnessed a ringed flying object similar to Saturn. Almiro Baraúna reportedly photographed the object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1966&#34;&gt;1966 &lt;a href=&#34;#1966&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights the Lead Masks Case near Niterói, where two men were found dead wearing lead masks. A UFO was allegedly seen flying near the location of their deaths. It also mentions the creation of SIOANI (Serviço de Informação de Objetos Aéreos Não Identificados), an office created to investigate UFO sightings northwest of São Paulo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1977&#34;&gt;1977 &lt;a href=&#34;#1977&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the Colares UFO flap, a series of sightings on Colares Island where UFOs allegedly attacked citizens with radiation beams. This led to the Brazilian government&amp;rsquo;s Operation Saucer (Operação Prato), an investigation by the Brazilian Air Force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1979&#34;&gt;1979 &lt;a href=&#34;#1979&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the alleged abduction of Antonio Carlos Ferreira, a security guard in Mirassol, São Paulo. He claimed to have been taken aboard a spacecraft by humanoid figures, shown images, and forced to mate with a female alien.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1980&#34;&gt;1980 &lt;a href=&#34;#1980&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions the experience of Elias Seixas de Mattos, a truck driver from Rio de Janeiro, and his two friends, who reported an unexplainable encounter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1982&#34;&gt;1982 &lt;a href=&#34;#1982&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes a mass sighting during a 1982 Campeonato Brasileiro Série A match between Operário-MS and CR Vasco da Gama at the Morenão stadium. Over 24,000 spectators, including players and the referee José de Assis Aragão, reported seeing flying objects. Ademar José Gevaerd, a prominent Brazilian ufologist, was a witness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1986&#34;&gt;1986 &lt;a href=&#34;#1986&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the 1986 Brazilian UFO incident, a series of sightings across southeastern Brazil that led to jet fighters being scrambled. Pilots reported the UFOs&amp;rsquo; ability to make sharp turns and fly at hypersonic speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1995&#34;&gt;1995 &lt;a href=&#34;#1995&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes an incident on January 12, 1995, where a luminous object was seen falling onto a farm in Jaíba district, Feira de Santana, Bahia. A major power outage occurred in nearby cities shortly after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1996&#34;&gt;1996 &lt;a href=&#34;#1996&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details two incidents:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Varginha UFO incident, involving reports of UFOs and strange creatures (allegedly extraterrestrials) in Varginha, Brazil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Haroldo Westendorff&amp;rsquo;s sighting of a cone-shaped UFO at Patos Lagoon. He reported flying around the object and a smaller object emerging from it. The sighting was also detected by radar at Pelotas&amp;rsquo; airport.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2008&#34;&gt;2008 &lt;a href=&#34;#2008&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers two cases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Dossier Riolândia,&amp;rdquo; produced by Inape, which allegedly documents UFO sightings in Riolândia on January 20, 2008.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Claudio Case in Cláudio, Minas Gerais, where military police chased luminous humanoid creatures and photographed UFOs. The case report includes photographs and a police report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2013&#34;&gt;2013 &lt;a href=&#34;#2013&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions a light seen during the 2013 protests in Brazil. Initially reported as a UFO, it was later believed to be a drone used by &lt;em&gt;Folha de S. Paulo&lt;/em&gt; newspaper for aerial photography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2020&#34;&gt;2020 &lt;a href=&#34;#2020&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes sightings in Magé, Rio de Janeiro, where residents recorded videos of strange lights and objects in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Brazil&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Brazil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
