<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mantis Beings on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/mantis-beings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mantis Beings on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 06:34:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/mantis-beings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mantis Overlords  Ancient Aliens or Earth’s Hidden Rulers?</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_2bbf18bbf848/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 06:34:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_2bbf18bbf848/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;mantis-overlords-ancient-aliens-or-earths-hidden-rulers&#34;&gt;Mantis Overlords: Ancient Aliens or Earth’s Hidden Rulers? &lt;a href=&#34;#mantis-overlords-ancient-aliens-or-earths-hidden-rulers&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;encounters-along-the-musconetcong-river&#34;&gt;Encounters Along the Musconetcong River &lt;a href=&#34;#encounters-along-the-musconetcong-river&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on reported sightings of Mantis beings along the Musconetcong River in New Jersey, starting around 2006. Key elements include the consistency of witness accounts, describing tall, insectoid figures accompanied by electronic malfunctions and a silent forest. Paul Jax&amp;rsquo;s sighting, where he made eye contact with a seven-foot-tall Mantis being, is highlighted. Joe Pari&amp;rsquo;s experience details telepathic contact, memory extraction, and paralysis, suggesting a hierarchical extraterrestrial structure with the Mantis beings in a leadership role. The Musconetcong River area is presented as a hotspot for these encounters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;patterns-in-abduction-testimonies&#34;&gt;Patterns in Abduction Testimonies &lt;a href=&#34;#patterns-in-abduction-testimonies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the commonalities found in numerous alien abduction reports involving Mantis beings. It emphasizes the consistent descriptions of their physical appearance: triangular heads, large black eyes, and thin, insect-like bodies. The section also highlights the Mantis beings&amp;rsquo; commanding presence and their role as supervisors of smaller gray aliens during abduction procedures. The Terry Lovelace case from Devil’s Den State Park is mentioned as an example where gray aliens are seen working under the direction of Mantis beings. The Mantis beings are portrayed as cold, efficient, and in complete control, often communicating telepathically and overseeing medical procedures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ancient-evidence-in-stone&#34;&gt;Ancient Evidence in Stone &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-evidence-in-stone&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section delves into potential historical evidence suggesting the presence of Mantis-like figures in ancient art and mythology. It mentions a petroglyph in Tamura, Iran, depicting a humanoid figure with mantis-like features, dating back thousands of years. The rock art of the San people (Khoisan) in Africa, which includes mantis-headed figures often associated with creator gods, is also discussed. The section emphasizes the widespread nature of these depictions across different continents and cultures, from Mesopotamian and Egyptian texts to Native American legends, implying a long-standing global presence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-portal-in-new-jersey&#34;&gt;A Portal in New Jersey? &lt;a href=&#34;#a-portal-in-new-jersey&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the theory that certain geographic locations, like the Musconetcong River area, may act as interdimensional portals. It suggests that fault lines near the river could generate unusual electromagnetic fields, similar to NASA&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;X-points&amp;rdquo; or magnetic portals. The section proposes that these locations could serve as doorways for beings like the Mantis to enter our reality. Witnesses&amp;rsquo; descriptions of time distortions, electronic interference, and sensory overload during Mantis encounters are linked to the potential presence of these portals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-they-after&#34;&gt;What Are They After? &lt;a href=&#34;#what-are-they-after&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines the potential motives and purposes of the Mantis beings. It contrasts them with the typical image of curious extraterrestrial explorers, suggesting they have a specific agenda. Theories discussed include the possibility that they have guided human development from behind the scenes, influenced civilizations, or are conducting long-term genetic experiments. The idea of them harvesting knowledge and energy from humanity is also presented. The section emphasizes the consistent theme that the Mantis beings are not new to Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-overlords-among-us&#34;&gt;The Overlords Among Us? &lt;a href=&#34;#the-overlords-among-us&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section concludes by addressing the credibility of abduction accounts and the implications of the Mantis phenomenon. It mentions the work of paranormal researchers, including Harvard psychiatrist Dr. John Mack, who have documented abduction cases and found them difficult to dismiss as mere delusions. The section raises the question of the Mantis beings&amp;rsquo; true identity and purpose, suggesting they could be interdimensional travelers, ancient creators, or something else entirely. It emphasizes the chilling reality of the experience for those who have encountered them and suggests they have been present on Earth for millennia, hidden in shadows and recorded in ancient texts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latest-ufo-sightings.net/2025/05/mantis-overlords-ancient-aliens-or-earths-hidden-rulers.html&#34;&gt;https://www.latest-ufo-sightings.net/2025/05/mantis-overlords-ancient-aliens-or-earths-hidden-rulers.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
