<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Extraterrestrial Contact on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/extraterrestrial-contact/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Extraterrestrial Contact on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 02:45:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/extraterrestrial-contact/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contactee</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e161eb739be7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 02:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e161eb739be7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;contactee&#34;&gt;Contactee &lt;a href=&#34;#contactee&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A contactee is a person who claims to have experienced contact with extraterrestrial beings. Evidence for these claims is anecdotal. The phenomenon gained prominence in the 1950s and continues to this day. Contactees often share their experiences through books, articles, lectures, and conventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;paranormal-series&#34;&gt;Paranormal Series &lt;a href=&#34;#paranormal-series&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists various topics related to the paranormal, including astral projection, astrology, clairvoyance, cryptozoology, demonic possession, exorcism, fortune-telling, ghost hunting, magic, mediumship, miracles, the occult, psychic phenomena, reincarnation, spiritualism, telekinesis, ufology, and related skeptical viewpoints and parapsychological concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;verification-needed&#34;&gt;Verification Needed &lt;a href=&#34;#verification-needed&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a standard Wikipedia notice indicating that the article requires additional citations to reliable sources for verification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section defines contactees as individuals claiming communication with benign extraterrestrial beings, often receiving messages of cosmic importance. It notes the rise of contactees after the beginning of the modern UFO era in the late 1940s, their activities at UFO conventions, and the skeptical view of them as charlatans or deluded individuals. Susan Clancy is mentioned as attributing such claims to false memories. Common themes in contactee claims, as summarized by Curtis Peebles, include physical or mental contact with humanoid aliens, travel aboard alien spacecraft, aliens&amp;rsquo; desire to help humanity solve its problems, and the existence of sinister figures like the Men in Black who suppress the truth about UFOs. J. Allen Hynek is quoted defining contactees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section traces the history of contactee claims, starting with early examples like Emanuel Swedenborg in the 18th century, who claimed psychic contact with inhabitants of other planets. Thomas Blott&amp;rsquo;s 1891 book, &lt;em&gt;The Man From Mars&lt;/em&gt;, is mentioned as an early example of a contactee account. George Adamski, a prominent contactee of the 1950s, is noted for his earlier interest in the occult. Christopher Partridge is cited for observing that pre-1947 contactee claims did not involve UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-examples&#34;&gt;Early Examples &lt;a href=&#34;#early-examples&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection highlights Emanuel Swedenborg&amp;rsquo;s 1758 publication, &lt;em&gt;Concerning Earths in the Solar System&lt;/em&gt;, detailing his alleged journeys to inhabited planets. J. Gordon Melton&amp;rsquo;s observation that Swedenborg&amp;rsquo;s travels stopped at Saturn, the furthest known planet at the time, is included. Thomas Blott&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;em&gt;The Man From Mars&lt;/em&gt; is mentioned, noting the unusual detail of the Martian communicating in English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1900s&#34;&gt;1900s &lt;a href=&#34;#1900s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection focuses on George Adamski, noting his earlier involvement with the occult and the Royal Order of Tibet. Michael Barkun&amp;rsquo;s observation that Adamski&amp;rsquo;s later messages from Venusians resembled his earlier occult teachings is included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contactees-in-the-ufo-era&#34;&gt;Contactees in the UFO Era &lt;a href=&#34;#contactees-in-the-ufo-era&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses how contactees in the 1950s sometimes presented photographs as evidence, noting that George Adamski&amp;rsquo;s photos of a &amp;ldquo;Venusian scout ship&amp;rdquo; resembled a chicken egg incubator. George Van Tassel&amp;rsquo;s annual &amp;ldquo;Giant Rock Interplanetary Spacecraft Convention&amp;rdquo; in the Mojave Desert is also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;response-to-contactee-claims&#34;&gt;Response to Contactee Claims &lt;a href=&#34;#response-to-contactee-claims&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the general dismissal of contactees within ufology as either charlatans or the lunatic fringe. Jacques Vallée&amp;rsquo;s statement that serious investigators were never worried by contactee claims is included. Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s skepticism is presented, highlighting his anecdote about aliens being unable to answer specific, technical questions. David M. Jacobs&amp;rsquo; observation that contactee accounts grew more elaborate over time, with older contactees backdating their first encounters, is also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-contactees&#34;&gt;List of Contactees &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-contactees&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of prominent UFO contactees, including George Adamski, Wayne Sulo Aho, Orfeo Angelucci, Truman Bethurum, Daniel Fry, Gabriel Green, Steven M. Greer, Betty and Barney Hill, George King, Elizabeth Klarer, Aladino Félix (Dino Kraspedon), Gloria Lee, Nancy Lieder, Riley Martin, Billy Meier, Howard Menger, Buck Nelson, Ted Owens, Sixto Paz Wells, Reinhold O. Schmidt, Whitley Strieber, Sun Ra, George Van Tassel, Samuel Eaton Thompson, Claude Vorilhon, George Hunt Williamson, and Dwight York.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the references cited in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External Links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external websites offering additional information about 1950s contactees and their associated religious cults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufos-template&#34;&gt;UFOs Template &lt;a href=&#34;#ufos-template&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a navigation template for UFO-related topics, including claimed sightings, types of UFOs, types of alleged extraterrestrial beings, studies and timelines, hypotheses, conspiracy theories, involvement, culture, skepticism, and government responses. It lists various UFO sightings throughout history and across different countries, as well as confirmed hoaxes and notable figures and organizations in the field of ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contactees&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contactees&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact (1985 novel)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_aadcaf1f76f6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 04:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_aadcaf1f76f6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;contact-1985-novel&#34;&gt;Contact (1985 novel) &lt;a href=&#34;#contact-1985-novel&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article provides information about Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s 1985 science fiction novel, &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt;. It distinguishes the novel from other works with the same title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot centers around Eleanor &amp;ldquo;Ellie&amp;rdquo; Arroway, a scientist with a strong aptitude for science and mathematics. Her father&amp;rsquo;s death deeply affects her, and she finds herself at odds with her stepfather. Ellie pursues a career in radio astronomy, eventually directing Project Argus, a SETI initiative in New Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project detects a signal from Vega, which is analyzed and found to contain a retransmission of Hitler&amp;rsquo;s 1936 Olympic speech. Later, a third message reveals plans for an advanced machine. Ellie works with Ken der Heer and Vaygay Lunacharsky to decipher the message. Religious leaders Billy Jo Rankin and Palmer Joss also become involved. The final piece of the message is discovered with the help of S.R. Hadden, revealing the primer needed to build the machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A race to build the machine ensues between the U.S. and the Soviet Union. An extremist bombing delays the project. Ellie learns Hadden has secretly built a third machine in Hokkaido, Japan. Ellie, Vaygay, Devi Sukhavati, Abonnema Eda, and Xi Qiaomu travel through wormholes to a station near the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;s center. There, they meet extraterrestrials who explain their motives and a project to alter the universe&amp;rsquo;s properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon returning to Earth, the travelers find their journey seemingly took no time at all. Their video recordings are erased, and officials suspect a hoax. Ellie finds evidence of her journey in the digits of pi, confirming the reality of her experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication-history&#34;&gt;Publication history &lt;a href=&#34;#publication-history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a child, Sagan was inspired by science fiction and fantasy. He preferred realistic stories that helped readers understand real science and history. In 1978, Sagan predicted that science fiction would make young people interested in extraterrestrial contact. Simon &amp;amp; Schuster gave Sagan a $2 million advance on the novel in 1981. Kip Thorne provided Sagan with ideas on wormholes. Eleanor Arroway was named after Eleanor Roosevelt and Voltaire. The character is based on Jill Tarter. The novel won the Locus Award for Best First Novel in 1986.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to related topics, including communication with extraterrestrial intelligence, the Fermi paradox, and &lt;em&gt;His Master&amp;rsquo;s Voice&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes &lt;a href=&#34;#notes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section clarifies two points related to the plot. The first note explains why a sequence of prime numbers is a predicted first message from alien intelligence. The second note updates the distance to Vega based on measurements from the Hipparcos satellite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including books and articles by Carl Sagan, Keay Davidson, and Jennifer Spence. It also includes links to online resources, such as Warner Bros.&amp;rsquo; website and Space.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources &lt;a href=&#34;#sources&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of sources used in the creation of the article, including books by Keay Davidson and Carl Sagan, as well as an archived webpage by Jennifer Spence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to Larry Klaes&amp;rsquo; in-depth analysis of the film and novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;carl-sagan-template&#34;&gt;Carl Sagan Template &lt;a href=&#34;#carl-sagan-template&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This template provides links to various aspects of Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s life and work, including his scientific career, books, media appearances, family, prizes, and related topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;locus-award-template&#34;&gt;Locus Award Template &lt;a href=&#34;#locus-award-template&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This template provides links to the winners of the Locus Award for Best First Novel from 1980 to 2024, as well as links to other Locus Awards categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;authority-control-databases&#34;&gt;Authority control databases &lt;a href=&#34;#authority-control-databases&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists links to various authority control databases, including VIAF, United States Library of Congress, Israel National Library, and MusicBrainz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contact_(novel)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contact_(novel)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
