<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Extraterrestrial Contact on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/extraterrestrial-contact/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Extraterrestrial Contact on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 04:33:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/extraterrestrial-contact/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contact (1985 novel)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_aadcaf1f76f6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 04:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_aadcaf1f76f6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;contact-1985-novel&#34;&gt;Contact (1985 novel) &lt;a href=&#34;#contact-1985-novel&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article provides information about Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s 1985 science fiction novel, &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt;. It distinguishes the novel from other works with the same title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot centers around Eleanor &amp;ldquo;Ellie&amp;rdquo; Arroway, a scientist with a strong aptitude for science and mathematics. Her father&amp;rsquo;s death deeply affects her, and she finds herself at odds with her stepfather. Ellie pursues a career in radio astronomy, eventually directing Project Argus, a SETI initiative in New Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project detects a signal from Vega, which is analyzed and found to contain a retransmission of Hitler&amp;rsquo;s 1936 Olympic speech. Later, a third message reveals plans for an advanced machine. Ellie works with Ken der Heer and Vaygay Lunacharsky to decipher the message. Religious leaders Billy Jo Rankin and Palmer Joss also become involved. The final piece of the message is discovered with the help of S.R. Hadden, revealing the primer needed to build the machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A race to build the machine ensues between the U.S. and the Soviet Union. An extremist bombing delays the project. Ellie learns Hadden has secretly built a third machine in Hokkaido, Japan. Ellie, Vaygay, Devi Sukhavati, Abonnema Eda, and Xi Qiaomu travel through wormholes to a station near the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;s center. There, they meet extraterrestrials who explain their motives and a project to alter the universe&amp;rsquo;s properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon returning to Earth, the travelers find their journey seemingly took no time at all. Their video recordings are erased, and officials suspect a hoax. Ellie finds evidence of her journey in the digits of pi, confirming the reality of her experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication-history&#34;&gt;Publication history &lt;a href=&#34;#publication-history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a child, Sagan was inspired by science fiction and fantasy. He preferred realistic stories that helped readers understand real science and history. In 1978, Sagan predicted that science fiction would make young people interested in extraterrestrial contact. Simon &amp;amp; Schuster gave Sagan a $2 million advance on the novel in 1981. Kip Thorne provided Sagan with ideas on wormholes. Eleanor Arroway was named after Eleanor Roosevelt and Voltaire. The character is based on Jill Tarter. The novel won the Locus Award for Best First Novel in 1986.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to related topics, including communication with extraterrestrial intelligence, the Fermi paradox, and &lt;em&gt;His Master&amp;rsquo;s Voice&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes &lt;a href=&#34;#notes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section clarifies two points related to the plot. The first note explains why a sequence of prime numbers is a predicted first message from alien intelligence. The second note updates the distance to Vega based on measurements from the Hipparcos satellite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including books and articles by Carl Sagan, Keay Davidson, and Jennifer Spence. It also includes links to online resources, such as Warner Bros.&amp;rsquo; website and Space.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources &lt;a href=&#34;#sources&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of sources used in the creation of the article, including books by Keay Davidson and Carl Sagan, as well as an archived webpage by Jennifer Spence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to Larry Klaes&amp;rsquo; in-depth analysis of the film and novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;carl-sagan-template&#34;&gt;Carl Sagan Template &lt;a href=&#34;#carl-sagan-template&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This template provides links to various aspects of Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s life and work, including his scientific career, books, media appearances, family, prizes, and related topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;locus-award-template&#34;&gt;Locus Award Template &lt;a href=&#34;#locus-award-template&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This template provides links to the winners of the Locus Award for Best First Novel from 1980 to 2024, as well as links to other Locus Awards categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;authority-control-databases&#34;&gt;Authority control databases &lt;a href=&#34;#authority-control-databases&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists links to various authority control databases, including VIAF, United States Library of Congress, Israel National Library, and MusicBrainz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contact_(novel)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contact_(novel)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
