<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Animation on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/animation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Animation on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 18:46:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/animation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Futurama</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_1c6176f68ef4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 18:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_1c6176f68ef4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;futurama&#34;&gt;Futurama &lt;a href=&#34;#futurama&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 1999 American animated science fiction sitcom created by Matt Groening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;genre&#34;&gt;Genre &lt;a href=&#34;#genre&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Animated sitcom, science fiction, and satire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;created-by&#34;&gt;Created by &lt;a href=&#34;#created-by&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt Groening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;developed-by&#34;&gt;Developed by &lt;a href=&#34;#developed-by&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt Groening and David X. Cohen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;voices-of&#34;&gt;Voices of &lt;a href=&#34;#voices-of&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Billy West, Katey Sagal, John DiMaggio, Tress MacNeille, Maurice LaMarche, Phil LaMarr, Lauren Tom, and David Herman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;opening-theme&#34;&gt;Opening theme &lt;a href=&#34;#opening-theme&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Theme from &lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; composed by Christopher Tyng.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;country-of-origin&#34;&gt;Country of origin &lt;a href=&#34;#country-of-origin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;original-language&#34;&gt;Original language &lt;a href=&#34;#original-language&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;number-of-seasons&#34;&gt;Number of seasons &lt;a href=&#34;#number-of-seasons&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;number-of-episodes&#34;&gt;Number of episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#number-of-episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;160&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-producers&#34;&gt;Executive producers &lt;a href=&#34;#executive-producers&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt Groening, David X. Cohen, Ken Keeler, and Claudia Katz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;producers&#34;&gt;Producers &lt;a href=&#34;#producers&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lew Morton, J. Stewart Burns, Patric M. Verrone, Bill Odenkirk, Eric Kaplan, Michael Rowe, Brian J. Cowan, Jason Grode, Jane O&amp;rsquo;Brien, and Lee Supercinski.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;editors&#34;&gt;Editors &lt;a href=&#34;#editors&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul D. Calder, Danik Thomas, and Chris Vallance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production-companies&#34;&gt;Production companies &lt;a href=&#34;#production-companies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Curiosity Company, 20th Century Fox Television (seasons 1–7), and 20th Television Animation (season 8–present).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;original-release&#34;&gt;Original release &lt;a href=&#34;#original-release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fox:&lt;/strong&gt; March 28, 1999 – August 10, 2003&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comedy Central:&lt;/strong&gt; March 23, 2008 – September 4, 2013&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hulu:&lt;/strong&gt; July 24, 2023 – present&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;premise&#34;&gt;Premise &lt;a href=&#34;#premise&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series follows Philip J. Fry, a pizza delivery boy who is cryogenically preserved for 1,000 years and revived on December 31, 2999. Fry finds work at the interplanetary delivery company Planet Express, working alongside the one-eyed mutant Leela and the robot Bender. Groening envisioned the series in the mid-1990s while working on &lt;em&gt;The Simpsons&lt;/em&gt;, and brought David X. Cohen aboard to develop storylines and characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;characters&#34;&gt;Characters &lt;a href=&#34;#characters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot revolves around the Planet Express interplanetary delivery company and its employees. Episodes usually feature the central trio of Fry, Leela, and Bender, though occasional storylines center on the other main characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Philip J. Fry:&lt;/strong&gt; Voiced by Billy West, Fry is an immature, slovenly, yet good-hearted pizza delivery boy who is cryogenically frozen for 1,000 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turanga Leela:&lt;/strong&gt; Voiced by Katey Sagal, Leela is the competent, one-eyed captain of the Planet Express Ship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bender Bending Rodriguez:&lt;/strong&gt; Voiced by John DiMaggio, Bender is a foul-mouthed, heavy-drinking, cigar-smoking, kleptomaniacal, misanthropic, egocentric, ill-tempered robot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Professor Hubert J. Farnsworth:&lt;/strong&gt; Voiced by Billy West, Professor Farnsworth is Fry&amp;rsquo;s distant nephew and the founder of Planet Express Inc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hermes Conrad:&lt;/strong&gt; Voiced by Phil LaMarr, Hermes is the Jamaican accountant of Planet Express.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. John A. Zoidberg:&lt;/strong&gt; Voiced by Billy West, Zoidberg is a Decapodian and the neurotic staff physician of Planet Express.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amy Wong:&lt;/strong&gt; Voiced by Lauren Tom, Amy is an incredibly rich, blunt, ditzy, and accident-prone intern at Planet Express.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting&#34;&gt;Setting &lt;a href=&#34;#setting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt; is set in New New York at the turn of the 31st century. The city of New New York has been built over the ruins of present-day New York City, which has become a catacomb-like space that acts as New New York&amp;rsquo;s sewer, referred to as &amp;ldquo;Old New York&amp;rdquo;. Parts of the sewers are inhabited by mutants. Various devices and architecture are similar to the Populuxe style. Global warming, inflexible bureaucracy, and substance abuse are a few of the subjects given a 31st-century exaggeration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list of episodes follows the season box sets, which feature the episodes in the original production season order, ignoring the order of broadcast. The Hulu revival has alternatively been titled the eighth and ninth seasons (production), and the eleventh and twelfth seasons (broadcast). The tenth and eleventh production seasons will also be considered as &lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s thirteenth and fourteenth broadcast seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Season&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Episodes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Originally released&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Network&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;March 28, 1999 – November 14, 1999&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fox&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;19&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;November 21, 1999 – December 3, 2000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fox&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;22&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;January 21, 2001 – December 8, 2002&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fox&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;February 10, 2002 – August 10, 2003&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fox&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;March 23, 2008 – August 30, 2009&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Comedy Central&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;26&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;June 24, 2010 – September 8, 2011&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Comedy Central&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;26&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;June 20, 2012 – September 4, 2013&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Comedy Central&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;July 24, 2023 – September 25, 2023&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hulu&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;July 29, 2024 – September 30, 2024&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hulu&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;development&#34;&gt;Development &lt;a href=&#34;#development&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fox expressed a strong desire in the mid-1990s for Matt Groening to create a new series after the success of &lt;em&gt;The Simpsons&lt;/em&gt;. In 1995, he enlisted David X. Cohen to assist in developing the show. When they pitched the series to Fox in April 1998, Groening and Cohen had composed many characters and story lines. Fox ordered thirteen episodes. Fox feared the themes of the show were not suitable for the network and Groening and Fox executives argued over whether the network would have any creative input into the show. The episode &amp;ldquo;I, Roommate&amp;rdquo; was produced to address Fox&amp;rsquo;s concerns. The name &lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt; comes from a pavilion at the 1939 New York World&amp;rsquo;s Fair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;writing&#34;&gt;Writing &lt;a href=&#34;#writing&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The planning for each episode began with a table meeting of writers, who discussed the plot ideas as a group. A single staff writer wrote an outline and then produced a script. Once the first draft of a script was finished, the writers and executive producers called in the actors for a table read. After this script reading, the writers collaborated to rewrite the script as a group before sending it to the animation team. The writing staff held three Ph.D.s, seven master&amp;rsquo;s degrees, and cumulatively had more than 50 years at Harvard University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;voice-actors&#34;&gt;Voice actors &lt;a href=&#34;#voice-actors&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt; had eight main cast members. Billy West performed the voices of Philip J. Fry, Professor Farnsworth, Doctor Zoidberg, Zapp Brannigan, and many other incidental characters. Katey Sagal voiced Leela, and is the only member of the main cast to voice only one character. John DiMaggio performed the voice of the robot Bender Bending Rodríguez and other, more minor, characters. Phil LaMarr voices Hermes Conrad, his son Dwight, Ethan Bubblegum Tate, and Reverend Preacherbot. Lauren Tom voices Amy Wong, and Tress MacNeille voices Mom and various other characters. Maurice LaMarche voices Kif Kroker and several supporting characters. David Herman voiced Scruffy and various supporting characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;animation&#34;&gt;Animation &lt;a href=&#34;#animation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt; is produced by The Curiosity Company and 20th Television Animation with the animation being done by Rough Draft Studios. In addition to traditional cartoon drawing, Rough Draft Studios often used CGI for fast or complex shots. The series began high-definition production in season 6, with &lt;em&gt;Bender&amp;rsquo;s Big Score&lt;/em&gt;. For the final episode of season 6, &lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt; was completely reanimated in three different styles: Fleischer- and Walter Lantz-style animation, a low-resolution video game, and Japanese anime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hallmarks&#34;&gt;Hallmarks &lt;a href=&#34;#hallmarks&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;opening-sequence&#34;&gt;Opening sequence &lt;a href=&#34;#opening-sequence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Planet Express Ship&lt;/em&gt; flies across the screen with the title of the show being spelled out in its wake. Underneath the title is a joke caption. After flying through downtown New New York and past various recurring characters, the Planet Express ship crashes through a large screen showing a short clip from a classic cartoon. The &lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt; theme was created by Christopher Tyng.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;languages&#34;&gt;Languages &lt;a href=&#34;#languages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three alternative alphabets that appear often in the background of episodes. The first alphabet consists of abstract characters and is referred to as Alienese, a simple substitution cipher from the Latin alphabet. The second alphabet uses a more complex modular addition code. The third language sometimes used is Hebrew. The show predicts that several English expressions will have evolved by the year 3000&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alienese&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alienese&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
