<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Entertainment on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/entertainment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Entertainment on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/entertainment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Roswell That Ends Well</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_0abf491c999f/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 16:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_0abf491c999f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;roswell-that-ends-well&#34;&gt;Roswell That Ends Well &lt;a href=&#34;#roswell-that-ends-well&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Roswell That Ends Well&amp;rdquo; is the 19th episode of the third season of the animated television series &lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt;. It originally aired on December 9, 2001.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Planet Express crew, while observing a supernova, accidentally time travel to 1947 after Fry microwaves a metal pan of popcorn. They crash-land in Roswell, New Mexico, becoming part of the Roswell Incident. Bender is shattered upon impact. The crew searches for a way back to the 31st century. Zoidberg is captured by the U.S. military and experimented on at Roswell Air Base. The military reconstructs Bender&amp;rsquo;s body into a flying saucer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crew needs a microwave oven to return to their time. Professor Farnsworth warns Fry against interacting with his grandfather, Enos, to avoid a grandfather paradox. Fry tries to protect Enos, but Enos dies in a nuclear weapon test. Fry sleeps with Mildred, Enos&amp;rsquo;s fiancée, and realizes she is his grandmother, making him his own grandfather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crew storms Roswell Air Base to steal a microwave dish. Fry and Leela rescue Zoidberg from an alien autopsy. Farnsworth retrieves Bender&amp;rsquo;s body. While time jumping, Bender&amp;rsquo;s head is left behind. Back in the 31st century, the crew returns to Roswell, finds Bender&amp;rsquo;s head, and reattaches it to his body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writing team developed the episode from ideas initially considered for &amp;ldquo;Anthology of Interest II.&amp;rdquo; The writers initially avoided time travel in &lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt;, but changed their minds. They made the time travel unintentional, triggered by a supernova, to avoid regular time travel. The episode was directed by Rich Moore, who used screen position and character movement to represent time travel. Actions to the left represented the past, while actions to the right indicated progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultural-references&#34;&gt;Cultural references &lt;a href=&#34;#cultural-references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The episode references time travel stories like &lt;em&gt;Back to the Future&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Terminator&lt;/em&gt;. It also shares similarities with the &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: Deep Space Nine&lt;/em&gt; episode &amp;ldquo;Little Green Men.&amp;rdquo; Bender&amp;rsquo;s head buried in the sand is similar to Data&amp;rsquo;s head in &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: The Next Generation&lt;/em&gt;. Enos&amp;rsquo;s character is based on Gomer Pyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;broadcast-and-reception&#34;&gt;Broadcast and reception &lt;a href=&#34;#broadcast-and-reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Roswell That Ends Well&amp;rdquo; won an Emmy Award for Outstanding Animated Program (Programming Less Than One Hour) in 2002. Rich Moore won an Annie Award for directing. IGN ranked it as one of the best &lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt; episodes. David X. Cohen considered it one of his favorite episodes. &lt;em&gt;Sci Fi Weekly&lt;/em&gt; gave it an &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; grade. Despite critical acclaim, the episode had low ratings during its original airing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell_That_Ends_Well&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell_That_Ends_Well&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien TV (2019 TV series)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f9ec66618d5e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f9ec66618d5e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-tv-2019-tv-series&#34;&gt;Alien TV (2019 TV series) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-tv-2019-tv-series&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien TV&lt;/em&gt; is a live-action/CG animation television series that premiered on 9Go! in Australia on November 23, 2019, and on Netflix. The show was created by Ian Brown and developed by Doug Hadders and Adam Rotstein. The series follows a television news crew of extraterrestrials named Ixbee, Pixbee, and Squee, who are sent to Earth to learn about the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main voice cast includes Rob Tinkler as Ixbee, Julie Lemieux as Pixbee, John Cleland as Squee, Kyle Dooley as Squood, and Rupert Degas as the Translator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series consists of two seasons. Season 1 was released on August 21, 2020, and Season 2 was released on March 19, 2021. There are no plans for a season 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;series-overview&#34;&gt;Series Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#series-overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series is divided into two seasons, with 13 episodes each. Season 1 was released in 2020, and Season 2 in 2021. Each episode contains three segments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-1-2020&#34;&gt;Season 1 (2020) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-1-2020&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season 1 consists of 13 episodes, each containing three segments. Each segment focuses on the aliens&amp;rsquo; experiences with different aspects of Earth culture and activities, such as bicycles, gymnastics, camping, playgrounds, art, gum, gyms, birthdays, restaurants, BBQs, offices, Halloween, pizza, magic, cleaning, arcades, dumplings, presents, junkyards, spas, love, movies, kindergarten, sickness, babies, supermarkets, tea, weddings, Loch Ness, soccer, skateboards, mannequins, survival, toyshops, laundromats, yoga, Santa, trophies, and makeup. Each segment is directed by Ian Brown and written by various writers, including Doug Hadders, Adam Rotstein, Jeff Sager, Brian Hartigan, Shawn Kalb, Cleon Prineas, Laurie Elliott, Bruce Griffiths, Simon Dodd, Jennifer Daley, Thomas Duncan-Watt and Naomi Jardine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-2-2021&#34;&gt;Season 2 (2021) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-2-2021&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season 2 also consists of 13 episodes, each containing three segments. The segments continue to explore the aliens&amp;rsquo; interactions with Earth, featuring topics such as trains, barbershops, gnomes, florists, fashion, teeth, pools, dinner parties, skiing, joke shops, the Outback, fire halls, baby showers, yard sales, aquariums, dance, international games, shopping, school, holidays, lucha libre, cars, sleep, golf, airplanes, water parks, mail, music, bowling, gardening, museums, Bollywood, castles, ballet, energy, leprechauns, glasses, trials, and scary things. Ian Brown directs all segments, and the writing credits include Naomi Jardine, Jerome Simpson, Bruce Griffiths, Jennifer Daley, Jeff Sager, Kyle Dooley, Simon Dodd, Cleon Prineas, Brian Hartigan, and Gina Roncoli Bruce Griffiths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_TV&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_TV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
