<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Art on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Art on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 04:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Barlowe&#39;s Guide to Extraterrestrials</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_1aa9be759342/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 04:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_1aa9be759342/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;barlowes-guide-to-extraterrestrials&#34;&gt;Barlowe&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Extraterrestrials &lt;a href=&#34;#barlowes-guide-to-extraterrestrials&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Barlowe&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Extraterrestrials&lt;/em&gt; is a science fiction book published in 1979, with a second edition in 1987. The book is authored by artist Wayne Barlowe, with text contributions from Ian Summers and Beth Meacham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary &lt;a href=&#34;#summary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a listing of the extraterrestrial species featured in the book. Each entry includes the alien&amp;rsquo;s name, the author who created it, and the specific work of science fiction in which the alien appears. Some of the notable aliens included are the Abyormenite from Hal Clement&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Cycle of Fire&lt;/em&gt;, the Athshean from Ursula K. Le Guin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Word for World Is Forest&lt;/em&gt;, the Black Cloud from Fred Hoyle&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Black Cloud&lt;/em&gt;, and the Guild Steersman from Frank Herbert&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Dune Messiah&lt;/em&gt;. The list continues with numerous other aliens from a wide range of science fiction novels and stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the critical reception of &lt;em&gt;Barlowe&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Extraterrestrials&lt;/em&gt;. Wendy Bousfield in &lt;em&gt;Library Journal&lt;/em&gt; offered a mixed review, praising the colorful drawings but finding them somewhat static and artificial. She also noted the omission of publication details for the novels from which the aliens were drawn. Claudia J. Morner in &lt;em&gt;School Library Journal&lt;/em&gt; gave a positive review, highlighting the colorful drawings and the fold-out size chart. The book was nominated for an American Book Award and the Hugo Award for Best Related Work in 1980.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited within the article. These include the book itself, reviews from &lt;em&gt;Library Journal&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;School Library Journal&lt;/em&gt;, and links to the Hugo Awards website and a &lt;em&gt;Kirkus Reviews&lt;/em&gt; article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external resources related to &lt;em&gt;Barlowe&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Extraterrestrials&lt;/em&gt;, including its listing on the Internet Speculative Fiction Database and its entry in Open Library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barlowe%27s_Guide_to_Extraterrestrials&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barlowe%27s_Guide_to_Extraterrestrials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
