<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Norway on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/norway/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Norway on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 18:11:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/norway/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in Norway</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_426ec68be70d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 18:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_426ec68be70d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-sightings-in-norway&#34;&gt;UFO Sightings in Norway &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-sightings-in-norway&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article documents reported UFO sightings in Norway, spanning from 1986 to 2009. Each sighting includes a brief description, location, and any explanations or analyses provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1986&#34;&gt;1986 &lt;a href=&#34;#1986&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details a sighting that occurred on July 13, 1986, near Torpo. Married couples Tova and Tonning observed two bright objects in the sky, and Mr. Tonning filmed the event. The film was analyzed by Ground Saucer Watch (GSW), which found no evidence of a hoax but couldn&amp;rsquo;t definitively identify the objects due to a lack of reference points. Other experts suggested the objects were Jupiter and Arcturus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2006&#34;&gt;2006 &lt;a href=&#34;#2006&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section recounts a widespread sighting on August 21, 2006, where a bright, green orb was seen across northern Norway, from Finnsnes in Troms to Bodø in Nordland. Witnesses described the object as moving at great speed and being larger than an aircraft. Initially considered a possible UFO, the phenomenon was later attributed to a bolide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2009&#34;&gt;2009 &lt;a href=&#34;#2009&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the 2009 Norwegian spiral anomaly, which occurred on December 9, 2009. A bluish spiraling light was observed, filmed, and photographed over Norway. While the exact cause remains uncertain, Norwegian news sources attributed the event to a failed Russian missile launch. A link to the main article on the anomaly is provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the general &amp;ldquo;List of reported UFO sightings&amp;rdquo; page on Wikipedia, allowing readers to explore UFO sightings in other locations and contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nordic UFO Newsletter-N. 1 -1988&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Norway in UFO Photographs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Strange &amp;lsquo;Norway spiral&amp;rsquo; was an out-of-control missile&amp;rdquo; (New Scientist)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to MUFON&amp;rsquo;s (Mutual UFO Network) website, specifically to their page displaying the last 20 UFO sightings and pictures reported to the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Norway&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Norway&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
