<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 23:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>NASA Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena Independent Study Team</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_47d13a747092/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 23:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_47d13a747092/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;nasa-unidentified-anomalous-phenomena-independent-study-team&#34;&gt;NASA Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena Independent Study Team &lt;a href=&#34;#nasa-unidentified-anomalous-phenomena-independent-study-team&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NASA Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena Independent Study Team (UAPIST) was a group of experts assembled by NASA to create a plan for analyzing unidentified anomalous phenomena (UAPs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;David Spergel, chair of NASA&amp;rsquo;s independent study on UAPs, answers a question during a public meeting of the team on May 31, 2023.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Agency overview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Formed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 24, 2022 (2022-05-24)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dissolved&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;September 14, 2023 (2023-09-14)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Agency executives&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;* David Spergel, chair * Daniel Evans, designated federal official&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Parent agency&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NASA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Website&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Official website&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scope-and-objectives&#34;&gt;Scope and objectives &lt;a href=&#34;#scope-and-objectives&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UAPIST was officially created by Karen St. Germain, the director of NASA&amp;rsquo;s Earth Science Division, as a subcommittee of the Earth Science Advisory Committee (ESAC) on May 24, 2022. NASA appointed astrophysicist David Spergel as the chair of the team, and Daniel Evans as the official responsible for the study. The team&amp;rsquo;s goal was to gather data from various sources (civilians, government, non-profits, companies) to analyze UAPs. NASA emphasized openness and transparency, stating that findings would be shared publicly. The study was separate from the Department of Defense&amp;rsquo;s UAP efforts, although NASA coordinated with the government. In July 2022, the Department of Defense replaced the Airborne Object Identification and Management Synchronization Group with the All-domain Anomaly Resolution Office (AARO). Further terms of reference were signed on May 18, 2023, extending the UAPIST and renaming it by changing &amp;ldquo;Aerial&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Anomalous&amp;rdquo;. Sean Kirkpatrick, director of the Defense Department&amp;rsquo;s AARO, spoke at the first public meeting on May 31, 2023, emphasizing the complementary nature of NASA and AARO&amp;rsquo;s efforts. NASA focused on unclassified data, while AARO included classified material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;uap-versus-ufo-terminology&#34;&gt;UAP versus UFO terminology &lt;a href=&#34;#uap-versus-ufo-terminology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term UAP emerged in the late 1960s, while &amp;ldquo;unidentified flying object&amp;rdquo; (UFO) dates back to 1947. UAP avoids the cultural associations with extraterrestrial life linked to UFOs. UFO has become associated with aliens, conspiracy theories, and religious movements. NASA updated the name of its independent study team at the start of 2023 from &amp;ldquo;unidentified aerial phenomena&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;unidentified anomalous phenomena&amp;rdquo; to be consistent with the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;team-members&#34;&gt;Team members &lt;a href=&#34;#team-members&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA announced the UAP study team members on October 21, 2022. The team included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Spergel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anamaria Berea (George Mason University)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Federica Bianco (University of Delaware)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paula Bontempi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reggie Brothers (AE Industrial Partners)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jen Buss (Potomac Institute for Policy Studies)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nadia Drake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mike Gold (Redwire)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Grinspoon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scott Kelly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matt Mountain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Warren Randolph (FAA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walter Scott (Maxar Technologies)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joshua Semeter (Boston University)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Karlin Toner (FAA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shelley Wright (University of California, San Diego)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg Eghigian noted that the NASA study team represents a significant shift, with many academics now supporting scholarly research into UFOs. He highlighted that NASA&amp;rsquo;s involvement and the scientifically informed questions being asked are unprecedented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;team-member-commentary&#34;&gt;Team member commentary &lt;a href=&#34;#team-member-commentary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the first public meeting on May 31, 2023, the NASA team addressed questions about UFOs. They emphasized collecting empirical data and improving UAP analysis. Spergel noted that many UAP events could be attributed to commercial aircraft, drones, balloons, weather, and ionospheric phenomena, but some events remain unexplained due to poor data quality. He cited fast radio bursts as an example of how anomalies can lead to novel physical phenomena. Regarding David Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims of a government coverup, Joshua Semeter stated that the NASA team is collaborating with the Defense Department&amp;rsquo;s AARO to determine the origin and nature of UAPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-report&#34;&gt;Final report &lt;a href=&#34;#final-report&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The independent study team&amp;rsquo;s final report was published on September 14, 2023, along with the announcement of a director of UAP research at NASA. The report found no evidence of extraterrestrial life. The report stated that the lack of reproducible data makes it difficult to draw conclusions about some UAP origins. It recommended a rigorous, evidence-based approach to studying UAPs, including data collection methods using artificial intelligence and citizen observers. NASA was deemed well-positioned to lead this study. According to its 2023 terms of reference, the team was dissolved upon the completion and submission of its final report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NASA%27s_UAP_independent_study_team&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NASA%27s_UAP_independent_study_team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA Director of UAP Research</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a1b07ce337c7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 22:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a1b07ce337c7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;director-of-unidentified-anomalous-phenomena-research&#34;&gt;Director of Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena Research &lt;a href=&#34;#director-of-unidentified-anomalous-phenomena-research&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article provides information about the Director of Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena Research at NASA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the origins of the Director position. Key points include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The position was announced on September 14, 2023, by NASA Administrator Bill Nelson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was created based on the recommendation of NASA&amp;rsquo;s UAP independent study team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initially, the identity of the director was to be kept secret to prevent harassment, but Mark McInerney was revealed as the director shortly after the announcement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The need for UAP research stems from national security concerns, the Space Race, and growing international interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists related articles on Wikipedia:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All-domain Anomaly Resolution Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NASA&amp;rsquo;s UAP independent study team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFO Report (U.S. Intelligence)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of citations used in the article, including links to news articles and government documents. Some of the sources include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yahoo! News&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The New York Times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;U.S. Congress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Council on Foreign Relations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;U.S. News &amp;amp; World Report&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Baltic Times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NASA_Director_of_UAP_Research&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NASA_Director_of_UAP_Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
