<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alleged Extraterrestrial Beings on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/alleged-extraterrestrial-beings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alleged Extraterrestrial Beings on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 22:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/alleged-extraterrestrial-beings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nordic aliens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_7c6654f96aa5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 22:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_7c6654f96aa5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alleged-humanoid-extraterrestrials&#34;&gt;Alleged humanoid extraterrestrials &lt;a href=&#34;#alleged-humanoid-extraterrestrials&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This entry focuses on &amp;ldquo;Nordics,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Nordic aliens,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Tall Whites,&amp;rdquo; which are names given in ufology to alleged humanoid extraterrestrial races. These beings are said to originate from the Pleiades star cluster and are called Pleiadians. They are described as resembling Nordic, Germanic, or Scandinavian humans, being taller than average (6-7 ft), with blond hair, blue eyes, and fair skin. Some reports mention pale-blue/grey or pastel purple skin tones. George Adamski, a Polish-American ufologist, was among the first to report contact with these beings in the 1950s. The mythology surrounding these aliens often includes telepathy, benevolence, and physical beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section explores the historical context of Nordic alien stories. Cultural historian David J. Skal suggests that the 1951 film &lt;em&gt;The Day the Earth Stood Still&lt;/em&gt; may have inspired early stories. Bates College professor Stephanie Kelley-Romano describes alien abduction beliefs as a &amp;ldquo;living myth,&amp;rdquo; noting that Nordic aliens are often associated with spiritual growth and act as protectors. They are often portrayed as benevolent beings concerned about Earth&amp;rsquo;s ecology and world peace, possessing telepathic powers and described as paternal, watchful, smiling, affectionate, and youthful. While popular in the 1950s, claims of encounters with Nordic aliens became less common as the grey alien became more prevalent in extraterrestrial encounter accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publications-by-those-claiming-to-have-been-contacted&#34;&gt;Publications by those claiming to have been contacted &lt;a href=&#34;#publications-by-those-claiming-to-have-been-contacted&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists books written by individuals who claim to have had personal contact with Nordic aliens. These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flying Saucers Have Landed&lt;/em&gt; by George Adamski and Desmond Leslie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inside the Space Ships&lt;/em&gt; by George Adamski&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Outer Space to You&lt;/em&gt; by Howard Menger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Walton Experience&lt;/em&gt; by Travis Walton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Millennial Hospitality&lt;/em&gt; by Charles James Hall (adapted into the film &lt;em&gt;Walking with the Tall Whites&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also mentions &amp;ldquo;Talks with Teachings from my Cosmic Friends,&amp;rdquo; published by the UFO religion Universe People.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics and figures in ufology, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Space Brothers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Truman Bethurum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elizabeth Klarer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Billy Meier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linda Moulton Howe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of alleged extraterrestrial beings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star people (New Age)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arcturians (New Age)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFOs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFO religion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including books, academic papers, and online resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to Wikimedia Commons for media related to Nordic aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_aliens&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_aliens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
