<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Comic Book on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/comic-book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Comic Book on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 03:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/comic-book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Nation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_eed570f8ae8c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 03:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_eed570f8ae8c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-nation&#34;&gt;Alien Nation &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-nation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A science fiction police procedural television series that aired on Fox from 1989 to 1990. It&amp;rsquo;s based on the 1988 film &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series is set in the near future, beginning in 1990, after a flying saucer crashes in the Mojave Desert. The ship contains the Tenctonese, a race of extraterrestrials escaping slavery. They are accepted as immigrants to the US, and the series explores their integration into American society. Storylines often address themes of racism and bigotry, using the Newcomers as a stand-in for discriminated minorities. The series uses social commentary to illustrate what it means to be human and the often bizarre rituals we observe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detective Matthew &amp;ldquo;Matt&amp;rdquo; Sikes:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Gary Graham, a human detective partnered with George Francisco.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detective George Francisco:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Eric Pierpoint, a Newcomer detective partnered with Matthew Sikes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Susan Francisco:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Michele Scarabelli, George&amp;rsquo;s wife, a Newcomer advertising businesswoman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emily Francisco:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Lauren Woodland, George and Susan&amp;rsquo;s young daughter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buck Francisco:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Sean Six, George and Susan&amp;rsquo;s initially delinquent teenage son.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cathy Frankel:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Terri Treas, Matt&amp;rsquo;s Newcomer neighbor and on-off girlfriend, a bio-chemist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Albert Einstein:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Jeff Marcus, a timid Newcomer janitor working at the police department.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cpt. Bryon Grazer:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Ron Fassler, Matt and George&amp;rsquo;s human superior officer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beatrice Zepeda:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Jenny Gago, a human detective in Matt and George&amp;rsquo;s squad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Burns:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Jeff Doucette, a human photographer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sergeant Dobbs:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Lawrence Hilton-Jacobs, a human police officer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jill:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Molly Morgan, a human girl and Emily&amp;rsquo;s friend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uncle Moodri:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by James Greene, an eccentric but wise Newcomer and member of the Francisco family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenneth Johnson, responsible for other science-fiction television series, was approached for the television adaptation of the 1988 film &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt;. He initially had no interest in the project but was later inspired to create a series focusing on social commentary about the integration of a new minority group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;changes-from-the-film&#34;&gt;Changes from the film &lt;a href=&#34;#changes-from-the-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several changes were made from the original film. The human detective Matthew Sykes was played by James Caan in the film, but Gary Graham in the TV series. Detective George Francisco was played by Mandy Patinkin in the film, but Eric Pierpoint in the TV series. The TV series explores Newcomer culture more deeply than the film. Francisco&amp;rsquo;s family also differs, with a daughter, Emily, added to the TV series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cancellation&#34;&gt;Cancellation &lt;a href=&#34;#cancellation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series ran for one season on Fox. Despite building a strong fan base, the show was cancelled due to the network&amp;rsquo;s financial difficulties. The season ended on a cliffhanger, and popular demand led to the unproduced second season premiere being adapted as a novel and comic book. Years later, Fox produced five television films to continue the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series consists of 22 episodes, each dealing with the integration of the Newcomers into human society and the challenges they face. The episodes often involve police procedural elements, with Sikes and Francisco investigating crimes involving both humans and Newcomers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;television-films&#34;&gt;Television films &lt;a href=&#34;#television-films&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five television films continued the story after the series&amp;rsquo; cancellation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation: Dark Horizon&lt;/em&gt; (1994)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation: Body and Soul&lt;/em&gt; (1995)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation: Millennium&lt;/em&gt; (1996)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation: The Enemy Within&lt;/em&gt; (1996)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation: The Udara Legacy&lt;/em&gt; (1997)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;home-media&#34;&gt;Home media &lt;a href=&#34;#home-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complete series was released on DVD by 20th Century Fox in 2006. The five television films were later released as a collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;revival&#34;&gt;Revival &lt;a href=&#34;#revival&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2009, Syfy announced a new take on the series with Tim Minear writing. However, the series was later cancelled. In 2015, a remake was reported to be in the works with Art Marcum and Matt Holloway writing the script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Nation_(TV_series)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Nation_(TV_series)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time-traveler UFO hypothesis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_4666fb28cb0a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 17:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_4666fb28cb0a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;time-traveler-ufo-hypothesis&#34;&gt;Time-traveler UFO hypothesis &lt;a href=&#34;#time-traveler-ufo-hypothesis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time-traveler hypothesis, also known as chrononaut UFO, future humans, extratempestrial model, and Terminator theory, proposes that unidentified flying objects (UFOs) are humans traveling from the future using advanced technology. This concept has gained recent attention from figures like retired NASA aerospace engineer Larry Lemke, Wisconsin congressman Mike Gallagher, and filmmaker Steven Spielberg. Mainstream scholars consider this hypothesis extremely implausible, and it&amp;rsquo;s generally viewed as unorthodox even among fringe conspiracy theorists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;antecedents&#34;&gt;Antecedents &lt;a href=&#34;#antecedents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the origins of the ideas that led to the time-traveler UFO hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;origins-of-time-travel-speculation&#34;&gt;Origins of time travel speculation &lt;a href=&#34;#origins-of-time-travel-speculation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection traces the concept of time travel from the future to the past back to its literary origins. Pierre Boitard&amp;rsquo;s 1861 book &lt;em&gt;Paris avant les hommes&lt;/em&gt; is credited with introducing the idea, featuring a man sent back to prehistoric Earth. Camille Flammarion&amp;rsquo;s 1887 novel &lt;em&gt;Lumen&lt;/em&gt; also explored the theme of a soul traveling through different historical periods. The section also notes that while time travel is considered physically impossible by most, theoretical research continues to explore its potential feasibility, with scientists like J. Richard Gott and Ronald Mallet speculating on the possibility of future human time travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;speculation-of-future-human-evolution&#34;&gt;Speculation of future human evolution &lt;a href=&#34;#speculation-of-future-human-evolution&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the history of speculation about the future evolution of mankind. It highlights H.G. Wells&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;The Time Machine&lt;/em&gt; as an early example of both time travel and speculative evolution. Other authors mentioned include Edgar Rice Burroughs, Olaf Stapledon, Kurt Vonnegut, Stephen Baxter, and Cevdet Mehmet Kösemen. The section also identifies climate change, the technological singularity, space travel, and genetic enhancement as potential factors that could alter human evolution, leading to transhuman and posthuman scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ufos-and-initial-explanations&#34;&gt;UFOs and initial explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#ufos-and-initial-explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection provides a brief overview of the history of UFO sightings. It mentions reports of unknown objects in the skies dating back to antiquity, as well as the mystery airship sightings of the 1890s and the Foo fighters and ghost rockets during World War II. The modern UFO era is said to have begun in the summer of 1947, following Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting. Initial explanations for these sightings ranged from novel US or Soviet technology to misidentification of mundane objects and mass hysteria. Fringe theories included extraterrestrial or interdimensional origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;formation-and-spread&#34;&gt;Formation and spread &lt;a href=&#34;#formation-and-spread&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the development and popularization of the time-traveler UFO hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;implausibility-of-humanoid-aliens&#34;&gt;Implausibility of humanoid aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#implausibility-of-humanoid-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection addresses the common depiction of aliens as humanoids in contactee and alien abduction folklore. It cites George Gaylord Simpson&amp;rsquo;s 1964 article &lt;em&gt;The Nonprevalence of Humanoids&lt;/em&gt;, which argues that it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely for extraterrestrial intelligence to exist and even more unlikely for it to be humanoid. The section also mentions Stephen Jay Gould&amp;rsquo;s thought experiment about rewinding evolution, suggesting that humans would likely not evolve again. Biologist Jack Cohen&amp;rsquo;s view on the implausibility of Grey aliens evolving a physiology similar to humans is also included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;modern-popularization&#34;&gt;Modern popularization &lt;a href=&#34;#modern-popularization&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explores the modern resurgence of the time-traveler hypothesis. It mentions Jacques Vallée&amp;rsquo;s 1975 book &lt;em&gt;The Invisible College&lt;/em&gt; as an early example. Other figures and works mentioned include David S. Anderson, Jenny Randles, James Herbert Brennan, and Philip J. Corso and William J. Birnes&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;The Day After Roswell&lt;/em&gt;, which reported Hermann Oberth&amp;rsquo;s belief that the Roswell craft could have been a time machine. The History channel series &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; is also mentioned for its episodes exploring the concept. Michael P. Masters&amp;rsquo; book &lt;em&gt;Identified Flying Objects&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Extratempestrial Model&lt;/em&gt; are highlighted for their in-depth exploration of the hypothesis. Tim Peake and Steven Spielberg are mentioned for their recent public comments on the theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection lists examples of the time-traveler hypothesis in popular culture. It includes the TV series &lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s About Time&lt;/em&gt;, Gregory Benford&amp;rsquo;s novel &lt;em&gt;Timescape&lt;/em&gt;, David Drake&amp;rsquo;s novel &lt;em&gt;Birds of Prey&lt;/em&gt;, Michael Crichton&amp;rsquo;s novel &lt;em&gt;Sphere&lt;/em&gt;, the TV film &lt;em&gt;Official Denial&lt;/em&gt;, the comic book series &lt;em&gt;Blake and Mortimer&lt;/em&gt;, the band Yes, Jordan Peele&amp;rsquo;s movie &lt;em&gt;Nope&lt;/em&gt;, and the movie &lt;em&gt;Interstellar&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;terminology-and-connection-to-other-theories&#34;&gt;Terminology and connection to other theories &lt;a href=&#34;#terminology-and-connection-to-other-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection clarifies the terminology used to describe the hypothesis, noting that while Michael P. Masters uses the term &amp;ldquo;extratempestrial,&amp;rdquo; the overall idea is often referred to as &amp;ldquo;the time-traveler hypothesis.&amp;rdquo; It also discusses the overlap between the time-traveler hypothesis and the interdimensional hypothesis, with figures like John Ventre and Harold E. Puthoff using the terms interchangeably. The section also notes that the time-traveler hypothesis provides an alternative explanation for the absence of future time travelers, similar to how the extraterrestrial hypothesis addresses Fermi&amp;rsquo;s paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;criticism&#34;&gt;Criticism &lt;a href=&#34;#criticism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents criticisms of the time-traveler hypothesis. It notes that the hypothesis is considered pseudoscientific. Neil deGrasse Tyson is quoted as calling the hypothesis illogical, and Robert Sheaffer criticizes Michael P. Masters&amp;rsquo; work for relying on the belief that time travel is possible. David J. Darling argues that the extraterrestrial and time-travel hypotheses are equally unlikely and unnecessary. Ian Ridpath suggests that Jim Penniston&amp;rsquo;s claims about time-traveling UFOs may have been influenced by the film &lt;em&gt;Official Denial&lt;/em&gt;. Isaac Arthur is mentioned for debunking the concept as presented in &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;. Fabio Costa is quoted as saying that time travel requires two doors, one in the future and one in the past, raising the question of where the time machine is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics, including Time travel, Posthumanism, Transhumanism, Timeline of the far future, Longtermism, Speculative Evolution, Cryptoterrestrial hypothesis, Psychosocial hypothesis, Interdimensional hypothesis, and Space animal hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time-traveller_UFO_hypothesis&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time-traveller_UFO_hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
