<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New Religious Movements on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/new-religious-movements/</link>
    <description>Recent content in New Religious Movements on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 04:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/new-religious-movements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO religion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_0a1958d0044c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 04:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_0a1958d0044c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-religion&#34;&gt;UFO Religion &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-religion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A UFO religion is a religion where belief in extraterrestrial entities operating unidentified flying objects (UFOs) is a core element. Adherents typically believe these ETs are interested in humanity&amp;rsquo;s welfare and that humanity will eventually join an existing ET civilization. Some UFO religions incorporate ETs into a supernatural worldview, blurring the lines between aliens and angels. These religions draw inspiration from early science fiction, ufology, UFO sightings, and alien abduction stories. The Aetherius Society, founded by George King, is considered the first UFO religion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary &lt;a href=&#34;#summary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adherents believe that the arrival or rediscovery of alien civilizations, technologies, and spirituality will enable humans to overcome ecological, spiritual, and social problems. Issues like hatred, war, bigotry, and poverty are believed to be resolvable through superior alien technology and spiritual abilities. These belief systems are often millenarian in their outlook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFO religions developed in countries like the United States, Canada, France, the United Kingdom, and Japan, where technology is advanced enough to conceive of ETs and where religion is not suppressed. The term &amp;ldquo;flying saucers&amp;rdquo; and the popular notion of the UFO originated in 1947. The study of UFO religions by sociologists, historians, theologians, scholars of religious studies, and new religious movements began in the 1950s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notable-ufo-religions&#34;&gt;Notable UFO Religions &lt;a href=&#34;#notable-ufo-religions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFO religions generally involve belief in communication with extraterrestrial beings through physical contact, telepathy, and astral projection. These groups often believe that humanity will be saved by aliens who will educate humans on a better way to live or take believers to a more positive location. Extraterrestrial beings are often seen pleading with humanity to improve itself and move away from greed and violence. UFO religions emphasize spiritual growth and the evolution of humanity. A UFO religion can form before or after an individual claims to have experienced an alien abduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. Gordon Melton identifies the &amp;ldquo;I AM&amp;rdquo; Activity, founded by Guy Ballard, as the first UFO religion, although Christopher Hugh Partridge views it as a theosophical religion. Partridge notes that UFO religions believe the supreme being or &amp;ldquo;evolved entity&amp;rdquo; came from another plane or planet. The 1947 Roswell incident is a key point in time within UFO spirituality. James R. Lewis notes that Ufologists see it as the date of the &amp;ldquo;emergence of UFOs into the public consciousness.&amp;rdquo; Partridge places UFO religion within the context of theosophical esotericism and asserts that it began to be associated as &amp;ldquo;UFO religion&amp;rdquo; after the Roswell incident. He notes that most UFO religions still have many of the key points associated with Theosophy, such as belief in the same Spiritual Hierarchy, and he also draws parallels to New Age thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen Hunt describes the Aetherius Society, founded by George King in 1955, as &amp;ldquo;probably the first and certainly the most enduring UFO cult.&amp;rdquo; Hunt places the Aetherius Society and Raëlism among the &amp;ldquo;most renowned&amp;rdquo; of the &amp;ldquo;flying saucer cults.&amp;rdquo; Melodie Campbell and Stephen A. Kent place the Aetherius Society and Unarius as among the &amp;ldquo;oldest and most studied&amp;rdquo; of the flying saucer cults. They describe Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate and Order of the Solar Temple as the &amp;ldquo;most controversial groups combining UFO belief with variations of contactee assertions.&amp;rdquo; Gregory L. Reece classes Scientology as a &amp;ldquo;UFO group,&amp;rdquo; discussing elements of the Xenu cosmogony and Space opera in Scientology doctrine. He compares Scientology to the Aetherius Society and Ashtar Command. Victoria Nelson writes that &amp;ldquo;[t]he most prominent current UFO religion is probably the science fiction writer L. Ron Hubbard&amp;rsquo;s Church of Scientology.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_religion&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_religion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
