<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philae on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/philae/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philae on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 14:52:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/philae/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>European mission to study Comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko (2004–2016)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_d45625f68907/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 14:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_d45625f68907/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;european-mission-to-study-comet-67pchuryumov-gerasimenko-20042016&#34;&gt;European mission to study Comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko (2004–2016) &lt;a href=&#34;#european-mission-to-study-comet-67pchuryumov-gerasimenko-20042016&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces the &lt;em&gt;Rosetta&lt;/em&gt; mission, a European Space Agency (ESA) project launched in 2004 to study Comet 67P/Churyumov–Gerasimenko. It highlights that &lt;em&gt;Rosetta&lt;/em&gt;, along with its lander module &lt;em&gt;Philae&lt;/em&gt;, conducted a detailed study of the comet. The mission involved flybys of Earth, Mars, and asteroids 21 Lutetia and 2867 Šteins. It was the third cornerstone mission of ESA&amp;rsquo;s Horizon 2000 program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;mission-overview&#34;&gt;Mission overview &lt;a href=&#34;#mission-overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a summary of the &lt;em&gt;Rosetta&lt;/em&gt; mission&amp;rsquo;s timeline and objectives. Key points include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launch on March 2, 2004, from the Guiana Space Centre in Kourou, French Guiana, aboard an Ariane 5 rocket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arrival at Comet Churyumov–Gerasimenko on May 7, 2014, and entering orbit on August 6, 2014, becoming the first spacecraft to orbit a comet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Philae&lt;/em&gt; lander&amp;rsquo;s successful landing on the comet nucleus on November 12, 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loss of communication with &lt;em&gt;Philae&lt;/em&gt; due to battery power depletion, with brief restoration in June and July 2015.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;End of mission on September 30, 2016, with &lt;em&gt;Rosetta&lt;/em&gt; hard-landing on the comet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mention of the European Space Operations Centre (ESOC) in Darmstadt, Germany, as the control center and the European Space Astronomy Centre (ESAC) near Madrid, Spain, for scientific payload planning and data management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Estimated involvement of 2,000 people in the mission over a decade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the background and naming of the &lt;em&gt;Rosetta&lt;/em&gt; mission. Key points include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mission evolved from earlier cooperative efforts between ESA and NASA, including the Comet Rendezvous Asteroid Flyby (CRAF) and Comet Nucleus Sample Return (CNSR) missions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NASA&amp;rsquo;s cancellation of CRAF led ESA to develop a similar project independently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mission was redesigned due to budgetary constraints, resembling the cancelled CRAF mission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gerhard Schwehm was the mission manager until his retirement in March 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mission included generational team management for continuity and knowledge transfer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The probe was named after the Rosetta Stone, and the lander after the Philae obelisk, symbolizing the deciphering of cometary composition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The spacecraft carried a micro-etched nickel prototype of the Rosetta disc with language translations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;mission-firsts&#34;&gt;Mission firsts &lt;a href=&#34;#mission-firsts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights the groundbreaking achievements of the &lt;em&gt;Rosetta&lt;/em&gt; mission. Key points include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First European close encounter with asteroids in the asteroid belt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First spacecraft to fly close to Jupiter&amp;rsquo;s orbit using solar cells as its main power source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First spacecraft to orbit a comet nucleus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First spacecraft to fly alongside a comet as it headed towards the inner Solar System.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First controlled touchdown on a comet nucleus by the &lt;em&gt;Philae&lt;/em&gt; lander.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First images from a comet&amp;rsquo;s surface and &lt;em&gt;in situ&lt;/em&gt; analysis of its composition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;design-and-construction&#34;&gt;Design and construction &lt;a href=&#34;#design-and-construction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the technical aspects of the &lt;em&gt;Rosetta&lt;/em&gt; spacecraft. Key points include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The spacecraft&amp;rsquo;s dimensions, mass, and construction materials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Details about the solar arrays, power generation, and batteries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information on the propulsion system, including thrusters and propellant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mention of the clean room construction and COSPAR rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total mission cost of about €1.3 billion (US$1.8 billion).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;launch&#34;&gt;Launch &lt;a href=&#34;#launch&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the launch details and trajectory of the &lt;em&gt;Rosetta&lt;/em&gt; spacecraft. Key points include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initial launch plan for January 12, 2003, targeting comet 46P/Wirtanen, which was abandoned due to an Ariane 5 ECA failure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revised plan to target comet 67P/Churyumov–Gerasimenko, with a launch date of February 26, 2004.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Successful launch on March 2, 2004, from the Guiana Space Centre using an Ariane 5 G+ rocket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presence of Klim Churyumov and Svetlana Gerasimenko, the co-discoverers of the comet, at the launch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;deep-space-manoeuvres&#34;&gt;Deep space manoeuvres &lt;a href=&#34;#deep-space-manoeuvres&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the gravity assist maneuvers used by &lt;em&gt;Rosetta&lt;/em&gt; to reach its target. Key points include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use of gravity assist maneuvers to accelerate throughout the inner Solar System.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First Earth flyby on March 4, 2005.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low-altitude flyby of Mars on February 25, 2007, which involved a risky period in the planet&amp;rsquo;s shadow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second Earth flyby on November 13, 2007, during which &lt;em&gt;Rosetta&lt;/em&gt; was briefly mistaken for a near-Earth asteroid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flyby of asteroid 2867 Šteins on September 5, 2008.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Third and final Earth flyby on November 12, 2009.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flyby of asteroid 21 Lutetia on July 10, 2010.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Series of eight burns in May 2014 to reduce the relative velocity between the spacecraft and 67P.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;reaction-control-system-problems&#34;&gt;Reaction control system problems &lt;a href=&#34;#reaction-control-system-problems&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes technical issues encountered during the mission. Key points include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A leak in the reaction control system (RCS) in 2006, causing lower operating pressure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased levels of &amp;ldquo;bearing friction noise&amp;rdquo; in two of the spacecraft&amp;rsquo;s four reaction wheels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efforts to relubricate the reaction wheels and manage their operating temperatures and speed ranges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development of new on-board software to allow &lt;em&gt;Rosetta&lt;/em&gt; to operate with only two active reaction wheels if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;orbit-around-67p&#34;&gt;Orbit around 67P &lt;a href=&#34;#orbit-around-67p&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details &lt;em&gt;Rosetta&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s orbital maneuvers around comet 67P. Key points include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rendezvous with comet 67P in August 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Series of maneuvers to establish triangular paths around the nucleus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entry into orbit about the comet on September 10, 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mapping of the comet&amp;rsquo;s surface to determine a landing site for &lt;em&gt;Philae&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selection of Site J, named &lt;em&gt;Agilkia&lt;/em&gt;, as the lander&amp;rsquo;s destination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;philae-lander&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Philae&lt;/em&gt; lander &lt;a href=&#34;#philae-lander&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the &lt;em&gt;Philae&lt;/em&gt; lander&amp;rsquo;s mission. Key points include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Philae&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s detachment from &lt;em&gt;Rosetta&lt;/em&gt; on November 12, 2014, and approach to 67P.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initial landing at 15:33 UTC, followed by two bounces and final settling at 17:33 UTC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Failure of harpoons to fire upon landing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Philae&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s science mission objectives, including characterization of the nucleus and determination of chemical compounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Philae&lt;/em&gt; settling in the shadow of a cliff, leading to inadequate solar power collection and loss of contact after three days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brief reestablishment of contact several months later, followed by permanent loss of communication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discovery of the lander&amp;rsquo;s precise location in September 2016 through high-resolution images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;notable-results&#34;&gt;Notable results &lt;a href=&#34;#notable-results&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights some of the significant scientific findings from the mission. Key points include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discovery that the magnetic field of 67P oscillated at 40–50 millihertz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determination that the comet&amp;rsquo;s nucleus has no magnetic field, with the detected field likely caused by the solar wind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Isotopic signature of water vapor from comet 67P being substantially different from that found on Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increase in the rate at which water vapor was released by the comet between June and August 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determination that electrons, not direct photons, are responsible for the degradation of water and carbon dioxide molecules in the comet&amp;rsquo;s coma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;end-of-mission&#34;&gt;End of mission &lt;a href=&#34;#end-of-mission&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the conclusion of the &lt;em&gt;Rosetta&lt;/em&gt; mission. Key points include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decision to guide &lt;em&gt;Rosetta&lt;/em&gt; down to the comet&amp;rsquo;s surface due to decreasing sunlight reaching the solar panels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Announcement that the end of mission would occur at the end of September 2016.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Descent maneuver initiated on September 29, 2016, targeting a site in the Ma&amp;rsquo;at region.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impact on the comet&amp;rsquo;s surface on September 30, 2016, with the final data packet transmitted at 10:39:28.895 UTC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Estimated speed at the time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rosetta_(spacecraft)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rosetta_(spacecraft)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
