<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dover Demon on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/dover-demon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dover Demon on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 16:02:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/dover-demon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dover Demon</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_670cdf070164/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 16:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_670cdf070164/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;dover-demon&#34;&gt;Dover Demon &lt;a href=&#34;#dover-demon&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dover Demon is a cryptid reportedly sighted in Dover, Massachusetts, in April 1977.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sightings&#34;&gt;Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section details the reported sightings of the Dover Demon in April 1977. William &amp;ldquo;Bill&amp;rdquo; Bartlett, John Baxter, and Abby Brabham, all teenagers at the time, independently reported seeing a strange creature. Bartlett described it as about 4 feet tall with glowing orange eyes and no nose or mouth, with a watermelon-shaped head, perched on a broken stone wall on Farm Street. Baxter reported a similar sighting on Miller Hill Road the same evening, and Brabham claimed to have seen the creature the following night on Springdale Avenue. The teenagers drew sketches of the creature, with Bartlett swearing on a stack of Bibles to the accuracy of his depiction. The locations of the sightings, when plotted on a map, formed a straight line over 2 miles. The sightings became public in May, drawing comparisons to the creatures involved in the Kelly–Hopkinsville encounter of 1955. The Mutual UFO Network also investigated the sightings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;possible-explanations&#34;&gt;Possible explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#possible-explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section explores potential explanations for the Dover Demon sightings. One suggestion is that the creature was a foal or a moose calf. Skeptic Joe Nickell proposes that the creature was likely a snowy owl, citing its size, plumage, and the reflection of yellow headlights in its eyes, creating the peach color described by Bartlett. Nickell also suggests that the &amp;ldquo;long spindly arms&amp;rdquo; could have been the partially opened wings of an owl. Police suggested the sightings were a hoax. Ben Radford suggests the sightings may have been influenced by the release of &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt; in 1977.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the Dover Demon&amp;rsquo;s appearances in popular culture. It was featured in an episode of the American horror television series &lt;em&gt;Lost Tapes&lt;/em&gt; on Animal Planet in 2009. The Dover Demon appears as a character in the comic book series &lt;em&gt;Proof&lt;/em&gt;, where it can see into the future, and in &lt;em&gt;The Perhapanauts&lt;/em&gt;. It also made appearances in &lt;em&gt;The Pound: Ghouls Night Out&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Hack/Slash: Entry Wound&lt;/em&gt;. A Dover Demon appears in the webcomic &lt;em&gt;Gunnerkrigg Court&lt;/em&gt;. In the manga series &lt;em&gt;Dandadan&lt;/em&gt;, an alien known as Dover Demon takes the form of a bipedal crustacean-like alien with the ability to transform into a stronger form resembling that of a mantis shrimp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dover_Demon&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dover_Demon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
