<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Friendship on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/friendship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Friendship on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 12:44:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/friendship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial (1982 film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e4b54ac7181b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 12:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e4b54ac7181b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;et-the-extra-terrestrial-1982-film&#34;&gt;E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial (1982 film) &lt;a href=&#34;#et-the-extra-terrestrial-1982-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive overview of the 1982 American science fiction film produced and directed by Steven Spielberg and written by Melissa Mathison. The film tells the story of a boy, Elliott, who befriends an extraterrestrial stranded on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A race of alien botanists visits Earth, but one of them gets separated from the group and is left behind. The alien takes shelter in a shed belonging to the family of ten-year-old Elliott Taylor. Elliott lures the alien back to his home with Reese&amp;rsquo;s Pieces, and he hides the creature in his room. Elliott introduces E.T. to his older brother, Michael, and five-year-old sister Gertie, who agree to keep E.T. hidden from their mother, Mary. Elliott and the creature begin to bond, they start to share thoughts and emotions. E.T. displays telekinetic abilities and revives a dead chrysanthemum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At school, Elliott becomes intoxicated because E.T. is drinking beer and watching television at home. Inspired by a Buck Rogers comic strip, E.T. builds a makeshift device to &amp;ldquo;phone home&amp;rdquo;, using various parts around the Taylor home. On Halloween, the children disguise E.T. as a ghost and Elliott sneaks E.T. into the forest, where they set up the device to call E.T.&amp;rsquo;s people. Elliott begs E.T. to stay on Earth with him, before falling asleep and waking alone in the forest the next day. He returns home to his worried family, while Michael searches for E.T., finding him pale and weakened in a culvert. He takes E.T. home, where Elliott is also growing weaker, and reveal the creature to Mary just before government agents invade and quarantine the house. The lead agent, Keys, asks for Elliott&amp;rsquo;s help to save E.T., stating that meeting aliens was his childhood dream and he considers E.T&amp;rsquo;s arrival a genuine miracle. However, E.T. dies while Elliott rapidly recovers. Left alone to say goodbye, Elliott tells E.T. that he loves him, but E.T.&amp;rsquo;s heart begins to glow and he is revived and restored to health. E.T. tells Elliott that his people are returning for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elliott and Michael flee with E.T. on their bikes, flanked by Michael&amp;rsquo;s friends who help them evade the pursuing authorities. Heading towards a roadblock, E.T. levitates the boys to safety and lands them in the forest. E.T.&amp;rsquo;s ship arrives, and he says goodbye to Michael and Gertie, who gifts him the chrysanthemum he previously revived. Elliott tearfully asks E.T. to stay, but E.T. places his glowing finger on Elliott&amp;rsquo;s head and tells him that he will always be there. The children, Mary, and Keys observe as the ship blasts off into space, leaving a rainbow in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main cast includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dee Wallace as Mary Taylor, the single mother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Henry Thomas as Elliott Taylor, the boy who befriends E.T.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peter Coyote as Keys, the government agent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert MacNaughton as Michael Taylor, Elliott&amp;rsquo;s older brother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drew Barrymore as Gertie Taylor, Elliott&amp;rsquo;s younger sister.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other cast members include K.C. Martel, Sean Frye, C. Thomas Howell, Erika Eleniak, David O&amp;rsquo;Dell, Richard Swingler, Frank Toth, Robert Barton, Michael Darrell, and Pat Welsh as the voice of E.T.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details the development, pre-production, casting, filming, and music of the movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;development&#34;&gt;Development &lt;a href=&#34;#development&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film&amp;rsquo;s concept originated from an imaginary friend Steven Spielberg created after his parents&amp;rsquo; divorce. He initially planned a darker project called &lt;em&gt;Night Skies&lt;/em&gt; but developed a subplot into what became &lt;em&gt;E.T.&lt;/em&gt; Melissa Mathison wrote the first draft, titled &lt;em&gt;E.T. and Me&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pre-production&#34;&gt;Pre-production &lt;a href=&#34;#pre-production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carlo Rambaldi designed the animatronics for E.T., inspired by his painting &lt;em&gt;Women of Delta&lt;/em&gt; and the faces of Carl Sandburg, Albert Einstein, and Ernest Hemingway. Kathleen Kennedy visited the Jules Stein Eye Institute to study eyes for E.T. Four heads were created for filming, one as the main animatronic and the others for facial expressions, as well as a costume. Tamara De Treaux, Pat Bilon, and Matthew DeMeritt took turns wearing the costume. Mars, Incorporated refused to allow M&amp;amp;M&amp;rsquo;s to be used in the film, so The Hershey Company was asked if Reese&amp;rsquo;s Pieces could be used, and it agreed. Henry Feinberg created E.T.&amp;rsquo;s communicator device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;casting&#34;&gt;Casting &lt;a href=&#34;#casting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spielberg cast Henry Thomas as Elliott after an impressive improvised audition scene. Robert MacNaughton played Michael, and Drew Barrymore was cast as Gertie. Pat Welsh provided the major voice work for E.T., with additional sounds from Debra Winger, Spielberg, and various animals. A scene featuring Harrison Ford as the school principal was cut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;filming&#34;&gt;Filming &lt;a href=&#34;#filming&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Principal photography began on September 8, 1981, in Los Angeles County and the San Fernando Valley, under the cover name &lt;em&gt;A Boy&amp;rsquo;s Life&lt;/em&gt;. Filming locations included Culver City High School, Northridge, Tujunga, Laird International Studios in Culver City, and a redwood forest near Crescent City in Northern California. The exterior Halloween scene and the &amp;ldquo;flying bicycle&amp;rdquo; chase scenes were filmed in Porter Ranch. The film was shot in roughly chronological order to achieve convincing emotional performances from the young cast. Sean Frye revealed how the visual effect close-up shots for the climax of the &amp;ldquo;flying bicycle&amp;rdquo; chase scene were filmed. BMX riders Robert Cardoza, Greg Maes, and David Lee served as stunt doubles for the scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;Music &lt;a href=&#34;#music&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Williams composed the score, taking a modernist approach with polytonality and the Lydian mode. Spielberg edited the final chase sequence to suit Williams&amp;rsquo; music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes &lt;a href=&#34;#themes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film explores themes of divorce, alienation, growing up, and communication. Critics have noted parallels between E.T. and Elliott, as well as religious parallels between E.T. and Jesus. Some see the movie as a modern fairy tale, drawing comparisons to Peter Pan and The Wizard of Oz. Kathleen Kennedy highlighted tolerance as an important theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details the film&amp;rsquo;s release, sales, critical response, and accolades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;release-and-sales&#34;&gt;Release and sales &lt;a href=&#34;#release-and-sales&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;E.T.&lt;/em&gt; premiered at the 1982 Cannes Film Festival and was released in the United States on June 11, 1982. It opened at number one at the US box office and stayed at the top for six weeks. In 1983, &lt;em&gt;E.T.&lt;/em&gt; surpassed &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; to become the highest-grossing film of all time. The film was also a merchandising success, with dolls selling 15 million units by September 1982 and becoming the best-selling toy that Christmas season. The film was re-released in 1985 and 2002, earning another $60 million and $68 million respectively. It was re-released in IMAX on August 12, 2022, to commemorate the film&amp;rsquo;s 40th anniversary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;home-media&#34;&gt;Home media &lt;a href=&#34;#home-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;E.T.&lt;/em&gt; was released on VHS and LaserDisc on October 27, 1988. The videos were priced with a recommended retail price of $24.95, the lowest initial price at the time for a major movie compared to the normal price of $89.95. The film doubled the record pre-orders of &lt;em&gt;Cinderella&lt;/em&gt; released the same month and went on to sell over 15 million VHS units in the United States, and grossed over $250 million in video sales revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;critical-response&#34;&gt;Critical response &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-response&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received near-universal acclaim. Roger Ebert gave it four out of four stars, and Michael Sragow of &lt;em&gt;Rolling Stone&lt;/em&gt; called Spielberg &amp;ldquo;a space age Jean Renoir.&amp;rdquo; George Will was one of few to pan the film. The film holds a 99% approval rating on Rotten Tomatoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;accolades&#34;&gt;Accolades &lt;a href=&#34;#accolades&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film was nominated for nine Oscars at the 55th Academy Awards, winning four: Best Original Score, Best Sound, Best Sound Effects Editing, and Best Visual Effects. It also won Golden Globe Awards for Best Picture (Drama) and Best Original Score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legacy&#34;&gt;Legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film has been voted one of the greatest films of all time by the American Film Institute. The line &amp;ldquo;E.T. phone home&amp;rdquo; was ranked 15th on AFI&amp;rsquo;s 100 Years&amp;hellip;100 Movie Quotes list. In 1994, it was selected for preservation in the U.S. National Film Registry. In 2023, actress Rita Moreno named &lt;em&gt;E.T.&lt;/em&gt; as one of her top five favorite films. Many people in the world of entertainment have cited &lt;em&gt;E.T.&lt;/em&gt; as among their favorite films, including filmmakers Stanley Kubrick, Sidney Lumet, Edgar Wright, J. A. Bayona, Dustin Lance Black, Spenser Cohen, Dustin Guy Defa, Gareth Edwards, Michael Giacchino, Sarah Greenwood, Chad Hartigan, Max Hechtman, Jordan Horowitz, Phil Joanou, Travis Knight, David Lowery, Rod Roddenberry, Céline Sciamma, Ed Solomon, Goran Stolevski, Clement Virgo and Molly Manning Walker, actors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/E.T._the_Extra-Terrestrial&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/E.T._the_Extra-Terrestrial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
