<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monster on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/monster/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Monster on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 13:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/monster/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Trespass (2009 Film)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_916dbe083330/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 13:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_916dbe083330/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-trespass-2009-film&#34;&gt;Alien Trespass (2009 Film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-trespass-2009-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a description of the 2009 film &lt;em&gt;Alien Trespass&lt;/em&gt;, directed by R.W. Goodwin. The film is a science-fiction comedy that pays homage to the B movies of the 1950s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is set in 1957 in California&amp;rsquo;s Mojave Desert. Astronomer Ted Lewis and his wife Lana are observing a meteor shower when something crashes nearby. Ted investigates and discovers an alien spaceship. His body is then taken over by Urp, a well-meaning alien who is searching for Ghota, a one-eyed monster that escaped from the ship. Ghota consumes people to grow and multiply, threatening Earth. Urp enlists the help of Tammy, a local waitress, to stop Ghota. The local police, Chief Dawson and Officer Vern, are skeptical. Urp and Tammy hunt down Ghota, and they eventually fall in love. At the end, Urp returns to his home planet, leaving Tammy to pursue her dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film stars Eric McCormack as Ted Lewis/Urp, Jenni Baird as Tammy, Robert Patrick as Vernon, Jody Thompson as Lana Lewis, and Dan Lauria as Chief Dawson. Other cast members include Sarah Smyth, Aaron Brooks, Andrew Dunbar, Dayna Reid, Chelah Horsdal, Sage Brocklebank, Jonathon Young, and Tom McBeath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;analysis&#34;&gt;Analysis &lt;a href=&#34;#analysis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film replicates the look and feel of 1950s science fiction films, with the exception of being in color. The film uses the trope of monsters terrorizing small desert towns, which was common in 1950s B movies due to lower production costs. The character of Lana Lewis is depicted as a &amp;ldquo;sexpot,&amp;rdquo; a common archetype in 1950s science fiction films. The Ghota is similar to B.O.B. from &lt;em&gt;Monsters vs. Aliens&lt;/em&gt;. The romance between Urp and Tammy is reminiscent of &lt;em&gt;The Day the Earth Stood Still&lt;/em&gt;. Director Goodwin states that the film takes elements from &lt;em&gt;The Day the Earth Stood Still&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;It Came from Outer Space&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The War of the Worlds&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received mixed reviews. Rotten Tomatoes gives it a 38% approval rating, with the consensus being that it loses its charm due to tedious dialogue and cheesy special effects. Roger Ebert gave the film two out of four stars, stating that it was a labor of love but questioning whether there was a demand for cheesy 1950s sci-fi movies. Jeannette Catsoulis of &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; described the film as a charming but pointless homage. Betsy Sharkey of the &lt;em&gt;Los Angeles Times&lt;/em&gt; felt that the film stayed too true to the era and genre, forgetting to entertain. IGN praised the film&amp;rsquo;s recreation of the 1950s aesthetic but found that it couldn&amp;rsquo;t decide whether to emulate or satirize the genre. Ty Burr of &lt;em&gt;The Boston Globe&lt;/em&gt; felt that the film was superior to &lt;em&gt;Monsters vs. Aliens&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Entertainment Weekly&lt;/em&gt; gave the film a &amp;ldquo;B+&amp;rdquo; rating, praising its warm tone and anti-CGI look. Gary Westfahl considers the film an overlooked gem that captures the charm of 1950s science fiction films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article lists other films related to the genre, including &lt;em&gt;Earth vs. the Flying Saucers&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Forbidden Planet&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Invaders from Mars&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Mars Attacks!&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Lost Skeleton of Cadavra&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources &lt;a href=&#34;#sources&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article cites several sources, including reviews by Roger Ebert, Gary Westfahl, and articles from AMC.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article includes a list of references to support the information presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article provides links to the film&amp;rsquo;s official website, IMDb page, Rotten Tomatoes page, TCM Movie Database page, and articles from &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, AMCtv.com, and &lt;em&gt;Starlog&lt;/em&gt; magazine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Trespass&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Trespass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
