<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UFO Religion on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ufo-religion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UFO Religion on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 22:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ufo-religion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nordic aliens</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cf4950bfe155/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 22:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cf4950bfe155/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alleged-humanoid-extraterrestrials&#34;&gt;Alleged humanoid extraterrestrials &lt;a href=&#34;#alleged-humanoid-extraterrestrials&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry focuses on &amp;ldquo;Nordics,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Nordic aliens,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Tall Whites,&amp;rdquo; a type of humanoid extraterrestrial beings often discussed in ufology. These beings are said to originate from the Pleiades star cluster and are described as resembling Nordic, Germanic, or Scandinavian humans. They are typically depicted as taller than average humans (6-7 ft), with blond hair, blue eyes, and fair skin. Some accounts mention skin tones of pale blue/grey or pastel purple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;George Adamski, a Polish-American ufologist, is noted as one of the first to publicly claim contact with Nordic beings in the 1950s. The mythology surrounding these beings often includes themes of telepathy, benevolence, beauty, and grace. Telepathy is often described as the primary form of communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the historical context and cultural influences surrounding the Nordic alien narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cultural historian David J. Skal suggests that the 1951 film &lt;em&gt;The Day the Earth Stood Still&lt;/em&gt; may have inspired early stories of Nordic-type aliens. The film features an extraterrestrial arriving on Earth to warn humanity about the dangers of atomic weapons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bates College professor Stephanie Kelley-Romano describes alien abduction beliefs as a &amp;ldquo;living myth,&amp;rdquo; noting that Nordic aliens are often associated with spiritual growth, love, and protection among believers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nordic aliens are often portrayed as benevolent beings concerned about Earth&amp;rsquo;s ecology and world peace, possessing telepathic powers and described as paternal, watchful, smiling, affectionate, and youthful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Claims of encounters with Nordic aliens were common in Europe during the 1950s but became less frequent in later decades, as the grey alien became more prevalent in extraterrestrial encounter accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;publications-by-those-claiming-to-have-been-contacted&#34;&gt;Publications by those claiming to have been contacted &lt;a href=&#34;#publications-by-those-claiming-to-have-been-contacted&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists books written by individuals who claim to have had personal contact with Nordic aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The books mentioned include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flying Saucers Have Landed&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Inside the Space Ships&lt;/em&gt; by George Adamski&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Outer Space to You&lt;/em&gt; by Howard Menger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Walton Experience&lt;/em&gt; by Travis Walton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Millennial Hospitality&lt;/em&gt; by Charles James Hall (adapted into the film &lt;em&gt;Walking with the Tall Whites&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UFO religion Universe People also publishes interactions as &amp;ldquo;Talks with Teachings from my Cosmic Friends&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics and figures within the realm of ufology and extraterrestrial beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Space Brothers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Truman Bethurum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elizabeth Klarer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Billy Meier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linda Moulton Howe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of alleged extraterrestrial beings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star people (New Age)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arcturians (New Age)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFOs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFO religion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the references used in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to media related to Nordic aliens on Wikimedia Commons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_alien&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_alien&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
