<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1970 on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/1970/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1970 on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 01:44:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/1970/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO 1</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b717bfb4c2c5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 01:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b717bfb4c2c5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-1&#34;&gt;UFO 1 &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-1&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry details the debut studio album by the British rock band UFO, released in October 1970 in the UK. It notes the album&amp;rsquo;s initial lack of charting success in the UK and US, but its popularity in Germany and Japan. It also mentions reissues of the album under different names, including one with tracks from their second album and a later compilation album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;track-listing&#34;&gt;Track listing &lt;a href=&#34;#track-listing&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists all the songs on the album, divided into side one and side two, as they appeared on the original vinyl release. It includes the song titles, writers, and the length of each track. Writers include Pete Way, Phil Mogg, Andy Parker, Mick Bolton, Eddie Cochran, Jerry Capehart, Fred Hellerman, and Fran Minkoff, as well as Ellas McDaniel (Bo Diddley). It also notes a change in the title of &amp;ldquo;Boogie for George&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Boogie&amp;rdquo; on a CD reissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;personnel&#34;&gt;Personnel &lt;a href=&#34;#personnel&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the members of UFO who performed on the album: Phil Mogg (vocals), Mick Bolton (guitar), Pete Way (bass), and Andy Parker (drums). It also credits Guy Fletcher and Doug Flett as producers and Milton Samuel as executive producer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of citations used in the article, linking to sources such as AllMusic, books, and hitparade.ch to verify the information presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the album&amp;rsquo;s entry on Discogs, offering a list of releases and further information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_1&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
