<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Torture on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/torture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Torture on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 16:45:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/torture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Verdade Sufocada</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_b81ddac6c8f3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_b81ddac6c8f3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-verdade-sufocada&#34;&gt;A Verdade Sufocada &lt;a href=&#34;#a-verdade-sufocada&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry details the book &amp;ldquo;A Verdade Sufocada&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;The Suffocated Truth&amp;rdquo;) written by Carlos Alberto Brilhante Ustra, a Brazilian military colonel convicted of torture during Brazil&amp;rsquo;s military dictatorship (1964-1985). The book presents Ustra&amp;rsquo;s perspective on the left-wing armed resistance during that period and his experiences as head of DOI-CODI, an agency known for political repression, torture, and murder of the dictatorship&amp;rsquo;s opponents. The book&amp;rsquo;s publication faced boycotts, requiring the author&amp;rsquo;s family to finance its print runs. It gained attention after being quoted by Jair Bolsonaro during Dilma Rousseff&amp;rsquo;s impeachment vote in 2016 and became a bestseller. However, it has been heavily criticized by historians and sociologists who question its reliability as a historical document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-book&#34;&gt;The book &lt;a href=&#34;#the-book&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the content of &amp;ldquo;A Verdade Sufocada,&amp;rdquo; explaining that it presents the military&amp;rsquo;s version of events during the Brazilian dictatorship, emphasizing attacks by leftist groups. The author&amp;rsquo;s wife, a historian, collaborated on the book, providing context related to the Cold War.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;criticism&#34;&gt;Criticism &lt;a href=&#34;#criticism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the criticisms leveled against &amp;ldquo;A Verdade Sufocada.&amp;rdquo; Luciano Oliveira, a sociology professor, deems the book historically worthless but acknowledges its value as confirmation of the disgracefulness of torture. Neusah Cerveira, a historian, points out the lack of explicit bibliographic citations and describes the book as superficial despite its length and strong title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bibliography&#34;&gt;Bibliography &lt;a href=&#34;#bibliography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists academic works that reference or analyze &amp;ldquo;A Verdade Sufocada.&amp;rdquo; These include studies on persuasive communication as a strategy for controlling collective memory, discursive strategies of perpetrators of the Brazilian military dictatorship, and the portrayal of the left by the right in books written by military personnel involved in repression during the dictatorship. The listed authors are Fernando Cibelli de Castro, Fabricio Fernandes, and Clarissa Grahl dos Santos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics and figures, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Torture Never Again:&lt;/strong&gt; An organization or movement opposed to torture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List of people killed by and disappeared during the Brazilian military dictatorship:&lt;/strong&gt; A record of victims of the regime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Securing Sex:&lt;/strong&gt; A potentially related book or study.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sérgio Paranhos Fleury:&lt;/strong&gt; A controversial figure associated with repression during the dictatorship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ternuma:&lt;/strong&gt; Possibly a military unit or operation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vladimir Herzog:&lt;/strong&gt; A journalist whose death under torture became a symbol of resistance against the dictatorship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited within the article, providing specific details about each source, including authors, titles, publishers, publication dates, and URLs where available. These references support the information presented in the article and allow readers to verify the claims made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the official website/blog associated with the book, maintained by Joseíta Brilhante Ustra, the author&amp;rsquo;s widow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Verdade_Sufocada&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Verdade_Sufocada&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
