<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UFO Flaps on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ufo-flaps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UFO Flaps on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ufo-flaps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO flap</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_3c67de8f7353/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_3c67de8f7353/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-flap&#34;&gt;UFO Flap &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-flap&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A UFO flap refers to a sudden increase in reports of unidentified flying objects (UFOs). The term &amp;ldquo;flap,&amp;rdquo; originally a military term for a period of panic or chaos, is used by ufologists to describe surges of sightings in a specific geographical area. Larger surges spanning multiple countries are sometimes called &amp;ldquo;waves.&amp;rdquo; The frequency of UFO sightings, public interest, and news coverage varies significantly. The terms UFO, flap, and wave allow for the discussion of various unrelated phenomena in the night sky as if they are part of the same aerial event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt; journalist Sarah Scoles traced the origin of the term &amp;ldquo;UFO flap&amp;rdquo; to the 1947 flying saucer craze, which began with Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting. Edward Ruppelt, an Air Force officer involved in governmental UFO investigations, defined &amp;ldquo;flap&amp;rdquo; in Air Force terminology as a state of confusion that hasn&amp;rsquo;t reached panic. Scoles suggests that even without Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting, a similar event would have occurred due to the cultural climate of the time, characterized by fear of outsiders, fear of invasions, and awe of technology. UFO flaps can be intensified by hoaxers exploiting the increased interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notable-flaps&#34;&gt;Notable Flaps &lt;a href=&#34;#notable-flaps&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists specific instances of UFO flaps throughout history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mystery airship wave of 1896–1897:&lt;/strong&gt; A series of sightings of mysterious airships across the United States.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foo fighters of World War II:&lt;/strong&gt; Reports of unusual aerial phenomena by military pilots during World War II.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ghost rockets of 1946:&lt;/strong&gt; Sightings of unidentified rocket-like objects over Sweden and Finland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947 flying disc craze:&lt;/strong&gt; A surge of UFO sightings in the United States, triggered by Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting. Key events include the Kenneth Arnold UFO sighting, Flight 105 UFO sighting, the Roswell incident, the Rhodes photographs, the Twin Falls saucer hoax, and the Maury Island hoax.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952 UFO Flap:&lt;/strong&gt; A significant increase in UFO sightings, including the Wonsan-Sunchon UFO incident, the publication of &amp;ldquo;Have We Visitors From Space?&amp;rdquo;, the Passaic UFO photographs, the 1952 Washington, D.C., UFO incident, and the release of &amp;ldquo;The Report on Unidentified Flying Objects.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Great 1954 Greek UFO flap:&lt;/strong&gt; A period of heightened UFO activity in Greece.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michigan &amp;ldquo;swamp gas&amp;rdquo; UFO reports:&lt;/strong&gt; A series of UFO sightings in Michigan, later attributed to swamp gas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1967 UFO flap in Britain:&lt;/strong&gt; A surge of UFO sightings in the United Kingdom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1977 Colares flap:&lt;/strong&gt; A series of UFO sightings and alleged encounters in Brazil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1984 Hudson Valley UFO sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; A wave of UFO sightings in the Hudson Valley region of the United States.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gulf Breeze UFO incident of 1987–88:&lt;/strong&gt; A controversial series of UFO sightings and photographs in Gulf Breeze, Florida.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Belgian UFO wave of 1989–90:&lt;/strong&gt; A large number of UFO sightings, including triangular-shaped objects, over Belgium.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1994 Michigan UFO event:&lt;/strong&gt; A widely reported UFO sighting in Michigan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phoenix Lights of 1997:&lt;/strong&gt; A mass sighting of unidentified lights over Phoenix, Arizona.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2024 Northeastern United States drone sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; Recent reports of drone sightings in the Northeastern United States.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See Also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists related topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extraterrestrial hypothesis:&lt;/strong&gt; The idea that UFO reports are best explained as interplanetary or interstellar spacecraft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psychosocial hypothesis:&lt;/strong&gt; The idea that UFO reports are best explained by social contagion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UFO conspiracy theories:&lt;/strong&gt; Theories that governments or other organizations are concealing information about UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_flap&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_flap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
