<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alien Abduction on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/alien-abduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alien Abduction on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:25:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/alien-abduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien abduction</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_85a477e6d898/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_85a477e6d898/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-abduction&#34;&gt;Alien Abduction &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-abduction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alien abduction, also known as abduction phenomenon, alien abduction syndrome, or UFO abduction, is the subjective experience of individuals reporting being kidnapped by extraterrestrial beings and subjected to physical and psychological experimentation. Those who claim to have been abducted are referred to as &amp;ldquo;abductees&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;experiencers.&amp;rdquo; The prevailing scientific and mental health perspective attributes these experiences to factors like suggestibility, sleep paralysis, deception, and psychopathology. Skeptics note similarities between alien descriptions and those in science fiction films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mainstream scientists generally dismiss claims of literal alien abduction. However, some researchers, like psychiatrist John E. Mack, argue that many abductees are sane individuals. A subculture has developed around the phenomenon, complete with support groups and a detailed mythos involving various alien types (Greys, Reptilians, Nordics) with specific roles and motivations. Some abductees explain the lack of wider awareness as a result of extraterrestrial or governmental cover-ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;paleo-abductions&#34;&gt;Paleo-abductions &lt;a href=&#34;#paleo-abductions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section discusses older stories that some UFO researchers, like Jerome Clark, have interpreted as possible early cases of alien abduction, termed &amp;ldquo;paleo-abductions.&amp;rdquo; Examples include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A November 27, 1896, report in &lt;em&gt;The Evening Mail&lt;/em&gt; of Stockton, California, where Colonel H. G. Shaw claimed he and a friend were harassed by tall, slender humanoids who tried to kidnap them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A 1953 &lt;em&gt;Man to Man Magazine&lt;/em&gt; article by Leroy Thorpe, questioning if humans were being captured by flying saucers for experimentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Harold T. Wilkins&amp;rsquo;s 1955 publication &lt;em&gt;Flying Saucers Uncensored&lt;/em&gt;, which reported the mysterious disappearance of Karl Hunrath and Wilbur Wilkinson, who had claimed contact with aliens, suggesting they might have been abducted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;two-landmark-cases&#34;&gt;Two Landmark Cases &lt;a href=&#34;#two-landmark-cases&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section highlights two early alien abduction claims that gained significant attention:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Antônio Vilas-Boas case in Brazil in the mid-1950s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Betty and Barney Hill abduction in 1961, which received widespread publicity and was dramatized in a 1975 television film. The Hill incident is considered a prototypical abduction case, introducing the beings later known as the Greys and explicitly identifying an extraterrestrial origin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skeptic Peter Rogerson notes that these cases established a template for later abduction reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;later-developments&#34;&gt;Later Developments &lt;a href=&#34;#later-developments&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the evolution of the alien abduction phenomenon and the involvement of key figures:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R. Leo Sprinkle, a University of Wyoming psychologist, became interested in abductions in the 1960s and linked them to cattle mutilation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Budd Hopkins, an artist interested in UFOs, began using hypnosis in the 1970s to uncover details of abduction experiences, becoming a figurehead in the abductee subculture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 1980s saw increased mainstream attention, with works by Hopkins, Whitley Strieber, David M. Jacobs, and John E. Mack presenting alien abduction as a plausible experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thomas E. Bullard&amp;rsquo;s comparative analysis of nearly 300 alleged abductees was also published in the 1980s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jacobs and Hopkins argued that alien abduction was far more common than previously suspected and that aliens were attempting to create human-alien hybrids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Linda Rodriguez McRobbie of the &lt;em&gt;Boston Globe&lt;/em&gt;, abduction stories have declined in mainstream media in recent decades. Michael Shermer suggests that camera phones have increased the burden of evidence for such claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;john-e-mack&#34;&gt;John E. Mack &lt;a href=&#34;#john-e-mack&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on Harvard psychiatry professor John E. Mack, who believed in the credibility of alien abduction claims. Niall Boyce, writing in &lt;em&gt;The Lancet&lt;/em&gt;, criticized Mack for uncritically elaborating on abduction tales and potentially creating false memories. Mack interviewed over 800 people and wrote two books on the subject, but his professional reputation suffered as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abductees&#34;&gt;Abductees &lt;a href=&#34;#abductees&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the demographics and mental health of alleged abductees. The precise number of abductees is uncertain, with estimates ranging from 1,700 claimants in early studies to 5–6 percent of the general population in contested surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;demographics&#34;&gt;Demographics &lt;a href=&#34;#demographics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reports are usually made by adults, but sometimes young children report similar experiences. These child-reports often feature very specific details in common with reports of abduction made by adults, including the circumstances, narrative, entities and aftermaths of the alleged occurrences. Often, these young abductees have family members who have reported having abduction experiences. Family involvement in the military, or a residence near a military base is also common among child abduction claimants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mental-health&#34;&gt;Mental Health &lt;a href=&#34;#mental-health&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some studies suggest that abductees have psychological characteristics that render their testimony suspect, while others show that &amp;ldquo;as a group, abduction experients are not different from the general population in term of psychopathology prevalence&amp;rdquo;. Elizabeth Slater conducted a blind study of nine abduction claimants and found them to be prone to &amp;ldquo;mildly paranoid thinking&amp;rdquo;, nightmares and having a weak sexual identity, while Richard McNally of Harvard Medical School concluded in a similar study of 10 abductees that &amp;ldquo;none of them was suffering from any sort of psychiatric illness.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;political-conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;Political Conspiracy Theories &lt;a href=&#34;#political-conspiracy-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section explores the connections between radical politics and conspiracy theories involving UFOs, alien visitation, and government cover-ups. Political scientist Michael Barkun highlights the rise of &amp;ldquo;improvisional millenarism&amp;rdquo; and the role of UFO and abduction stories in stigmatized knowledge narratives. He notes the emergence of alien-related conspiracy theories in far-right politics from the 1980s onwards. TV shows like &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt; are mentioned as examples of popular culture incorporating alien conspiracies. Jodi Dean notes that the stigma of alien abduction stories is seductive to dismiss &amp;ldquo;consensus reality&amp;rdquo; in favor of deviant alternative realities. Self-described abduction victims may join self-help communities and espouse conspiracy theories involving mind control and a New World Order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abduction-narrative&#34;&gt;Abduction Narrative &lt;a href=&#34;#abduction-narrative&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the common elements and sequence of events reported in abduction narratives. According to CUFOS&amp;rsquo;s definition of &lt;em&gt;abductee&lt;/em&gt;, the person must have been taken against their will by apparent non-human beings, taken to a special place perceived as extraterrestrial or to be a spaceship. They then must experience being subjected to an examination or to engage in some form of communication with the beings (or both). Communication may be perceived as telepathic rather than verbal. The memory of the experience may be conscious or &amp;ldquo;recovered&amp;rdquo; through means like hypnosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas E. Bullard argues that there is a broad, fairly consistent sequence and description of events that make up the typical &amp;ldquo;close encounter of the fourth kind.&amp;rdquo; These events include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capture:&lt;/strong&gt; The abductee is rendered incapable of resisting and taken to an alien spacecraft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Examination and Procedures:&lt;/strong&gt; Invasive physiological and psychological procedures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conference:&lt;/strong&gt; Communication with the abductors, typically telepathically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tour:&lt;/strong&gt; A tour of the captors&amp;rsquo; vessel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loss of Time:&lt;/strong&gt; Rapid forgetting of the experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Return:&lt;/strong&gt; Return to Earth, sometimes in a different location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theophany:&lt;/strong&gt; A profound sense of love or a mystical experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aftermath:&lt;/strong&gt; Coping with the psychological, physical, and social effects of the experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David M. Jacobs emphasizes the orchestrated nature of the abduction event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;capture&#34;&gt;Capture &lt;a href=&#34;#capture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abduction claimants report unusual feelings preceding the onset of an abduction experience. These feelings manifest as a compulsive desire to be at a certain place at a certain time or as expectations that something &amp;ldquo;familiar yet unknown&amp;rdquo; will soon occur. Abductees also report feeling severe, undirected anxiety at this point even though nothing unusual has actually occurred yet. Eventually, the experiencer will undergo an apparent &amp;ldquo;shift&amp;rdquo; into an altered state of consciousness. As consciousness shifts one or more lights are alleged to appear, occasionally accompanied by a strange mist. As the alleged abduction proceeds, claimants say they will walk or be levitated into an alien craft, in the latter case often through solid objects such as walls, ceilings or a closed window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;examination&#34;&gt;Examination &lt;a href=&#34;#examination&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The examination phase is characterized by medical procedures and examinations performed by alien beings against the will of the experiencer. These procedures often focus on sex and reproductive biology. John G. Miller notes differences between human medicine and what is reported as being practiced by the abductors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;subsequent-procedures&#34;&gt;Subsequent Procedures &lt;a href=&#34;#subsequent-procedures&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the medical exam, abductees often report other procedures, including imaging, envisioning, staging, and testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Imaging&amp;rdquo; involves viewing screens displaying emotionally provocative images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Envisioning&amp;rdquo; involves images projected into the experiencer&amp;rsquo;s mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Staging&amp;rdquo; involves the abductee interacting with an illusionary scenario.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Testing&amp;rdquo; involves operating a complicated electronic device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;child-presentation&#34;&gt;Child Presentation &lt;a href=&#34;#child-presentation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abductees sometimes report being shown a &amp;ldquo;child&amp;rdquo; who appears to be a hybrid between humans and their abductors. Thomas E. Bullard could not identify a child presentation phase in the abduction narrative, even after undertaking a study of 300 abduction reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;less-common-elements&#34;&gt;Less Common Elements &lt;a href=&#34;#less-common-elements&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bullard&amp;rsquo;s study of 300 abduction reports also identified less prominent aspects of the claims, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The conference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The journey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theophany&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These episodes tend to happen between the medical examination and the return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;return&#34;&gt;Return &lt;a href=&#34;#return&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_abduction&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_abduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
