<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unexplained Phenomena on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/unexplained-phenomena/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unexplained Phenomena on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/unexplained-phenomena/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>List of reported UFO sightings</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_87427e94ae10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_87427e94ae10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-reported-ufo-sightings&#34;&gt;List of Reported UFO Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-reported-ufo-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Wikipedia page serves as a dynamic list of notable reported sightings of Unidentified Flying Objects (UFOs), also referred to as Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena (UAP). It includes instances with claims of close encounters and alien abduction. The list acknowledges that most UFOs are eventually identified as known objects or phenomena, but a small percentage remain unexplained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;antiquity&#34;&gt;Antiquity &lt;a href=&#34;#antiquity&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details alleged UFO sightings from ancient times, drawing from historical texts and records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c. 1450 BC: Tulli Papyrus:&lt;/strong&gt; Describes an event during Thutmose III&amp;rsquo;s reign in Ancient Egypt, where a &amp;ldquo;star came down&amp;rdquo; and set fire to his adversaries. The account is based on the Tulli Papyrus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;218 BC: Ships in the sky:&lt;/strong&gt; A &amp;ldquo;phantom navy&amp;rdquo; was seen shining in the sky over Italia during the Roman Republic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;76 BC: Spark from a falling star:&lt;/strong&gt; A spark fell from a star in Asia (Roman province), grew to the size of the Moon, ascended, and transformed into a torch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;73 BC: Flame-like wine-jars from the sky:&lt;/strong&gt; During a battle between Lucullus and Mithridates VI of Pontus in Phrygia, a &amp;ldquo;huge, flame-like body&amp;rdquo; shaped like a wine-jar (pithos) fell between the two armies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AD 65: Sky army:&lt;/strong&gt; Flavius Josephus reported chariots &amp;ldquo;hurtling through the clouds&amp;rdquo; over Judaea before the First Jewish–Roman War.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AD 196: Angel hair:&lt;/strong&gt; Cassius Dio described a &amp;ldquo;fine rain resembling silver&amp;rdquo; descending from a clear sky upon the Forum of Augustus in Rome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;8th-century&#34;&gt;8th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#8th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a single entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AD c. 740: Air ship of Clonmacnoise:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;Ships with their crews were seen in the air&amp;rdquo; over Teltown and Clonmacnoise in Ireland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;16th17th-centuries&#34;&gt;16th–17th Centuries &lt;a href=&#34;#16th17th-centuries&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details alleged UFO sightings from the 16th and 17th centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1561: Celestial phenomenon over Nuremberg:&lt;/strong&gt; An aerial battle followed by the appearance of a black spear and hundreds of spheres and cylinders moving erratically over Nuremberg, Bavaria.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1566: Celestial phenomenon over Basel:&lt;/strong&gt; A broadsheet depicted numerous spherical objects appearing out of the sun over Basel, Switzerland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1609: Gwanghaegun period UFO Turmoil:&lt;/strong&gt; Multiple witnesses in Joseon (Korea) described a Halo or washbowl that was divided in two in the sky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;19th-century&#34;&gt;19th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#19th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details alleged UFO sightings from the 19th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1883: Bonilla observation:&lt;/strong&gt; Astronomer José Bonilla photographed hundreds of dark objects crossing the sun at Zacatecas Observatory in Mexico.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1896-1897: Mystery airships:&lt;/strong&gt; Reports of strange airships and lights appeared in newspapers across California and other states. Descriptions included bright lights, cigar-shaped bodies, movable wings, and metallic hulls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1897: Aurora, Texas, UFO incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Local correspondent S.E. Hayden reported the crash of an airship piloted by an alien in Aurora, Texas. The pilot was allegedly buried in the local cemetery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;20th-century&#34;&gt;20th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#20th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details alleged UFO sightings from the 20th century, split into two subsections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;19001949&#34;&gt;1900–1949 &lt;a href=&#34;#19001949&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1904: USS &lt;em&gt;Supply&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Three &amp;ldquo;bright red&amp;rdquo; objects in geometrical formation flight pattern were observed by three crew members about 300 miles from California.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1907: Mihal Grameno UFO:&lt;/strong&gt; Albanian fighters stationed on a mountain top witnessed a shiny object suspended in the air.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1909: New Zealand airship sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; Moving and whirring lights were reported in the sky around Otago, New Zealand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1917: Miracle of the Sun:&lt;/strong&gt; Thousands of people in Fátima, Portugal, claimed to see bizarre solar activity, later interpreted as a mass UFO sighting by some.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1926: Nicholas Roerich UFO sighting:&lt;/strong&gt; Nicholas Roerich reported an oval in the sky above his caravan in Tibet, later interpreted as a &amp;ldquo;flying saucer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1933: Frank Smythe UFO sighting:&lt;/strong&gt; Frank Smythe witnessed two spots hovering and pulsating in the sky during the 1933 Mount Everest expedition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1940s: Foo fighters:&lt;/strong&gt; Allied fighter pilots reported colorful balls of light following their aircraft at high speeds over Europe during World War II.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1941: Cape Girardeau UFO legend:&lt;/strong&gt; A local legend tells of a crashed flying saucer near Cape Girardeau, Missouri, where a reverend administered last rites to the dying crew.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1942: Battle of Los Angeles:&lt;/strong&gt; U.S. radar stations picked up an unidentified aerial object, leading to anti-aircraft artillery firing thousands of rounds over Los Angeles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1942: Army Air Corps Flying School:&lt;/strong&gt; Control tower operator observes two reddish colored round objects descend-hover-accelerate away near Columbus, Missouri.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1944: 468th Bomb Group:&lt;/strong&gt; An object of &amp;ldquo;intense red or orange&amp;rdquo; color followed a bomber for about 8 minutes near Palembang, Sumatra.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1945: Trinity UFO Case:&lt;/strong&gt; Conflicting accounts emerged of an avocado-shaped craft piloted by insectoid aliens crashing at the site of the first atomic bomb detonation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1946: The Ghost Rockets:&lt;/strong&gt; Thousands of UFO sightings were reported over Europe, leading to investigations by the Swedish and Greek governments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1946: Ängelholm UFO memorial:&lt;/strong&gt; Swedish entrepreneur Gösta Carlsson attributed his success to a 1946 UFO encounter, commemorated with a monument in Ängelholm, Sweden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947: Kenneth Arnold UFO sighting:&lt;/strong&gt; Private pilot Kenneth Arnold reported seeing a group of reflective craft moving at high speeds near Mount Rainier, Washington, coining the term &amp;ldquo;flying saucers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947: 1947 flying disc craze:&lt;/strong&gt; Over 800 similar sightings were reported after the Kenneth Arnold sighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947: Flight 105 UFO sighting:&lt;/strong&gt; A United Airlines crew witnessed nine unidentified objects en route from Boise, Idaho, to Pendleton, Oregon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947: Rhodes UFO photographs:&lt;/strong&gt; William Albert Rhodes took photographs of a silent grey object in Phoenix, Arizona.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947: The Roswell Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; A press release announced the &amp;ldquo;capture&amp;rdquo; of a &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; near Roswell, New Mexico, later explained as a crashed weather balloon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947: Maury Island hoax:&lt;/strong&gt; Fred Crisman mailed an account of a UFO encounter to Raymond A. Palmer, claiming his dog was killed and his son injured by debris.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948: The Green Fireballs:&lt;/strong&gt; Reports of green flares streaking across the sky were investigated by the US Air Force.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948: Mantell UFO incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Captain Thomas F. Mantell died in the crash of his P-51 Mustang fighter plane near Franklin, Kentucky, after being sent in pursuit of an unidentified flying object.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948: Aztec, New Mexico UFO hoax:&lt;/strong&gt; Conmen Silas Newton and Leo Gebauer sold &amp;ldquo;magnetic oil-detecting machines&amp;rdquo; based on a story about replicated technology from a crashed spaceship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948: Chiles-Whitted UFO encounter:&lt;/strong&gt; Clarence Chiles and John Whitted, commercial pilots, reported that their airplane had nearly collided with a UFO near Montgomery, Alabama.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948: Gorman dogfight:&lt;/strong&gt; A US Air Force pilot sighted and pursued a UFO for 27 minutes over Fargo, North Dakota.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;19501974&#34;&gt;1950–1974 &lt;a href=&#34;#19501974&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1950: McMinnville UFO photographs:&lt;/strong&gt; A farmer took pictures of a purported &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; near McMinnville, Oregon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1950: Mariana UFO incident:&lt;/strong&gt; The manager of Great Falls&amp;rsquo; pro baseball team took color film of two UFOs flying over Great Falls, Montana.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1951: Sioux City mystery plane incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Two pilots and a military officer passenger aboard a commercial DC-3 reported being buzzed by an unidentified straight-winged plane over Sioux City, Iowa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1951: Lubbock Lights:&lt;/strong&gt; Several lights in V-shaped formations were repeatedly spotted flying over Lubbock, Texas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952: Wonsan-Sunchon UFO incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Four American military personnel aboard two different B-29 bombers reported seeing an orange globe-shaped light over two different cities in northern Korea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952: Washington, D.C. UFO incident:&lt;/strong&gt; A series of sightings accompanied radar contacts in the Washington, D.C. area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952: Nash-Fortenberry UFO sighting:&lt;/strong&gt; William B. Nash and William H. Fortenberry, pilots of a DC-4 airliner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_reported_UFO_sightings&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_reported_UFO_sightings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
