<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UFO Sightings on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ufo-sightings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UFO Sightings on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 17:06:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ufo-sightings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in the United States</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8d3b71993ef9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 17:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8d3b71993ef9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-the-united-states&#34;&gt;List of Alleged UFO Sightings in the United States &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-the-united-states&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a comprehensive list of alleged UFO sightings in the United States, presented in a tabular format. Each entry includes the date, city, state, a link to a main article if available, and a brief description of the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;table-of-sightings&#34;&gt;Table of Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#table-of-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This table details numerous alleged UFO sightings across the United States, spanning from the late 19th century to recent years. Key information includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; Reports from the late 1800s, such as the 1865 Cadotte Pass incident in Montana involving a trapper&amp;rsquo;s account of a crashed craft with hieroglyphics, and the 1896-1897 mystery airship sightings across multiple states. The Aurora, Texas, UFO incident in 1897 is also noted, where residents claimed an airship crashed and an alien pilot was buried in the local cemetery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mid-20th Century Incidents:&lt;/strong&gt; Significant events like the 1942 Battle of Los Angeles, initially mistaken for a Japanese attack, and the 1945 Trinity UFO Case in New Mexico, where boys reported a crashed &amp;ldquo;avocado-shaped&amp;rdquo; object with insect-like creatures. The 1947 Maury Island incident in Washington, predating Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting, and the famous Roswell UFO incident in New Mexico are also included. Other notable cases are the 1948 Mantell Incident in Kentucky, the Chiles-Whitted UFO Encounter in Alabama, and the Gorman Dogfight in North Dakota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1950s and 1960s Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; The 1950 McMinnville UFO photographs in Oregon, the 1950 Sperry sighting in Maryland, the 1951 Lubbock Lights in Texas, and the 1952 Washington D.C. UFO incident are listed. The 1952 Flatwoods monster sighting in West Virginia, the 1953 Felix Moncla incident over Lake Superior, the 1957 Levelland UFO case in Texas, the 1961 Betty and Barney Hill abduction in New Hampshire, the 1964 Lonnie Zamora incident in New Mexico, the 1965 Exeter incident in New Hampshire, and the 1965 Kecksburg UFO incident in Pennsylvania are also included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Late 20th Century and Early 21st Century Incidents:&lt;/strong&gt; The 1969 Jimmy Carter UFO incident in Georgia, the 1973 Pascagoula Abduction in Mississippi, the 1975 Stonehenge incident in New Jersey, the 1975 Travis Walton UFO incident in Arizona, the 1977 Council Bluffs, Iowa fireball, the 1979 Val Johnson incident in Minnesota, the 1980 Cash-Landrum incident in Texas, the 1987 Gulf Breeze UFO incident in Florida, the 1994 Lake Michigan UFO event, and the 1997 Phoenix Lights in Arizona and Nevada are listed. More recent sightings include the 2000 Highland, Illinois &amp;ldquo;Black Triangle&amp;rdquo; sighting, the 2004 Chicago sightings, the 2006 Chicago O&amp;rsquo;Hare UFO sighting, the 2009 Morristown UFO hoax in New Jersey, the 2018 Arizona desert sighting, the 2021 Clayton, New Mexico sighting, and the 2023 Alaska and Lake Huron high-altitude object incidents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to related Wikipedia articles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List of reported UFO sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; A broader list of UFO sightings from around the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psychological perspectives on UFO belief:&lt;/strong&gt; An exploration of the psychological factors influencing beliefs about UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists the citations used to support the information presented in the article. These references include news articles, books, and reports from various sources, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think AboutIts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University of California Press&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Southern Illinois University Press&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;San Francisco virtual museum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hancock House Publishers Ltd.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oxford University Press&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indiana University Press&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doubleday &amp;amp; Company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Oregonian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project 1947&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;National UFO Reporting Center&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Village Voice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hudson Reporter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Star-Ledger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Historical and Preservation Society of Pottawattamie County&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CNN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chicago Tribune&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LiveScience.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Newsweek&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skeptics Society&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fortune&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forbes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reuters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ABC News&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The New York Times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Observer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CNN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ABC7 Chicago&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helena Independent Record&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Politico&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section is currently empty, suggesting there are no external links provided in the original article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_the_United_States&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_the_United_States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
