<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Play on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/play/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Play on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 03:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/play/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zanfretta UFO Incident</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7f4eecfa5008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7f4eecfa5008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;zanfretta-ufo-abduction&#34;&gt;Zanfretta UFO Abduction &lt;a href=&#34;#zanfretta-ufo-abduction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Zanfretta UFO incident is an alleged alien encounter involving Italian nightwatchman Pier Fortunato Zanfretta, who claimed to have been abducted multiple times between 1978 and 1981.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-encounter&#34;&gt;Initial encounter &lt;a href=&#34;#initial-encounter&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 6, 1978, at approximately 23:30, Zanfretta was inspecting the villa &amp;ldquo;Casa Nostra&amp;rdquo; in Marzano di Torriglia, Genoa, when he encountered a large, red, oval object. He contacted his supervisor, who reported hearing Zanfretta scream before communication was lost. Zanfretta claimed to have encountered tall beings with mottled skin, yellow triangular eyes, and clawed feet, exclaiming they were not men. He was later found unconscious and in shock. Under hypnosis, Zanfretta described being taken aboard the alien craft into a bright room. He further detailed the beings as green with triangular yellow eyes, thorns, wrinkled skin, iron-like mouths, red veins, pointed ears, and clawed hands, claiming they were from the &amp;ldquo;third galaxy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aftermath&#34;&gt;Aftermath &lt;a href=&#34;#aftermath&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incident gained notoriety after Zanfretta appeared on the show &lt;em&gt;Portobello&lt;/em&gt; to share his story. The Carabinieri launched an investigation and found 52 witnesses who claimed to have seen the UFO. One witness reported seeing the craft at 19:30 on December 6, hovering at approximately 1,500 meters. Investigators found a horseshoe-shaped impression, about 2 meters in diameter, at the location where Zanfretta claimed the craft had landed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Zanfretta case was adapted into a play titled &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Loro– Storia vera del più famoso rapimento alieno in Italia&amp;rdquo; (The True Story of the Most Famous Alien Abduction in Italy)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zanfretta_UFO_Incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zanfretta_UFO_Incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
