<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unexplained on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/unexplained/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unexplained on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/unexplained/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>List of reported UFO sightings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_3778b5598b1f/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_3778b5598b1f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-reported-ufo-sightings&#34;&gt;List of Reported UFO Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-reported-ufo-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Wikipedia article provides a compilation of notable reported sightings of Unidentified Flying Objects (UFOs), including claims of close encounters and alien abduction. It clarifies that UFOs encompass any aerial phenomenon that cannot be immediately identified, noting that most are eventually explained as known objects or atmospheric phenomena. The article also mentions the use of the term &amp;ldquo;Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena&amp;rdquo; (UAP) to avoid associations with UFO conspiracy theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;antiquity&#34;&gt;Antiquity &lt;a href=&#34;#antiquity&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details alleged UFO sightings from ancient times, drawing from historical texts and records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c. 1450 BC:&lt;/strong&gt; The Tulli Papyrus describes a &amp;ldquo;star&amp;rdquo; that came down and set fire to enemies of Thutmose III during a battle in Ancient Egypt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;218 BC:&lt;/strong&gt; Mentions &amp;ldquo;ships in the sky&amp;rdquo; reported over Italia in the Roman Republic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;76 BC:&lt;/strong&gt; Describes a &amp;ldquo;spark from a star&amp;rdquo; that grew to the size of the Moon over Asia in the Roman Republic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;73 BC:&lt;/strong&gt; Plutarch&amp;rsquo;s account of a &amp;ldquo;flame-like body&amp;rdquo; resembling a wine-jar falling between Roman and Pontic armies in Phrygia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AD 65:&lt;/strong&gt; Flavius Josephus&amp;rsquo;s report of chariots &amp;ldquo;hurtling through the clouds&amp;rdquo; over Judaea before the First Jewish-Roman War.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AD 196:&lt;/strong&gt; Cassius Dio&amp;rsquo;s description of a &amp;ldquo;fine rain resembling silver&amp;rdquo; falling on the Forum of Augustus in Rome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;8th-century&#34;&gt;8th century &lt;a href=&#34;#8th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section includes a single entry:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AD c. 740:&lt;/strong&gt; The &amp;ldquo;Air ship of Clonmacnoise&amp;rdquo; describes &amp;ldquo;ships with their crews were seen in the air&amp;rdquo; over Ireland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;16th17th-centuries&#34;&gt;16th–17th centuries &lt;a href=&#34;#16th17th-centuries&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers reports from the Renaissance and early modern periods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1561:&lt;/strong&gt; The 1561 celestial phenomenon over Nuremberg describes an aerial battle with spheres, cylinders, and other objects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1566:&lt;/strong&gt; The 1566 celestial phenomenon over Basel depicts spherical objects appearing out of the sun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1609:&lt;/strong&gt; Mentions UFO turmoil during the Gwanghaegun period in Joseon (Korea), with multiple witnesses describing a divided &amp;ldquo;halo&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;washbowl&amp;rdquo; in the sky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;19th-century&#34;&gt;19th century &lt;a href=&#34;#19th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists sightings from the 1800s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1883:&lt;/strong&gt; The Bonilla observation involves astronomer José Bonilla photographing hundreds of dark objects crossing the sun in Mexico.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1896-1897:&lt;/strong&gt; The Mystery airships wave across the United States, with reports of strange airships and lights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1897:&lt;/strong&gt; The Aurora, Texas, UFO incident, where a local correspondent reported the crash of an airship piloted by an alien.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;20th-century&#34;&gt;20th century &lt;a href=&#34;#20th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is divided into two sub-sections: 1900-1949 and 1950-1974.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;19001949&#34;&gt;1900–1949 &lt;a href=&#34;#19001949&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1904:&lt;/strong&gt; USS &lt;em&gt;Supply&lt;/em&gt; sighting of three red objects in geometrical formation flight pattern in the North Pacific.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1907:&lt;/strong&gt; Mihal Grameno UFO sighting in Albania, where a shiny object was seen hovering in the air.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1909:&lt;/strong&gt; New Zealand airship sightings, with reports of moving lights and whirring sounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1917:&lt;/strong&gt; The Miracle of the Sun in Fátima, Portugal, interpreted by some as a mass UFO sighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1926:&lt;/strong&gt; Nicholas Roerich UFO sighting in Tibet, describing an oval object in the sky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1933:&lt;/strong&gt; Frank Smythe UFO sighting on Mount Everest, witnessing two spots hovering in the sky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1940s:&lt;/strong&gt; Foo fighters reported by Allied fighter pilots during World War II.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1941:&lt;/strong&gt; Cape Girardeau UFO legend, involving a crashed flying saucer and dying crew.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1942:&lt;/strong&gt; The Battle of Los Angeles, where U.S. radar stations picked up an unidentified aerial object.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1942:&lt;/strong&gt; Army Air Corps Flying School near Columbus, Missouri, control tower operator observes two reddish colored round objects descend-hover-accelerate away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1944:&lt;/strong&gt; 468th Bomb Group returning from a bombing mission at an altitude of 14000 feet, speed &amp;ldquo;about 210 mph&amp;rdquo;: 500 yards (about 457 meters) from the starboard an object appeared which the pilot estimated at the distance viewed was &amp;ldquo;probably 5-6 feet in diameter&amp;rdquo; (1.5-1.8 meters) - &amp;ldquo;intense red or orange&amp;rdquo; color - throbbed or vibrated constantly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1945:&lt;/strong&gt; Trinity UFO Case, involving a crashed avocado-shaped craft piloted by insectoid aliens at the site of the first atomic bomb detonation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1946:&lt;/strong&gt; The Ghost Rockets sightings over Europe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1946:&lt;/strong&gt; Ängelholm UFO memorial in Sweden, commemorating a 1946 UFO encounter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; Kenneth Arnold UFO sighting near Mount Rainier, sparking the term &amp;ldquo;flying saucers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; The 1947 flying disc craze, with over 800 similar sightings reported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; Flight 105 UFO sighting, where a United Airlines crew witnessed nine unidentified objects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; Rhodes UFO photographs taken in Phoenix, Arizona.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; The Roswell Incident, involving the &amp;ldquo;capture&amp;rdquo; of a &amp;ldquo;flying saucer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; Maury Island hoax, involving claims of flying doughnut-shaped objects and threats from Men in Black.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; The Green Fireballs sightings across the Southwestern United States.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; Mantell UFO incident, where Captain Thomas F. Mantell died in a plane crash while pursuing a UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; Aztec, New Mexico UFO hoax, involving conmen selling &amp;ldquo;magnetic oil-detecting machines&amp;rdquo; based on a crashed spaceship story.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; Chiles-Whitted UFO encounter, where commercial pilots reported a near-collision with a UFO near Montgomery, Alabama.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; Gorman dogfight, where a US Air Force pilot pursued a UFO over Fargo, North Dakota.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;19501974&#34;&gt;1950–1974 &lt;a href=&#34;#19501974&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1950:&lt;/strong&gt; McMinnville UFO photographs taken in Oregon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1950:&lt;/strong&gt; Mariana UFO incident, where the manager of a baseball team filmed two UFOs over Great Falls, Montana.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1951:&lt;/strong&gt; Sioux City mystery plane incident, involving pilots and a military officer being buzzed by an unidentified plane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1951:&lt;/strong&gt; Lubbock Lights, with lights in V-shaped formations spotted over Lubbock, Texas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952:&lt;/strong&gt; Wonsan-Sunchon UFO incident, where American military personnel reported seeing an orange globe-shaped light over Korea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952:&lt;/strong&gt; 1952 Washington, D.C. UFO incident, with sightings and radar contacts in the Washington area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952:&lt;/strong&gt; Nash-Fortenberry UFO sighting, where pilots reported eight large, round, glowing red objects over Norfolk, Virginia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952:&lt;/strong&gt; The Flatwoods Monster sighting in West Virginia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1954:&lt;/strong&gt; Marius Dewilde sighting in France, where a metalworker claimed to have become a contactee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1954:&lt;/strong&gt; Fiorentina Stadium mass sighting in Florence, Italy, where a football game was interrupted by a group of UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1955:&lt;/strong&gt; Kelly–Hopkinsville encounter, where eleven people witnessed creatures at a farmhouse in Kentucky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1956:&lt;/strong&gt; Lakenheath-Bentwaters incident, involving radar operators detecting objects over Suffolk, England.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1956:&lt;/strong&gt; Elizabeth Klarer claimed detailed adventures with an alien race including having had an alien lover, Akon, who would have fathered her son Ayling in South Africa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1957:&lt;/strong&gt; Gordon Cooper UFO Sightings, where one of the original Project Mercury astronauts witnessed a metallic craft without wings flying over Germany.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1957:&lt;/strong&gt; Milton Torres 1957 UFO Encounter, where a U.S. Air Force fighter pilot reports that he was ordered to intercept and fire on a UFO over East Anglia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1957:&lt;/strong&gt; Antônio Vilas-Boas Abduction in Brazil, where a law student described being abducted by humanoid aliens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1957:&lt;/strong&gt; Levelland UFO case, where drivers observed cigar-shaped lights above the highway in Texas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1957:&lt;/strong&gt; Kirtland AFB UFO sighting, where tower operators reported seeing an egg shape emitting a white light in New Mexico.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1961:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_major_UFO_sightings&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_major_UFO_sightings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
