<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ancient Texts on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ancient-texts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ancient Texts on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 08:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ancient-texts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ancient astronauts</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7253d7032fb2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 08:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7253d7032fb2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ancient-astronauts&#34;&gt;Ancient Astronauts &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-astronauts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ancient astronauts, also known as ancient aliens, is a pseudoscientific belief that intelligent extraterrestrial beings visited Earth in ancient times and influenced the development of human civilization. Proponents suggest that these aliens affected cultures, technologies, religions, and even human biology. A common idea is that deities in many religions were actually extraterrestrials, and their advanced technologies were seen as divine powers by early humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;claims&#34;&gt;Claims &lt;a href=&#34;#claims&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The central claim is that intelligent extraterrestrial life visited Earth in ancient times and significantly impacted human civilization. This idea is related to archaeology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;paranormal&#34;&gt;Paranormal &lt;a href=&#34;#paranormal&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists various paranormal topics, including astral projection, astrology, auras, clairvoyance, cryptozoology, demonic possession, fortune-telling, ghost hunting, magic, mediumship, miracles, the occult, psychic phenomena, reincarnation, spiritualism, telekinesis, ufology, and more. It also includes links to related topics like skepticism, parapsychology, anomalistics, and pseudoscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various terms are used to describe claims about ancient astronauts, including &amp;ldquo;ancient aliens,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;ancient ufonauts,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;paleocontact.&amp;rdquo; Believers often argue that humans are descendants or creations of extraterrestrial intelligence. They also suggest that human knowledge, religion, and culture originated from these ancient alien visitors, who acted as a &amp;ldquo;mother culture.&amp;rdquo; Proponents claim that extraterrestrials built or helped build structures like the Egyptian pyramids and the Moai statues of Easter Island. Evidence is drawn from perceived gaps in historical and archaeological records and interpretations of archaeological artifacts and artwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The History Channel series &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; is mentioned as an example of fringe media that promotes these ideas. The series is criticized for mixing fact with fiction and promoting theories that align with white supremacist, nativist, imperialist, settler-colonial, and Christian Identity beliefs. Proponents are often portrayed as mavericks fighting against a conspiracy by &amp;ldquo;big archaeology.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus on monumental structures is seen as implying that indigenous people could not have built them without alien help. However, some indigenous voices argue that the ancient alien theory supports their own stories of extraterrestrial origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common theme is the portrayal of aliens as light-skinned or Aryan, as seen in Erich von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; Some proponents are associated with white supremacism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainstream archaeologists have largely ignored these claims, but when addressed, they are universally rejected. Carl Sagan is quoted as saying that the cases cited by ancient astronaut proponents have reasonable alternative explanations, misrepresentations, or are outright fabrications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34;&gt;History of ancient aliens beliefs and their proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of paleocontact appeared in early science fiction and was later proposed by journalist Harold T. Wilkins in 1954. It gained popularity in the 1960s due to the Space Race and the works of Erich von Däniken. Critics emerged in the 1970s, discrediting Von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s claims, and by the early 1980s, the idea had little support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;shklovskii-and-sagan&#34;&gt;Shklovskii and Sagan &lt;a href=&#34;#shklovskii-and-sagan&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Sagan and Soviet astrophysicist Iosif Shklovsky co-authored &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Life in the Universe&lt;/em&gt; (1966). Sagan later expressed disapproval of writers like von Däniken who uncritically presented speculations about ancient astronauts as valid evidence. He argued that most evidence cited could be explained with conventional hypotheses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;erich-von-däniken&#34;&gt;Erich von Däniken &lt;a href=&#34;#erich-von-d%c3%a4niken&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erich von Däniken popularized the ancient astronaut hypothesis in the late 1960s and early 1970s with his book &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; He argued that certain artifacts, such as Stonehenge, Pumapunku, the Moai of Easter Island, the Great Pyramid of Giza, and the Baghdad Batteries, required more advanced technology than was available to ancient cultures. He also claimed that ancient art and iconography depict air and space vehicles, intelligent non-human creatures, and advanced technology. Von Däniken interpreted the origins of many religions as reactions to encounters with alien races.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critics argue that von Däniken misrepresented data and that his claims are unfounded. Christian creationists have also criticized his work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the Nazca Lines, von Däniken initially saw them as an airfield for spacecraft, exhibiting confirmation bias. Kenneth L. Feder argues that readers are more likely to associate such features with extraterrestrial origins when presented in a book about aliens. Von Däniken later admitted that the Nazca markings could have been created using a system of coordinates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;zecharia-sitchin&#34;&gt;Zecharia Sitchin &lt;a href=&#34;#zecharia-sitchin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zecharia Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Earth Chronicles&lt;/em&gt; series revolves around his interpretation of ancient Sumerian and Middle Eastern texts, megalithic sites, and artifacts. He hypothesized that the gods of ancient Mesopotamia were astronauts from the planet Nibiru, which he claimed the Sumerians believed to be a remote &amp;ldquo;12th planet.&amp;rdquo; According to Sitchin, the Anunnaki came to Earth approximately 400,000 years ago to mine raw materials, especially gold, and genetically engineered humans to work the mines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His work has not received mainstream scholarly support and has been criticized by professionals. Semitic languages scholar Michael S. Heiser says that Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s translations are inconsistent with Mesopotamian cuneiform dictionaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alan F. Alford, initially an adherent of Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s hypotheses, later found fault with them, stating that the gods personified the falling sky and that their descent was a poetic rendition of a cataclysm myth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;robert-temple&#34;&gt;Robert Temple &lt;a href=&#34;#robert-temple&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert K. G. Temple&amp;rsquo;s 1976 book, &lt;em&gt;The Sirius Mystery,&lt;/em&gt; argues that the Dogon people of Mali preserved an account of extraterrestrial visitation from around 5,000 years ago. He cites advanced astronomical knowledge, descriptions, and comparative belief systems as evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His conclusions have been criticized by scientists, who point out discrepancies and suggest that the Dogon may have received their astronomical information from European sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ufo-religions&#34;&gt;UFO religions &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-religions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various new religious movements, including some branches of Theosophy, Scientology, Raëlism, Aetherius Society, and Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate, believe in ancient and present-day contact with extraterrestrial intelligence. These faiths see ancient scriptures and recent revelations as connected with the action of aliens. Psychologists have found that UFO religions have similarities that suggest members associate enchantment with science fiction memes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;claims-of-proponents&#34;&gt;Claims of proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#claims-of-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientific consensus is that the ancient astronaut hypothesis is unjustified and unnecessary. The &amp;ldquo;mysteries&amp;rdquo; cited as evidence can be explained without invoking ancient astronauts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ancient-religious-texts&#34;&gt;Ancient religious texts &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-religious-texts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proponents cite ancient mythologies, interpreting creation myths of gods descending from the heavens as representations of alien visitors. They draw an analogy to cargo cults, where isolated cultures interpret advanced technology as sent from the gods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ancient Sumerian myth of &lt;em&gt;Enûma Eliš&lt;/em&gt; says humankind was created to serve gods called the &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Annunaki&lt;/em&gt;,&amp;rdquo; who proponents believe were aliens who came to Earth to mine gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;ramayana&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ramayana&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#ramayana&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Hindu mythology, gods and their avatars travel in flying vehicles called &lt;em&gt;Vimana&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;Ramayana&lt;/em&gt; contains mentions of these flying objects. Erich von Däniken discusses the &lt;em&gt;Ramayana&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;vimanas&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt;, suggesting that they were &amp;ldquo;space vehicles.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-bible&#34;&gt;The Bible &lt;a href=&#34;#the-bible&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;book-of-genesis-and-book-of-enoch&#34;&gt;Book of Genesis and Book of Enoch &lt;a href=&#34;#book-of-genesis-and-book-of-enoch&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Book of Genesis describes the &amp;ldquo;sons of God&amp;rdquo; marrying the &amp;ldquo;daughters of humans&amp;rdquo; and the emergence of the Nephilim. Ancient Astronaut proponents argue that Adam and Eve ate of the forbidden fruit &amp;ldquo;to be godlike,&amp;rdquo; marking the first step in human evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Book of Enoch expands on Genesis, stating that the &amp;ldquo;sons of God&amp;rdquo; were a group of 200 &amp;ldquo;angels&amp;rdquo; called &amp;ldquo;Watchers&amp;rdquo; who descended to Earth to breed with humans. Some ancient astronaut proponents argue that this is a historical account of extraterrestrials visiting Earth, called Watchers because their mission was to observe humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chuck Missler and Mark Eastman argue that modern UFOs carry fallen angels or their offspring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Von Däniken suggests that the two angels who visited Lot in Genesis 19 were ancient astronauts who used atomic weapons to destroy Sodom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marc Dem reinterprets the Book of Genesis, writing that humanity started on another planet and that the God of the Bible is an extraterrestrial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;book-of-ezekiel&#34;&gt;Book of Ezekiel &lt;a href=&#34;#book-of-ezekiel&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapter 1 of the Book of Ezekiel recounts a vision in which Ezekiel sees &amp;ldquo;an immense cloud&amp;rdquo; containing fire and emitting lightning. Von Däniken suggests that Ezekiel had seen a spaceship or spaceships. Josef F. Blumrich described this hypothesis in detail in his book &lt;em&gt;The Spaceships of Ezekiel&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;elsewhere-in-the-bible&#34;&gt;Elsewhere in the Bible &lt;a href=&#34;#elsewhere-in-the-bible&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The characteristics of the Ark of the Covenant and the Urim and Thummim have been said to suggest high technology, perhaps from alien origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Dione and Paul Misraki published books in the 1960s describing the events in the Bible as caused by alien technology. Barry Downing argued that Jesus was an extraterrestrial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some proponents believe that the concept of hell in the Bible could be a description of Venus brought to Earth by extraterrestrials. They also suggest that &amp;ldquo;God&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Satan&amp;rdquo; were aliens who disagreed on whether humans should be allowed the information offered by the tree of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-book-of-invasions&#34;&gt;The Book of Invasions &lt;a href=&#34;#the-book-of-invasions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Childress and others have written that the passage in the &lt;em&gt;Book of Invasions&lt;/em&gt; describing the arrival of the Tuatha Dé Danann in Ireland records &amp;ldquo;the arrival of aliens in spacecraft with cloaking devices&amp;rdquo; at Slieve Anier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronaut&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronaut&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
