<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Origin of Life on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/origin-of-life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Origin of Life on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 05:26:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/origin-of-life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial life</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_9c80ff0dfe5c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 05:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_9c80ff0dfe5c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-life&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial Life &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-life&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Extraterrestrial life, also known as alien life, refers to life that originates from a world other than Earth. While no such life has been conclusively detected, the possibility ranges from simple prokaryotes to intelligent beings and civilizations. The study of extraterrestrial life falls under the domain of astrobiology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;unsolved-problem-in-astronomy&#34;&gt;Unsolved problem in astronomy &lt;a href=&#34;#unsolved-problem-in-astronomy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The question of whether life exists elsewhere in the universe remains an unsolved problem in astronomy. Key questions include: Could life have arisen elsewhere? What are the requirements for life? Are there exoplanets like Earth? How likely is the evolution of intelligent life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speculation-about-extraterrestrial-life&#34;&gt;Speculation about extraterrestrial life &lt;a href=&#34;#speculation-about-extraterrestrial-life&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speculation about life beyond Earth dates back to antiquity. Early Christian writers discussed the &amp;ldquo;plurality of worlds,&amp;rdquo; an idea proposed by thinkers like Democritus. Augustine referenced Epicurus&amp;rsquo;s concept of innumerable worlds throughout space. Pre-modern writers often assumed extraterrestrial worlds were inhabited. William Vorilong considered the possibility of Jesus visiting other worlds. Nicholas of Cusa theorized that all extraterrestrial bodies, including the Sun, could be inhabited. Descartes acknowledged the speculative nature of intelligent creatures on other stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;atmospheric-composition-and-ecosystems&#34;&gt;Atmospheric composition and ecosystems &lt;a href=&#34;#atmospheric-composition-and-ecosystems&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compared to Earth, the atmospheric composition and ecosystems of other celestial bodies can make extraterrestrial life seem speculative. However, extreme ecosystems on Earth, such as hydrothermal vents, acidic hot springs, and volcanic lakes, support life under harsh conditions, providing parallels to extreme environments on other planets and supporting the possibility of extraterrestrial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;active-research&#34;&gt;Active research &lt;a href=&#34;#active-research&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the mid-20th century, active research has sought signs of extraterrestrial life, including current and historic life, and extraterrestrial intelligent life. Methods range from analyzing telescope and specimen data to using radios to detect communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultural-impact&#34;&gt;Cultural impact &lt;a href=&#34;#cultural-impact&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The concept of extraterrestrial life, especially extraterrestrial intelligence, has significantly impacted culture, particularly in science fiction. Science fiction has communicated scientific ideas, imagined possibilities, and influenced public interest in extraterrestrial life. The debate over communicating with extraterrestrial intelligence continues, with some advocating for aggressive contact methods and others warning of potential dangers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context &lt;a href=&#34;#context&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article is part of a series on life in the universe, including planetary habitability in the Solar System (Venus, Earth, Mars, Europa, Enceladus, Titan), life outside the Solar System (habitable zone, potentially habitable exoplanets, galactic habitable zone), and the habitability of binary star systems, natural satellites, neutron star systems, red dwarf systems, K-type main-sequence star systems, yellow dwarf systems, and F-type main-sequence star systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-conditions&#34;&gt;Initial conditions &lt;a href=&#34;#initial-conditions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, the universe was too hot for life after the Big Bang. It cooled to temperate levels 15 million years later, but the elements for life did not yet exist. Carbon and oxygen appeared 50 million years later through stellar fusion. Planetary systems emerged, and organic compounds may have formed in protoplanetary disks. Earth, initially molten, became more receptive to organics after cooling. Life started on Earth through abiogenesis. Alternatively, life may have spread between habitable planets via meteoroids in a process called panspermia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stellar-evolution&#34;&gt;Stellar evolution &lt;a href=&#34;#stellar-evolution&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stars combine hydrogen nuclei to make helium nuclei through stellar fusion, releasing energy. This process continues until the star exhausts its fuel. In its last stages, stars combine helium nuclei to form carbon nuclei, and higher-sized stars can further combine carbon nuclei to create oxygen and silicon, and so on until iron. The star then blows its content back into the stellar medium, which would join clouds that would eventually become new generations of stars and planets. Many of those materials are the raw components of life on Earth. As this process takes place in all the universe, said materials are ubiquitous in the cosmos and not a rarity from the Solar System.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;location-in-the-universe&#34;&gt;Location in the universe &lt;a href=&#34;#location-in-the-universe&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earth is a planet in the Solar System, which is part of the Milky Way galaxy. The Milky Way is part of the Local Group, a galaxy group within the Laniakea Supercluster. The universe is composed of all similar structures. Immense distances between celestial objects pose a challenge for studying extraterrestrial life. Humans have only set foot on the Moon and sent probes to other planets and moons in the Solar System. Probes face time delays due to distance. No probe has reached extrasolar planetary systems. Voyager 2 has left the Solar System, but would take 100,000 years to reach the Alpha Centauri system. Telescopes have limitations in studying such systems. Dark matter, though abundant, is not usually considered by astrobiology due to its limited role in stellar evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;circumstellar-habitable-zone&#34;&gt;Circumstellar habitable zone &lt;a href=&#34;#circumstellar-habitable-zone&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The circumstellar habitable zone, or &amp;ldquo;Goldilocks zone,&amp;rdquo; is the area around a star where water may exist in liquid form on a planetary surface. However, planetary habitability is complex and defined by several factors. Being in the habitable zone is not enough for a planet to be habitable. Venus is located in the habitable zone of the Solar System but does not have liquid water because of the conditions of its atmosphere. Gas giants are not considered habitable even if they orbit close enough to their stars as hot Jupiters, due to crushing atmospheric pressures. The actual distances for the habitable zones vary according to the type of star, and even the solar activity of each specific star influences the local habitability. The type of star also defines the time the habitable zone will exist, as its presence and limits will change along with the star&amp;rsquo;s stellar evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cosmic-perspective&#34;&gt;Cosmic perspective &lt;a href=&#34;#cosmic-perspective&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Big Bang occurred 13.8 billion years ago, the Solar System formed 4.6 billion years ago, and the first hominids appeared 6 million years ago. Life on other planets may have started, evolved, given birth to extraterrestrial intelligences, and perhaps even faced a planetary extinction event millions or even billions of years ago. The brief times of existence of Earth&amp;rsquo;s species, when considered from a cosmic perspective, may suggest that extraterrestrial life may be equally fleeting under such a scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;habitable-epoch-of-the-early-universe&#34;&gt;Habitable Epoch of the Early Universe &lt;a href=&#34;#habitable-epoch-of-the-early-universe&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;During a period of about 7 million years, from about 10 to 17 million after the Big Bang, the background temperature was between 373 and 273 K (100 and 0 °C; 212 and 32 °F), allowing the possibility of liquid water if any planets existed. Avi Loeb speculated that primitive life might have appeared during this window, which he called &amp;ldquo;the Habitable Epoch of the Early Universe&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ubiquitous-life&#34;&gt;Ubiquitous life &lt;a href=&#34;#ubiquitous-life&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Life on Earth is ubiquitous and has adapted to almost all available environments. Extremophiles and the deep biosphere thrive even in hostile conditions. It is inferred that life in other celestial bodies may be equally adaptive. However, the origin of life is unrelated to its ease of adaptation and may have stricter requirements. A celestial body may not have any life on it, even if it were habitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;likelihood-of-existence&#34;&gt;Likelihood of existence &lt;a href=&#34;#likelihood-of-existence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is unclear if life, and more importantly, intelligent life in the cosmos is ubiquitous or rare. The hypothesis of ubiquitous extraterrestrial life relies on three main ideas: the size and age of the universe, the ubiquity of chemical elements that make up life, and the universality of physical laws. Scientists such as Carl Sagan and Stephen Hawking argue that it would be improbable for life not to exist somewhere other than Earth. This argument is embodied in the Copernican principle and the mediocrity principle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rare-earth-hypothesis&#34;&gt;Rare Earth hypothesis &lt;a href=&#34;#rare-earth-hypothesis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other authors consider that life in the cosmos, or at least multicellular life, may be rare. The Rare Earth hypothesis maintains that life on Earth is possible because of a series of factors that range from the location in the galaxy and the configuration of the Solar System to local characteristics of the planet, and that it is unlikely that all such requirements are simultaneously met by another planet. Proponents of this hypothesis consider that very little evidence suggests the existence of extraterrestrial life and that at this point it is just a desired result and not a reasonable scientific explanation for any gathered data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;drake-equation&#34;&gt;Drake equation &lt;a href=&#34;#drake-equation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1961, astronomer and astrophysicist Frank Drake devised the Drake equation as a way to stimulate scientific dialogue at a meeting on the search for extraterrestrial intelligence (SETI). The Drake equation is a probabilistic argument used to estimate the number of active, communicative extraterrestrial civilizations in the Milky Way galaxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hubble-space-telescope&#34;&gt;Hubble Space Telescope &lt;a href=&#34;#hubble-space-telescope&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on observations from the Hubble Space Telescope, there are nearly 2 trillion galaxies in the observable universe. It is estimated that at least ten percent of all Sun-like stars have a system of planets, i.e. there are 6.25×1018 stars with planets orbiting them in the observable universe. Even if it is assumed that only one out of a billion of these stars has planets supporting life, there would be some 6.25 billion life-supporting planetary systems in the observable universe. A 2013 study based on results from the &lt;em&gt;Kepler&lt;/em&gt; spacecraft estimated that the Milky Way contains at least as many planets as it does stars, resulting in 100–400 billion exoplanets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nebular-hypothesis&#34;&gt;Nebular hypothesis &lt;a href=&#34;#nebular-hypothesis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Nebular hypothesis that explains the formation of the Solar System and other planetary systems would suggest that those can have several configurations, and not all of them may have rocky planets within the habitable zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fermi-paradox&#34;&gt;Fermi paradox &lt;a href=&#34;#fermi-paradox&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The apparent contradiction between high estimates of the probability of the existence of extraterrestrial civilizations and the lack of evidence for such civilizations is known as the Fermi paradox. Dennis W. Sciama claimed that life&amp;rsquo;s existence in the universe depends on various fundamental constants. Zhi-Wei Wang and Samuel L. Braunstein suggest that a random universe capable of supporting life is likely&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_life&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
