<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Area 51 on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/area-51/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Area 51 on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 09:29:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/area-51/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Area 51</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1bb36472371e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 09:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1bb36472371e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;area-51&#34;&gt;Area 51 &lt;a href=&#34;#area-51&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Area 51, officially called Homey Airport (KXTA) or Groom Lake, is a highly classified United States Air Force (USAF) facility located within the Nevada Test and Training Range. It&amp;rsquo;s a remote detachment administered by Edwards Air Force Base. While details of its operations are not public, it&amp;rsquo;s widely believed to support the development and testing of experimental aircraft and weapons systems. The intense secrecy surrounding the base has made it a central subject of conspiracy theories and UFO folklore. The CIA publicly acknowledged the base&amp;rsquo;s existence in 2013, following a Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography &lt;a href=&#34;#geography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;area-51-1&#34;&gt;Area 51 &lt;a href=&#34;#area-51-1&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The original rectangular base is part of the &amp;ldquo;Groom box,&amp;rdquo; a restricted airspace area. It&amp;rsquo;s connected to the Nevada Test Site (NTS) road network, with roads leading to Mercury and Yucca Flat. Groom Lake Road runs northeast through the Jumbled Hills, past a security checkpoint, and eventually connects with State Route 375, the &amp;ldquo;Extraterrestrial Highway,&amp;rdquo; south of Rachel, Nevada. Area 51 shares a border with the Yucca Flat region of the Nevada Test Site, the location of many nuclear tests. The Yucca Mountain nuclear waste repository is southwest of Groom Lake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;groom-lake&#34;&gt;Groom Lake &lt;a href=&#34;#groom-lake&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Groom Lake is a salt flat in Nevada used for runways of the Nellis Bombing Range Test Site airport (XTA/KXTA) on the north of the Area 51 USAF military installation. It&amp;rsquo;s located within the Groom Lake Valley portion of the Tonopah Basin, south of Rachel, Nevada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The origin of the name &amp;ldquo;Area 51&amp;rdquo; is unclear. The facility is also referred to as Homey Airport (XTA/KXTA) and Groom Lake. Other nicknames include &amp;ldquo;Dreamland&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Paradise Ranch.&amp;rdquo; The special use airspace around the field is referred to as Restricted Area 4808 North (R-4808N). Lead and silver were discovered in the Groom Range in 1864, leading to mining operations until the early 1950s. The airfield began service in 1942 as Indian Springs Air Force Auxiliary Field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;u-2-program&#34;&gt;U-2 program &lt;a href=&#34;#u-2-program&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The CIA established the Groom Lake test facility in April 1955 for Project AQUATONE: the development of the Lockheed U-2 strategic reconnaissance aircraft. Project director Richard M. Bissell Jr. sought a secure testing site. Lockheed&amp;rsquo;s Kelly Johnson identified Groom Lake as ideal. The CIA asked the AEC to acquire the land, designated &amp;ldquo;Area 51.&amp;rdquo; Johnson named the area &amp;ldquo;Paradise Ranch.&amp;rdquo; The Ranch initially consisted of shelters, workshops, and trailer homes. CIA, Air Force, and Lockheed personnel began arriving by July 1955.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;oxcart-program&#34;&gt;OXCART program &lt;a href=&#34;#oxcart-program&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Project OXCART was established in August 1959 for work on the Lockheed A-12. Construction of A-12 test facilities began in September 1960, including a new runway. Reynolds Electrical and Engineering Company (REECo) upgraded base facilities. The contractor marked an Archimedean spiral on the dry lake. Security was enhanced, and the FAA expanded the restricted airspace. The CIA facility received various USAF aircraft for training and support. The first A-12 test aircraft arrived in February 1962 and made its first flight in April 1962. Groom was also the site of the first Lockheed D-21 drone test flight in December 1964. By the end of 1963, nine A-12s were at Area 51, assigned to the CIA-operated &amp;ldquo;1129th Special Activities Squadron.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;d-21-tagboard&#34;&gt;D-21 Tagboard &lt;a href=&#34;#d-21-tagboard&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following the loss of Gary Powers&amp;rsquo; U-2, there were discussions about using the A-12 OXCART as an unpiloted drone aircraft. The Air Force agreed to fund the study of a high-speed, high-altitude drone aircraft in October 1962. The project designated &amp;ldquo;Q-12&amp;rdquo; was renamed the &amp;ldquo;D-21&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;Tagboard&amp;rdquo; was the project&amp;rsquo;s code name. The first D-21 was completed in the spring of 1964 by Lockheed. It was to be carried by a two-seat derivative of the A-12, designated the &amp;ldquo;M-21&amp;rdquo;. Difficulties were addressed throughout 1964 and 1965 at Groom Lake with various technical issues. The first D-21 launch was made on 5 March 1966 with a successful flight. An accident on 30 July 1966 with a fully fueled D-21 caused it to collide with the M-21 launch aircraft. Kelly Johnson personally cancelled the entire program. A number of D-21s had already been produced, and Johnson again proposed to the Air Force that they be launched from a B-52H bomber. Several more tests, including two over China, were made from Beale AFB, California, in 1969 and 1970, to varying degrees of success. On 15 July 1971, Kelly Johnson received a wire canceling the D-21B program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;foreign-technology-evaluation&#34;&gt;Foreign technology evaluation &lt;a href=&#34;#foreign-technology-evaluation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the Cold War, the United States tested and evaluated captured Soviet fighter aircraft. Beginning in the late 1960s, Area 51 hosted Soviet-built aircraft. Munir Redfa&amp;rsquo;s defection with a Mikoyan-Gurevich MiG-21 from Iraq for Israel&amp;rsquo;s Mossad in Operation Diamond led to the HAVE DOUGHNUT, HAVE DRILL and HAVE FERRY programs. The first MiGs flown in the United States were used to evaluate the aircraft in performance, technical, and operational capabilities, pitting the types against U.S. fighters. In August 1966, Iraqi Air Force fighter pilot Captain Munir Redfa defected, flying his MiG-21 to Israel. His aircraft was transferred to Groom Lake in late 1967 for study. In 1968, the US Air Force and Navy jointly formed a project known as HAVE DOUGHNUT in which Air Force Systems Command, Tactical Air Command, and the U.S. Navy&amp;rsquo;s Air Test and Evaluation Squadron Four (VX-4) flew this acquired Soviet-made aircraft in simulated air combat training. On 12 August 1968, two Syrian air force lieutenants, Walid Adham and Radfan Rifai, took off in a pair of MiG-17Fs on a training mission. They lost their way and landed at the Betzet Landing Field in northern Israel. Prior to the end of 1968 these MiG-17s were transferred from Israeli stocks and added to the Area 51 test fleet. In May 1973, Project HAVE IDEA was formed, which took over from the older HAVE DOUGHNUT, HAVE FERRY and HAVE DRILL projects, and the project was transferred to the Tonopah Test Range Airport. Area 51 also hosted another foreign materiel evaluation program called HAVE GLIB. The Air Force began funding improvements to Area 51 in 1977 under project SCORE EVENT. In 1979, the CIA transferred jurisdiction of the Area 51 site to the Air Force Flight Test Center at Edwards AFB, California. In 2017, a USAF aircraft crashed at the site, killing the pilot, Lt. Colonel Eric &amp;ldquo;Doc&amp;rdquo; Schultz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;have-bluef-117-program&#34;&gt;Have Blue/F-117 program &lt;a href=&#34;#have-bluef-117-program&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Lockheed Have Blue prototype stealth fighter first flew at Groom in December 1977. In 1978, the Air Force awarded a full-scale development contract for the F-117 to Lockheed Corporation&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Development Projects. On 17 January 1981 the Lockheed test team at Area 51 accepted delivery of the first full-scale development (FSD) prototype 79–780, designated YF-117A. On 18 June 1981 Lockheed Skunk Works test pilot Hal Farley lifted the nose of YF-117A 79–780 off the runway of Area 51. Tactical Air Command (TAC) decided to set up a group-level organization to guide the F-117A to an initial operating capability. That organization became the 4450th Tactical Group, which officially activated on 15 October 1979 at Nellis AFB, Nevada, although the group was physically located at Area 51. On 15 October 1982, Major Alton C. Whitley Jr. became the first USAF 4450th TG pilot to fly the F-117A. Tonopah Test Range Airport was selected for operations of the first USAF F-117 unit, the 4450th Tactical Group (TG). By early 1982, four more YF-117As were operating at the base. Testing of a series of ultra-secret prototypes continued at Area 51 until mid-1981 when testing transitioned to the initial production of F-117 stealth fighters. The F-117s were moved to and from Area 51 by C-5 during darkness to maintain security. While the &amp;ldquo;Baja Scorpions&amp;rdquo; were working on the F-117, there was also another group at work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Area_51&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Area_51&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
