<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unproduced Film on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/unproduced-film/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unproduced Film on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 13:56:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/unproduced-film/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Alien</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_73e88702e51c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 13:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_73e88702e51c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-alien&#34;&gt;The Alien &lt;a href=&#34;#the-alien&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the history of &lt;em&gt;The Alien&lt;/em&gt;, an unproduced science fiction film conceived by Indian filmmaker Satyajit Ray in the late 1960s. The film was a joint venture between India and the United States, with Columbia Pictures slated to produce it. Despite the involvement of notable actors like Peter Sellers and Marlon Brando, the film was ultimately shelved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story centers around an alien spaceship that lands in a rural village in Bengal, India. The villagers, awestruck by the craft, begin to worship it. The alien, named &amp;ldquo;Mr. Ang,&amp;rdquo; communicates with a young boy named Haba through dreams and engages in playful pranks within the village. The narrative also includes an Indian businessman, a journalist from Calcutta (now Kolkata), and an American engineer. A specific scene is highlighted, describing the alien&amp;rsquo;s interaction with plant life, showcasing its gentle and curious nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Columbia Pictures was the producer for this planned US–India co-production, and Peter Sellers and Marlon Brando were slated to play lead roles. However, Ray discovered that his script had been copyrighted by Michael Wilson, his representative in Hollywood, who claimed co-writer credit without contributing to the writing. Marlon Brando later left the project, and although James Coburn was considered as a replacement, Ray became discouraged and returned to Calcutta. Columbia Pictures expressed interest in reviving the project in the 1970s and 1980s, but it never materialized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legacy&#34;&gt;Legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses the similarities between &lt;em&gt;The Alien&lt;/em&gt; and Steven Spielberg&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial&lt;/em&gt;, released in 1982. Satyajit Ray pointed out the parallels between his script and Spielberg&amp;rsquo;s film, suggesting that &lt;em&gt;E.T.&lt;/em&gt; would not have been possible without his script being available in Hollywood. Spielberg denied these claims. The article also mentions the Hindi film &lt;em&gt;Koi&amp;hellip; Mil Gaya&lt;/em&gt;, directed by Rakesh Roshan, as another film that appears to be based on &lt;em&gt;The Alien&lt;/em&gt;, particularly in its focus on an intellectually disabled person interacting with a friendly alien. In 2003, Satyajit Ray&amp;rsquo;s son, Sandip Ray, began adapting Ray&amp;rsquo;s original 1962 story &lt;em&gt;Bankubabur Bandhu&lt;/em&gt; into a Bengali television movie of the same name, which was eventually broadcast in India in 2006.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Alien_(unproduced_film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Alien_(unproduced_film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
