<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Iran on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/iran/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iran on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 02:23:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/iran/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1976 Tehran UFO incident</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_0f836f85743b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 02:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_0f836f85743b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;1976-tehran-ufo-incident&#34;&gt;1976 Tehran UFO Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#1976-tehran-ufo-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1976 Tehran UFO incident involved radar and visual sightings of an unidentified flying object (UFO) over Tehran, Iran, in the early morning hours of September 19, 1976. Two Imperial Iranian Air Force (IIAF) F-4 Phantom II jet interceptors were dispatched to investigate. Pilots reported instrumentation and communication failures as they approached the object, which were restored upon withdrawal. One aircraft also experienced a temporary weapons systems failure while preparing to fire. An initial report was relayed to the U.S. Joint Chiefs of Staff on the day of the incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;incident&#34;&gt;Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On September 19, 1976, at least four civilians reported a shining object in the sky above Tehran. Lieutenant Yaddi Nazeri and a weapons officer were sent to investigate in an F-4 Phantom II. Nazeri reported losing all instruments and communications upon reaching Tehran, prompting a return to base where the instruments returned to normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major Parviz Jafari, a squadron commander, and First Lieutenant Jalal Damirian were dispatched in a second F-4 Phantom II. Jafari acquired radar lock on an object 27 nautical miles away, estimating its size to be comparable to a Boeing KC-135 Stratotanker. As he approached, Jafari described the object as flashing intense red, green, orange, and blue lights. His plane&amp;rsquo;s communications system shut off. When he attempted to fire an AIM-9 Sidewinder missile, his equipment failed and only returned to normal after moving away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jafari reported a round object emerging from the primary object and moving towards him at high speed. His weapons control panel failed, and he lost all instruments and radio communication. Instructed to return to base, Jafari saw the primary, diamond-shaped object and another bright object descending towards the ground, emitting a bright light. The next day, Jafari and Damirian searched the area by helicopter but found nothing. Residents reported hearing a loud noise and seeing a bright flash of light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;analysis&#34;&gt;Analysis &lt;a href=&#34;#analysis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Martin Bridgstock of Griffith University summarized the incident as Iranian air force jets investigating lights in the sky, with at least one jet experiencing electrical failures and an attempt to fire a missile. A nearby airliner also suffered radio failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philip J. Klass suggested the pilots initially mistook Jupiter for a UFO. He attributed equipment failures to pilot incompetence and equipment malfunction. Klass noted that only the first F-4 reported equipment failure and had a history of electrical outages. A McDonnell Douglas repair supervisor suggested the radar might have been in &amp;ldquo;manual track&amp;rdquo; mode, leading to misinterpretation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bridgstock criticized UFOlogists&amp;rsquo; reports and highlighted Klass&amp;rsquo;s findings that only one aircraft had electrical malfunctions and that the aircrews were tired and could have mistaken stars or meteors for UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brian Dunning noted that the incident occurred during the peak of the Gamma Piscids and Southern Piscids meteorite showers, making observations of falling objects common. A beeping transponder from a C-141 aircraft was found at the supposed crash site. Dunning concluded that the Tehran 1976 UFO case was unusual only because planes chased celestial objects and experienced equipment failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-to-incident-in-the-media&#34;&gt;Reference to incident in the media &lt;a href=&#34;#reference-to-incident-in-the-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Sightings&lt;/em&gt; television program covered the incident in 1994, interviewing participants. &lt;em&gt;The Daily Telegraph&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; listed it among their top 10 UFO sightings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;Gallery &lt;a href=&#34;#gallery&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gallery includes an editorial from the United States Air Force Security Services quarterly &lt;em&gt;MIJI&lt;/em&gt; newsletter, which Dunning describes as a dramatized retelling of the incident offered as an editorial on jamming and interference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links to related articles including UFO sightings in Iran and a list of UFO sightings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A list of references is provided, including reports from the National Security Agency, articles from &lt;em&gt;The Times&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Columbia Journalism Review&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Herald-Tribune&lt;/em&gt;, Skeptoid.com, books by Leslie Kean and Philip J. Klass, and articles from &lt;em&gt;The Daily Telegraph&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links to external resources such as the original report, DIA reports, and articles from Skeptoid.com and NICAP.org.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1976_Tehran_UFO_incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1976_Tehran_UFO_incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in Iran</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_05f2243b54d6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 17:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_05f2243b54d6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-within-the-nation-of-iran&#34;&gt;List of alleged UFO sightings within the nation of Iran &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-within-the-nation-of-iran&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article documents alleged sightings of unidentified flying objects (UFOs) in Iran.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1976&#34;&gt;1976 &lt;a href=&#34;#1976&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the 1976 Tehran UFO incident. This event involved radar and visual sightings of a UFO over Tehran. Key aspects include electromagnetic interference affecting approaching F-4 jet interceptors, causing instrumentation and communication failures that were resolved upon retreat. One F-4 also experienced weapons system failure when preparing to engage the object. The incident is documented in a U.S. Defense Intelligence Agency (DIA) report distributed to high-ranking officials and agencies. Iranian military officers involved publicly stated their belief that the object was extraterrestrial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1982&#34;&gt;1982 &lt;a href=&#34;#1982&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions a mass sighting in Isfahan during the summer of 1982. Thousands of people reportedly witnessed a large reflection of an object in the sky. However, this event lacks a citation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2003&#34;&gt;2003 &lt;a href=&#34;#2003&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details a sighting near the Caspian Sea in August 2003. Two tourists reported observing a couple of yellow-white colored UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2004&#34;&gt;2004 &lt;a href=&#34;#2004&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes a mass UFO sighting event, known as the 2004 Iran UFO sighting, which occurred between April 12–21. Thousands of people witnessed the UFOs, and one was filmed by Iranian TV. The nature of the objects remains unclear, with possibilities including UFOs, surveillance aircraft, or the planet Venus. Photos surfaced, with some deemed unknown by UFO groups but others dismissed as hoaxes, conventional aircraft, or Venus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2005&#34;&gt;2005 &lt;a href=&#34;#2005&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions a report from a tourist who claimed to have seen a UFO hovering near the Tomb of Cyrus the Great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2007&#34;&gt;2007 &lt;a href=&#34;#2007&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses a reported UFO crash in the Barez Mounts of Kerman province. Eyewitnesses informed the Fars News Agency (FNA) about a radiant UFO crash. Abulghassem Nasrollahi, the Deputy General of Kerman province, confirmed that all aircraft in the area were accounted for but didn&amp;rsquo;t dismiss the possibility of a meteor. Another source told FNA that the object was on fire with thick smoke, suggesting it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a meteor. A similar incident was reported in Rafsanjan a few days prior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to related articles, including the &amp;ldquo;List of reported UFO sightings.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including links to UFOinfo.com and BBC News articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Iran&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Iran&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
