<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Western on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/western/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Western on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 23:27:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/western/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cowboys &amp; Aliens (2011 film)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_31a87c5e29e6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 23:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_31a87c5e29e6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;cowboys--aliens-2011-film&#34;&gt;Cowboys &amp;amp; Aliens (2011 film) &lt;a href=&#34;#cowboys--aliens-2011-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article provides a detailed overview of the 2011 American science fiction Western film &lt;em&gt;Cowboys &amp;amp; Aliens&lt;/em&gt;, directed by Jon Favreau. It covers various aspects of the film, including its plot, cast, production, themes, marketing, release, reception, and home media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot unfolds in 1873 New Mexico Territory, where an amnesiac outlaw named Jake Lonergan, portrayed by Daniel Craig, awakens with a mysterious metal bracelet attached to his wrist. He finds himself in the town of Absolution, which is soon attacked by aliens. The aliens abduct several townspeople, including Sheriff Taggart and Percy Dolarhyde. Lonergan&amp;rsquo;s bracelet activates, transforming into a weapon that he uses to shoot down an alien ship. A posse, including Colonel Woodrow Dolarhyde (Harrison Ford) and a mysterious woman named Ella Swenson (Olivia Wilde), forms to track the aliens. Lonergan&amp;rsquo;s memories gradually return, revealing his past abduction and the death of his lover, Alice. Ella reveals herself to be an alien from another race, who came to Earth to help resist the invaders. The group plans an attack on the aliens&amp;rsquo; mothership, resulting in a final confrontation where Ella sacrifices herself to destroy the ship and save Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film features a prominent cast:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daniel Craig&lt;/strong&gt; as Jake Lonergan, an amnesiac outlaw.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harrison Ford&lt;/strong&gt; as Woodrow Dolarhyde, a powerful cattleman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Olivia Wilde&lt;/strong&gt; as Ella Swenson, an alien traveler.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam Rockwell&lt;/strong&gt; as Doc, a doctor and saloon owner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adam Beach&lt;/strong&gt; as Nat Colorado, Dolarhyde&amp;rsquo;s Apache right-hand man.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Dano&lt;/strong&gt; as Percy Dolarhyde, Woodrow&amp;rsquo;s son.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Noah Ringer&lt;/strong&gt; as Emmett Taggart, Taggart&amp;rsquo;s grandson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keith Carradine&lt;/strong&gt; as Sheriff John Taggart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clancy Brown&lt;/strong&gt; as Meacham, Absolution&amp;rsquo;s preacher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The production section details the film&amp;rsquo;s development, casting, writing, filming, design, and visual effects. The project began in 1997, with Universal Pictures and DreamWorks Pictures acquiring film rights to a concept by Scott Mitchell Rosenberg. Jon Favreau joined as director in 2009, and Daniel Craig and Harrison Ford were cast in the lead roles. Filming took place in New Mexico and California in 2010. The film was shot in the anamorphic format on 35mm film to achieve a classic movie feel. Industrial Light &amp;amp; Magic (ILM) created the visual effects, with Legacy Effects producing practical puppet aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes &lt;a href=&#34;#themes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film explores themes of redemption, unity against a common enemy, and the clash between low-tech and high-tech cultures. Jon Favreau aimed for a plausible approach to how 19th-century humans could confront technologically superior extraterrestrial beings. The film also draws parallels between the alien invasion and the historical conflicts between European settlers and Native Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;marketing&#34;&gt;Marketing &lt;a href=&#34;#marketing&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The marketing section discusses the challenges of promoting a film with an &amp;ldquo;inherently comic&amp;rdquo; title and premise. The studio aimed to convey the film&amp;rsquo;s serious tone and adventure elements through trailers and presentations at events like San Diego Comic-Con.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cowboys &amp;amp; Aliens&lt;/em&gt; premiered at San Diego Comic-Con in July 2011 and was released theatrically in the United States and Canada on July 29, 2011. Paramount Pictures released the film in IMAX theaters internationally, and Reliance Entertainment released it in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reception section covers the film&amp;rsquo;s box office performance and critical response. &lt;em&gt;Cowboys &amp;amp; Aliens&lt;/em&gt; underperformed at the box office, earning $174.8 million worldwide on a $163 million budget. Critics praised the acting and special effects but criticized the screenplay and tone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;home-media&#34;&gt;Home Media &lt;a href=&#34;#home-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film was released on DVD and Blu-ray Disc on December 6, 2011, including an extended version, behind-the-scenes featurettes, and commentary with Jon Favreau. In 2024, Kino Lorber released a 4K Blu-ray of the theatrical cut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;infringement-lawsuit&#34;&gt;Infringement Lawsuit &lt;a href=&#34;#infringement-lawsuit&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steven John Busti filed a lawsuit against Universal, DreamWorks, Platinum Studios, and Scott Mitchell Rosenberg, claiming copyright infringement. Busti claimed he wrote a preview for his story &lt;em&gt;Cowboys and Aliens&lt;/em&gt; in 1994, which was published in the April 1995 issue of &lt;em&gt;Bizarre Fantasy #1&lt;/em&gt;. The lawsuit was dismissed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-legend&#34;&gt;Historical Legend &lt;a href=&#34;#historical-legend&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The capsized steamboat that appears in the film is presumed to be the &lt;em&gt;Iron Mountain&lt;/em&gt; which, according to legend, steamed out of Vicksburg towing two barges. Two hours later, another boat found the barges adrift. The ship was not found until later, having apparently been refloated by flood waters and carried through a break in a levee, and grounded in a cotton field at Omega Landing, near Tallulah, Louisiana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cowboys_%26_Aliens&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cowboys_%26_Aliens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
