<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science Fiction on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/science-fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science Fiction on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 20:16:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/science-fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Resident Alien (American television series)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cfe3116ab8df/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 20:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cfe3116ab8df/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;resident-alien-american-television-series&#34;&gt;Resident Alien (American television series) &lt;a href=&#34;#resident-alien-american-television-series&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a comprehensive overview of the American television series &lt;em&gt;Resident Alien&lt;/em&gt;, detailing its genre, creators, cast, production, and reception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-information&#34;&gt;General Information &lt;a href=&#34;#general-information&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides a quick overview of the show, including its genre (comedy-drama, mystery, science fiction), creator (Chris Sheridan), and the comic book it&amp;rsquo;s based on (by Peter Hogan and Steve Parkhouse). It lists the main actors: Alan Tudyk, Sara Tomko, Corey Reynolds, Alice Wetterlund, Levi Fiehler, Judah Prehn, and Elizabeth Bowen. It also mentions the opening theme song (&amp;ldquo;Bilgewater&amp;rdquo; by Brown Bird), the country of origin (United States), the original language (English), the number of seasons (3), and episodes (34). Production details include executive producers, producer (Alan Tudyk), production locations (Delta, British Columbia, Canada), running time (43–46 minutes), production companies, original network (Syfy), and release dates (January 27, 2021 – April 3, 2024). It also notes the show&amp;rsquo;s move to USA Network for a fourth season. A picture depicts the alien language used in the series, which is Esperanto written in an invented script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;premise&#34;&gt;Premise &lt;a href=&#34;#premise&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the central plot of the series. An alien crashes on Earth, kills a doctor, and assumes his identity in Patience, Colorado. He is tasked with wiping out humanity but grapples with the morality of his mission, especially after developing compassion and dealing with a child who can see his true form. The alien eventually defends humanity from other extraterrestrial threats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast-and-characters&#34;&gt;Cast and Characters &lt;a href=&#34;#cast-and-characters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section details the main and recurring cast members and their roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;main&#34;&gt;Main &lt;a href=&#34;#main&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alan Tudyk&lt;/strong&gt; plays the alien, &amp;ldquo;Harry Vanderspeigle,&amp;rdquo; who takes on the identity of a doctor. He also plays the real Dr. Harry Vanderspeigle, a corrupt doctor. Keith Arbuthnot portrays the alien in his true form, and David Bianchi portrays Goliath, Harry&amp;rsquo;s future self.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sara Tomko&lt;/strong&gt; is Asta Twelvetrees, the doctor&amp;rsquo;s assistant and a member of the Ute tribe. Brylee Smith and Zara Bacic portray young Asta in flashbacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corey Reynolds&lt;/strong&gt; plays Sheriff Mike Thompson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alice Wetterlund&lt;/strong&gt; is D&amp;rsquo;arcy Bloom, the town bartender and Asta&amp;rsquo;s best friend. Elle Rivas portrays young D&amp;rsquo;arcy in flashbacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Levi Fiehler&lt;/strong&gt; plays Ben Hawthorne, the town&amp;rsquo;s mayor. Lukas Goas and Jude Wylie portray young Ben in flashbacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Judah Prehn&lt;/strong&gt; is Max Hawthorne, Ben&amp;rsquo;s son, who can see Harry&amp;rsquo;s alien form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elizabeth Bowen&lt;/strong&gt; plays Deputy Liv Baker. Jessica Halliburton portrays young Liv in flashbacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recurring&#34;&gt;Recurring &lt;a href=&#34;#recurring&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists actors and their recurring roles, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meredith Garretson as Kate Hawthorne&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ben Cotton as Jimmy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kaylayla Raine as Jay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deborah Finkel as Abigail Hodges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gary Farmer as Dan Twelvetrees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mandell Maughan as Agent Lisa Casper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alex Barima as Lieutenant David Logan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jenna Lamia as Judy Cooper (Lilly Dean portrays young Judy in flashbacks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sarah Podemski as Kayla (Acahkos Johnson portrays young Kayla in flashbacks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diana Bang as Ellen Cho&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elvy Yost as Isabelle Vanderspeigle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gracelyn Awad Rinke as Sahar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linda Hamilton as General Eleanor McCallister (Alix West Lefler portrays young Eleanor Wright in flashbacks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michael Cassidy as Dr. Ethan Stone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nathan Fillion as the voice of 42&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alvin Sanders as Lewis Thompson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trevor Carroll as John Baker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terry O&amp;rsquo;Quinn as Peter Bach (Dylan Sloane portrays young Peter Bach in flashbacks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Justin Rain as Elliot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paul Piaskowski as Robert Hutchins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enver Gjokaj as &amp;ldquo;Joseph Rainier&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nicola Correia-Damude as Detective Lena Torres&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kesler Talbot and Andrea Geones as the &amp;ldquo;Humalien&amp;rdquo; / &amp;ldquo;Bridget&amp;rdquo; (Talbot also portrays the real Bobby Smallwood in flashbacks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edi Patterson as &amp;ldquo;Heather&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jewel Staite as Jules Gardner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;guest&#34;&gt;Guest &lt;a href=&#34;#guest&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists guest actors and their roles, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jan Bos as Dr. Sam Hodges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giorgio A. Tsoukalos as himself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Lewis as Mitch Green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alex Borstein as Carlyn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lini Evans as Bethany Bloom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Barclay Hope as Gerald Bloom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taylor Blackwell as Liza Vanderspeigle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maxim Roy as Violinda Darvell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Karina Logue as Mary-Ellen Taylor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;George Takei as the voice of a Grey alien&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hwaa Hawk as Leo / Bishop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grace Sunar as Mari&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mary Walsh as Patty Baker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erin Karpluk as Dr. Wendy Beasley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clancy Brown as the voice of a Mantid alien&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peter Hogan as Mr. Hogan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides an overview of the series&amp;rsquo; episodes, broken down by season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;series-overview&#34;&gt;Series overview &lt;a href=&#34;#series-overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A table summarizes the number of episodes per season, the original release dates, and the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-1-2021&#34;&gt;Season 1 (2021) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-1-2021&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A table lists each episode of the first season with its title, director, writer, original release date, and U.S. viewership. Brief summaries of each episode&amp;rsquo;s plot are included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-2-2022&#34;&gt;Season 2 (2022) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-2-2022&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A table lists each episode of the second season with its title, director, writer, original release date, and U.S. viewership. Brief summaries of each episode&amp;rsquo;s plot are included. The season is divided into two parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-3-2024&#34;&gt;Season 3 (2024) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-3-2024&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A table lists each episode of the third season with its title, director, writer, original release date, and U.S. viewership. Brief summaries of each episode&amp;rsquo;s plot are included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section details the development, casting, and filming aspects of the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;development&#34;&gt;Development &lt;a href=&#34;#development&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Series creator Chris Sheridan was inspired by the &lt;em&gt;Resident Alien&lt;/em&gt; comic book series and a personal UFO sighting experience. Syfy announced the TV adaptation in 2018, with Universal Cable Productions, Dark Horse Entertainment, and Amblin Television developing the pilot. Syfy gave a series order in 2019, with production in Vancouver and David Dobkin directing the pilot. Robert Duncan McNeill executive produced and directed the remaining episodes. The series was renewed for a second season in 2021 and a third season in 2022. The episode count for the third season was reduced from 12 to 8. In June 2024, the series was renewed for a fourth season and moved to USA Network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;casting&#34;&gt;Casting &lt;a href=&#34;#casting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alan Tudyk was cast as the main character, Dr. Harry Vanderspeigle, along with Sara Tomko, Corey Reynolds, Alice Wetterlund, and Levi Fiehler. Linda Hamilton, Mandell Maughan, and Alex Barima were cast in recurring roles, followed by Elizabeth Bowen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;filming&#34;&gt;Filming &lt;a href=&#34;#filming&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Principal photography for the first season began in September 2020 and concluded in October 2020 in Delta, British Columbia, Canada. Filming for the second season began in August 2021 and concluded in April 2022, with locations including Ladysmith, British Columbia. Filming for the third season began in January 2023 and concluded in May 2023. Filming for the fourth season began on December 2, 2024 and concluded on March 31, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Syfy announced the series premiere for summer 2020, later moved to January 2021. The series premiered in Canada on CTV Sci-Fi Channel and in the United Kingdom on Sky One.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the critical reception and ratings of the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;critical-response&#34;&gt;Critical response &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-response&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first season received positive reviews, with Rotten Tomatoes reporting a 94% approval rating and Metacritic giving it a score of 70 out of 100. The second season received a 100% approval rating on Rotten Tomatoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ratings&#34;&gt;Ratings &lt;a href=&#34;#ratings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides viewership and ratings data for each episode of the first season, including live viewership, DVR viewership, and total viewership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;accolades&#34;&gt;Accolades &lt;a href=&#34;#accolades&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A table lists the awards and nominations received by the series, including Saturn Awards, Critics Choice Super Awards, Dragon Awards, Hollywood Critics Association Television Awards, Satellite Awards, Joey Awards, Leo Awards, and Young Artist Awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes &lt;a href=&#34;#notes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides additional information and clarifications about specific details in the article, such as the spelling of a character&amp;rsquo;s name, special guest star credits, and ratings information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists all the sources used in the article, including news articles, press releases, and websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to the official website and the show&amp;rsquo;s IMDb page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resident_Alien_(TV_series)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resident_Alien_(TV_series)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
