<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science Fiction on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/science-fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science Fiction on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 13:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/science-fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO conspiracy theories</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_58890638264e/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 13:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_58890638264e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;UFO Conspiracy Theories &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-conspiracy-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Wikipedia article discusses various conspiracy theories surrounding Unidentified Flying Objects (UFOs), particularly the idea that governments, especially the United States government, are suppressing evidence of extraterrestrial life or technology. It also explores the evolution of these theories, their proponents, and their presence in popular culture and religion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces the core concept of UFO conspiracy theories: governments concealing evidence of extraterrestrial involvement. It traces the origins of these theories back to pulp science fiction and the &amp;ldquo;lost continent&amp;rdquo; myths. The section highlights Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s 1947 sighting as a catalyst for widespread UFO reports and the subsequent speculation about secret technologies. Donald Keyhoe is identified as a key figure in popularizing the idea of a government cover-up. The emergence of the &amp;ldquo;Men in Black&amp;rdquo; concept is also mentioned. The section further explains how UFO conspiracy theories became more prevalent after the Kennedy assassination, linking his death to aliens. The term &amp;ldquo;Cosmic Watergate&amp;rdquo; is introduced to describe the alleged cover-up. The section also mentions the influence of films like &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt; and the introduction of the Roswell incident to a mass audience. The shift from benevolent &amp;ldquo;space brothers&amp;rdquo; to malevolent aliens in the 1980s is discussed, along with the connection of UFO cover-ups to alien abductions, cattle mutilations, and the JFK assassination. The section concludes by noting the resurgence of interest in UFO conspiracy theories in the 1990s and 2017 with Leslie Kean&amp;rsquo;s stories of a Pentagon UFO program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mainstream-views&#34;&gt;Mainstream Views &lt;a href=&#34;#mainstream-views&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents the mainstream scientific perspective on UFOs. It acknowledges the historical and cultural prominence of UFO sightings, particularly after World War II and during the Space Age. It mentions government investigations like Project Blue Book and Project Condign, as well as studies by organizations and individuals. The section emphasizes that these investigations have not confirmed claims of extraterrestrial intelligence or other unconventional explanations for UFOs. It highlights that scientists and skeptical organizations offer prosaic explanations, such as natural phenomena, human technology, delusions, and hoaxes. The section also notes that beliefs surrounding UFOs have inspired new religions and that social scientists view the ongoing interest in UFOs as a form of modern folklore and mythology. Benjamin Radford&amp;rsquo;s argument against the feasibility of a long-term, international UFO cover-up is also presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notable-proponents&#34;&gt;Notable Proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#notable-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section identifies key individuals who have promoted UFO conspiracy theories. Donald Keyhoe, Jacque Vallee, J. Allen Hynek, and Stanton Friedman are mentioned as prominent figures from the 1950s to the 1970s. The section also notes that some proponents, like Richard Shaver and Paul Bennewitz, had mental health issues, while others, like Gray Barker, Carl Allen, Richard Doty, Bill Moore, and Ray Santelli, confessed to hoaxes or lies. The violent ends of Morris Jessup, James E. McDonald, and Bill Cooper are also mentioned. The section lists individuals who have suggested that UFO evidence is being suppressed, including Barry Goldwater, Lord Hill-Norton, Roscoe H. Hillenkoetter, Gordon Cooper, and Edgar Mitchell. 21st-century proponents such as Paul Hellyer, Garry Nolan, Haim Eshed, Jim Semivan, Harold E. Puthoff, Tom DeLonge, Luis Elizondo, and David Grusch are also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-fiction&#34;&gt;In Popular Fiction &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-fiction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the presence of UFO conspiracy theories in popular culture. It mentions films like &lt;em&gt;2001: A Space Odyssey&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Easy Rider&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Flight of the Navigator&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Total Recall&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Independence Day&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Men in Black&lt;/em&gt;. Television series such as &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Dark Skies&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Stargate&lt;/em&gt; are also mentioned as featuring government efforts to conceal information about extraterrestrial beings. John Glenn&amp;rsquo;s appearance on &lt;em&gt;Frasier&lt;/em&gt;, where he confesses to a UFO cover-up, is also noted. The Sidney Sheldon novel &lt;em&gt;The Doomsday Conspiracy&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;American Horror Story: Double Feature&lt;/em&gt; series are also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-religion&#34;&gt;In Religion &lt;a href=&#34;#in-religion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines the connection between UFO conspiracy theories and new religious movements. It identifies the Nation of Islam, Scientology, and Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate as examples of religious groups that have incorporated UFO-related beliefs. Mormon cosmology&amp;rsquo;s view of inhabited planets is also mentioned. Theosophists and occultists, such as Meade Layne, George Adamski, George Hunt Williamson, and Guy Warren Ballard, are discussed as early proponents of extraterrestrial contact. The Nation of Islam&amp;rsquo;s concept of The Mother Plane is also explored. The section also mentions UFO religions such as Unarius, the Aetherius Society, Raëlism, and the Order of the Solar Temple. The Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate mass suicide, linked to the Hale-Bopp comet, is also discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chronology-of-ufo-conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;Chronology of UFO Conspiracy Theories &lt;a href=&#34;#chronology-of-ufo-conspiracy-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a detailed timeline of the development of UFO conspiracy theories, starting with Raymond Palmer&amp;rsquo;s pulp magazine in the 1940s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1940s-origin-in-raymond-palmers-pulp-magazine&#34;&gt;1940s Origin in Raymond Palmer&amp;rsquo;s Pulp Magazine &lt;a href=&#34;#1940s-origin-in-raymond-palmers-pulp-magazine&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection focuses on Raymond Palmer, the editor of &lt;em&gt;Amazing Stories&lt;/em&gt;, and his role in popularizing UFO conspiracy theories. It mentions his hiring of Kenneth Arnold to investigate the Maury Island incident and the magazine&amp;rsquo;s claims of a cover-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;spaceships-of-the-shaver-mystery&#34;&gt;Spaceships of &amp;ldquo;The Shaver Mystery&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#spaceships-of-the-shaver-mystery&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses Richard Shaver&amp;rsquo;s stories of a secret underground race and their spaceships, published in &lt;em&gt;Amazing Stories&lt;/em&gt;. It mentions Palmer&amp;rsquo;s argument that governments were aware of spaceships visiting Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kenneth-arnold-ignites-flying-disc-craze&#34;&gt;Kenneth Arnold Ignites Flying Disc Craze &lt;a href=&#34;#kenneth-arnold-ignites-flying-disc-craze&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s 1947 sighting and the subsequent &amp;ldquo;flying disc craze.&amp;rdquo; It mentions the Roswell incident and Palmer&amp;rsquo;s investigation of the Maury Island report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aftermath&#34;&gt;Aftermath &lt;a href=&#34;#aftermath&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the aftermath of the 1947 flying disc craze, including Palmer&amp;rsquo;s linking of the sightings to Shaver&amp;rsquo;s claims and Shaver&amp;rsquo;s prediction that the truth about the discs would remain secret. It also mentions Palmer&amp;rsquo;s later linking of UFOs to the JFK assassination and Watergate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;national-coverage-in-the-1950s&#34;&gt;National Coverage in the 1950s &lt;a href=&#34;#national-coverage-in-the-1950s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the increase in governmental and civilian investigative efforts and reports of public disinformation and suppression of evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aztec-alien-bodies-hoax&#34;&gt;Aztec &amp;ldquo;Alien Bodies&amp;rdquo; Hoax &lt;a href=&#34;#aztec-alien-bodies-hoax&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection details the Frank Scully&amp;rsquo;s claims of recovered alien bodies from crashed flying saucers and the subsequent exposure of the hoax by &lt;em&gt;True&lt;/em&gt; magazine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;air-force-accounts&#34;&gt;Air Force Accounts &lt;a href=&#34;#air-force-accounts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers the Air Force&amp;rsquo;s response to UFO sightings, including General John Samford&amp;rsquo;s press conference and the Robertson Panel&amp;rsquo;s recommendation for public education. It also mentions Al Chop&amp;rsquo;s role as a press officer for Project Bluebook and the film &lt;em&gt;Unidentified Flying Objects: The True Story of Flying Saucers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;philadelphia-experiment-hoax&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Philadelphia Experiment&amp;rdquo; Hoax &lt;a href=&#34;#philadelphia-experiment-hoax&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the Morris K. Jessup&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;em&gt;The Case for the UFO&lt;/em&gt; and the &amp;ldquo;Philadelphia Experiment&amp;rdquo; hoax, involving Carl Meredith Allen&amp;rsquo;s letters and annotations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;men-in-black-legends&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Men in Black&amp;rsquo; Legends &lt;a href=&#34;#men-in-black-legends&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explores the origin of the &amp;ldquo;Men in Black&amp;rdquo; concept in Gray Barker&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;em&gt;They Knew Too Much About Flying Saucers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1960-70s-growing-distrust-in-government&#34;&gt;1960-70s: Growing Distrust in Government &lt;a href=&#34;#1960-70s-growing-distrust-in-government&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the increasing government skepticism during the 1960s and 1970s, fueled by events like the Kennedy assassination, the Pentagon Papers, and the Watergate scandal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fred-crisman-and-jfk-conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;Fred Crisman and JFK Conspiracy Theories &lt;a href=&#34;#fred-crisman-and-jfk-conspiracy-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers Jim Garrison&amp;rsquo;s prosecution of Clay Shaw and the involvement of Fred Crisman, linking UFO conspiracy theories to the Kennedy assassination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cosmic-watergate&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cosmic Watergate&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#cosmic-watergate&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the concept of a &amp;ldquo;Cosmic Watergate,&amp;rdquo; with J. Allen Hynek&amp;rsquo;s accusations of a government cover-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-bodies-at-hangar-18&#34;&gt;Alien Bodies at &amp;ldquo;Hangar 18&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-bodies-at-hangar-18&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explores the legends of alien bodies stored at &amp;ldquo;Hangar 18&amp;rdquo; at Wright-Patterson Air Force Base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-abductions&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Alien Abductions&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-abductions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the emergence of alien abduction reports, starting with the Betty and Barney Hill case and the Travis Walton incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;close-encounters-of-the-third-kind&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#close-encounters-of-the-third-kind&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection examines the influence of the film &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt; on UFO conspiracy theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;jesse-marcel-and-roswell&#34;&gt;Jesse Marcel and Roswell &lt;a href=&#34;#jesse-marcel-and-roswell&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers Jesse Marcel&amp;rsquo;s changing statements about the Roswell incident and the increasing attention given to the story by the &lt;em&gt;National Enquirer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;doty-and-lear-promote-the-dark-side&#34;&gt;Doty and Lear Promote the &amp;ldquo;Dark Side&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#doty-and-lear-promote-the-dark-side&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the shift towards &amp;ldquo;ufology&amp;rsquo;s dark side&amp;rdquo; in the 1980s, with Richard Doty and John Lear promoting theories of government collusion with evil aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cattle-mutilations-and-quiet-helicopters&#34;&gt;Cattle Mutilations and Quiet Helicopters &lt;a href=&#34;#cattle-mutilations-and-quiet-helicopters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explores the connection between cattle mutilations, UFO sightings, and &amp;ldquo;quiet helicopters&amp;rdquo; in the Colorado-New Mexico border region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;doty-deceives-mutiliation-researchers&#34;&gt;Doty Deceives Mutiliation Researchers &lt;a href=&#34;#doty-deceives-mutiliation-researchers&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers Richard Doty&amp;rsquo;s deception of Paul Bennewitz and Linda Moulton Howe, feeding them false stories of a UFO conspiracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;doty-and-bill-moore-spread-bogus-mj-12-docs&#34;&gt;Doty and Bill Moore Spread Bogus MJ-12 Docs &lt;a href=&#34;#doty-and-bill-moore-spread-bogus-mj-12-docs&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the spread of fabricated Majestic 12 documents by Richard Doty and Bill Moore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lear-promotes-bill-cooper-and-bob-lazar&#34;&gt;Lear Promotes Bill Cooper and Bob Lazar &lt;a href=&#34;#lear-promotes-bill-cooper-and-bob-lazar&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explores John Lear&amp;rsquo;s promotion of Bill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_conspiracy_theory&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_conspiracy_theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resident Alien (American television series)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cfe3116ab8df/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 20:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cfe3116ab8df/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;resident-alien-american-television-series&#34;&gt;Resident Alien (American television series) &lt;a href=&#34;#resident-alien-american-television-series&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a comprehensive description of the Wikipedia article for the American television series &lt;em&gt;Resident Alien&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a brief introduction to the television series &lt;em&gt;Resident Alien&lt;/em&gt;. It establishes the show&amp;rsquo;s genre as a science fiction mystery comedy-drama and identifies Chris Sheridan as the creator. It also mentions that the show is based on the comic book series of the same name by Peter Hogan and Steve Parkhouse. The premiere date of the first season on Syfy is noted, along with the star, Alan Tudyk. The renewals for subsequent seasons, including the move to USA Network for the fourth season, are also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;premise&#34;&gt;Premise &lt;a href=&#34;#premise&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the central plot of the series. An alien arrives on Earth with the mission to wipe out humanity. After crashing in Colorado, the alien assumes the identity of a doctor named Harry Vanderspeigle. As he lives among humans, he begins to question his mission. A young boy, Max Hawthorne, can see through his disguise. The alien grapples with his mission and ultimately defends humanity from other extraterrestrial threats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast-and-characters&#34;&gt;Cast and characters &lt;a href=&#34;#cast-and-characters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the main and recurring cast members and their respective characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;main&#34;&gt;Main &lt;a href=&#34;#main&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alan Tudyk&lt;/strong&gt; plays the alien, who takes on the identity of Dr. Harry Vanderspeigle. He is sent to Earth to destroy humanity but develops compassion. Tudyk also portrays the real Dr. Harry Vanderspeigle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sara Tomko&lt;/strong&gt; plays Asta Twelvetrees, the assistant to the town doctor and a member of the Ute tribe. She is the first person after Max to discover Harry&amp;rsquo;s true identity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corey Reynolds&lt;/strong&gt; plays Sheriff Mike Thompson, the town&amp;rsquo;s sheriff, who is dealing with past trauma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alice Wetterlund&lt;/strong&gt; plays D&amp;rsquo;arcy Bloom, the owner of the town pub and Asta&amp;rsquo;s best friend. She discovers Harry&amp;rsquo;s true identity after learning that the real Harry killed Sam Hodges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Levi Fiehler&lt;/strong&gt; plays Ben Hawthorne, the town&amp;rsquo;s mayor, who has a history of alien abductions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Judah Prehn&lt;/strong&gt; plays Max Hawthorne, Ben&amp;rsquo;s son, who can see Harry&amp;rsquo;s alien form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elizabeth Bowen&lt;/strong&gt; plays Deputy Liv Baker, the town&amp;rsquo;s deputy, who is fascinated by extraterrestrials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recurring&#34;&gt;Recurring &lt;a href=&#34;#recurring&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists actors and the recurring characters they portray, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meredith Garretson as Kate Hawthorne&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ben Cotton as Jimmy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kaylayla Raine as Jay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deborah Finkel as Abigail Hodges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gary Farmer as Dan Twelvetrees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mandell Maughan as Agent Lisa Casper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alex Barima as Lieutenant David Logan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jenna Lamia as Judy Cooper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sarah Podemski as Kayla&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diana Bang as Ellen Cho&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elvy Yost as Isabelle Vanderspeigle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gracelyn Awad Rinke as Sahar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linda Hamilton as General Eleanor McCallister&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michael Cassidy as Dr. Ethan Stone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nathan Fillion as the voice of 42&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alvin Sanders as Lewis Thompson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trevor Carroll as John Baker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terry O&amp;rsquo;Quinn as Peter Bach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Justin Rain as Elliot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paul Piaskowski as Robert Hutchins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enver Gjokaj as Joseph Rainier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nicola Correia-Damude as Detective Lena Torres&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kesler Talbot and Andrea Geones as the &amp;ldquo;Humalien&amp;rdquo; / &amp;ldquo;Bridget&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edi Patterson as &amp;ldquo;Heather&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jewel Staite as Jules Gardner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;guest&#34;&gt;Guest &lt;a href=&#34;#guest&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists actors and the guest characters they portray, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jan Bos as Dr. Sam Hodges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giorgio A. Tsoukalos as himself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Lewis as Mitch Green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alex Borstein as Carlyn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lini Evans as Bethany Bloom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Barclay Hope as Gerald Bloom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taylor Blackwell as Liza Vanderspeigle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maxim Roy as Violinda Darvell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Karina Logue as Mary-Ellen Taylor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;George Takei as the voice of a Grey alien&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hwaa Hawk as Leo / Bishop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grace Sunar as Mari&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mary Walsh as Patty Baker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erin Karpluk as Dr. Wendy Beasley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clancy Brown as the voice of a Mantid alien&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peter Hogan as Mr. Hogan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides an overview of the series&amp;rsquo; episodes, broken down by season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;series-overview&#34;&gt;Series overview &lt;a href=&#34;#series-overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection presents a table summarizing the number of episodes per season, the original release dates, and the network on which each season aired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-1-2021&#34;&gt;Season 1 (2021) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-1-2021&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the titles, directors, writers, original release dates, and U.S. viewership numbers for each of the 10 episodes of the first season. It also provides a brief summary of each episode&amp;rsquo;s plot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-2-2022&#34;&gt;Season 2 (2022) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-2-2022&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the titles, directors, writers, original release dates, and U.S. viewership numbers for each of the 16 episodes of the second season. It also provides a brief summary of each episode&amp;rsquo;s plot. The season is split into two parts, each with eight episodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-3-2024&#34;&gt;Season 3 (2024) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-3-2024&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the titles, directors, writers, original release dates, and U.S. viewership numbers for each of the 8 episodes of the third season. It also provides a brief summary of each episode&amp;rsquo;s plot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the development, casting, and filming aspects of the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;development&#34;&gt;Development &lt;a href=&#34;#development&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explains the origins of the series, stating that Chris Sheridan was inspired by the novels and comic book series of the same name. It also mentions Sheridan&amp;rsquo;s personal experience with a UFO sighting as inspiration. The initial pilot order by Syfy, along with the involvement of Universal Cable Productions, Dark Horse Entertainment, and Amblin Television, is mentioned. The series order, production location in Vancouver, and David Dobkin&amp;rsquo;s role as director and executive producer are also noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;casting&#34;&gt;Casting &lt;a href=&#34;#casting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection lists the initial casting announcements, including Alan Tudyk as the lead, along with Sara Tomko, Corey Reynolds, Alice Wetterlund, and Levi Fiehler. It also mentions the casting of Linda Hamilton, Mandell Maughan, Alex Barima, and Elizabeth Bowen in recurring roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;filming&#34;&gt;Filming &lt;a href=&#34;#filming&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection provides information on the filming locations and timelines for each season. Principal photography for the first season took place in Delta, British Columbia, Canada. Filming details for the second and third seasons are also included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the release dates of the series. Syfy initially announced a summer 2020 premiere, which was later moved to January 2021. International premiere dates in Canada and the United Kingdom are also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the critical reception and ratings of the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;critical-response&#34;&gt;Critical response &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-response&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection presents the review scores from Rotten Tomatoes and Metacritic for the first and second seasons, highlighting the positive critical reception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ratings&#34;&gt;Ratings &lt;a href=&#34;#ratings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection provides a table with viewership and ratings per episode for the first season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;accolades&#34;&gt;Accolades &lt;a href=&#34;#accolades&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the awards and nominations received by the series, including those from the Saturn Awards, Critics Choice Super Awards, Dragon Awards, and Hollywood Critics Association Television Awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes &lt;a href=&#34;#notes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides clarifying information and context for certain details within the article, such as character name spellings, guest star credits, and rating metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a list of citations used throughout the article, providing sources for the information presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to the official website and the IMDb page for the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resident_Alien_(TV_series)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resident_Alien_(TV_series)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Futurama</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1c6176f68ef4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 18:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1c6176f68ef4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;futurama&#34;&gt;Futurama &lt;a href=&#34;#futurama&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 1999 American animated science fiction sitcom created by Matt Groening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;genre&#34;&gt;Genre &lt;a href=&#34;#genre&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Animated sitcom, science fiction, and satire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;created-by&#34;&gt;Created by &lt;a href=&#34;#created-by&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt Groening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;developed-by&#34;&gt;Developed by &lt;a href=&#34;#developed-by&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt Groening and David X. Cohen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;voices-of&#34;&gt;Voices of &lt;a href=&#34;#voices-of&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Billy West, Katey Sagal, John DiMaggio, Tress MacNeille, Maurice LaMarche, Phil LaMarr, Lauren Tom, and David Herman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;opening-theme&#34;&gt;Opening theme &lt;a href=&#34;#opening-theme&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Theme from &lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; composed by Christopher Tyng.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;country-of-origin&#34;&gt;Country of origin &lt;a href=&#34;#country-of-origin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;original-language&#34;&gt;Original language &lt;a href=&#34;#original-language&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;number-of-seasons&#34;&gt;Number of seasons &lt;a href=&#34;#number-of-seasons&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;number-of-episodes&#34;&gt;Number of episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#number-of-episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;160&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-producers&#34;&gt;Executive producers &lt;a href=&#34;#executive-producers&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt Groening, David X. Cohen, Ken Keeler, and Claudia Katz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;producers&#34;&gt;Producers &lt;a href=&#34;#producers&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lew Morton, J. Stewart Burns, Patric M. Verrone, Bill Odenkirk, Eric Kaplan, Michael Rowe, Brian J. Cowan, Jason Grode, Jane O&amp;rsquo;Brien, and Lee Supercinski.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;editors&#34;&gt;Editors &lt;a href=&#34;#editors&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul D. Calder, Danik Thomas, and Chris Vallance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production-companies&#34;&gt;Production companies &lt;a href=&#34;#production-companies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Curiosity Company, 20th Century Fox Television (seasons 1–7), and 20th Television Animation (season 8–present).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;original-release&#34;&gt;Original release &lt;a href=&#34;#original-release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fox:&lt;/strong&gt; March 28, 1999 – August 10, 2003&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comedy Central:&lt;/strong&gt; March 23, 2008 – September 4, 2013&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hulu:&lt;/strong&gt; July 24, 2023 – present&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;premise&#34;&gt;Premise &lt;a href=&#34;#premise&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series follows Philip J. Fry, a pizza delivery boy who is cryogenically preserved for 1,000 years and revived on December 31, 2999. Fry finds work at the interplanetary delivery company Planet Express, working alongside the one-eyed mutant Leela and the robot Bender. Groening envisioned the series in the mid-1990s while working on &lt;em&gt;The Simpsons&lt;/em&gt;, and brought David X. Cohen aboard to develop storylines and characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;characters&#34;&gt;Characters &lt;a href=&#34;#characters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot revolves around the Planet Express interplanetary delivery company and its employees. Episodes usually feature the central trio of Fry, Leela, and Bender, though occasional storylines center on the other main characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Philip J. Fry:&lt;/strong&gt; Voiced by Billy West, Fry is an immature, slovenly, yet good-hearted pizza delivery boy who is cryogenically frozen for 1,000 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turanga Leela:&lt;/strong&gt; Voiced by Katey Sagal, Leela is the competent, one-eyed captain of the Planet Express Ship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bender Bending Rodriguez:&lt;/strong&gt; Voiced by John DiMaggio, Bender is a foul-mouthed, heavy-drinking, cigar-smoking, kleptomaniacal, misanthropic, egocentric, ill-tempered robot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Professor Hubert J. Farnsworth:&lt;/strong&gt; Voiced by Billy West, Professor Farnsworth is Fry&amp;rsquo;s distant nephew and the founder of Planet Express Inc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hermes Conrad:&lt;/strong&gt; Voiced by Phil LaMarr, Hermes is the Jamaican accountant of Planet Express.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. John A. Zoidberg:&lt;/strong&gt; Voiced by Billy West, Zoidberg is a Decapodian and the neurotic staff physician of Planet Express.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amy Wong:&lt;/strong&gt; Voiced by Lauren Tom, Amy is an incredibly rich, blunt, ditzy, and accident-prone intern at Planet Express.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting&#34;&gt;Setting &lt;a href=&#34;#setting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt; is set in New New York at the turn of the 31st century. The city of New New York has been built over the ruins of present-day New York City, which has become a catacomb-like space that acts as New New York&amp;rsquo;s sewer, referred to as &amp;ldquo;Old New York&amp;rdquo;. Parts of the sewers are inhabited by mutants. Various devices and architecture are similar to the Populuxe style. Global warming, inflexible bureaucracy, and substance abuse are a few of the subjects given a 31st-century exaggeration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list of episodes follows the season box sets, which feature the episodes in the original production season order, ignoring the order of broadcast. The Hulu revival has alternatively been titled the eighth and ninth seasons (production), and the eleventh and twelfth seasons (broadcast). The tenth and eleventh production seasons will also be considered as &lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s thirteenth and fourteenth broadcast seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Season&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Episodes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Originally released&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Network&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;March 28, 1999 – November 14, 1999&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fox&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;19&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;November 21, 1999 – December 3, 2000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fox&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;22&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;January 21, 2001 – December 8, 2002&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fox&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;February 10, 2002 – August 10, 2003&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fox&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;March 23, 2008 – August 30, 2009&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Comedy Central&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;26&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;June 24, 2010 – September 8, 2011&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Comedy Central&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;26&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;June 20, 2012 – September 4, 2013&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Comedy Central&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;July 24, 2023 – September 25, 2023&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hulu&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;July 29, 2024 – September 30, 2024&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hulu&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;development&#34;&gt;Development &lt;a href=&#34;#development&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fox expressed a strong desire in the mid-1990s for Matt Groening to create a new series after the success of &lt;em&gt;The Simpsons&lt;/em&gt;. In 1995, he enlisted David X. Cohen to assist in developing the show. When they pitched the series to Fox in April 1998, Groening and Cohen had composed many characters and story lines. Fox ordered thirteen episodes. Fox feared the themes of the show were not suitable for the network and Groening and Fox executives argued over whether the network would have any creative input into the show. The episode &amp;ldquo;I, Roommate&amp;rdquo; was produced to address Fox&amp;rsquo;s concerns. The name &lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt; comes from a pavilion at the 1939 New York World&amp;rsquo;s Fair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;writing&#34;&gt;Writing &lt;a href=&#34;#writing&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The planning for each episode began with a table meeting of writers, who discussed the plot ideas as a group. A single staff writer wrote an outline and then produced a script. Once the first draft of a script was finished, the writers and executive producers called in the actors for a table read. After this script reading, the writers collaborated to rewrite the script as a group before sending it to the animation team. The writing staff held three Ph.D.s, seven master&amp;rsquo;s degrees, and cumulatively had more than 50 years at Harvard University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;voice-actors&#34;&gt;Voice actors &lt;a href=&#34;#voice-actors&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt; had eight main cast members. Billy West performed the voices of Philip J. Fry, Professor Farnsworth, Doctor Zoidberg, Zapp Brannigan, and many other incidental characters. Katey Sagal voiced Leela, and is the only member of the main cast to voice only one character. John DiMaggio performed the voice of the robot Bender Bending Rodríguez and other, more minor, characters. Phil LaMarr voices Hermes Conrad, his son Dwight, Ethan Bubblegum Tate, and Reverend Preacherbot. Lauren Tom voices Amy Wong, and Tress MacNeille voices Mom and various other characters. Maurice LaMarche voices Kif Kroker and several supporting characters. David Herman voiced Scruffy and various supporting characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;animation&#34;&gt;Animation &lt;a href=&#34;#animation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt; is produced by The Curiosity Company and 20th Television Animation with the animation being done by Rough Draft Studios. In addition to traditional cartoon drawing, Rough Draft Studios often used CGI for fast or complex shots. The series began high-definition production in season 6, with &lt;em&gt;Bender&amp;rsquo;s Big Score&lt;/em&gt;. For the final episode of season 6, &lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt; was completely reanimated in three different styles: Fleischer- and Walter Lantz-style animation, a low-resolution video game, and Japanese anime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hallmarks&#34;&gt;Hallmarks &lt;a href=&#34;#hallmarks&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;opening-sequence&#34;&gt;Opening sequence &lt;a href=&#34;#opening-sequence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Planet Express Ship&lt;/em&gt; flies across the screen with the title of the show being spelled out in its wake. Underneath the title is a joke caption. After flying through downtown New New York and past various recurring characters, the Planet Express ship crashes through a large screen showing a short clip from a classic cartoon. The &lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt; theme was created by Christopher Tyng.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;languages&#34;&gt;Languages &lt;a href=&#34;#languages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three alternative alphabets that appear often in the background of episodes. The first alphabet consists of abstract characters and is referred to as Alienese, a simple substitution cipher from the Latin alphabet. The second alphabet uses a more complex modular addition code. The third language sometimes used is Hebrew. The show predicts that several English expressions will have evolved by the year 3000&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alienese&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alienese&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien (film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e4fdfa33a63f/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 05:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e4fdfa33a63f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-film&#34;&gt;Alien (film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; is a 1979 science fiction horror film directed by Ridley Scott and written by Dan O&amp;rsquo;Bannon. The film follows the crew of the commercial spaceship Nostromo as they encounter a deadly extraterrestrial creature. The film stars Tom Skerritt, Sigourney Weaver, Veronica Cartwright, Harry Dean Stanton, John Hurt, Ian Holm, and Yaphet Kotto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The commercial spaceship Nostromo is returning to Earth when its computer detects a transmission from a nearby planetoid. The crew investigates a derelict alien spaceship and discovers a chamber containing hundreds of eggs. One of the crew members, Kane, is attacked by a creature that attaches itself to his face. The creature eventually detaches itself, and Kane appears to be fine. However, during a meal, a small alien creature bursts from his chest, killing him. The crew then tries to hunt down and kill the alien, which grows into a deadly creature. The crew members are killed off one by one, until only Ripley remains. She initiates the ship&amp;rsquo;s self-destruct sequence and escapes in a shuttle, but the alien stows away. Ripley manages to blast the alien into space before putting herself into stasis for the return to Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tom Skerritt&lt;/strong&gt; as Dallas, captain of the Nostromo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sigourney Weaver&lt;/strong&gt; as Ripley, the warrant officer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Veronica Cartwright&lt;/strong&gt; as Lambert, the navigator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry Dean Stanton&lt;/strong&gt; as Brett, the engineering technician.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Hurt&lt;/strong&gt; as Kane, the executive officer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ian Holm&lt;/strong&gt; as Ash, the science officer who is revealed to be an android.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yaphet Kotto&lt;/strong&gt; as Parker, the chief engineer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bolaji Badejo&lt;/strong&gt; as the alien.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Helen Horton&lt;/strong&gt; as the voice of Mother, the Nostromo&amp;rsquo;s computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;writing&#34;&gt;Writing &lt;a href=&#34;#writing&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan O&amp;rsquo;Bannon and Ronald Shusett collaborated on the screenplay, with O&amp;rsquo;Bannon initially writing 29 pages titled &lt;em&gt;Memory&lt;/em&gt;. The story was influenced by various science fiction and horror works, including &lt;em&gt;The Thing from Another World&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Forbidden Planet&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Planet of the Vampires&lt;/em&gt;. The script was pitched as &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Jaws&lt;/em&gt; in space&amp;rdquo;. Hill and Giler made revisions to the script, adding the android character Ash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;development&#34;&gt;Development &lt;a href=&#34;#development&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20th Century-Fox greenlit &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; after the success of &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;. Ridley Scott was chosen as the director. Scott created detailed storyboards, which led to the film&amp;rsquo;s budget being doubled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;casting&#34;&gt;Casting &lt;a href=&#34;#casting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Casting calls were held in New York City and London. Scott wanted strong actors to focus on the film&amp;rsquo;s visual style. The crew of the Nostromo was intended to resemble working astronauts, described as &amp;ldquo;truckers in space&amp;rdquo;. Scott wrote backstories for each character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;filming&#34;&gt;Filming &lt;a href=&#34;#filming&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Filming took place at Pinewood Studios and Shepperton Studios near London, and model filming was done at Bray Studios. The production schedule was short due to the film&amp;rsquo;s low budget. Sets were constructed for the alien planetoid, the Nostromo, and the derelict spacecraft. The space suits were thick and bulky, causing discomfort for the actors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;post-production&#34;&gt;Post-production &lt;a href=&#34;#post-production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editing and post-production took roughly 20 weeks. The film was edited to have a slow pace to build suspense. One scene that was cut involved Ripley encountering Dallas and Brett, who had been partially cocooned by the alien.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;Music &lt;a href=&#34;#music&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jerry Goldsmith composed the musical score. Scott initially wanted Isao Tomita, but Fox wanted a more familiar composer. Goldsmith&amp;rsquo;s score was nominated for a Golden Globe Award and a Grammy Award, and it won a BAFTA Award.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design &lt;a href=&#34;#design&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;creature-effects&#34;&gt;Creature effects &lt;a href=&#34;#creature-effects&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;H. R. Giger designed the alien and its environment. The &amp;ldquo;facehugger&amp;rdquo; was the first creature Giger designed. The &amp;ldquo;chestburster&amp;rdquo; design was inspired by Francis Bacon&amp;rsquo;s painting &lt;em&gt;Three Studies for Figures at the Base of a Crucifixion&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-alien&#34;&gt;The alien &lt;a href=&#34;#the-alien&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giger made conceptual paintings of the adult alien before settling on the final version. Carlo Rambaldi manufactured the head. Bolaji Badejo portrayed the alien in most scenes. Scott chose not to show the full alien for most of the film to create a sense of terror.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sets&#34;&gt;Sets &lt;a href=&#34;#sets&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sets of the Nostromo&amp;rsquo;s three decks were created in one piece. Ron Cobb created industrial-style symbols and color-coded signs. The company that owns the Nostromo is referred to as &amp;ldquo;Weylan-Yutani&amp;rdquo;. Art director Roger Christian used scrap metal and parts to create set pieces and props.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;spaceships-and-planets&#34;&gt;Spaceships and planets &lt;a href=&#34;#spaceships-and-planets&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ron Cobb and Chris Foss worked on designs for the spaceship and space suits. Cobb created sketches of the ship&amp;rsquo;s interiors and exteriors. The spaceships and planets were shot using models and miniatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;title-sequence&#34;&gt;Title sequence &lt;a href=&#34;#title-sequence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title sequence was developed by R/Greenberg Associates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; was rated &amp;ldquo;R&amp;rdquo; in the United States and &amp;ldquo;X&amp;rdquo; in the United Kingdom. It opened in a limited release in American theaters on May 25, 1979, and received a wide release on June 22.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;box-office&#34;&gt;Box office &lt;a href=&#34;#box-office&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film was a commercial success, grossing $78.9 million in the United States and £7,886,000 in the United Kingdom during its first run. Its total worldwide gross has been estimated at between $104.9 million and $203.6 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;critical-reception&#34;&gt;Critical reception &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critical reaction to &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; was initially mixed. However, in subsequent years, it was critically reassessed and is now considered one of the greatest science fiction and horror films of all time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;accolades&#34;&gt;Accolades &lt;a href=&#34;#accolades&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; won the Academy Award for Best Visual Effects and Saturn Awards for Best Science Fiction Film, Best Direction for Ridley Scott, and Best Supporting Actress for Veronica Cartwright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;post-release&#34;&gt;Post-release &lt;a href=&#34;#post-release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;home-video&#34;&gt;Home video &lt;a href=&#34;#home-video&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; has been released in many home video formats over the years, including VHS, LaserDisc, and DVD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;directors-cut&#34;&gt;Director&amp;rsquo;s Cut &lt;a href=&#34;#directors-cut&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2003, 20th Century Fox released a &amp;ldquo;Director&amp;rsquo;s Cut&amp;rdquo; of &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt;, which included restored footage and recut scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cinematic-analysis&#34;&gt;Cinematic analysis &lt;a href=&#34;#cinematic-analysis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critics have analyzed &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s sexual overtones and its use of abjection. The film has been interpreted as a metaphor for male fear of penetration and as a representation of the &amp;ldquo;monstrous-feminine&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;audience-research&#34;&gt;Audience research &lt;a href=&#34;#audience-research&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Findings from an international audience research project were published in 2016 as &lt;em&gt;Alien Audiences: Remembering and Evaluating a Classic Movie&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;re-release&#34;&gt;Re-release &lt;a href=&#34;#re-release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For its 45th anniversary, &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; was re-released in theaters on April 26, 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legacy&#34;&gt;Legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;critical-reassessment&#34;&gt;Critical reassessment &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-reassessment&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite initial mixed reviews, &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; has received critical acclaim over the years and is seen as one of the most influential science-fiction films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cultural-influences&#34;&gt;Cultural influences &lt;a href=&#34;#cultural-influences&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; had both an immediate and long-term impact on the science fiction and horror genres. The &amp;ldquo;chestburster&amp;rdquo; effect was parodied in Mel Brooks&amp;rsquo;s comedy &lt;em&gt;Spaceballs&lt;/em&gt;. Nintendo&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Metroid&lt;/em&gt; video game series was significantly influenced by &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;merchandise&#34;&gt;Merchandise &lt;a href=&#34;#merchandise&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alan Dean Foster wrote a novelization of the film. &lt;em&gt;Heavy Metal&lt;/em&gt; magazine published a graphic novel adaptation. Model kits and action figures of the alien were released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;school-play-adaptation&#34;&gt;School play adaptation &lt;a href=&#34;#school-play-adaptation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2019, students at North Bergen High School adapted the film into a play, which gained social media recognition and praise from Ridley Scott and Sigourney Weaver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;video-game-adaptation&#34;&gt;Video game adaptation &lt;a href=&#34;#video-game-adaptation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two downloadable content packs for the video game &lt;em&gt;Alien: Isolation&lt;/em&gt; depict alternate versions of key events from the film, with the original cast members reprising their roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sequels-and-franchise&#34;&gt;Sequels and franchise &lt;a href=&#34;#sequels-and-franchise&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The success of &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; led to three direct sequels: &lt;em&gt;Aliens&lt;/em&gt; (1986), &lt;em&gt;Alien 3&lt;/em&gt; (1992), and &lt;em&gt;Alien Resurrection&lt;/em&gt; (1997). The story of Ripley&amp;rsquo;s encounters with the aliens became the thematic and narrative core of the series. The film series resulted in a media franchise with novels, comic books, video games, and merchandise. A prequel series was started with &lt;em&gt;Prometheus&lt;/em&gt; (2012) and continued with &lt;em&gt;Alien: Covenant&lt;/em&gt; (2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_(film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_(film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrials in fiction</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_86feb41cd744/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 03:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_86feb41cd744/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;fictional-depictions-of-extraterrestrial-life&#34;&gt;Fictional Depictions of Extraterrestrial Life &lt;a href=&#34;#fictional-depictions-of-extraterrestrial-life&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses extraterrestrials as they are portrayed in works of fiction, distinguishing them from alleged real-life encounters. It includes a link to a separate article listing alleged extraterrestrial beings. A banner at the top indicates that the article relies heavily on a limited number of sources and needs more citations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the historical evolution of extraterrestrial depictions in fiction, starting from antiquity and progressing through modern times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;antiquity&#34;&gt;Antiquity &lt;a href=&#34;#antiquity&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers early depictions of extraterrestrials, beginning with Lucian&amp;rsquo;s 2nd-century satire &lt;em&gt;True History&lt;/em&gt;, where the protagonist visits the Moon and finds it inhabited by warring factions. It emphasizes how early concepts of extraterrestrials were tied to the development of astronomy and the understanding of celestial objects as physical entities. Early depictions often portrayed aliens as human-like, as exemplified by Voltaire&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Micromégas&lt;/em&gt; and works by Johannes Kepler, Francis Godwin, and Cyrano de Bergerac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-20th-century&#34;&gt;Early 20th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#early-20th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the impact of Charles Darwin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;On the Origin of Species&lt;/em&gt; on alien depictions, leading to the creation of non-humanoid aliens in fiction. Camille Flammarion&amp;rsquo;s works are mentioned as early examples of genuinely alien lifeforms. The section also highlights H.G. Wells&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;The War of the Worlds&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The First Men in the Moon&lt;/em&gt; as influential works that explored the implications of evolution and alien civilizations. The rise of pulp magazines and their role in popularizing science fiction with various alien tropes are also discussed, including the common use of Martians, Venusians, and other Solar System inhabitants. Stanley G. Weinbaum&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;A Martian Odyssey&lt;/em&gt; is noted for its unique Martian ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;modern-times&#34;&gt;Modern Times &lt;a href=&#34;#modern-times&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the evolution of alien depictions in more recent times. It mentions &lt;em&gt;The Eternaut&lt;/em&gt; by Héctor Germán Oesterheld, an Argentine work that critiques imperialism and colonialism through an alien invasion of Buenos Aires. The Barney and Betty Hill incident is discussed as a pivotal event that popularized the &amp;ldquo;grey alien&amp;rdquo; archetype. The influence of TV and films, particularly &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt;, is highlighted, noting the trend towards human-like aliens due to budgetary constraints. The section concludes by mentioning the impact of computer-generated imagery (CGI) on creating more diverse and bizarre alien lifeforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;types&#34;&gt;Types &lt;a href=&#34;#types&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section categorizes the various ways extraterrestrials are portrayed in fiction. It discusses differences in intelligence levels, biological forms (humanoid, Earth-species-like, or bizarre), and attitudes towards humanity (hostile, friendly, or indifferent). It also mentions that some extraterrestrials in fiction originate from unexplored areas of Earth, such as the sea, sky, underground, or other dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See Also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related Wikipedia articles, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parasites in fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of fictional extraterrestrials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of films featuring extraterrestrials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of humanoid aliens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mars in fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First contact (science fiction)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including books, journal articles, and online resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bibliography&#34;&gt;Bibliography &lt;a href=&#34;#bibliography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists additional books related to the topic of extraterrestrials in fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further Reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of additional resources for readers interested in learning more about the topic, including books and articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External Links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a link to an external website with additional information on the use of aliens as metaphors in fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_life_in_popular_culture&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_life_in_popular_culture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of films featuring extraterrestrials</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_3a10b87fbe1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 03:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_3a10b87fbe1b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-films-featuring-extraterrestrials&#34;&gt;List of Films Featuring Extraterrestrials &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-films-featuring-extraterrestrials&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Wikipedia page serves as a comprehensive index of films that prominently feature extraterrestrial beings. It provides a tabular listing of movies, their release years, and any associated franchises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;film-listing&#34;&gt;Film Listing &lt;a href=&#34;#film-listing&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core of the page is a sortable table presenting an extensive list of films featuring extraterrestrials. Each entry includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt; The name of the film, linked to its respective Wikipedia page for more information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year:&lt;/strong&gt; The year the film was released.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Franchise:&lt;/strong&gt; If the film is part of a larger franchise, it&amp;rsquo;s indicated here, linking to the franchise&amp;rsquo;s Wikipedia page. Many films are standalone entries, while others belong to well-known series like &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Cloverfield&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Godzilla&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list spans a wide range of cinematic history, from early silent films to recent releases, and encompasses various genres, including science fiction, horror, comedy, and animation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See Also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to other relevant Wikipedia articles, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lists of fictional extraterrestrials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFOs in fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These links allow readers to explore related topics and delve deeper into the portrayal of aliens and UFOs in various forms of media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a comprehensive list of citations used to verify the information presented in the film listing. These references include links to reputable sources such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AllMovie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rotten Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Hollywood Reporter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empire Magazine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The New York Times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Variety&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Space.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;British Film Institute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turner Classic Movies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And many more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These references ensure the accuracy and reliability of the information provided on the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_films_featuring_extraterrestrials&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_films_featuring_extraterrestrials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Guardian Alien</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8d4c72af093b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 09:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8d4c72af093b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-guardian-alien&#34;&gt;My Guardian Alien &lt;a href=&#34;#my-guardian-alien&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2024 Philippine television drama series broadcast by GMA Network. It is a science fiction drama directed by Zig Madamba Dulay, starring Marian Rivera. The series premiered on April 1, 2024, and concluded on June 28, 2024, with 65 episodes. Originally titled &lt;em&gt;Against All Odds&lt;/em&gt;, it was later renamed. The series is also available for streaming on YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;premise&#34;&gt;Premise &lt;a href=&#34;#premise&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot centers around Katherine, who dies in a shooting accident. During her funeral, an alien &amp;ldquo;pod&amp;rdquo; lands on Earth, and the alien takes Katherine&amp;rsquo;s form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast-and-characters&#34;&gt;Cast and Characters &lt;a href=&#34;#cast-and-characters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the actors and the characters they portray in the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lead Cast:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marian Rivera plays Katherine Villegas-Soriano / 11-1-20-8-5-22-9-12-5 / Grace B. Formin / Mommy Two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supporting Cast:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gabby Concepcion plays Carlos Soriano.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Max Collins plays Venus del Rosario.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raphael Landicho plays Adrian &amp;ldquo;Doy&amp;rdquo; Soriano.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gabby Eigenmann plays Cepheus &amp;ldquo;Ceph&amp;rdquo; Corona.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caitlyn Stave plays Halley del Rosario.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Josh Ford plays Aries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kiray Celis plays Marites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arnold Reyes plays Minggoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tanya Gomez plays Isay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sean Lucas plays Kevin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marissa Delgado plays Nova Soriano.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guest Cast:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maricar de Mesa as younger Nova&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ana Marin as Aurora &amp;ldquo;Auring&amp;rdquo; Vega-Corona&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tart Carlos as Karen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christian Antolin as Sputnik&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kirst Viray as Delfin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyn Barro as Aera Simmons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shanelle Agustin as Emily&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jericho Arceo as Ikong&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Richard Arellano as Generoso&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luke Conde as Vega / Arnold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anne Garcia as Ofel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kitsi Pagaspas as Belen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ira Ruzz as Jenny&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ryan Sandoval as Chito&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orlando Sol as Isko&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Richard Arellano as Generoso&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rodjun Cruz as a dancer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Juan Rodrigo as Tiago&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rochelle Barrameda as Juliet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anjay Anson as Sandro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stanley Abuloc as Tonyo / 11-15-2-12-78-15-22-31-12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists all 65 episodes of &lt;em&gt;My Guardian Alien&lt;/em&gt; with their titles and original release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1: &amp;ldquo;World Premiere&amp;rdquo; (April 1, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 2: &amp;ldquo;Paano Makaka-move On?&amp;rdquo; (April 2, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 3: &amp;ldquo;Ang Pagdating&amp;rdquo; (April 3, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 4: &amp;ldquo;Tao Nga Ba?&amp;rdquo; (April 4, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 5: &amp;ldquo;Memories&amp;rdquo; (April 5, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 6: &amp;ldquo;First Encounter&amp;rdquo; (April 8, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 7: &amp;ldquo;Super Hero&amp;rdquo; (April 9, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 8: &amp;ldquo;Mommy Two&amp;rdquo; (April 10, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 9: &amp;ldquo;How to Hide an Alien?&amp;rdquo; (April 11, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 10: &amp;ldquo;Boses ni Katherine&amp;rdquo; (April 12, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 11: &amp;ldquo;Protect Doy&amp;rdquo; (April 15, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 12: &amp;ldquo;Fight, Fight, Fight&amp;rdquo; (April 16, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 13: &amp;ldquo;Cheers&amp;rdquo; (April 17, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 14: &amp;ldquo;Carlos Meets Alien&amp;rdquo; (April 18, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 15: &amp;ldquo;Alien Encounter&amp;rdquo; (April 19, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 16: &amp;ldquo;Peace Offering&amp;rdquo; (April 22, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 17: &amp;ldquo;Ghost Hunting&amp;rdquo; (April 23, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 18: &amp;ldquo;Babang Luksa&amp;rdquo; (April 24, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 19: &amp;ldquo;The Search&amp;rdquo; (April 25, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 20: &amp;ldquo;Together Again&amp;rdquo; (April 26, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 21: &amp;ldquo;Hello, Grace&amp;rdquo; (April 29, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 22: &amp;ldquo;Time to Recharge&amp;rdquo; (April 30, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 23: &amp;ldquo;Invasion of Privacy&amp;rdquo; (May 1, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 24: &amp;ldquo;Surprise&amp;rdquo; (May 2, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 25: &amp;ldquo;Confrontation&amp;rdquo; (May 3, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 26: &amp;ldquo;Alien Dance&amp;rdquo; (May 6, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 27: &amp;ldquo;Riot sa Bar&amp;rdquo; (May 7, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 28: &amp;ldquo;Lesson in Fear&amp;rdquo; (May 8, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 29: &amp;ldquo;Rejection&amp;rdquo; (May 9, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 30: &amp;ldquo;Crush Landing&amp;rdquo; (May 10, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 31: &amp;ldquo;Confession&amp;rdquo; (May 13, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 32: &amp;ldquo;First LQ&amp;rdquo; (May 14, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 33: &amp;ldquo;Connection&amp;rdquo; (May 15, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 34: &amp;ldquo;Truth Serum&amp;rdquo; (May 16, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 35: &amp;ldquo;Best Day Ever&amp;rdquo; (May 17, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 36: &amp;ldquo;Parental Guidance&amp;rdquo; (May 20, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 37: &amp;ldquo;Bitter Ampalaya&amp;rdquo; (May 21, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 38: &amp;ldquo;Snaky Moves&amp;rdquo; (May 22, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 39: &amp;ldquo;Rage&amp;rdquo; (May 23, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 40: &amp;ldquo;Resbak&amp;rdquo; (May 24, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 41: &amp;ldquo;Scheme&amp;rdquo; (May 27, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 42: &amp;ldquo;Traydor&amp;rdquo; (May 28, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 43: &amp;ldquo;Matinding Duda&amp;rdquo; (May 29, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 44: &amp;ldquo;Rebelasyon&amp;rdquo; (May 30, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 45: &amp;ldquo;Backfire&amp;rdquo; (May 31, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 46: &amp;ldquo;Guilty as Hell&amp;rdquo; (June 3, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 47: &amp;ldquo;Truth and Lies&amp;rdquo; (June 4, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 48: &amp;ldquo;The Confession&amp;rdquo; (June 5, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 49: &amp;ldquo;Dark Secrets&amp;rdquo; (June 6, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 50: &amp;ldquo;Taken&amp;rdquo; (June 7, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 51: &amp;ldquo;Tuso&amp;rdquo; (June 10, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 52: &amp;ldquo;Special Glue&amp;rdquo; (June 11, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 53: &amp;ldquo;FH Virus&amp;rdquo; (June 12, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 54: &amp;ldquo;The Proposal&amp;rdquo; (June 13, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 55: &amp;ldquo;Friend or Spy?&amp;rdquo; (June 14, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 56: &amp;ldquo;Sukdulan&amp;rdquo; (June 17, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 57: &amp;ldquo;In Danger&amp;rdquo; (June 18, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 58: &amp;ldquo;Missing&amp;rdquo; (June 19, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 59&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Guardian_Alien&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Guardian_Alien&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abhimanyu Ki Alien Family</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_138e93881cf7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 05:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_138e93881cf7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;abhimanyu-ki-alien-family&#34;&gt;Abhimanyu Ki Alien Family &lt;a href=&#34;#abhimanyu-ki-alien-family&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abhimanyu Ki Alien Family&lt;/strong&gt; is an Indian animated science fiction comedy series that premiered on Nickelodeon India on April 24, 2023. The show is directed by Abhijit Daripkar and Santosh Pednekar and produced by Hi-Tech Animation. The title track&amp;rsquo;s lyrics are by Gulzar, with music by Simaab Sen. The series revolves around a 12-year-old boy named Abhimanyu who can transform into an alien, focusing on his efforts to fit into human society, make friends, hide his identity, and overcome challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;synopsis&#34;&gt;Synopsis &lt;a href=&#34;#synopsis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series tells the story of Abhimanyu, a 12-year-old who can transform into an alien. The narrative focuses on his journey to integrate with humans, form friendships, conceal his true identity, and tackle various challenges. It also highlights his family&amp;rsquo;s adaptation struggles. Characters are shown in both human and alien forms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The voice cast includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jasleen Singh as Abhimanyu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merlin James as Arya&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mohit Sinha as Naveen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roop Thakkar as Kookie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sanchit Wartak as Supremo of Planet Zonga and Mr. Ghotala&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asavari Ajinkya as Mrs. Ghotala&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pratik Verma as Ronnie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;characters&#34;&gt;Characters &lt;a href=&#34;#characters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abhimanyu:&lt;/strong&gt; The protagonist, a smart and strong alien who can assimilate powers from objects. He must conceal his abilities to maintain his human disguise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arya:&lt;/strong&gt; Abhimanyu&amp;rsquo;s sister and the first-in-command on the Earth mission, serving as Supremo&amp;rsquo;s eyes and ears. Her elastic tongue helps her solve problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Naveen:&lt;/strong&gt; Abhimanyu&amp;rsquo;s father, who can turn people into statues with a touch. He is timid and clumsy, struggling with physical contact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kookie:&lt;/strong&gt; Abhimanyu&amp;rsquo;s mother, who can move massive objects and manipulate wind. She is fascinated by Earth fashion and enjoys shopping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supremo of Planet Zonga:&lt;/strong&gt; The commander of the aliens&amp;rsquo; Earth mission, instructing them to maintain human forms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr. Ghotala:&lt;/strong&gt; The Kumar family&amp;rsquo;s neighbor, an alien research scientist who suspects aliens are nearby. His catchphrase is &amp;ldquo;Aiga!&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mrs. Ghotala:&lt;/strong&gt; The neighbor and friend of the Kumar family. Her catchphrase is &amp;ldquo;Sahi samay par sahi jagah tapakne ki toh meri aadat hai!&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ronnie:&lt;/strong&gt; The Ghotalas&amp;rsquo; son, a bully who uses his height and fashion sense to cause trouble. He is Abhimanyu&amp;rsquo;s enemy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viacom18&amp;rsquo;s Kids TV Network produces the series, and Nickelodeon distributes it. Hi-Tech Animation conceptualized and produced the show using 3D animation techniques with 2D rendering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-1&#34;&gt;Season 1 &lt;a href=&#34;#season-1&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season 1 consists of 70 episodes, with titles including &amp;ldquo;Being Human,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Ghotala Dinner,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Alien Sunglasses,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Beware Of Dog,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Charge Ho Jao,&amp;rdquo; and many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Garima Das of &lt;em&gt;Outlook India&lt;/em&gt; included &lt;em&gt;Abhimanyu Ki Alien Family&lt;/em&gt; in a list of sci-fi shows to watch, highlighting the show&amp;rsquo;s premise and the challenges faced by the alien characters as they navigate human life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abhimanyu_Ki_Alien_Family&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abhimanyu_Ki_Alien_Family&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien Agent (2007 Film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_2bf42b8912c4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_2bf42b8912c4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-agent-2007-film&#34;&gt;Alien Agent (2007 Film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-agent-2007-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry details the 2007 Canadian science fiction action film &lt;em&gt;Alien Agent&lt;/em&gt;. It includes information about the film&amp;rsquo;s director, writers, producers, cast, release date, running time, budget, and other relevant details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rykker, an intergalactic warrior, is stranded on Earth and battles the Syndicate, a group of aliens plotting to take over the planet. Saylon, a Syndicate leader, arrives on Earth to build a wormhole for a full-scale invasion. Isis, the Syndicate&amp;rsquo;s leader, aims to destroy Rykker. Julie, whose family was killed by the Syndicate, seeks revenge and joins Rykker. They journey across the country, pursued by Isis and her forces. The climax occurs at a nuclear reactor, where Rykker and Julie fight Isis, Saylon, and their army to destroy the portal and prevent the invasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film stars Mark Dacascos as Rykker, Amelia Cooke as Isis, and Emma Lahana as Julie. Other cast members include William MacDonald as Sheriff Devlin, Kim Coates as Carl Roderick, Billy Zane as Tom Hanson/Saylon, Dominiquie Vandenberg as Sartek, and Darren Shahlavi as Kaylor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received negative reviews from critics. Adam-Troy Castro of Sci Fi Weekly criticized the film&amp;rsquo;s uninteresting characters and plot. Leah Holmes of SFX magazine gave it a low rating, calling it &amp;ldquo;stupid and nonsensical.&amp;rdquo; George Tiller of PopMatters also gave it a very poor rating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the references used in the article, including reviews from Sci Fi Weekly, SFX magazine, and PopMatters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links to the film&amp;rsquo;s entry on IMDb and the TCM Movie Database are provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;films-directed-by-jesse-v-johnson&#34;&gt;Films directed by Jesse V. Johnson &lt;a href=&#34;#films-directed-by-jesse-v-johnson&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A template listing other films directed by Jesse V. Johnson is included. Films listed include &lt;em&gt;Pit Fighter&lt;/em&gt; (2005), &lt;em&gt;Charlie Valentine&lt;/em&gt; (2009), &lt;em&gt;Green Street Hooligans 2&lt;/em&gt; (2009), &lt;em&gt;The Butcher&lt;/em&gt; (2009), &lt;em&gt;The Package&lt;/em&gt; (2013), &lt;em&gt;Savage Dog&lt;/em&gt; (2017), &lt;em&gt;Accident Man&lt;/em&gt; (2018), &lt;em&gt;Triple Threat&lt;/em&gt; (2019), &lt;em&gt;The Mercenary&lt;/em&gt; (2019), &lt;em&gt;Avengement&lt;/em&gt; (2019), &lt;em&gt;White Elephant&lt;/em&gt; (2022), &lt;em&gt;One Ranger&lt;/em&gt; (2023), and &lt;em&gt;Chief of Station&lt;/em&gt; (2024).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Agent&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Agent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joe Alien</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_76dd0cdfb364/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 23:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_76dd0cdfb364/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;joe-alien&#34;&gt;Joe Alien &lt;a href=&#34;#joe-alien&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe Alien is a British comic book character who appeared in strips published by Fleetway Publications. He debuted in the preview issue of the science fiction anthology &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; in October 1988. The character&amp;rsquo;s strip was one of four linked serials in &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; and was later briefly featured in &lt;em&gt;Eagle&lt;/em&gt; after &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; was canceled. Joe Alien is the last survivor of the planet Xgangbe-4 and joins the &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; mission to help humanity find a new home, commanding the &lt;em&gt;Wildcat 2&lt;/em&gt; exploration shuttle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;creation&#34;&gt;Creation &lt;a href=&#34;#creation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barrie Tomlinson created Joe Alien as part of a new science fiction anthology, &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt;, for Fleetway Publications. The concept involved linking all five features in the comic to form an overall narrative centered on the spaceship &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt;. Tomlinson created four lead characters, including Joe Alien, to head exploration teams. Massimo Belardinelli was the initial artist for &amp;ldquo;Joe Alien,&amp;rdquo; with Tomlinson praising his ability to bring the story to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publishing-history&#34;&gt;Publishing history &lt;a href=&#34;#publishing-history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; began publication in October 1988, featuring &amp;ldquo;Joe Alien&amp;rdquo; as the color strip. Ron Smith took over as the artist from the third issue. &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; was canceled after 12 issues and merged with &lt;em&gt;Eagle&lt;/em&gt; in March 1989. &amp;ldquo;Joe Alien&amp;rdquo; continued in &lt;em&gt;Eagle&lt;/em&gt; for four weeks in May 1989 to complete the story arc and also featured in three episodes of &amp;ldquo;The Wildcat Complete&amp;rdquo; anthology. Rebellion Developments purchased the rights to &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; in 2016 and announced plans to reprint the contents in collected editions. As of 2025, only &amp;ldquo;Turbo Jones&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Loner&amp;rdquo; have been released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot-summary&#34;&gt;Plot summary &lt;a href=&#34;#plot-summary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe Alien joins the &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; mission after Turbo Jones realizes Earth is doomed. Joe, the last survivor of Xgangbe-4, possesses vast knowledge stored in an external brain-pack. He is selected for his intelligence and physical attributes. After the &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; launches, Joe&amp;rsquo;s sensors locate a potential new home for the refugees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He leads the &lt;em&gt;Wildcat Two&lt;/em&gt; shuttle to scout Area 17, where his team encounters carnivorous vegetation and a two-headed alien. They discover that the plants are controlled by a mad human astronaut from a 2079 Mars mission, who is now worshipped as a god. Joe brokers an alliance with giant insects to escape and later participates in other expeditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe shares the story of the Xgangbe&amp;rsquo;s destruction by the Kargroz and his revenge. He is later chosen to find an alien shapeshifter on board the &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt;. Joe, along with Jones, Loner, and Magee, is kidnapped by a Gamemaster of the Glarzon race but is released after defeating the Glarzon&amp;rsquo;s troops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graham Kibble-White described Joe Alien as &amp;ldquo;dopily designed.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joe_Alien&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joe_Alien&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
