<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reverse-Engineering on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/reverse-engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reverse-Engineering on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 17:04:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/reverse-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>David Grusch UFO whistleblower claims</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_20bdbf3bb53b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 17:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_20bdbf3bb53b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;david-grusch-former-us-military-intelligence-officers-claims-about-non-human-spacecraft-recovery&#34;&gt;David Grusch: Former U.S. Military Intelligence Officer&amp;rsquo;s Claims About &amp;ldquo;Non-Human&amp;rdquo; Spacecraft Recovery &lt;a href=&#34;#david-grusch-former-us-military-intelligence-officers-claims-about-non-human-spacecraft-recovery&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article focuses on the claims made by David Grusch, a former U.S. Air Force officer and intelligence official, regarding the U.S. government&amp;rsquo;s alleged involvement in recovering and reverse-engineering &amp;ldquo;non-human&amp;rdquo; spacecraft. It also covers the responses to these claims from various experts and government entities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Charles Grusch is introduced as an Afghanistan combat veteran and former intelligence officer who worked at the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA) and the National Reconnaissance Office (NRO). From 2019 to 2021, he served as the NRO representative to the Unidentified Aerial Phenomena Task Force. He assisted in drafting the National Defense Authorization Act of 2023, which included whistleblower protections for UFO reporting. The section notes that Congressional interest in UFOs increased prior to Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims due to the downing of four objects by the Air Force in February 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gruschs-claims&#34;&gt;Grusch&amp;rsquo;s Claims &lt;a href=&#34;#gruschs-claims&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the specific claims made by David Grusch. He alleges that the U.S. federal government maintains a highly secretive UFO retrieval program, possessing multiple spacecraft of &amp;ldquo;non-human&amp;rdquo; origin and the deceased pilots. He also claims there is evidence of white-collar crime to conceal these programs and that officials have stated people were killed to maintain secrecy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grusch further elaborated on his claims in an interview with &lt;em&gt;Le Parisien&lt;/em&gt;, suggesting UFOs could be from extra dimensions and that the U.S. government transferred crashed UFOs to a defense contractor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a Congressional hearing in July 2023, Grusch testified that he was informed of a multi-decade UAP crash retrieval and reverse-engineering program, but was denied access. He stated that the U.S. government possesses UAP based on interviews with 40 witnesses. He also claimed the U.S. has retrieved &amp;ldquo;non-human &amp;lsquo;biologics&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; from the crafts. When asked about harm or injury related to cover-ups, Grusch said yes, but could only provide details in a SCIF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;responses-from-relevant-experts&#34;&gt;Responses from Relevant Experts &lt;a href=&#34;#responses-from-relevant-experts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents the perspectives of various experts on Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims. It highlights that his assertions are primarily based on alleged documents and conversations, rather than testable evidence. The scientific community generally views claims of government concealment of extraterrestrial visitation as untrue due to a lack of supporting evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joshua Semeter of NASA&amp;rsquo;s UAP independent study team emphasizes the lack of data or material evidence. Adam Frank, an astrophysics professor, criticizes the claims as hearsay. Stuart Clark&amp;rsquo;s opinion piece in &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; includes questions from scientists like Avi Loeb, Michael Garrett, and Sara Russell, who point out the lack of observed extraterrestrial activity and the ease of identifying extraterrestrial materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg Eghigian, a history professor, notes the historical pattern of individuals making &amp;ldquo;bombshell allegations&amp;rdquo; about UFOs without corroboration. Seth Shostak of the SETI Institute questions the lack of physical evidence and dismisses the claims as an &amp;ldquo;argument from authority.&amp;rdquo; Michael Shermer of &lt;em&gt;Skeptic&lt;/em&gt; magazine notes the absence of physical evidence and scientific community involvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Physicist Sean M. Carroll calls the evidence &amp;ldquo;laughable&amp;rdquo; and describes Grusch as a &amp;ldquo;complete crackpot.&amp;rdquo; NASA&amp;rsquo;s JPL director Laurie Leshin denies seeing spacecraft from outside Earth. Michio Kaku suggests the burden of proof has shifted to the Pentagon, a statement Ross Pomeroy criticizes as unscientific.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;responses-from-the-united-states-government&#34;&gt;Responses from the United States Government &lt;a href=&#34;#responses-from-the-united-states-government&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the responses from various U.S. government entities to Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;White House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre referred questions to the Department of Defense (DoD). The Pentagon stated that AARO has not discovered any verifiable information to substantiate claims of programs regarding the possession or reverse-engineering of extraterrestrial materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General Mark Milley, Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, stated he had never encountered evidence to verify Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims. NASA stated it has not found any credible evidence of extraterrestrial life and no evidence that UAPs are extraterrestrial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representative Mike Turner, chairman of the House Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, stated there is no evidence to support claims of the U.S. possessing UFOs from outer space. Senator Lindsey Graham found the claims unreasonable. Senator Josh Hawley expressed less surprise, while other senators, like Kirsten Gillibrand and Marco Rubio, expressed concern about potential unbriefed special access programs and firsthand knowledge from individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senators Chuck Schumer and Mike Rounds proposed the UAP Disclosure Act 2023, an amendment to the 2024 National Defence Authorization Act, to increase access to UAP records. The enrolled bill directs the National Archives to collect government documents about UAPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members of the House Oversight Committee&amp;rsquo;s national security subcommittee received a classified briefing from the Intelligence Community Inspector General (IC IG) Thomas A. Monheim regarding UAP reporting transparency. Some members expressed frustration with the lack of new information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2023-house-committee-oversight-and-accountability-hearing&#34;&gt;2023 House Committee Oversight and Accountability Hearing &lt;a href=&#34;#2023-house-committee-oversight-and-accountability-hearing&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representatives Anna Paulina Luna and Tim Burchett organized a hearing on July 26, 2023, in response to Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims. Grusch testified, repeating his earlier UFO claims. Representative Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez asked where to look for evidence, to which Grusch offered to provide specific information in a closed environment. Officials later informed lawmakers that Grusch lacked the security clearance to discuss the issues in a SCIF. A bipartisan group of U.S. representatives called for the formation of a select committee on UAPs with subpoena power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AARO&amp;rsquo;s director Sean Kirkpatrick criticized Grusch for refusing to speak with AARO and described the hearing as &amp;ldquo;insulting&amp;rdquo; to DoD and Intelligence Community officers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sean-kirkpatrick&#34;&gt;Sean Kirkpatrick &lt;a href=&#34;#sean-kirkpatrick&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After retiring from AARO, Kirkpatrick wrote an opinion piece for &lt;em&gt;Scientific American&lt;/em&gt; stating that the US Government UFO coverup allegations &amp;ldquo;derive from inadvertent or unauthorized disclosures of legitimate U.S. programs or related R&amp;amp;D that have nothing to do with extraterrestrial issues or technology.&amp;rdquo; He described the allegations&amp;rsquo; supporters as &amp;ldquo;a small group of interconnected believers and others with possibly less than honest intentions,&amp;rdquo; who promote a &amp;ldquo;whirlwind of tall tales, fabrication and secondhand or thirdhand retellings&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an interview with Peter Bergen, Kirkpatrick said that Grusch may have misinterpreted things or fallen under the influence of a core group of people. He characterized the situation as a conspiracy by UFO true believers to get the government involved in investigating aliens, a &amp;ldquo;self licking ice cream cone&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;media-reporting-on-gruschs-claims&#34;&gt;Media Reporting on Grusch&amp;rsquo;s Claims &lt;a href=&#34;#media-reporting-on-gruschs-claims&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines how the media has covered Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;connections-to-studies-funded-by-robert-bigelow&#34;&gt;Connections to Studies Funded by Robert Bigelow &lt;a href=&#34;#connections-to-studies-funded-by-robert-bigelow&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keith Kloor writing for &lt;em&gt;Scientific American&lt;/em&gt; draws a connection between Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims and studies funded by Robert Bigelow, noting the specific reference to &amp;ldquo;a football field–sized UFO&amp;rdquo; in both Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims and past claims by Bigelow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reporting-on-psychiatric-treatment-received-by-grusch&#34;&gt;Reporting on Psychiatric Treatment Received by Grusch &lt;a href=&#34;#reporting-on-psychiatric-treatment-received-by-grusch&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ken Klippenstein reported in &lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt; that Grusch was twice committed after incidents involving drunkenness and suicidal comments. Police records mentioned PTSD. Grusch was placed under an emergency custody order and transported to an emergency room, then transferred to an inpatient psychiatric program. The article noted that Grusch&amp;rsquo;s ability to keep his security clearance despite this history &amp;ldquo;appears to contrast with the government&amp;rsquo;s treatment of other employees&amp;rdquo;. Grusch later sued Loudoun County Sheriff for releasing the information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;news-stories-and-commentary&#34;&gt;News Stories and Commentary &lt;a href=&#34;#news-stories-and-commentary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick Pope, who previously ran the British Ministry of Defense &amp;ldquo;UFO Desk,&amp;rdquo; expressed hope for confirmation but notes the difficulty given Grusch&amp;rsquo;s lost security clearance and lack of a &amp;ldquo;smoking gun.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marina Koren wrote in &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt; that the case fits a pattern of unprovable claims. Matt Laslo, writing for &lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt;, described the sympathetic hearing of Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims by some members of Congress as an indication that once-fringe notions have built-in fan bases. Tucker Carlson publicized the claims in a video posted to Twitter and in an interview with Grusch. Tom Rogan, writing in the &lt;em&gt;Washington Examiner&lt;/em&gt;, was skeptical but opined that the claims should be investigated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Prokop, writing for &lt;em&gt;Vox&lt;/em&gt;, noted that skeptics question whether Grusch is repeating tall tales and that mainstream media sources have remained wary. Sean Thomas expressed confusion that others have tried to convince officials and the public that UFOs are worthy of serious consideration. &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; columnist Ross Douthat noted that one interpretation is that parts of the U.S. government see benefit in promoting belief in UFOs. Matt Stieb, writing for &lt;em&gt;New York&lt;/em&gt;, described Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims as &amp;ldquo;crazy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ezra Klein, a columnist with &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, interviewed Leslie Kean, noting the polarized reactions to the story. Steven Greenstreet, a documentary filmmaker, criticized Grusch for associating with ufologists Jeremy Corbell and George Knapp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story received attention from multiple foreign mainstream news outlets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disinformation-campaign-allegations&#34;&gt;Disinformation Campaign Allegations &lt;a href=&#34;#disinformation-campaign-allegations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grusch claimed that intentional disinformation was being promoted by the US government to cast doubt on the veracity of &amp;ldquo;non-human&amp;rdquo; UFO claims. Adam Gabbatt of &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; described Grusch&amp;rsquo;s position as &amp;ldquo;a common conspiracy trope in the UFO community&amp;rdquo;. Others have suggested that Grusch was given disinformation about aliens to encourage belief in the extraordinary claim of aliens. Gareth Nicholson, editor for the *South&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Grusch&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Grusch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
