<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Contactees on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/contactees/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Contactees on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 02:45:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/contactees/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contactee</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_dbb6d230d909/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 02:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_dbb6d230d909/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;contactee&#34;&gt;Contactee &lt;a href=&#34;#contactee&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A contactee is a person who claims to have experienced contact with extraterrestrial beings. Evidence for these claims is anecdotal. The phenomenon gained prominence in the 1950s and continues to this day. Contactees often share their experiences through books, articles, lectures, and conventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;paranormal-series&#34;&gt;Paranormal Series &lt;a href=&#34;#paranormal-series&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists various topics related to the paranormal, including astral projection, astrology, clairvoyance, cryptozoology, demonic possession, exorcism, fortune-telling, ghost hunting, magic, mediumship, miracles, the occult, psychic phenomena, reincarnation, spiritualism, telekinesis, ufology, and related skeptical viewpoints and parapsychological concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;verification-needed&#34;&gt;Verification Needed &lt;a href=&#34;#verification-needed&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a standard Wikipedia notice indicating that the article requires additional citations to reliable sources for verification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section defines contactees as individuals claiming communication with benign extraterrestrial beings, often receiving messages of cosmic importance. It notes the rise of contactees after the beginning of the modern UFO era in the late 1940s, their activities at UFO conventions, and the skeptical view of them as charlatans or deluded individuals. Susan Clancy is mentioned, attributing such claims to false memories. Common features of contactee claims, as summarized by Curtis Peebles, include physical or mental contact with humanoid aliens, travel on alien spacecraft, the aliens&amp;rsquo; desire to help humanity solve its problems, and the existence of sinister &amp;ldquo;Men in Black&amp;rdquo; who suppress the message of peace. J. Allen Hynek is quoted, defining contactees as chosen recipients of messages of &amp;ldquo;cosmic importance&amp;rdquo; from benign beings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section traces the history of contactee claims, starting with early examples like Emanuel Swedenborg in the 18th century, who claimed psychic contact with inhabitants of other planets. Thomas Blott&amp;rsquo;s 1891 book, &lt;em&gt;The Man From Mars&lt;/em&gt;, is mentioned as an early example of a contactee account. George Adamski, a prominent contactee of the 1950s, is discussed, noting his earlier interest in the occult and the similarity between his messages from Venusians and his earlier teachings. Christopher Partridge is cited, highlighting that pre-1947 contactee claims did not involve UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-examples&#34;&gt;Early Examples &lt;a href=&#34;#early-examples&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection highlights Emanuel Swedenborg&amp;rsquo;s 18th-century claims of contact with inhabitants of other planets and Thomas Blott&amp;rsquo;s 1891 book, &lt;em&gt;The Man From Mars&lt;/em&gt;, as early examples of contactee accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1900s&#34;&gt;1900s &lt;a href=&#34;#1900s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses George Adamski&amp;rsquo;s background in the occult and the Royal Order of Tibet, a neo-theosophical organization he founded in the 1930s. Michael Barkun&amp;rsquo;s observation that Adamski&amp;rsquo;s later messages from Venusians resembled his earlier occult teachings is noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contactees-in-the-ufo-era&#34;&gt;Contactees in the UFO Era &lt;a href=&#34;#contactees-in-the-ufo-era&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses how contactees in the 1950s sometimes provided photographs of alleged flying saucers or their occupants as evidence. George Adamski&amp;rsquo;s photos of a &amp;ldquo;Venusian scout ship&amp;rdquo; are mentioned, noting their resemblance to a chicken egg incubator. George Van Tassel&amp;rsquo;s annual &amp;ldquo;Giant Rock Interplanetary Spacecraft Convention&amp;rdquo; in the Mojave Desert is also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;response-to-contactee-claims&#34;&gt;Response to Contactee Claims &lt;a href=&#34;#response-to-contactee-claims&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the general dismissal of contactees within ufology as charlatans or the lunatic fringe. Jacques Vallée&amp;rsquo;s statement that &amp;ldquo;No serious investigator has ever been very worried by the claims of the &amp;lsquo;contactees&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; is quoted. Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s skepticism is presented, noting that aliens seem happy to answer vague questions but remain silent when confronted with specific, technical questions. David M. Jacobs&amp;rsquo; observation that contactee accounts grew more elaborate over time and that older contactees often backdated their first encounters is mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-contactees&#34;&gt;List of Contactees &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-contactees&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of prominent UFO contactees, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;George Adamski&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wayne Sulo Aho&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orfeo Angelucci&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Truman Bethurum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daniel Fry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gabriel Green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steven M. Greer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Betty and Barney Hill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;George King&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elizabeth Klarer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aladino Félix (aka Dino Kraspedon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gloria Lee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nancy Lieder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Riley Martin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Billy Meier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Howard Menger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buck Nelson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ted Owens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sixto Paz Wells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reinhold O. Schmidt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whitley Strieber&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sun Ra&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;George Van Tassel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Samuel Eaton Thompson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claude Vorilhon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;George Hunt Williamson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dwight York&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the references cited in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External Links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external websites offering additional information on 1950s contactees and their associated religious cults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contactee&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contactee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contactee</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e161eb739be7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 02:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e161eb739be7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;contactee&#34;&gt;Contactee &lt;a href=&#34;#contactee&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A contactee is a person who claims to have experienced contact with extraterrestrial beings. Evidence for these claims is anecdotal. The phenomenon gained prominence in the 1950s and continues to this day. Contactees often share their experiences through books, articles, lectures, and conventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;paranormal-series&#34;&gt;Paranormal Series &lt;a href=&#34;#paranormal-series&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists various topics related to the paranormal, including astral projection, astrology, clairvoyance, cryptozoology, demonic possession, exorcism, fortune-telling, ghost hunting, magic, mediumship, miracles, the occult, psychic phenomena, reincarnation, spiritualism, telekinesis, ufology, and related skeptical viewpoints and parapsychological concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;verification-needed&#34;&gt;Verification Needed &lt;a href=&#34;#verification-needed&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a standard Wikipedia notice indicating that the article requires additional citations to reliable sources for verification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section defines contactees as individuals claiming communication with benign extraterrestrial beings, often receiving messages of cosmic importance. It notes the rise of contactees after the beginning of the modern UFO era in the late 1940s, their activities at UFO conventions, and the skeptical view of them as charlatans or deluded individuals. Susan Clancy is mentioned as attributing such claims to false memories. Common themes in contactee claims, as summarized by Curtis Peebles, include physical or mental contact with humanoid aliens, travel aboard alien spacecraft, aliens&amp;rsquo; desire to help humanity solve its problems, and the existence of sinister figures like the Men in Black who suppress the truth about UFOs. J. Allen Hynek is quoted defining contactees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section traces the history of contactee claims, starting with early examples like Emanuel Swedenborg in the 18th century, who claimed psychic contact with inhabitants of other planets. Thomas Blott&amp;rsquo;s 1891 book, &lt;em&gt;The Man From Mars&lt;/em&gt;, is mentioned as an early example of a contactee account. George Adamski, a prominent contactee of the 1950s, is noted for his earlier interest in the occult. Christopher Partridge is cited for observing that pre-1947 contactee claims did not involve UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-examples&#34;&gt;Early Examples &lt;a href=&#34;#early-examples&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection highlights Emanuel Swedenborg&amp;rsquo;s 1758 publication, &lt;em&gt;Concerning Earths in the Solar System&lt;/em&gt;, detailing his alleged journeys to inhabited planets. J. Gordon Melton&amp;rsquo;s observation that Swedenborg&amp;rsquo;s travels stopped at Saturn, the furthest known planet at the time, is included. Thomas Blott&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;em&gt;The Man From Mars&lt;/em&gt; is mentioned, noting the unusual detail of the Martian communicating in English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1900s&#34;&gt;1900s &lt;a href=&#34;#1900s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection focuses on George Adamski, noting his earlier involvement with the occult and the Royal Order of Tibet. Michael Barkun&amp;rsquo;s observation that Adamski&amp;rsquo;s later messages from Venusians resembled his earlier occult teachings is included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contactees-in-the-ufo-era&#34;&gt;Contactees in the UFO Era &lt;a href=&#34;#contactees-in-the-ufo-era&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses how contactees in the 1950s sometimes presented photographs as evidence, noting that George Adamski&amp;rsquo;s photos of a &amp;ldquo;Venusian scout ship&amp;rdquo; resembled a chicken egg incubator. George Van Tassel&amp;rsquo;s annual &amp;ldquo;Giant Rock Interplanetary Spacecraft Convention&amp;rdquo; in the Mojave Desert is also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;response-to-contactee-claims&#34;&gt;Response to Contactee Claims &lt;a href=&#34;#response-to-contactee-claims&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the general dismissal of contactees within ufology as either charlatans or the lunatic fringe. Jacques Vallée&amp;rsquo;s statement that serious investigators were never worried by contactee claims is included. Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s skepticism is presented, highlighting his anecdote about aliens being unable to answer specific, technical questions. David M. Jacobs&amp;rsquo; observation that contactee accounts grew more elaborate over time, with older contactees backdating their first encounters, is also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-contactees&#34;&gt;List of Contactees &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-contactees&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of prominent UFO contactees, including George Adamski, Wayne Sulo Aho, Orfeo Angelucci, Truman Bethurum, Daniel Fry, Gabriel Green, Steven M. Greer, Betty and Barney Hill, George King, Elizabeth Klarer, Aladino Félix (Dino Kraspedon), Gloria Lee, Nancy Lieder, Riley Martin, Billy Meier, Howard Menger, Buck Nelson, Ted Owens, Sixto Paz Wells, Reinhold O. Schmidt, Whitley Strieber, Sun Ra, George Van Tassel, Samuel Eaton Thompson, Claude Vorilhon, George Hunt Williamson, and Dwight York.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the references cited in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External Links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external websites offering additional information about 1950s contactees and their associated religious cults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufos-template&#34;&gt;UFOs Template &lt;a href=&#34;#ufos-template&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a navigation template for UFO-related topics, including claimed sightings, types of UFOs, types of alleged extraterrestrial beings, studies and timelines, hypotheses, conspiracy theories, involvement, culture, skepticism, and government responses. It lists various UFO sightings throughout history and across different countries, as well as confirmed hoaxes and notable figures and organizations in the field of ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contactees&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contactees&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
