<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cryptozoology on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/cryptozoology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cryptozoology on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 17:24:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/cryptozoology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rod (optical phenomenon)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_f4bb8cead9e4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_f4bb8cead9e4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;rods-optical-phenomenon&#34;&gt;Rods (Optical Phenomenon) &lt;a href=&#34;#rods-optical-phenomenon&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rods, also known as skyfish, air rods, or solar entities, are elongated visual artifacts that appear in photographic images and video recordings. While cryptozoologists and ufologists consider them paranormal, most optical analyses conclude they are insects moving across the frame during capture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;optical-analysis&#34;&gt;Optical Analysis &lt;a href=&#34;#optical-analysis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the scientific explanations for the &amp;ldquo;rod&amp;rdquo; phenomenon. Robert Todd Carroll, consulting with entomologist Doug Yanega, identified rods as images of flying insects captured over several wing-beating cycles on video. This creates the illusion of a single, elongated body. A report by &amp;ldquo;The Straight Dope&amp;rdquo; also attributes rods to tricks of light and motion blur due to long exposure times when recording flying insects. The section emphasizes that claims of extraordinary or alien origins are often attributed to imagination or hoaxes. China Central Television (CCTV) aired a documentary debunking rods, revealing them to be ordinary insects captured by surveillance cameras. Scientists at Tonghua Zhenguo Pharmaceutical Company in Tonghua City, Jilin Province, captured &amp;ldquo;rods&amp;rdquo; in nets, finding them to be moths and other insects. UFO investigator Robert Sheaffer, after attending a lecture by Jose Escamilla, concluded that some &amp;ldquo;rods&amp;rdquo; were insects moving rapidly, while others were blurred bird wings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;paranormal-claims&#34;&gt;Paranormal Claims &lt;a href=&#34;#paranormal-claims&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the paranormal interpretations of rods, particularly those promoted by Jose Escamilla. Escamilla claimed to have filmed the first rods on March 19, 1994, in Roswell, New Mexico, while attempting to film a UFO. He subsequently created videos and gave lectures promoting his claims of rods being alien life forms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;explanatory-notes&#34;&gt;Explanatory Notes &lt;a href=&#34;#explanatory-notes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a footnote clarifying that claims of rods being extraordinary creatures are often exploited by unscrupulous individuals for profit, according to &amp;ldquo;Straight Dope&amp;rdquo; staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See Also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists related topics, including optical phenomena and orbs (optics).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of references used in the article, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert Todd Carroll&amp;rsquo;s entry on &amp;ldquo;rods&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;The Skeptic&amp;rsquo;s Dictionary&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doug Yanega&amp;rsquo;s explanation of rods in &amp;ldquo;The Straight Dope.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A report from SINA Technology News about CCTV&amp;rsquo;s documentary debunking rods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert Sheaffer&amp;rsquo;s article &amp;ldquo;ET, You&amp;rsquo;ve Got Mail&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;Skeptical Inquirer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External Links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external resources, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jose Escamilla&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Rods&amp;rdquo; Video Sequences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brian Dunning&amp;rsquo;s Skeptoid podcast episode on rods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A video of &amp;ldquo;rods&amp;rdquo; at the Cave of the Swallows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A detailed video analysis of rods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rod_(ufology)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rod_(ufology)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
