<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Betty and Barney Hill on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/betty-and-barney-hill/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Betty and Barney Hill on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 12:51:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/betty-and-barney-hill/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The UFO Incident</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_805568563ffd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 12:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_805568563ffd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-ufo-incident&#34;&gt;The UFO Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#the-ufo-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a Wikipedia article about the 1975 American made-for-television biographical film, &lt;em&gt;The UFO Incident&lt;/em&gt;. The film stars James Earl Jones and Estelle Parsons and is based on the alleged 1961 alien abduction of Barney and Betty Hill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the storyline of the film. It begins by introducing Barney and Betty Hill as an interracial couple who are troubled by a traumatic experience, a mysterious lapse in memory after seeing a UFO. They consult psychiatrist Doctor Benjamin Simon, who uses hypnosis to help them recall the event. Under hypnosis, Barney and Betty describe being abducted by grey aliens and subjected to medical experiments. The section concludes by stating that Barney died in 1969 and Betty lived until 2004.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-cast&#34;&gt;Main cast &lt;a href=&#34;#main-cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the main actors and the characters they portrayed in the film:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Earl Jones as Barney Hill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Estelle Parsons as Betty Hill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Barnard Hughes as Dr. Benjamin Simon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dick O&amp;rsquo;Neill as Gen. James Davison&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beeson Carroll as Lt. Col. Jack MacRainey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terrence O&amp;rsquo;Conner as Lisa MacRainey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jeanne Joe as &amp;ldquo;Examiner&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lou Wagner as &amp;ldquo;The Leader&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;releases&#34;&gt;Releases &lt;a href=&#34;#releases&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions that &lt;em&gt;The UFO Incident&lt;/em&gt; did not have an official home video release until June 21, 2022, when Kino Lorber Studio Classics released a 2K remaster of the film on Blu-ray. The release included bonus features such as a commentary by filmmaker and historian Gary Gerani, a documentary about the film&amp;rsquo;s music composer Billy Goldenberg, and optional English subtitles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;possible-remake&#34;&gt;Possible remake &lt;a href=&#34;#possible-remake&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses a potential remake of the film. In 2011, &lt;em&gt;The Huffington Post&lt;/em&gt; reported that a more detailed film depicting the events of the Hill&amp;rsquo;s alleged encounter and abduction was being considered. The new film was to be based on the book &lt;em&gt;Captured! The Betty and Barney Hill UFO Experience&lt;/em&gt; (2007) by Stanton Friedman and Kathleen Marden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historic-context&#34;&gt;Historic context &lt;a href=&#34;#historic-context&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides historical context for the film&amp;rsquo;s release. It mentions that the film aired shortly before the Travis Walton UFO incident, leading cognitive psychologist Susan Clancy to suggest that the film may have influenced Walton&amp;rsquo;s account of his alleged abduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including books and news articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the film&amp;rsquo;s page on IMDb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_UFO_Incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_UFO_Incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
