<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Virus on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/virus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Virus on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 11:49:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/virus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Hunter (2003 Film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ef89d1d65030/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 11:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ef89d1d65030/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-hunter-2003-film&#34;&gt;Alien Hunter (2003 Film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-hunter-2003-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry provides information about the 2003 American-Bulgarian science fiction thriller film &lt;em&gt;Alien Hunter&lt;/em&gt;. It includes details about the film&amp;rsquo;s production, plot, cast, and links to external resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot summary details a series of events triggered by a mysterious signal. In 1947, a radio operator disappears while investigating a signal from Roswell, New Mexico. In the present day, the same signal reappears, originating from the South Pole. Cryptologist Julian Rome (played by James Spader) is recruited to investigate an alien object discovered in Antarctica. The object, emitting the signal, contains a deadly virus and an alien. The virus kills members of the research team and threatens a global pandemic. A nuclear strike is ordered to contain the threat. Julian communicates with the alien before it is killed, discovering the virus&amp;rsquo;s potential to destroy all life on Earth. Julian and three others are rescued by an alien spacecraft moments before the nuclear strike. The government covers up the incident, claiming a nuclear reactor meltdown. The film concludes with the alien spacecraft carrying the survivors leaving the solar system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the actors and the characters they portray in the film. Key actors include James Spader as Julian Rome, John Lynch as Dr. Michael Straub, Leslie Stefanson as Nyla Olson, and Carl Lewis as Grisham. Other notable cast members include Roy Dotrice and Keir Dullea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a reference to &lt;em&gt;The Thing&lt;/em&gt; (1982 film), suggesting a thematic similarity or influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is empty, indicating a lack of citations within the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to the film&amp;rsquo;s entry on IMDb, the TCM Movie Database, and a full film on YouTube via Crackle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Hunter&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Hunter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
