<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Greece on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/greece/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Greece on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 17:56:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/greece/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in Greece</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7ee64ee5c34b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 17:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7ee64ee5c34b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-within-the-nation-of-greece&#34;&gt;List of alleged UFO sightings within the nation of Greece &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-within-the-nation-of-greece&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article catalogs alleged UFO sightings in Greece, spanning from ancient times to the modern era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;404-bc&#34;&gt;404 BC &lt;a href=&#34;#404-bc&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions a fiery pillar sighting near Athens during a stormy, moonless night in 404 BC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1946&#34;&gt;1946 &lt;a href=&#34;#1946&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the &amp;ldquo;Ghost rockets&amp;rdquo; phenomenon witnessed in Thessaloniki by British Army units. It mentions Prime Minister Konstantinos Tsaldaris reporting projectiles over Macedonia and Thessaloniki. Physicist Paul Santorini led a Greek government investigation that was later stopped after conferring with the U.S. Department of Defense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1954&#34;&gt;1954 &lt;a href=&#34;#1954&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the &amp;ldquo;Great 1954 Greek UFO flap,&amp;rdquo; a period of numerous UFO sightings. Specific incidents include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vrisa, Lesvos: Residents reported a small, star-like object maneuvering over the village.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anemotia, Lesvos: A large luminous object with a tail hovered over the village.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stipsi, Lesvos: A cigar-shaped object was witnessed by a boy and his father.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agios Georgios Nileias, Thessaly: A large luminous cigar-shaped object appeared.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agiasos, Lesvos: Reports of a luminescent UFO hovering over the village.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doxato: A bright tail moving in circles was observed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Didymoteicho: Residents witnessed a UFO landing of two cigar-shaped objects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Antimachia, Kos: A flying object emitting a blinding light was witnessed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rhodos: A disc was reported traveling at high speeds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moudros, Lemnos: A flying frying pan was reported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pyrgos, Peloponnese: Witnesses observed a blinding flash in the sky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alissos, Patras: A bright luminous object was witnessed by hunters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pagasetic Gulf, Volos: A silvery flying saucer was witnessed and exploded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Komotini: A flying saucer was observed moving in circles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Athens: A luminous UFO was traveling over Faliro and Athens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plagiari, Pella: A priest and residents witnessed a flying saucer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Athens: A silvery object stood still in the air.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Halki: Farmers saw a bright object traveling at high speeds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Titani: An elderly man claimed to see a small car-like object rolling on a field that then took off into the sky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1955&#34;&gt;1955 &lt;a href=&#34;#1955&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions a sighting near Agrinio where a truck driver and hotel manager saw a luminous flying object overhead, causing the truck engine to stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1959&#34;&gt;1959 &lt;a href=&#34;#1959&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes a strong flash of light and a loud bang observed over Kalymnos island, followed by a rocket-shaped object moving across the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1968&#34;&gt;1968 &lt;a href=&#34;#1968&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details an automobile mechanic in Xiromero observing a bullet-like UFO hovering and moving vertically before traveling west.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1985&#34;&gt;1985 &lt;a href=&#34;#1985&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section includes two sightings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Komotini: Fishermen witnessed a dark, cigar-shaped object moving slowly and then stopping before traveling north.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Naxos, Lemnos, Corfu: Air traffic controllers at three locations reported a cigar-like object moving at extremely high speeds. Officials speculated it could be a spaceship or American laser tests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1990&#34;&gt;1990 &lt;a href=&#34;#1990&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes a UFO crash near Megaplatanos Fthiotida. Witnesses reported multiple UFOs, one of which crashed. The remaining UFOs allegedly landed and collected debris until sunrise. The Hellenic Air Force investigated, suggesting it might have been a Soviet satellite or plane. Metallic pieces were sent to the Space Research Institute in Brussels. Georg N. Pantoulas interviewed witnesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to related articles, including &amp;ldquo;List of reported UFO sightings,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;National Observatory of Athens,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;UFO sightings in the Canary Islands.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bibliography&#34;&gt;Bibliography &lt;a href=&#34;#bibliography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of books and articles used as resources for the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Greece&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Greece&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
