<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anthropology on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/anthropology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anthropology on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 23:17:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/anthropology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Uncontacted peoples</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_87f3a49b74f0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 23:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_87f3a49b74f0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;uncontacted-peoples&#34;&gt;Uncontacted Peoples &lt;a href=&#34;#uncontacted-peoples&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncontacted peoples are Indigenous groups who live without sustained contact with neighboring communities and the world community. They choose to remain isolated, and are referred to as indigenous peoples in voluntary isolation. Estimates suggest there are between 100 and 200 uncontacted tribes, totaling up to 10,000 individuals, primarily located in South America, especially northern Brazil. Knowledge about these groups is mainly gathered from neighboring Indigenous communities and aerial footage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;definition&#34;&gt;Definition &lt;a href=&#34;#definition&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;uncontacted peoples&amp;rdquo; refers to Indigenous groups who have remained largely isolated, maintaining their traditional lifestyles independently from political or governmental entities. While most Indigenous groups have had some form of contact due to European exploration and colonization, &amp;ldquo;uncontacted&amp;rdquo; signifies a lack of sustained contact with the majority of non-Indigenous society today. The Inter-American Commission on Human Rights calls them &amp;ldquo;Indigenous peoples in voluntary isolation,&amp;rdquo; defined by their rejection of contact with outsiders, including those who previously had contact but chose to return to isolation. These groups are viewed as contemporaries of modernity, not relics of the past. A 2009 United Nations report also includes &amp;ldquo;peoples in initial contact&amp;rdquo; who are beginning to integrate into mainstream society. International organizations emphasize their agency by calling them &amp;ldquo;Indigenous peoples in isolation&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;in voluntary isolation,&amp;rdquo; also known as &amp;ldquo;hidden peoples&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;uncontacted tribes.&amp;rdquo; Historically, European colonial ideas about uncontacted peoples were influenced by the search for Prester John and the Ten Lost Tribes of Israel, identifying them as &amp;ldquo;lost tribes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;relations-with-outsiders&#34;&gt;Relations with Outsiders &lt;a href=&#34;#relations-with-outsiders&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International organizations emphasize protecting indigenous peoples&amp;rsquo; lands and environment, preventing exploitation and abuse, and avoiding contact to prevent the spread of modern diseases. Historic exploitation has led governments to grant legal protection and land rights to uncontacted peoples, such as in the Vale do Javari in Brazil and North Sentinel Island in India. In 1961, British explorer Richard Mason was killed by the Panará tribe. Contact in 1973, when the BR-163 road was built through their territory, led to disease and environmental degradation, killing over 250 of the 350 Panará members within a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contention often arises from governments&amp;rsquo; desire to extract natural resources. In Brazil, the government attempted assimilation in the 1960s and 1970s, but in 1987, the Department of Isolated Indians (FUNAI) was created, securing protected lands. In Colombia, contact with the Nukak tribe by an evangelical group led to respiratory infections, clashes with drug traffickers, and the death of over half the tribe, resulting in government relocation and poverty. Exploitation for lumbering, ranching, oil prospecting, and poaching poses significant dangers. Former Peruvian President Alan García claimed uncontacted groups were a &amp;ldquo;fabrication of environmentalists.&amp;rdquo; In 2016, a Chinese mining subsidiary in Bolivia ignored signs of encroaching on uncontacted tribes. Missionaries can also cause great damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2014, Acre Indians contacted the Brazilian government due to threats from cocaine traffickers, indicating awareness of the outside world and strategic decisions to avoid contact. Satellite images show tribes migrating away from roads and logging. Indigenous rights activists advocate for leaving isolated peoples alone to protect their self-determination. FUNAI collaborates with experts to make controlled initial contact, operating trading posts for metal tools and cooking instruments, preventing conflicts, and delivering vaccinations. However, FUNAI reported receiving only 15% of its requested budget in 2017. In 2018, FUNAI released videos and images of tribes to raise public awareness and protect them from commercial pressures, investigating a possible mass homicide against the Flecheiros tribe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United Nations Human Rights Council (2009) and the Inter-American Commission on Human Rights (2013) introduced guidelines including the right to choose self-isolation. Reports of &amp;ldquo;human safaris&amp;rdquo; in India&amp;rsquo;s Andaman Islands and the Peruvian Amazon, where tourists seek to view uncontacted peoples, are controversial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;by-region&#34;&gt;By Region &lt;a href=&#34;#by-region&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;india&#34;&gt;India &lt;a href=&#34;#india&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sentinelese&#34;&gt;Sentinelese &lt;a href=&#34;#sentinelese&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sentinelese people of North Sentinel Island reject contact, often with lethal force. Their language differs significantly from other Andaman languages, suggesting millennia of isolation. Experts consider them the most isolated people in the world. Indian visits to the island ceased in 1997. In 2018, John Allen Chau, an American missionary, was killed while illegally visiting the island. In 2025, a US citizen was arrested for making an unauthorized landing on the island. Survival International condemned these actions, noting the vulnerability of uncontacted peoples to contact-induced diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;shompen&#34;&gt;Shompen &lt;a href=&#34;#shompen&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shompen are the Indigenous people of Great Nicobar Island, with an estimated population of 300 in 2001. They practice a hunter-gatherer economy. Survival International identifies them as one of the most isolated peoples, with most refusing interactions with outsiders. The proposed Great Nicobar Development Plan, including an airport, international port, and industrial park, threatens their way of life. In February 2024, 39 genocide experts warned that the development would be a &amp;ldquo;death sentence&amp;rdquo; for the Shompen due to increased population and exposure to outside diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;south-america&#34;&gt;South America &lt;a href=&#34;#south-america&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bolivia&#34;&gt;Bolivia &lt;a href=&#34;#bolivia&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Toromona are an uncontacted people living near the Madidi and Heath Rivers. The government has created a protected area within Madidi National Park for them. Among the Ayoreo people of the Gran Chaco, a small number of uncontacted nomadic hunter-gatherers reside in the Kaa-Iya del Gran Chaco National Park. Pacahuaras are believed to be living in voluntary isolation in Pando Department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;brazil&#34;&gt;Brazil &lt;a href=&#34;#brazil&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until the 1970s, Brazil attempted to move people on commercially cultivatable lands. In 1987, the Department of Isolated Indians (FUNAI) was established, and the Vale do Javari was declared perpetually sealed off. In 2007, FUNAI reported 67 uncontacted Indigenous peoples, up from 40 in 2005. The Awá people live in the eastern Amazon rainforest, with approximately 350 members, 100 of whom are uncontacted. Their tribe is at risk due to conflicts with logging interests. The Kawahiva live in northern Mato Grosso, constantly moving and known primarily from physical evidence. In 2013, the government released video of the Kawahiva filmed in 2011. In 2025, FUNAI confirmed that the demarcation of the Kawahiva do Rio Pardo territory will happen by the end of 2025. The Korubu live in the lower Vale do Javari. The Flecheiros (&amp;ldquo;arrow people&amp;rdquo;) also live in the Vale do Javari. Other tribes may include the Uru-Eu-Wau-Wau and the Himarimã.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2019, two brothers of the Piripkura tribe initiated contact with FUNAI after their fire went out, becoming the focus of the documentary &lt;em&gt;Piripkura&lt;/em&gt;. Another man, the &amp;ldquo;Man of the Hole,&amp;rdquo; lived alone on 8,000 hectares, digging hundreds of holes. He was found dead in his dwelling in August 2022. Since 2021, uncontacted peoples in Brazil have been threatened by illegal land grabbers, loggers, and gold miners. The government of Jair Bolsonaro signaled its intention to develop the Amazon and reduce Indigenous reservations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;colombia&#34;&gt;Colombia &lt;a href=&#34;#colombia&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colombia is regarded as offering maximum protection to uncontacted Indigenous people through tribal reserves and strict patrolling. The Nukak people are nomadic hunter-gatherers living between the Guaviare and Inírida rivers. Groups, including the Carabayo, Yuri, and Passé, reside in Río Puré National Park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;ecuador&#34;&gt;Ecuador &lt;a href=&#34;#ecuador&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two isolated Indigenous peoples of Ecuador live in the Amazon region: the Tagaeri and the Taromenane, both eastern Huaorani peoples living in Yasuni National Park. These semi-nomadic people live in small groups, subsisting on hunting, gathering, and some crops. Since 2007, national policy mandates untouchability, self-determination, equality, and no contact. In 2013, more than 20 Taromenane were killed by Waorani, another Huaorani group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;paraguay&#34;&gt;Paraguay &lt;a href=&#34;#paraguay&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approximately 100 Ayoreo people, some of whom are in the Totobiegosode tribe, live uncontacted in the forest. They are nomadic hunter-gatherers in Amotocodie. They are the last uncontacted peoples south of the Amazon Basin, threatened by illegal deforestation. Brazilian company Yaguarete Porá S.A. is converting their ancestral territory into cattle ranching land. The Union of Ayoreo Natives of Paraguay is working for their protection, with support from the Iniciativa Amotocodie. In 2021, the Ayoreo appealed to the Inter-American Commission on Human Rights to save their land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;peru&#34;&gt;Peru &lt;a href=&#34;#peru&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Nomole (Mashco-Piro) are nomadic Arawak-speaking hunter-gatherers who inhabit Manú National Park. In 1998, their number was estimated at 100 to 250. They speak a dialect of the Piro languages. Amid incursions on their land, the tribe has made it clear they do not wish to be contacted. In July 2024, video and images of dozens of uncontact&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uncontacted_peoples&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uncontacted_peoples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First contact (anthropology)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_9169b770761b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 09:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_9169b770761b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-contact-anthropology&#34;&gt;First Contact (Anthropology) &lt;a href=&#34;#first-contact-anthropology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First contact, in anthropology, refers to the initial meeting between two communities that were previously unaware of each other. This phenomenon is often associated with significant cultural and societal impacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;consequences&#34;&gt;Consequences &lt;a href=&#34;#consequences&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When cultures with vastly different technological advancements meet, the more technologically advanced society often has a disruptive advantage. This can lead to dire consequences for the less advanced society. Disease transmission also plays a critical role, as isolated populations often lack immunity to illnesses carried by the more urbanized society. The relative sizes of the populations involved can also influence intercultural development. Outcomes of first contact can range from social integration and colonization to elimination (genocide).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before contemporary instances of contact with uncontacted peoples, many communities and states were isolated from each other, possessing limited knowledge of one another. The limited formal contact between Europe and China via the Silk Road and later with the Mongol Empire is one such example. European powers, such as Prince Henry the Navigator of Portugal, sought to reach Greater India, leading to the mistaken identification of the Americas as the West Indies and the indigenous peoples of the Americas as &amp;ldquo;Indians.&amp;rdquo; This &amp;ldquo;discovery&amp;rdquo; has been criticized as one-sided and has parallels in contemporary narratives of first contact beyond Earth, such as the Pioneer plaque. Colonialism often used first contact as a means to control knowledge and representation of &amp;ldquo;the other,&amp;rdquo; objectifying contact and its place on the frontier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notable-examples&#34;&gt;Notable Examples &lt;a href=&#34;#notable-examples&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerous instances of first contact have occurred throughout history, including Alexander the Great&amp;rsquo;s invasions from Persia to India in 330 BC and the establishment of Romano-Chinese relations in the 2nd century AD. However, well-established trade routes meant that many cultures were aware of each other before they met.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some specific examples include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;~1000:&lt;/strong&gt; Vikings, led by Leif Erikson, established a settlement at L&amp;rsquo;Anse Aux Meadows (present-day Canada) and encountered the Beothuk people (referred to as Skræling). The nature of this contact (peaceful or violent) is debated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12 October 1492:&lt;/strong&gt; Christopher Columbus&amp;rsquo;s first voyage led to contact between the Spanish Empire and the Taíno, Galibi, and Ciboney peoples in the West Indies. This contact was violent and resulted in numerous deaths, enslavement, and subjugation of the indigenous inhabitants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17 June 1579:&lt;/strong&gt; Francis Drake&amp;rsquo;s circumnavigation brought the English into contact with the Coast Miwok in Northern California. Relations remained peaceful during Drake&amp;rsquo;s month-long stay, during which he claimed the land for England as Nova Albion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21 July 1595:&lt;/strong&gt; Álvaro de Mendaña de Neira led a Spanish expedition to the Marquesas Islands (French Polynesia), resulting in initial friendly contact with the Polynesians that quickly turned violent, leading to 200 local deaths in the first two weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19 December 1642:&lt;/strong&gt; Abel Tasman&amp;rsquo;s first voyage led to contact between the Dutch and the Ngāti Tūmatakōkiri in New Zealand. The encounter resulted in the death of four Dutch and the wounding of one Māori, with no further communication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19 January 1788:&lt;/strong&gt; James Cook&amp;rsquo;s third voyage brought the British into contact with the Native Hawaiians on Kauai, Hawaii. General friendly trade occurred, but one Indigenous Hawaiian was killed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21 January 1788:&lt;/strong&gt; The First Fleet&amp;rsquo;s arrival in Sydney, Australia, led to contact between the British Empire and the Cadigal and Bidjigal peoples. The initial contact was friendly but reserved, with one aborigine likely beaten.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;29 November 1791:&lt;/strong&gt; William R. Broughton led a British expedition to Chatham Island, New Zealand, resulting in contact with the Moriori people. Initial shows of aggression by the Moriori were followed by peaceful relations, but a fight led to the death of one Moriori.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1930:&lt;/strong&gt; Mick Leahy led an Australian expedition to the New Guinea Highlands, resulting in contact with the Papuan people. The contact was friendly, with some Highland people believing the Australians were their ancestors and attempting to rub off their white skins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_contact_(anthropology)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_contact_(anthropology)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
