<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interdimensional on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/interdimensional/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interdimensional on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:25:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/interdimensional/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interdimensional UFO hypothesis</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cdc9008149f9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cdc9008149f9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;interdimensional-ufo-hypothesis&#34;&gt;Interdimensional UFO Hypothesis &lt;a href=&#34;#interdimensional-ufo-hypothesis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interdimensional UFO hypothesis (IUH) proposes that unidentified flying object (UFO) sightings result from encounters with other &amp;ldquo;dimensions&amp;rdquo; that coexist alongside our own. This idea is supported by ufologists who suggest that UFOs are a modern manifestation of phenomena throughout human history, previously attributed to mythological or supernatural beings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the historical context of the interdimensional UFO hypothesis, tracing its roots from pre-modern concepts to modern ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pre-modern-history&#34;&gt;Pre-modern history &lt;a href=&#34;#pre-modern-history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concepts similar to &amp;ldquo;other dimensions&amp;rdquo; exist in various religious and mystical traditions. Islamic mysticism, known as Sufism, includes the concept of &lt;em&gt;al-ghayb&lt;/em&gt;, referring to the hidden and unseen. Within this tradition, &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;ālam al-mithāl&lt;/em&gt;, or &amp;ldquo;the world of similitude,&amp;rdquo; is considered an intermediary realm between the physical and spiritual worlds, inhabited by intelligent non-human entities such as jinn and angels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;theorists&#34;&gt;Theorists &lt;a href=&#34;#theorists&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces key figures who have advanced the interdimensional UFO hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 19th century, spiritualists believed in &amp;ldquo;other dimensions.&amp;rdquo; H.P. Blavatsky popularized the term &amp;ldquo;planes,&amp;rdquo; proposing a cosmology of seven planes. The term &amp;ldquo;ether&amp;rdquo; was adopted from ancient Greek and incorporated into occult writings. Charles Webster Leadbeater and Annie Besant introduced the &amp;ldquo;etheric plane&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;etheric body&amp;rdquo; in Theosophy. The first use of the word, as &lt;em&gt;inter-dimensional&lt;/em&gt;, is in a novel by Z Gale of 1906.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;meade-layne-and-ether-ships&#34;&gt;Meade Layne and &amp;lsquo;Ether Ships&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#meade-layne-and-ether-ships&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meade Layne, an occultist, claimed in 1947 that flying discs were &amp;ldquo;etheric.&amp;rdquo; Layne claimed telepathic communication with &amp;ldquo;people in the saucers,&amp;rdquo; arguing that objects could pass from an etheric to a dense level of matter. He stated that these visitors were human beings living in their own world with good intentions. Layne is regarded as the earliest proponent of the interdimensional hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;john-keel-and-ultraterrestrials&#34;&gt;John Keel and &amp;lsquo;Ultraterrestrials&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#john-keel-and-ultraterrestrials&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Keel coined the term &amp;ldquo;ultraterrestrials&amp;rdquo; to describe UFO occupants as non-human entities existing in a wavelength of energy undetectable to us. In his book &lt;em&gt;UFOs: Operation Trojan Horse&lt;/em&gt;, Keel argued that a non-human intelligence has staged events to propagate erroneous belief systems, including monsters, ghosts, demons, fairies, vampires, mystery airships, anomalous creatures, poltergeists, and UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hynek-and-vallée&#34;&gt;Hynek and Vallée &lt;a href=&#34;#hynek-and-vall%c3%a9e&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. Allen Hynek, an astronomer and scientific advisor to the U.S. Air Force UFO studies, pioneered the &amp;ldquo;Close Encounter&amp;rdquo; classification system. Jacques Vallée, a student of Hynek, served as the inspiration for a character in the film &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt;. In &lt;em&gt;The Edge of Reality&lt;/em&gt;, Vallée and Hynek considered the possibility of &amp;ldquo;interlocking universes.&amp;rdquo; Vallée argued for a &amp;ldquo;parallel universe co-existing with our own&amp;rdquo; in his book &lt;em&gt;Passport to Magonia&lt;/em&gt;. Vallée&amp;rsquo;s 1990 paper &amp;ldquo;Five Arguments Against the Extraterrestrial Origin of Unidentified Flying Objects&amp;rdquo; summarized his objections to the extraterrestrial hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the presence of the interdimensional UFO hypothesis in popular culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2008 film &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull&lt;/em&gt; utilizes the interdimensional hypothesis, describing ancient aliens traveling into &amp;ldquo;the space between the spaces.&amp;rdquo; The 2014 movie &lt;em&gt;Interstellar&lt;/em&gt; employs a mix of the interdimensional and time-traveler hypotheses, with future humans evolving to exist in five dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-contrasting-hypothesis&#34;&gt;Other contrasting hypothesis &lt;a href=&#34;#other-contrasting-hypothesis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contrasts the IUH with other hypotheses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IUH contrasts with the extraterrestrial hypothesis, which suggests UFO sightings are caused by visitations from outside Earth, and the psychosocial hypothesis, which argues UFO sightings are best explained as psychological or social phenomena. Other contrasting hypotheses include the cryptoterrestrial hypothesis, space animal hypothesis, and time-traveler hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists related topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fallen angel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiverse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spiritualism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;String theory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interdimensional_hypothesis&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interdimensional_hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
