<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roswell Incident on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/roswell-incident/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Roswell Incident on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:23:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/roswell-incident/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Roswell, New Mexico</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cc35dd7d6510/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cc35dd7d6510/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;roswell-new-mexico&#34;&gt;Roswell, New Mexico &lt;a href=&#34;#roswell-new-mexico&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roswell is a city located in Chaves County, New Mexico, serving as its county seat. It&amp;rsquo;s known for the alleged Roswell incident and is home to the New Mexico Military Institute (NMMI) and an Eastern New Mexico University campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The area was first settled by pioneers from Missouri in 1865, though they abandoned the site due to lack of water. Van C. Smith and Aaron Wilburn established a general store and post office in 1869, which marked the beginning of the modern city. Smith named the town after his father, Roswell Smith. Captain Joseph Calloway Lea and his family acquired the land in 1877. The discovery of a major aquifer in 1890 and the arrival of the Pecos Valley Railroad in 1892 spurred growth. During World War II, a prisoner-of-war camp was located nearby, with German POWs contributing to infrastructure projects. Walker Air Force Base was important from 1941 to 1967, after which Roswell transitioned into a retirement community. The city has capitalized on the Roswell UFO incident, attracting tourists interested in UFOs and aliens. In 2024, Roswell was chosen to host the Reno Air Races starting in 2025. Felix Baumgartner&amp;rsquo;s record-breaking skydive occurred in Roswell in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography &lt;a href=&#34;#geography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roswell is situated in the High Great Plains of southeastern New Mexico, west of the Pecos River. U.S. Routes 70, 285, and 380 intersect in the city, providing connections to other cities like Clovis, Alamogordo, Santa Fe, Carlsbad, Brownfield, and Socorro. The city&amp;rsquo;s total area is approximately 29.776 square miles, with a small percentage covered by water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;climate&#34;&gt;Climate &lt;a href=&#34;#climate&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roswell has a cold semi-arid climate with four distinct seasons. Winters are cool and sunny, with occasional snowfall. Summers are hot, with temperatures exceeding 100 °F on average 30 days per year. The North American monsoon brings torrential downpours and thunderstorms during the summer. Fall is warm and pleasant. The record low is −24 °F, and the record high is 114 °F.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;demographics&#34;&gt;Demographics &lt;a href=&#34;#demographics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The population was 48,422 at the 2020 census. The racial and ethnic composition is diverse, with a significant Hispanic or Latino population. The median household income was $48,298, and the per capita income was $25,906 (2018–2022 in 2022 dollars).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education &lt;a href=&#34;#education&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public schools are managed by the Roswell Independent School District, which includes Goddard High School and Roswell High School. Private schools include All Saints Catholic School and Gateway Christian School. Higher education institutions include Eastern New Mexico University-Roswell and New Mexico Military Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sports&#34;&gt;Sports &lt;a href=&#34;#sports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Roswell Invaders play in the Pecos League of professional baseball. Joe Bauman set a minor-league record of 72 home runs for the Roswell Rockets in 1954. Willie Stargell played for the Roswell Pirates in 1959.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transportation&#34;&gt;Transportation &lt;a href=&#34;#transportation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roswell Air Center is served by American Airlines via American Eagle. Pecos Trails Transit provides bus routes. Greyhound Lines offers intercity services. Major highways include U.S. Route 70, U.S. Route 285, and U.S. Route 380. BNSF Railway provides freight services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;local-industry&#34;&gt;Local Industry &lt;a href=&#34;#local-industry&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leprino Foods, one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest mozzarella factories, is located in Roswell. The city was also home to the Transportation Manufacturing Corporation factory, known for producing RTS city buses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultural-attractions&#34;&gt;Cultural Attractions &lt;a href=&#34;#cultural-attractions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roswell&amp;rsquo;s tourism industry revolves around aerospace engineering and ufology museums and businesses, with alien-themed iconography. The International UFO Museum and Research Center is a major attraction. An annual UFO festival has been held since 1995. The Roswell Museum maintains an exhibit on Robert H. Goddard&amp;rsquo;s rocket engine development. The Anderson Museum of Contemporary Art features works by artists from the Roswell Artist-in-Residence program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notable-residents&#34;&gt;Notable Residents &lt;a href=&#34;#notable-residents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notable residents include businessman and philanthropist Robert O. Anderson, federal appellate judge Bobby Baldock, football player and sportscaster Tom Brookshier, pioneer John Chisum, politician Louise Holland Coe, singer John Denver, TV journalist Sam Donaldson, sheriff Pat Garrett, rocket pioneer Robert H. Goddard, opera singer Susan Graham, businessman J.J. Hagerman, politician James F. Hinkle, golfer Nancy Lopez, actor Jody McCrea, actress Demi Moore, Army colonel Sergio de la Peña, golfer Gerina Piller, actress Priscilla Presley, Marine Corps Sergeant Major Clinton A. Puckett, Lieutenant General James P. Riseley, jockey Mike E. Smith, actor Austin St. John, and quarterback Roger Staubach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell,_New_Mexico&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell,_New_Mexico&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roswell, Little Green Man</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_eed24a22f0c2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 14:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_eed24a22f0c2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;roswell-little-green-man&#34;&gt;Roswell, Little Green Man &lt;a href=&#34;#roswell-little-green-man&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article provides information about the &lt;em&gt;Roswell, Little Green Man&lt;/em&gt; comic book series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roswell, Little Green Man&lt;/em&gt; is a comic book series created by Bill Morrison and published by Bongo Comics. The series received four Eisner Award nominations. It began as a four-part story within &lt;em&gt;Simpsons Comics&lt;/em&gt; #19-22 in 1996, and later continued as its own six-issue title. The initial &lt;em&gt;Simpsons Comics&lt;/em&gt; story and the first three issues of the &lt;em&gt;Roswell, Little Green Man&lt;/em&gt; series, which detail the origin story of Roswell, were collected in the trade paperback &lt;em&gt;Roswell Walks Among Us&lt;/em&gt; in 1997.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inspiration&#34;&gt;Inspiration &lt;a href=&#34;#inspiration&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill Morrison stated that the series was inspired by the Roswell UFO incident and his interest in drawing 1940s vintage cars, fashions, and architecture. He also cited Dave Stevens&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;Rocketeer&lt;/em&gt; as a major influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources used to create the article. These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An article from &lt;em&gt;The News-Herald&lt;/em&gt; about Bill Morrison being featured at a Lincoln Park museum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A listing of 1998 Will Eisner Comic Industry Award nominees from the Comic Book Awards Almanac.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An article titled &amp;ldquo;Twenty Years of Terror&amp;rdquo; from &lt;em&gt;Comic Book Creator&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An interview with Bill Morrison on &lt;em&gt;Neatorama&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external websites related to the comic book series:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roswell: Little Green Man at Beek&amp;rsquo;s Books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roswell: Little Green Man at The Simpsons Archive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell,_Little_Green_Man&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell,_Little_Green_Man&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
