<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Time Travel on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/time-travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Time Travel on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 15:20:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/time-travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alienoid (2022 film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8384e2f45a9f/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8384e2f45a9f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alienoid-2022-film&#34;&gt;Alienoid (2022 film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alienoid-2022-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2022 South Korean science fiction action film directed by Choi Dong-hoon, starring Ryu Jun-yeol, Kim Woo-bin, and Kim Tae-ri. The film involves time travel between the Goryeo era and the present day, with the appearance of aliens. It was released in IMAX and 4DX formats. A sequel, &lt;em&gt;Alienoid: Return to the Future&lt;/em&gt;, was released in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot alternates between the modern day and the Goryeo era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prologue-1380-ad&#34;&gt;Prologue: 1380 A.D. &lt;a href=&#34;#prologue-1380-ad&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monk warriors fail to defeat an alien and its human host. Guard and Thunder, humanoid robots from the future, extract the alien. The dying host asks Guard to care for her baby, but Guard initially refuses due to non-interference policies. Thunder smuggles the infant back with them to the modern day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;timeline-1-2012-2022-ad&#34;&gt;Timeline 1: 2012-2022 A.D. &lt;a href=&#34;#timeline-1-2012-2022-ad&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guard raises the baby girl, Yi-an, without revealing his true identity. Yi-an becomes suspicious and discovers the truth about Guard, Thunder, and her origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yi-an finds her way to Jisan Hospital, the site of an incoming alien prisoner transport. Guard and Thunder explain alien imprisonment mechanics. A prisoner-aligned alien ship arrives, planning to awaken the Controller and release haava to transform Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere, awakening all alien prisoners and poisoning humanity. The pilot awakens the Controller and releases haava, devastating the city and awakening other prisoners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guard, Thunder, and Yi-an kill the alien pilot and prevent further haava release. Badly wounded, Yi-an travels back in time with the aliens, intending to strand them in the past. Guard is destroyed, Thunder sinks in a river, and the Controller is forced to abandon its host.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;timeline-2-1391-ad&#34;&gt;Timeline 2: 1391 A.D. &lt;a href=&#34;#timeline-2-1391-ad&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten years after Thunder crash-lands, a Taoist bounty hunter named Mureuk pursues the Divine Blade (Guard&amp;rsquo;s power source). Mureuk meets martial arts figures like the Monk Guru, the Dual Mages, and Dogturd. He also meets Yi-an (the &amp;ldquo;Girl Who Shoots Thunder&amp;rdquo;) and Suiter and Ja-jang, aliens from the future who have taken over a local cult. The Divine Blade and Thunder&amp;rsquo;s location are key to controlling the haava release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A chaotic battle ensues. Yi-an lures one alien away, while the other is defeated. Yi-an approaches Thunder&amp;rsquo;s location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monk Guru, the Dual Mages, and Dogturd were all near the initial alien crash and are potential hosts for the Controller. However, Mureuk, Monk Guru&amp;rsquo;s apprentice, rescued Yi-an and became the Controller&amp;rsquo;s new host, losing his memories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ryu Jun-yeol&lt;/strong&gt; as Mureuk, a Taoist bounty hunter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kim Woo-bin&lt;/strong&gt; as Guard and Thunder, supernatural beings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kim Tae-ri&lt;/strong&gt; as Yi-an, a woman who shoots thunder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So Ji-sub&lt;/strong&gt; as Moon Do-seok, a detective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yum Jung-ah&lt;/strong&gt; as Heug-seol, a mage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jo Woo-jin&lt;/strong&gt; as Cheong-woon, a mage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kim Eui-sung&lt;/strong&gt; as Ja-jang, a masked man.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lee Hanee&lt;/strong&gt; as Min Gae-in, a curious woman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shin Jung-geun&lt;/strong&gt; as Right King, a follower of Mureuk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lee Si-hoon&lt;/strong&gt; as Left King, a follower of Mureuk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ji Kun-woo&lt;/strong&gt; as Suiter, a man in a modern suit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kim Dae-myung&lt;/strong&gt; as the voice of Thunder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shim Dal-gi&lt;/strong&gt; as a bride replaced by Yi-an.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yoon Byung-hee&lt;/strong&gt; as a shaman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kim Ki-cheon&lt;/strong&gt; as Dogturd, a man who knows the location of the divine sword.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yoon Kyung-ho&lt;/strong&gt; as a patient at Jisan Hospital.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ok Ja-yeon&lt;/strong&gt; as a doctor at Jisan Hospital.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lee Seon-hee&lt;/strong&gt; as an inn owner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yoo Jae-myung&lt;/strong&gt; as Hyun-gam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kim Hae-sook&lt;/strong&gt; as an old woman in Goryeo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jeon Yeo-been&lt;/strong&gt; as Hong Eon-nyeon, a woman with an alien prisoner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Filming took place over 13 months, with both parts filmed simultaneously. Choi Dong-hoon spent two and a half years writing the script. Jang Young-gyu and Kim Tae-kyung were in charge of music and cinematography, respectively. Yoo Sang-seop and Ryu Seong-cheol served as martial arts directors. Ryu Seong-hee and Lee Ha-jun were the art directors. Dexter Studio handled the CG. Filming locations included Andong, North Gyeongsang Province. The production cost for both parts was estimated at 40 billion won.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alienoid&lt;/em&gt; was released on July 20, 2022, in South Korea in IMAX and 4DX formats by CJ E&amp;amp;M. Well Go USA acquired North American distribution rights. It was the closing film at the 21st New York Asian Film Festival and screened at the 26th Fantasia International Film Festival. It became available for streaming on Netflix from December 28, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received mixed reviews from South Korean critics, with some praising its unique worldview and others criticizing its confusing characters and lore. It was compared to Choi Dong-hoon&amp;rsquo;s previous film, &lt;em&gt;Jeon Woo-chi: The Taoist Wizard&lt;/em&gt;. The film was a box-office failure, requiring 7 million admissions to break even.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;sequel&#34;&gt;Sequel &lt;a href=&#34;#sequel&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alienoid: Return to the Future&lt;/em&gt; was released in January 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;accolades&#34;&gt;Accolades &lt;a href=&#34;#accolades&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received nominations for several awards, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baeksang Arts Awards: Yum Jung-ah nominated for Best Supporting Actress – Film&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue Dragon Film Awards: Nominated for Technical Award&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buil Film Awards: Yum Jung-ah nominated for Best Supporting Actress, also nominated for Best Music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chunsa Film Art Awards: Nominated for Technical Award (VFX)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Director&amp;rsquo;s Cut Awards: Choi Dong-hoon nominated for Best Director in film&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grand Bell Awards: Won Best Art Direction and Best Visual Effects, also nominated for Best Film Editing, Best Costume Design, and Best Music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alienoid&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alienoid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time-traveler UFO hypothesis</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_4666fb28cb0a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 17:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_4666fb28cb0a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;time-traveler-ufo-hypothesis&#34;&gt;Time-traveler UFO hypothesis &lt;a href=&#34;#time-traveler-ufo-hypothesis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time-traveler hypothesis, also known as chrononaut UFO, future humans, extratempestrial model, and Terminator theory, proposes that unidentified flying objects (UFOs) are humans traveling from the future using advanced technology. This concept has gained recent attention from figures like retired NASA aerospace engineer Larry Lemke, Wisconsin congressman Mike Gallagher, and filmmaker Steven Spielberg. Mainstream scholars consider this hypothesis extremely implausible, and it&amp;rsquo;s generally viewed as unorthodox even among fringe conspiracy theorists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;antecedents&#34;&gt;Antecedents &lt;a href=&#34;#antecedents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the origins of the ideas that led to the time-traveler UFO hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;origins-of-time-travel-speculation&#34;&gt;Origins of time travel speculation &lt;a href=&#34;#origins-of-time-travel-speculation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection traces the concept of time travel from the future to the past back to its literary origins. Pierre Boitard&amp;rsquo;s 1861 book &lt;em&gt;Paris avant les hommes&lt;/em&gt; is credited with introducing the idea, featuring a man sent back to prehistoric Earth. Camille Flammarion&amp;rsquo;s 1887 novel &lt;em&gt;Lumen&lt;/em&gt; also explored the theme of a soul traveling through different historical periods. The section also notes that while time travel is considered physically impossible by most, theoretical research continues to explore its potential feasibility, with scientists like J. Richard Gott and Ronald Mallet speculating on the possibility of future human time travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;speculation-of-future-human-evolution&#34;&gt;Speculation of future human evolution &lt;a href=&#34;#speculation-of-future-human-evolution&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the history of speculation about the future evolution of mankind. It highlights H.G. Wells&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;The Time Machine&lt;/em&gt; as an early example of both time travel and speculative evolution. Other authors mentioned include Edgar Rice Burroughs, Olaf Stapledon, Kurt Vonnegut, Stephen Baxter, and Cevdet Mehmet Kösemen. The section also identifies climate change, the technological singularity, space travel, and genetic enhancement as potential factors that could alter human evolution, leading to transhuman and posthuman scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ufos-and-initial-explanations&#34;&gt;UFOs and initial explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#ufos-and-initial-explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection provides a brief overview of the history of UFO sightings. It mentions reports of unknown objects in the skies dating back to antiquity, as well as the mystery airship sightings of the 1890s and the Foo fighters and ghost rockets during World War II. The modern UFO era is said to have begun in the summer of 1947, following Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting. Initial explanations for these sightings ranged from novel US or Soviet technology to misidentification of mundane objects and mass hysteria. Fringe theories included extraterrestrial or interdimensional origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;formation-and-spread&#34;&gt;Formation and spread &lt;a href=&#34;#formation-and-spread&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the development and popularization of the time-traveler UFO hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;implausibility-of-humanoid-aliens&#34;&gt;Implausibility of humanoid aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#implausibility-of-humanoid-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection addresses the common depiction of aliens as humanoids in contactee and alien abduction folklore. It cites George Gaylord Simpson&amp;rsquo;s 1964 article &lt;em&gt;The Nonprevalence of Humanoids&lt;/em&gt;, which argues that it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely for extraterrestrial intelligence to exist and even more unlikely for it to be humanoid. The section also mentions Stephen Jay Gould&amp;rsquo;s thought experiment about rewinding evolution, suggesting that humans would likely not evolve again. Biologist Jack Cohen&amp;rsquo;s view on the implausibility of Grey aliens evolving a physiology similar to humans is also included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;modern-popularization&#34;&gt;Modern popularization &lt;a href=&#34;#modern-popularization&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explores the modern resurgence of the time-traveler hypothesis. It mentions Jacques Vallée&amp;rsquo;s 1975 book &lt;em&gt;The Invisible College&lt;/em&gt; as an early example. Other figures and works mentioned include David S. Anderson, Jenny Randles, James Herbert Brennan, and Philip J. Corso and William J. Birnes&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;The Day After Roswell&lt;/em&gt;, which reported Hermann Oberth&amp;rsquo;s belief that the Roswell craft could have been a time machine. The History channel series &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; is also mentioned for its episodes exploring the concept. Michael P. Masters&amp;rsquo; book &lt;em&gt;Identified Flying Objects&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Extratempestrial Model&lt;/em&gt; are highlighted for their in-depth exploration of the hypothesis. Tim Peake and Steven Spielberg are mentioned for their recent public comments on the theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection lists examples of the time-traveler hypothesis in popular culture. It includes the TV series &lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s About Time&lt;/em&gt;, Gregory Benford&amp;rsquo;s novel &lt;em&gt;Timescape&lt;/em&gt;, David Drake&amp;rsquo;s novel &lt;em&gt;Birds of Prey&lt;/em&gt;, Michael Crichton&amp;rsquo;s novel &lt;em&gt;Sphere&lt;/em&gt;, the TV film &lt;em&gt;Official Denial&lt;/em&gt;, the comic book series &lt;em&gt;Blake and Mortimer&lt;/em&gt;, the band Yes, Jordan Peele&amp;rsquo;s movie &lt;em&gt;Nope&lt;/em&gt;, and the movie &lt;em&gt;Interstellar&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;terminology-and-connection-to-other-theories&#34;&gt;Terminology and connection to other theories &lt;a href=&#34;#terminology-and-connection-to-other-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection clarifies the terminology used to describe the hypothesis, noting that while Michael P. Masters uses the term &amp;ldquo;extratempestrial,&amp;rdquo; the overall idea is often referred to as &amp;ldquo;the time-traveler hypothesis.&amp;rdquo; It also discusses the overlap between the time-traveler hypothesis and the interdimensional hypothesis, with figures like John Ventre and Harold E. Puthoff using the terms interchangeably. The section also notes that the time-traveler hypothesis provides an alternative explanation for the absence of future time travelers, similar to how the extraterrestrial hypothesis addresses Fermi&amp;rsquo;s paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;criticism&#34;&gt;Criticism &lt;a href=&#34;#criticism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents criticisms of the time-traveler hypothesis. It notes that the hypothesis is considered pseudoscientific. Neil deGrasse Tyson is quoted as calling the hypothesis illogical, and Robert Sheaffer criticizes Michael P. Masters&amp;rsquo; work for relying on the belief that time travel is possible. David J. Darling argues that the extraterrestrial and time-travel hypotheses are equally unlikely and unnecessary. Ian Ridpath suggests that Jim Penniston&amp;rsquo;s claims about time-traveling UFOs may have been influenced by the film &lt;em&gt;Official Denial&lt;/em&gt;. Isaac Arthur is mentioned for debunking the concept as presented in &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;. Fabio Costa is quoted as saying that time travel requires two doors, one in the future and one in the past, raising the question of where the time machine is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics, including Time travel, Posthumanism, Transhumanism, Timeline of the far future, Longtermism, Speculative Evolution, Cryptoterrestrial hypothesis, Psychosocial hypothesis, Interdimensional hypothesis, and Space animal hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time-traveller_UFO_hypothesis&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time-traveller_UFO_hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time-traveler UFO hypothesis</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_d22d1894e3f5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 17:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_d22d1894e3f5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;time-traveler-ufo-hypothesis&#34;&gt;Time-traveler UFO hypothesis &lt;a href=&#34;#time-traveler-ufo-hypothesis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time-traveler hypothesis, also known as chrononaut UFO, future humans, extratempestrial model, and Terminator theory, proposes that unidentified flying objects (UFOs) are humans traveling from the future using advanced technology. This concept has gained recent attention from figures like retired NASA aerospace engineer Larry Lemke, Wisconsin congressman Mike Gallagher, and filmmaker Steven Spielberg. Mainstream scholars consider this hypothesis extremely implausible, and it&amp;rsquo;s generally viewed as unorthodox even among fringe conspiracy theorists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;antecedents&#34;&gt;Antecedents &lt;a href=&#34;#antecedents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the origins of the ideas that led to the time-traveler UFO hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;origins-of-time-travel-speculation&#34;&gt;Origins of time travel speculation &lt;a href=&#34;#origins-of-time-travel-speculation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection traces the literary roots of time travel, starting with Pierre Boitard&amp;rsquo;s 1861 book &lt;em&gt;Paris avant les hommes&lt;/em&gt;, which features a man traveling to prehistoric Earth. It also mentions Camille Flammarion&amp;rsquo;s 1887 novel &lt;em&gt;Lumen&lt;/em&gt;, which involves an alien soul traveling through time. The section acknowledges the theoretical research into the possibility of time travel, citing scientists like J. Richard Gott and Ronald Mallet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;speculation-of-future-human-evolution&#34;&gt;Speculation of future human evolution &lt;a href=&#34;#speculation-of-future-human-evolution&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the concept of future human evolution, referencing H.G. Wells&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;The Time Machine&lt;/em&gt; as an early example. It mentions other authors who have explored speculative evolution, including Edgar Rice Burroughs, Olaf Stapledon, Kurt Vonnegut, Stephen Baxter, and Cevdet Mehmet Kösemen. The section also identifies factors like climate change, the technological singularity, space travel, and genetic enhancement as potential drivers of future human evolution, leading to transhuman and posthuman scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ufos-and-initial-explanations&#34;&gt;UFOs and initial explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#ufos-and-initial-explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers the history of reported unknown objects in the skies, from ancient times to the modern era. It mentions mystery airships in the 1890s, Foo fighters, and ghost rockets during World War II. The section details the beginning of the modern UFO era in 1947, following Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting and the subsequent nationwide craze. It outlines the initial explanations for these sightings, including novel US or Soviet technology, misidentification of mundane objects, mass hysteria, and fringe theories involving extraterrestrials or interdimensional beings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;formation-and-spread&#34;&gt;Formation and spread &lt;a href=&#34;#formation-and-spread&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the development and popularization of the time-traveler UFO hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;implausibility-of-humanoid-aliens&#34;&gt;Implausibility of humanoid aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#implausibility-of-humanoid-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection addresses the unlikelihood of humanoid aliens, referencing George Gaylord Simpson&amp;rsquo;s 1964 article &lt;em&gt;The Nonprevalence of Humanoids&lt;/em&gt;. It cites the 2014 NASA collection of essays &lt;em&gt;Archaeology, Anthropology and Interstellar Communication&lt;/em&gt;, which discusses Simpson&amp;rsquo;s and Theodosius Dobzhansky&amp;rsquo;s views on the implausibility of humanoid extraterrestrial life. The section also mentions Stephen Jay Gould&amp;rsquo;s thought experiment about rewinding evolution and Jack Cohen&amp;rsquo;s position on the Grey alien representation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;modern-popularization&#34;&gt;Modern popularization &lt;a href=&#34;#modern-popularization&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explores the modern popularization of the time-traveler hypothesis. It mentions Jacques Vallée&amp;rsquo;s 1975 book &lt;em&gt;The Invisible College&lt;/em&gt; and contributions from David S. Anderson, Jenny Randles, and James Herbert Brennan. It also references Philip J. Corso and William J. Birnes&amp;rsquo; 1998 book &lt;em&gt;The Day After Roswell&lt;/em&gt;, which reported Hermann Oberth&amp;rsquo;s belief that the Roswell craft could have been a time machine. The section highlights the &amp;ldquo;Time Travelers&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Time Benders&amp;rdquo; episodes of &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;, featuring figures like Giorgio A. Tsoukalos, Erich von Däniken, and Ronald L. Mallett. It also mentions Nick Pope&amp;rsquo;s connection of the Rendlesham Forest incident and the Cabo Valdés Case to the time-traveler hypothesis. The section references a 2013 Huffington Post article discussing the theory and an online conspiracy theory about George W. Hoover&amp;rsquo;s alleged revelation about the Roswell incident involving future humans. It also discusses Michael P. Masters&amp;rsquo; 2019 book &lt;em&gt;Identified Flying Objects&lt;/em&gt; and his extratempestrial model, along with his appearances on podcasts like &lt;em&gt;Through the Glass Darkly&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Cryptid Factor&lt;/em&gt;. Mentions WatchMojo and TNW articles on the topic, Tim Peake&amp;rsquo;s interview on &lt;em&gt;Good Morning Britain&lt;/em&gt;, and Steven Spielberg&amp;rsquo;s interview with Stephen Colbert. The section concludes by mentioning motives for time travelers, such as historical interest and tourism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection lists examples of the time-traveler hypothesis in popular culture, including the TV series &lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s About Time&lt;/em&gt;, Gregory Benford’s novel &lt;em&gt;Timescape&lt;/em&gt;, David Drake&amp;rsquo;s novel &lt;em&gt;Birds of Prey&lt;/em&gt;, Michael Crichton&amp;rsquo;s novel &lt;em&gt;Sphere&lt;/em&gt;, the TV film &lt;em&gt;Official Denial&lt;/em&gt;, the comic book &lt;em&gt;The Strange Encounter&lt;/em&gt; from the Blake and Mortimer series, the Yes song &lt;em&gt;Aliens (Are Only Us from the Future)&lt;/em&gt;, Jordan Peele&amp;rsquo;s movie &lt;em&gt;Nope&lt;/em&gt;, and the movie &lt;em&gt;Interstellar&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;terminology-and-connection-to-other-theories&#34;&gt;Terminology and connection to other theories &lt;a href=&#34;#terminology-and-connection-to-other-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the terminology used to describe the hypothesis, noting that while Michael P. Masters uses &amp;ldquo;extratempestrial,&amp;rdquo; the overall idea is often called &amp;ldquo;the time-traveler hypothesis.&amp;rdquo; It explores the overlap between the time-traveler hypothesis and the interdimensional hypothesis, mentioning John Ventre and Harold E. Puthoff. It also notes Masters&amp;rsquo; view of his model as a subcategory of the interdimensional hypothesis. The section discusses how the time-traveler hypothesis provides an alternative explanation for the absence of future time travelers, referencing Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s statement about the possibility of time travelers already being here but unrecognized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;criticism&#34;&gt;Criticism &lt;a href=&#34;#criticism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents criticisms of the time-traveler hypothesis. It notes that the hypothesis is considered pseudoscientific and mentions Neil deGrasse Tyson&amp;rsquo;s view of it as illogical. It cites Robert Sheaffer&amp;rsquo;s criticism of Masters&amp;rsquo; work for relying on the belief that time travel is possible. The section also includes David J. Darling&amp;rsquo;s statement that the extraterrestrial and time-travel hypotheses are equally unlikely and unnecessary. It mentions Ian Ridpath&amp;rsquo;s suggestion that Jim Penniston&amp;rsquo;s time-traveling UFO allegations may have been influenced by the film &lt;em&gt;Official Denial&lt;/em&gt;. It also references Isaac Arthur&amp;rsquo;s debunking of the concept on the &lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Probably (not) Aliens&lt;/em&gt; podcast. Finally, it includes Fabio Costa&amp;rsquo;s explanation of the requirements for time travel and the question of the location of the time machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time-traveler_UFO_hypothesis&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time-traveler_UFO_hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
