<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project Mogul on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/project-mogul/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Project Mogul on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 19:29:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/project-mogul/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Roswell Incident (1980 book)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_35f31e4c5c9f/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 19:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_35f31e4c5c9f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-roswell-incident-1980-book&#34;&gt;The Roswell Incident (1980 book) &lt;a href=&#34;#the-roswell-incident-1980-book&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This entry focuses on the 1980 book &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt; by Charles Berlitz and William Moore, which significantly contributed to popularizing the Roswell incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for the Roswell incident, starting with the events of 1947.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;events-of-1947&#34;&gt;Events of 1947 &lt;a href=&#34;#events-of-1947&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This subsection details the initial reports surrounding the Roswell incident. It mentions the flying disc craze of 1947, Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting, and the Roswell Army Air Field&amp;rsquo;s initial press release about recovering a crashed object, which was quickly retracted and explained as a weather balloon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;roswell-revisited&#34;&gt;Roswell revisited &lt;a href=&#34;#roswell-revisited&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This subsection explains how the Roswell story gained renewed attention in 1978 when retired lieutenant colonel Jesse Marcel claimed in an interview with ufologist Stanton Friedman that the debris he retrieved was of extraterrestrial origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;authors&#34;&gt;Authors &lt;a href=&#34;#authors&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides background information on the authors of the book, Charles Berlitz and William Moore. Berlitz is noted for authoring &lt;em&gt;The Bermuda Triangle&lt;/em&gt;, a best-selling book that popularized the mysteries surrounding the Bermuda Triangle. In 1979, Berlitz partnered with UFO researcher William L. Moore to publish &lt;em&gt;The Philadelphia Experiment: Project Invisibility&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents &lt;a href=&#34;#contents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the book&amp;rsquo;s central argument: that an extraterrestrial craft crashed in the New Mexico desert while observing nuclear weapons activity, and the US government engaged in a cover-up. It highlights accounts of debris described as &amp;ldquo;nothing made on this earth&amp;rdquo; and mentions witnesses like Bill Brazel, Floyd Proctor, and Walt Whitman Jr. The book is described as &amp;ldquo;version 1&amp;rdquo; of the Roswell myth. It also introduced the idea that the debris shown in photos with Marcel was substituted as part of a cover-up and that the press was not allowed to closely inspect the recovered material. The authors claimed to have interviewed over 90 witnesses, but only a fraction of their testimonies appear in the book. The section also notes the elevation of Marcel&amp;rsquo;s narrative over that of Cavitt, whose description of the debris contradicted Marcel&amp;rsquo;s account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-bodies&#34;&gt;Alien bodies &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-bodies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the book&amp;rsquo;s introduction of the story about Barney Barnett and archaeology students encountering wreckage and &amp;ldquo;alien bodies&amp;rdquo; on the Plains of San Agustin, far from the initial Roswell crash site. It also mentions the conflation of the Roswell incident with the Aztec, New Mexico, UFO incident, a hoax promoted by journalist Frank Scully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section notes that critics have described &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt; as &amp;ldquo;a collection of wild hearsay&amp;rdquo; and that some have accused William Moore of involvement with fraudulent Majestic 12 documents. It also mentions that the book &amp;ldquo;did not make the commercial impact its authors hoped.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aftermath&#34;&gt;Aftermath &lt;a href=&#34;#aftermath&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section mentions that William Moore claimed to have engaged in &amp;ldquo;disinformation&amp;rdquo; activities against Paul Bennewitz on behalf of the Air Force Office of Special Investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modern-views&#34;&gt;Modern views &lt;a href=&#34;#modern-views&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section references a 1993 inquiry from US congressman Steven Schiff, which led to a General Accounting Office investigation and an Air Force report. The 1994 Air Force report concluded that the material recovered in 1947 was likely debris from Project Mogul, a military surveillance program using high-altitude balloons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Roswell_Incident_(1980_book)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Roswell_Incident_(1980_book)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
