<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 14:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flying saucer</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e1a122e1217a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e1a122e1217a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;purported-disk-shaped-aircraft&#34;&gt;Purported disk-shaped aircraft &lt;a href=&#34;#purported-disk-shaped-aircraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the history, description, and cultural impact of &amp;ldquo;flying saucers,&amp;rdquo; a term popularized in the late 1940s to describe disc-shaped unidentified flying objects (UFOs). It distinguishes flying saucers from the broader category of UFOs/UAPs and explores their evolution in popular culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section traces the origins and development of the flying saucer phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;precursors&#34;&gt;Precursors &lt;a href=&#34;#precursors&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explores earlier reports of unusual aerial phenomena that predate the term &amp;ldquo;flying saucer.&amp;rdquo; These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mysterious lights in the sky interpreted as spiritual phenomena in antiquity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;19th-century newspaper reports of massive airships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 1878 &lt;em&gt;Denison Daily News&lt;/em&gt; article describing an object resembling a saucer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Foo fighters&amp;rdquo; reported by Allied pilots during World War II.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Science fiction stories featuring disc-shaped aircraft, such as Jean de La Hire&amp;rsquo;s 1908 novel &lt;em&gt;La Roue fulgurante&lt;/em&gt; and &amp;ldquo;The Shaver Mystery&amp;rdquo; stories in &lt;em&gt;Amazing Stories&lt;/em&gt; magazine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fantasy artwork in pulp magazines depicting flying discs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;origins&#34;&gt;Origins &lt;a href=&#34;#origins&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection details the event that is credited with popularizing the term &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Kenneth Arnold UFO sighting on June 24, 1947, in Washington State.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arnold&amp;rsquo;s description of the objects&amp;rsquo; motion as &amp;ldquo;like a saucer skipping across the water.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The media&amp;rsquo;s coining of the terms &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;flying disc.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The subsequent wave of reported sightings across the United States, including the Flight 105 UFO sighting and the Roswell incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early speculation about the objects&amp;rsquo; origins, including secret military technology and Soviet aircraft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;development&#34;&gt;Development &lt;a href=&#34;#development&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers the evolution of the flying saucer concept and its association with extraterrestrial life:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The increasing association of flying saucers with extraterrestrial life in the 1950s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s speculation about an extraterrestrial origin for the objects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The emergence of unusual theories, such as Meade Layne&amp;rsquo;s speculation about alternate dimensions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The influence of pulp science fiction on beliefs about flying saucers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The rise of the &amp;ldquo;contactee&amp;rdquo; movement, with individuals like George Van Tassel and George Adamski claiming to have ridden aboard saucers and received messages from aliens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The development of ufology as a parallel social movement, with figures like Frank Scully, Donald Keyhoe, and Leonard H. Stringfield publishing books and forming UFO investigation groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The emergence of UFO photography as a subgenre of documentary photography.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The eventual decline in popularity of the term &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; and its replacement by &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;UAP.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description &lt;a href=&#34;#description&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the characteristics and identification of flying saucers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;identification&#34;&gt;Identification &lt;a href=&#34;#identification&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the identification of reported flying saucers with known phenomena:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experts have identified the majority of UFO reports as misidentifications or hoaxes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common explanations for saucer sightings include the planet Venus, weather phenomena, balloons, and airborne trash.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US Navy&amp;rsquo;s Skyhook spy balloon project, which led to numerous misidentified sightings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psychological studies of why people believe in flying saucers, including Georges Heuyer&amp;rsquo;s view of the phenomenon as a shared delusion and Michel Monnerie&amp;rsquo;s psychosocial UFO hypothesis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reported-sightings&#34;&gt;Reported sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#reported-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection summarizes the characteristics of reported flying saucer sightings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eyewitness descriptions differ in reported appearance, movement, and purpose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Astronomer Donald Howard Menzel&amp;rsquo;s overview of flying saucers, noting the variety of shapes, sizes, colors, and movements reported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The increasing standardization of alien descriptions over time, with Grey aliens becoming the most reported type of pilot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The influence of popular social and cultural expectations on the details of claimed observations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fictional-portrayals&#34;&gt;Fictional portrayals &lt;a href=&#34;#fictional-portrayals&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the portrayal of flying saucers in popular media:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early portrayals emphasized high-speed maneuvers, while later media shifted to slowly hovering discs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Examples of films and television series that feature flying saucers, such as &lt;em&gt;The Flying Saucer&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Day the Earth Stood Still&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Invaders&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;popular-culture&#34;&gt;Popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the cultural impact of flying saucers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;literature&#34;&gt;Literature &lt;a href=&#34;#literature&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the appearance of flying saucers in literature:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Precursors to modern flying saucers appeared in science fiction literature, including The Shaver Mystery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The emergence of a genre that treated fantastical stories as either true or plausibly true.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of advertisements to leverage cultural interest in flying saucers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The appearance of aliens and flying discs in 1950s science fiction comics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;film-and-television&#34;&gt;Film and television &lt;a href=&#34;#film-and-television&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the portrayal of flying saucers in film and television:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many early portrayals of flying saucers linked them to the Cold War.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Examples of films that feature flying saucers, such as &lt;em&gt;The Thing from Another World&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Day the Earth Stood Still&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Earth vs. the Flying Saucers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The adaptation of the flying saucer phenomenon by other countries, such as Japan and India.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of flying saucers in other genres, such as science fiction and comedy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;architecture&#34;&gt;Architecture &lt;a href=&#34;#architecture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the use of flying saucer motifs in architecture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The flying saucer as a symbol of 1950s culture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of flying saucer motifs in Googie architecture and Atomic Age décor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notable flying saucer structures, such as Seattle&amp;rsquo;s Space Needle and Los Angeles International Airport&amp;rsquo;s Theme Building.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The influence of Googie architecture on the futuristic structures in the cartoon &lt;em&gt;The Jetsons&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of the flying saucer as an architectural motif by Frank Lloyd Wright.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Examples of novelty architecture shaped like flying saucers, such as the Kielce Bus Station in Poland and the Spodek arena in Katowice, Poland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;broader-pop-culture&#34;&gt;Broader pop culture &lt;a href=&#34;#broader-pop-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the broader cultural impact of flying saucers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flying saucers were a ubiquitous part of pop culture from 1947 into the mid-1970s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of flying disc motifs in toys and other novelties, such as the frisbee and flying saucer candy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The release of novelty songs about flying discs and alien invaders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The appearance of flying saucers in video games, typically as antagonists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flying_saucers&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flying_saucers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
