<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Investigation on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/investigation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Investigation on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 11:08:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/investigation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>List of investigations of UFOs by governments</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_3b218ffd630c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 11:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_3b218ffd630c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-known-ufo-investigations-performed-by-governments-around-the-globe&#34;&gt;List of known UFO investigations performed by governments around the globe &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-known-ufo-investigations-performed-by-governments-around-the-globe&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document lists government-sponsored investigations and reports related to Unidentified Flying Objects (UFOs), also increasingly referred to as Unidentified Aerial Phenomena (UAP).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;brazil&#34;&gt;Brazil &lt;a href=&#34;#brazil&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on Brazil&amp;rsquo;s official UFO investigation, &lt;strong&gt;Operação Prato&lt;/strong&gt; (Operation Saucer).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operação Prato:&lt;/strong&gt; This was a Brazilian Air Force investigation conducted in 1977 in the Colares Island region. It involved military personnel observing and documenting alleged UFO activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;canada&#34;&gt;Canada &lt;a href=&#34;#canada&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists Canadian government projects related to UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Magnet:&lt;/strong&gt; A Canadian Department of Transport project led by Wilbert B. Smith in the 1950s to investigate UFOs and the possibility of using their technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Second Storey:&lt;/strong&gt; Another Canadian government project related to UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;france&#34;&gt;France &lt;a href=&#34;#france&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the French government&amp;rsquo;s UFO investigation efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GEPAN / SEPRA / GEIPAN:&lt;/strong&gt; Successive iterations of the French government&amp;rsquo;s UFO investigation unit. GEIPAN (Groupe d&amp;rsquo;Études et d&amp;rsquo;Informations sur les Phénomènes Aérospatiaux Non-identifiés) is the most recent name. This group collects and analyzes UFO reports, making its findings publicly available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;soviet-union&#34;&gt;Soviet Union &lt;a href=&#34;#soviet-union&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions a UFO investigation conducted by the Soviet Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institute 22:&lt;/strong&gt; A secret Soviet military research institute that studied anomalous atmospheric phenomena, including UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;united-kingdom&#34;&gt;United Kingdom &lt;a href=&#34;#united-kingdom&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists UFO investigations conducted by the UK government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flying Saucer Working Party:&lt;/strong&gt; A UK Ministry of Defence group formed in the early 1950s to investigate UFO sightings and determine if they posed a threat to national security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Condign:&lt;/strong&gt; A secret UK Ministry of Defence study conducted between 1997 and 2000 that analyzed UFO reports. The study concluded that most sightings could be explained as misidentified objects or phenomena.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;united-states&#34;&gt;United States &lt;a href=&#34;#united-states&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides an overview of various UFO investigations and incidents involving the United States government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced Aerospace Threat Identification Program (AATIP):&lt;/strong&gt; A Pentagon program that investigated UFOs from 2007 to 2012.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roswell UFO incident:&lt;/strong&gt; The alleged crash of a UFO near Roswell, New Mexico, in 1947.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brookings Report:&lt;/strong&gt; A 1960 NASA-commissioned report that considered the potential societal impact of discovering extraterrestrial life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Condon Committee:&lt;/strong&gt; A University of Colorado project, funded by the US Air Force, to scientifically study UFOs. Its 1968 report concluded that further study of UFOs was not justified.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Estimate of the Situation:&lt;/strong&gt; A classified US Air Force intelligence estimate from 1948 that concluded UFOs were likely extraterrestrial. This estimate was later rejected by higher authorities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Blue Book:&lt;/strong&gt; The US Air Force&amp;rsquo;s official UFO investigation project from 1952 to 1969. It investigated thousands of UFO reports, concluding that most were misidentified objects or natural phenomena.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Grudge:&lt;/strong&gt; A short-lived US Air Force UFO investigation project that preceded Project Blue Book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Serpo:&lt;/strong&gt; A purported top-secret exchange program between the US government and aliens from the planet Serpo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Sign:&lt;/strong&gt; The first US Air Force UFO investigation project, established in 1948.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Silver Bug:&lt;/strong&gt; A US Air Force project related to advanced aircraft technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Robertson Panel:&lt;/strong&gt; A CIA-convened panel of scientists that reviewed Project Blue Book in 1953. It recommended that the Air Force debunk UFO reports and engage in public education to reduce public interest in the subject.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All-domain Anomaly Resolution Office (AARO):&lt;/strong&gt; A current US Department of Defense office established to investigate UAPs across all domains (air, land, sea, and space).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NASA&amp;rsquo;s UAP independent study team:&lt;/strong&gt; A NASA-appointed team tasked with studying UAPs from a scientific perspective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena Disclosure Act:&lt;/strong&gt; A proposed US law aimed at declassifying government records related to UAPs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;uruguay&#34;&gt;Uruguay &lt;a href=&#34;#uruguay&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions the Uruguayan Air Force&amp;rsquo;s UFO investigation efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uruguayan Air Force Commission for the Reception and Investigation of Complaints of Unidentified Flying Objects (CRIDOVNI):&lt;/strong&gt; A commission within the Uruguayan Air Force responsible for investigating UFO reports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the references used in the document, including a link to the Uruguayan Air Force Commission&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides external links to resources related to government UFO investigations, including the CIA, Library and Archives Canada, the University of Colorado, and the UK National Archives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_investigations_of_UFOs_by_governments&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_investigations_of_UFOs_by_governments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
