<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UFOs and Alien Encounters on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/ufos-and-alien-encounters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UFOs and Alien Encounters on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 18:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/ufos-and-alien-encounters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cattle mutilation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_ee1c97534fee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 18:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_ee1c97534fee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;cattle-mutilation&#34;&gt;Cattle Mutilation &lt;a href=&#34;#cattle-mutilation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cattle mutilation refers to the killing and mutilation of cattle (and other animals) under unusual and often bloodless circumstances. The phenomenon is often linked to paranormal or supernatural explanations, including cults, government agencies, cryptids like the chupacabra, and extraterrestrials. Mutilations typically involve the removal of specific body parts such as ears, eyeballs, jaw flesh, tongues, lymph nodes, genitals, and rectums. Two independent federal investigations have been conducted in the United States to examine these incidents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-history&#34;&gt;Early History &lt;a href=&#34;#early-history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The earliest documented cases of unexplained livestock deaths occurred in England in 1606, with reports of sheep being slaughtered and only their tallow and some inward parts removed. Charles Fort collected accounts of similar cattle mutilations in England during the late 19th and early 20th centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-snippy-horse-death-of-1967&#34;&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Snippy&amp;rdquo; Horse Death of 1967 &lt;a href=&#34;#the-snippy-horse-death-of-1967&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The unexplained death and mutilation of a horse named &amp;ldquo;Snippy&amp;rdquo; in Alamosa, Colorado, in 1967 brought the phenomenon to wider attention. The horse&amp;rsquo;s head and neck were skinned and defleshed, and the body displayed precise cuts with no blood at the scene. This case was the first to link mutilations to extraterrestrial beings and unidentified flying objects. Wadsworth Ayer&amp;rsquo;s investigation for the Condon Committee found no evidence to support abnormal causes. Alamosa County Sheriff Ben Phillips initially attributed the death to a lightning strike. Later, two students confessed to shooting the horse weeks after the case gained publicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cattle-mutilations-19731980&#34;&gt;Cattle Mutilations 1973–1980 &lt;a href=&#34;#cattle-mutilations-19731980&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This period saw a surge in reported cattle mutilations across Kansas, Nebraska, Colorado, and New Mexico. In April 1973, sheriffs in Western Iowa reported unidentified helicopters involved in cattle and pig rustling. Similar rustling was reported in Missouri in August, with authorities warning farmers against firing on the helicopters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1973-kansas-wave&#34;&gt;1973 Kansas Wave &lt;a href=&#34;#1973-kansas-wave&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In June 1973, Cloud County sheriff Fred Modlin warned the public about suspicious phone calls from someone posing as a USDA official. A series of butchered cows were subsequently found on farms in the area, with right ears removed. Local press speculated about a &amp;ldquo;Mad Dog&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;phantom&amp;rdquo; butcher. By December, law enforcement reported investigating 40 mutilations across Kansas and Nebraska, with sexual organs often removed. State Senator Ross Doyen also reported a mutilation on his ranch. The Kansas Brand Commissioner&amp;rsquo;s office attributed most deaths to natural causes and predation, a conclusion disputed by Modlin and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1974-nebraska-wave&#34;&gt;1974 Nebraska Wave &lt;a href=&#34;#1974-nebraska-wave&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reports of mutilations continued in April 1974, with a Nebraska cow found mutilated and drained of blood. Sightings of unidentified helicopters were also reported. In May, two mutilations were reported in Mills County, Iowa, with coyotes suggested as the cause. By June, mutilations were reported in Lancaster County, Nebraska. In August, an unidentified helicopter was spotted hovering above a field where a mutilated cow was later found. Knox County Sheriff Herbert Thompson reported armed civilian patrols in response to helicopter sightings. Cloud County Attorney William Walsh suggested the mutilations were the work of devil-worshiping cultists. State Sen. John Decamp called for a coordinated investigation. By late August, 25 mutilations had been reported across five Nebraska counties. Authorities cautioned the public against shooting at aircraft. In September, an autopsy revealed a supposedly-mutilated cow had died of natural causes. Law enforcement officials from 24 counties met to discuss the mutilations, estimating that about 27 out of 80 cow deaths were suspected mutilations. South Dakota Attorney General Kermit Sande reported mutilations in his state. UFO expert J. Allen Hynek denied any link between UFOs and cattle mutilations. In December, mutilations were reported in Minnesota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1975-colorado&#34;&gt;1975 Colorado &lt;a href=&#34;#1975-colorado&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1975, the Colorado Associated Press voted the mutilations as the state&amp;rsquo;s top story. Senator Floyd K. Haskell contacted the FBI for assistance, claiming 130 mutilations in Colorado and reports across nine states. A 1979 FBI report estimated 8,000 mutilations in Colorado, causing approximately $1 million in damages. The Michigan ATF tasked Donald E. Flickinger with investigating possible links to a &amp;ldquo;Hell-oriented biker gang.&amp;rdquo; The Colorado Bureau of Investigation opened an investigation under Carl Whiteside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1976-dulce-new-mexico&#34;&gt;1976 Dulce, New Mexico &lt;a href=&#34;#1976-dulce-new-mexico&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In June 1976, Dulce rancher Manuel Gomez reported a mutilation to Officer Gabe Valdez of the New Mexico State Patrol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1979-public-meeting&#34;&gt;1979 Public Meeting &lt;a href=&#34;#1979-public-meeting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In April 1979, U.S. Attorney R. E. Thompson and US Senator Harrison Schmidt held a public meeting about cattle mutilations, attended by about 80 people. Paul Bennewitz reported seeing unidentified lights over Kirtland Air Force Base. In May 1979, Valdez reported finding two drugs in the remains of a mutilated bull: Chlorpromazine (Thorazine) and an unnamed drug used to clog the blood. In June 1981, investigators found a mutilated cow at the Gomez ranch with radar chaff nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;later-incidents&#34;&gt;Later Incidents &lt;a href=&#34;#later-incidents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many cases of mutilation have been reported worldwide since 1967, primarily in the Americas and Australia. In South America, an estimated 3,500 incidents have occurred since 2002. Investigators believe that a large number of cases go unreported. In 1993, photographic evidence surfaced of a mutilated human corpse found near the Guarapiranga reservoir of São Paulo, Brazil, in 1988, sparking theories ranging from homicide to alien abduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;characteristics&#34;&gt;Characteristics &lt;a href=&#34;#characteristics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cattle deaths due to natural causes are common. Mutilations are characterized by the absence of sex organs, udders, tongues, anus, rectum, and sometimes ears or eyes. Cuts are described as &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;surgical.&amp;rdquo; Some animals are reported to have been drained of blood with no sign of blood in the area. Strange marks or imprints have been found near the sites. In the &amp;ldquo;Snippy&amp;rdquo; case, there was an absence of tracks within a 100-foot radius of the carcass, with small holes &amp;ldquo;punched&amp;rdquo; in the ground and flattened bushes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;laboratory-reports&#34;&gt;Laboratory Reports &lt;a href=&#34;#laboratory-reports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Laboratory reports on some mutilated animals have shown unusual levels of vitamins or minerals in tissue samples and the presence of chemicals not normally found in animals. In a case documented by New Mexico police and the FBI involving a bull belonging to Manuel Gomez of Dulce, New Mexico, the animal displayed classic mutilation signs. The liver and heart were white and mushy, with the texture of peanut butter. Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory detected &lt;em&gt;Clostridium&lt;/em&gt; bacteria in the heart but could not reach any conclusions. Liver samples were devoid of copper and contained high levels of zinc, potassium, and phosphorus. Blood samples were light pink and did not clot. The animal&amp;rsquo;s hide was unusually brittle, and the flesh underneath was discolored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;helicopter-sightings&#34;&gt;Helicopter Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#helicopter-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In July 1974, two unregistered helicopters reportedly opened fire on Robert Smith Jr. in Honey Creek, Iowa. In August 1974, residents reported seeing unidentified helicopters shining spotlights into fields where mutilated cows were later found. Know County Sheriff Herbert Thompson claimed helicopter sightings had become a nightly occurrence. By 1975, some ranchers formed armed vigilante groups to patrol their fields. Authorities ran ads urging ranchers not to shoot at survey helicopters. In 1976, two Cache County, Utah, police officers reportedly confronted men in an unmarked U.S. Army helicopter at a small community airport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;official-investigations&#34;&gt;Official Investigations &lt;a href=&#34;#official-investigations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The New Mexico Livestock Board sought assistance from the Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory. Colorado Bureau of Investigation agents went undercover to investigate. Oklahoma convened a task force. Federal authorities launched a comprehensive investigation of the mutilation phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bureau-of-alcohol-tobacco-and-firearms&#34;&gt;Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms &lt;a href=&#34;#bureau-of-alcohol-tobacco-and-firearms&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In January 1975, the Minnesota field office of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms (ATF) launched an investigation headed by Agent Donald Flickinger to investigate possible connections between cults and cattle mutilation. Flickinger recorded unusual incidents and circumstantial evidence but found insufficient evidence of cult involvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;colorado-bureau-of-investigation&#34;&gt;Colorado Bureau of Investigation &lt;a href=&#34;#colorado-bureau-of-investigation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In May 1975, the Colorado Bureau of Investigation opened an investigation under the leadership of Carl Whiteside. 19 animals underwent necropsies at Colorado State University, but no conclusive results emerged. A $40,000 reward was offered. The US Bureau of Land Management grounded all helicopters in Eastern Colorado. By December, the CBI had investigated 203 reports of cattle mutilations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-mexico-state-police&#34;&gt;New Mexico State Police &lt;a href=&#34;#new-mexico-state-police&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;On June 13, 1976, the New Mexico State Police began an investigation headed by Officer Gabe Valdez, assisted by Cattle Inspector Jim Dyad and Officer Howard Johnston of the New Mexico Department of Game and Fish. Valdez solicited the assistance of retired Sandia National Laboratories scientist Howard Burgess. On the night of July 5, five animals were found to have been marked with a chemical that fluoresced under ultraviolet light. On June 14, 1981, intact radar chaff was found near a mutilated cow on the Gomez ranch. The investigation reported finding evidence that some mutilated animals had been tranquilized and treated with an anti-coagulant prior to their mutilation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rommel-investigation&#34;&gt;Rommel Investigation &lt;a href=&#34;#rommel-investigation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beginning in May 1979, an investigation was funded by a grant from the Law Enforcement Assistance Administration and headed by retired FBI agent Kenneth Rommel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle_mutilation&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle_mutilation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
