<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Future History on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/future-history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Future History on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 05:10:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/future-history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alliance–Union universe</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_beba5dc8e508/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 05:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_beba5dc8e508/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;allianceunion-universe&#34;&gt;Alliance–Union Universe &lt;a href=&#34;#allianceunion-universe&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Alliance–Union universe is a fictional setting created by C. J. Cherryh for her science fiction novels. It spans from the 21st century into the far future and centers on humanity&amp;rsquo;s expansion into space. The universe is dominated by three major powers: Earth Company, the Alliance, and the Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description &lt;a href=&#34;#description&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces the core concept of the Alliance-Union universe as a future history spanning millennia, focusing on humanity&amp;rsquo;s exploration and colonization of space. It highlights the emergence of three major economic powers: Earth Company, the Alliance (a confederation of interstellar trade merchants), and the Union (a breakaway government based on Cyteen). The section also mentions the Company Wars, the Union&amp;rsquo;s use of cloned humans called &lt;em&gt;azi&lt;/em&gt;, and the interconnectedness of Cherryh&amp;rsquo;s various series within this universe, forming a &amp;ldquo;megatext.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the historical timeline of the Alliance-Union universe, starting with the establishment of space stations by the Earth Company. It covers the development of distinct cultural identities among stationers and merchanters, the discovery of Pell&amp;rsquo;s World (a planet hospitable to humans and home to the Hisa), and the invention of faster-than-light (FTL) travel. The section describes the Company Wars between Earth and the Union, the rise of Conrad Mazian and the Company Fleet, the formation of the Alliance as a neutral power, and the subsequent rivalry between the Alliance and the Union. Key events include the conflict at Pell Station (described in &lt;em&gt;Downbelow Station&lt;/em&gt;) and the emergence of Ariane Emory as a political leader within the Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;genre&#34;&gt;Genre &lt;a href=&#34;#genre&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section categorizes the various works within the Alliance-Union universe by genre. It identifies elements of space opera, planetary romance, hard science fiction, military science fiction, science fantasy, and horror fiction. Specific works are mentioned as examples of each genre, such as &lt;em&gt;Cyteen&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Downbelow Station&lt;/em&gt; as hard science fiction, the &lt;em&gt;Faded Sun&lt;/em&gt; trilogy as military science fiction, and the &lt;em&gt;Merovingen Nights&lt;/em&gt; series as science fantasy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;books-and-reading-order&#34;&gt;Books and Reading Order &lt;a href=&#34;#books-and-reading-order&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides guidance on the order in which to read the books set in the Alliance-Union universe. It notes that most books can be read in any order, with two exceptions: &lt;em&gt;Heavy Time&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Hellburner&lt;/em&gt; should be read in that order, as should &lt;em&gt;Cyteen&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Regenesis&lt;/em&gt;. The section also advises reading the novels within the &lt;em&gt;Faded Sun&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Chanur&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Morgaine&lt;/em&gt; series in sequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;major-characters&#34;&gt;Major Characters &lt;a href=&#34;#major-characters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists and describes several key characters in the Alliance-Union universe. These include Pyanfar Chanur (Hani captain and leader of the Compact), Sten Duncan (Alliance soldier who joins the Mri), Ariane Emory (Union scientist and administrator), Damon Konstantin and Elene Quen (leaders of the Merchanter Alliance), Conrad Mazian (commander of the Earth Company Fleet), Signy Mallory (captain of the &lt;em&gt;Norway&lt;/em&gt;), Elizabeth McGee (Union scientist), James Robert Neihart (captain of &lt;em&gt;Finity&amp;rsquo;s End&lt;/em&gt;), Kurt Morgan (crewman of the &lt;em&gt;Endymion&lt;/em&gt;), Raen a Sul hant Meth-maren (human mediator with the Majat), and Thorn (human raised by the Shonunin).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sentient-alien-species&#34;&gt;Sentient Alien Species &lt;a href=&#34;#sentient-alien-species&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a table listing various sentient alien species encountered in the Alliance-Union universe. The table includes the species name, home system, home planet, the works in which they appear, and brief notes about their characteristics. Some of the species listed are the Amaut, Ahnit, Caliban, Chi, Elee, Hani, Hisa, Iduve, Kallia, Kif, Knnn, Majat, Mahendo&amp;rsquo;sat, Mri, Nemet, Regul, Stsho, Sharrh, Shonunin, and Tc&amp;rsquo;a.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;planets&#34;&gt;Planets &lt;a href=&#34;#planets&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes several key planets within the Alliance-Union universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pells-world&#34;&gt;Pell&amp;rsquo;s World &lt;a href=&#34;#pells-world&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pell&amp;rsquo;s World, orbiting Tau Ceti, is the first planet discovered with an advanced ecosystem and intelligent extraterrestrial life (the Hisa). Its discovery sparked moral and policy debates on Earth and disrupted the balance of power, contributing to the Company Wars. Pell Station orbits the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gehenna&#34;&gt;Gehenna &lt;a href=&#34;#gehenna&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gehenna, in the Zeta Reticuli system, is home to the calibans. Secretly colonized by the Union and then abandoned, it became a source of conflict between the Alliance and the Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cyteen&#34;&gt;Cyteen &lt;a href=&#34;#cyteen&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyteen, deep in Union territory, required terraforming due to its toxic atmosphere. It is the source of the rejuvenation drug and the center of azi research and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;merovin&#34;&gt;Merovin &lt;a href=&#34;#merovin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merovin is isolated and technologically backward due to poor interstellar relations with the Sharrh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;technologies&#34;&gt;Technologies &lt;a href=&#34;#technologies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the key technologies present in the Alliance-Union universe. These include the jump drive (allowing faster-than-light travel), rejuv (a life-extension drug), human cloning (particularly the creation of azi), tape (subliminal conditioning and information transfer), and terraforming technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;society&#34;&gt;Society &lt;a href=&#34;#society&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the societal structures and attitudes within the Alliance-Union universe. It highlights the divergence of attitudes between planet-dwellers, space station-dwellers, and starship crews. It also describes the cultural and psychological division between unengineered citizens and azi in the Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mazianni&#34;&gt;Mazianni &lt;a href=&#34;#mazianni&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section defines the Mazianni as the military starships and crews loyal to Conrad Mazian after he renounces allegiance to Earth. It describes their origins as the Earth Company Fleet, their role in the Company War, Mazian&amp;rsquo;s rebellion, and their subsequent guerrilla warfare against the major powers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;songs&#34;&gt;Songs &lt;a href=&#34;#songs&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions a collection of songs written by C. J. Cherryh about the station trade in the Alliance-Union universe, which were recorded by filk musician Leslie Fish and released on the album &lt;em&gt;Finity&amp;rsquo;s End&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;critical-reception&#34;&gt;Critical Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the critical reception of the Alliance-Union universe. John Clute calls it Cherryh&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;central achievement,&amp;rdquo; noting its rough edges but the impression of a larger, yet-to-be-revealed history. M. Keith Booker describes it as &amp;ldquo;so far-reaching that its overall outlines remain unclear and continue to develop.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hisa_(fictional_alien_species)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hisa_(fictional_alien_species)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
