<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mystery on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/mystery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mystery on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 17:59:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/mystery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in Italy</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b188fae19432/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 17:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b188fae19432/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-sightings-in-italy&#34;&gt;UFO Sightings in Italy &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-sightings-in-italy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article presents a list of alleged UFO sightings in Italy, spanning from ancient times to the late 20th century. It emphasizes that the content may contain original research and lacks sufficient citations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;100-bc&#34;&gt;100 BC &lt;a href=&#34;#100-bc&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section references reports by Iulius Obsequens, detailing a sighting in Tarquinia of a round object moving across the sky from west to east.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;91-bc&#34;&gt;91 BC &lt;a href=&#34;#91-bc&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another report from Iulius Obsequens describes events at Aenariae and Spoletum. At Aenariae, a loud noise and a globe of fire appeared in the sky. In Spoletum, a golden globe of fire fell to earth, increased in size, ascended back into the sky, and obscured the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;43-bc&#34;&gt;43 BC &lt;a href=&#34;#43-bc&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iulius Obsequens is cited again, reporting an object resembling a weapon or missile rising from the earth into the sky with a loud noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1933&#34;&gt;1933 &lt;a href=&#34;#1933&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the &amp;ldquo;Fascist UFO Files&amp;rdquo; published by Roberto Pinotti in 2000. It alleges that a flying saucer crashed near Milan in 1933 and was investigated by a secret Cabinet RS/33, supposedly authorized by Benito Mussolini and led by Guglielmo Marconi. The craft was allegedly stored in hangars of SIAI-Marchetti in Vergiate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1942&#34;&gt;1942 &lt;a href=&#34;#1942&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large object with four red lights was reportedly seen in Turin in March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1950&#34;&gt;1950 &lt;a href=&#34;#1950&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A factory worker near Varese allegedly encountered three humanoids near a craft. One of the entities supposedly shot a beam at the worker, then the humanoids entered the craft and flew away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1954&#34;&gt;1954 &lt;a href=&#34;#1954&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A UFO sighting occurred in Florence on October 28, 1954, accompanied by a fall of angel hair. Additionally, two UFOs were observed over Taormina, Sicily, with photographs taken by Giuseppe Grasso being published by United Press Newspictures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1973&#34;&gt;1973 &lt;a href=&#34;#1973&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Alitalia airplane flying from Rome to Naples sighted a round object, which was confirmed by two Italian Air Force planes from Ciampino. Another sighting occurred at Caselle airport near Turin in the same year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1978&#34;&gt;1978 &lt;a href=&#34;#1978&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two hikers on Monte Musinè near Torino saw a bright light. One of them temporarily disappeared and was later found in shock with a scald on his leg, claiming to have seen an elongated vehicle and strange beings. Both hikers suffered from conjunctivitis. A close encounter was reported in Torrita di Siena, where a motorist saw a bright object and two small beings in suits and helmets near his car. A boy in a nearby house reported seeing &amp;ldquo;a kind of small reddish sun&amp;rdquo; at the same time. The section also mentions the Pier Fortunato Zanfretta incident, an alleged alien abduction in Marzano, Torriglia, near Genoa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Italy&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Italy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
