<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MST3K on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/mst3k/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MST3K on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 01:19:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/mst3k/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extra Terrestrial Visitors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_6524ca714fe7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 01:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_6524ca714fe7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extra-terrestrial-visitors&#34;&gt;Extra Terrestrial Visitors &lt;a href=&#34;#extra-terrestrial-visitors&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry details the 1983 French-Spanish science fiction film &lt;em&gt;Extra Terrestrial Visitors&lt;/em&gt; (also known as &lt;em&gt;Los nuevos extraterrestres&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Pod People&lt;/em&gt;). It covers the film&amp;rsquo;s production, plot, cast, release, and reception, including its later cult status due to being featured on &lt;em&gt;Mystery Science Theater 3000&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story unfolds in the woods of New England, where egg poachers stumble upon a cave containing alien eggs. After one poacher destroys the eggs, a vengeful alien begins targeting the poachers and a rock band camping nearby. Meanwhile, a young boy named Tommy discovers the remaining egg, which hatches into a creature he names Trumpy. Tommy and Trumpy become friends, and Trumpy develops telekinetic powers. The alien mother searches for her offspring, leading to encounters with the rock band and Tommy&amp;rsquo;s family. The film culminates in a confrontation between the humans and the alien mother, with tragic consequences for some characters. Tommy and Trumpy say goodbye before Tommy returns to his family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cast includes Ian Serra as Rick, Nina Ferrer as Sharon, Susana Bequer as Lara Stapleton, Sara Palmer as Kathy, Óscar Martín as Tommy Stevens, Maria Albert as Tracy, Emilio Linder as Brian, Concha Cuetos as Molly Stevens, Manuel Pereiro as Bill Stevens, and Frank Braña as Burt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Extra Terrestrial Visitors&lt;/em&gt; was a co-production between France and Spain, filmed in Madrid. The cast consisted largely of Spanish actors, and the film was shot in both Spanish and French, later dubbed in post-production. Juan Piquer Simón directed the film. Faruk Alatan, Dick Randall, and Edward L. Montoro produced the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film was initially released in France. In the United States, it was sometimes shown on television under the title &lt;em&gt;The Unearthling&lt;/em&gt;. Film Ventures International later acquired the film and re-titled it &lt;em&gt;Pod People&lt;/em&gt; for U.S. television distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception-and-legacy&#34;&gt;Reception and legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#reception-and-legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received negative reviews, with some finding it unintentionally funny. Its legacy is largely tied to its appearance on &lt;em&gt;Mystery Science Theater 3000&lt;/em&gt; (MST3K), which lampooned the &lt;em&gt;Pod People&lt;/em&gt; version of the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mystery-science-theater-3000&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mystery Science Theater 3000&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#mystery-science-theater-3000&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film gained popularity after being featured on &lt;em&gt;Mystery Science Theater 3000&lt;/em&gt; in 1991. The MST3K episode used a print of the film re-titled &lt;em&gt;Pod People&lt;/em&gt; by Film Ventures International. The opening and ending credits of &lt;em&gt;Pod People&lt;/em&gt; are superimposed over footage from &lt;em&gt;The Galaxy Invader&lt;/em&gt;. The fictional pop band&amp;rsquo;s song &amp;ldquo;Hear the Engines Roll&amp;rdquo; became a recurring joke on the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;home-media&#34;&gt;Home media &lt;a href=&#34;#home-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film has been released on VHS under various titles, including &lt;em&gt;The Unearthling&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;E. T.: The Second Coming&lt;/em&gt;. The MST3K version of the film has been released on DVD and Blu-ray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extra_Terrestrial_Visitors&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extra_Terrestrial_Visitors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
