<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Newspaper on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/newspaper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Newspaper on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 10:36:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/newspaper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jafr alien invasion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_d7bf74b1dd15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 10:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_d7bf74b1dd15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;2010-jordanian-newspaper-prank-the-jafr-alien-invasion&#34;&gt;2010 Jordanian Newspaper Prank: The Jafr Alien Invasion &lt;a href=&#34;#2010-jordanian-newspaper-prank-the-jafr-alien-invasion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the events surrounding a prank published by the Jordanian newspaper &lt;em&gt;Al-Ghad&lt;/em&gt; on April 1, 2010. The prank involved a fabricated story about UFOs landing near the town of Jafr, Jordan, and the panic that ensued among the town&amp;rsquo;s residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary &lt;a href=&#34;#summary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article on the front page of &lt;em&gt;Al-Ghad&lt;/em&gt; claimed that UFOs had landed in the desert near Jafr, and the &amp;ldquo;pilots&amp;rdquo; were described as 3-meter-tall creatures. The story also stated that communications were disrupted by the UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;details-of-the-prank-and-reaction&#34;&gt;Details of the Prank and Reaction &lt;a href=&#34;#details-of-the-prank-and-reaction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story elaborated on the alien landing, describing how the town was illuminated by the flying saucers at night, causing residents to flee into the streets. The hoax caused widespread fear in Jafr, leading parents to keep their children home from school. The mayor of Jafr, Mohammed Mleihan, contacted security authorities and considered ordering an evacuation of the town&amp;rsquo;s 13,000 residents. He also expressed the residents&amp;rsquo; fear of an alien attack and considered suing the newspaper for spreading false information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apology-and-context&#34;&gt;Apology and Context &lt;a href=&#34;#apology-and-context&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The newspaper issued a formal apology for the disruption caused by the prank. The editor did not explain why Jafr was chosen as the target of the joke. However, the BBC noted that the area is known for its military bases, which have been used by American soldiers for joint exercises with the Jordanian military and had allegedly housed al-Qaida militants in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comparison-and-cultural-context&#34;&gt;Comparison and Cultural Context &lt;a href=&#34;#comparison-and-cultural-context&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prank is compared to the 1938 radio broadcast of &lt;em&gt;War of the Worlds&lt;/em&gt;, which caused panic in the United States. The article emphasizes that April Fool&amp;rsquo;s Day jokes are not a common practice in Jordanian newspapers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article cites two sources: a BBC article titled &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;Alien invasion&amp;rsquo; April Fools&amp;rsquo; story angers Jordan mayor&amp;rdquo; and a &lt;em&gt;USA Today&lt;/em&gt; article titled &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;Alien invasion&amp;rsquo; April Fools prank causes public panic.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External Links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article provides an external link to the original article in Arabic on the &lt;em&gt;Al-Ghad&lt;/em&gt; website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jafr_alien_invasion&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jafr_alien_invasion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
