<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mystery on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/mystery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mystery on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 20:38:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/mystery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Resident Alien (comics)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b0b6aa6676d7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 20:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b0b6aa6676d7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;resident-alien-comics&#34;&gt;Resident Alien (comics) &lt;a href=&#34;#resident-alien-comics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry details the American comic book series &lt;em&gt;Resident Alien&lt;/em&gt;, created by Peter Hogan and Steve Parkhouse, published by Dark Horse Comics. It outlines the publication history, collected editions, plot, critical reception, and television adaptation of the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication-information&#34;&gt;Publication Information &lt;a href=&#34;#publication-information&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section identifies Dark Horse Comics as the publisher of the monthly comic book series. It lists the titles of the various miniseries within the &lt;em&gt;Resident Alien&lt;/em&gt; series, noting that the original material was published as a set of limited series. The genre is identified as mystery. Publication dates for each miniseries are provided, starting with &lt;em&gt;Welcome to Earth!&lt;/em&gt; in April–July 2012 and continuing through &lt;em&gt;The Book of Life&lt;/em&gt; in June–September 2024. The total number of issues published is 34. The creative team is listed as Peter Hogan (writer), Steve Parkhouse (artist), and Philip R Simon (editor).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary &lt;a href=&#34;#summary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comic book series centers on an alien who crash lands on Earth and assumes the identity of a doctor while awaiting rescue. He is pursued by a government agency and spends his time solving murders and other mysteries. The series has been well-received by critics, who have praised Parkhouse&amp;rsquo;s artistic ability to convey expressions. A television adaptation starring Alan Tudyk premiered on Syfy on January 27, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication-history&#34;&gt;Publication History &lt;a href=&#34;#publication-history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the development and publication of the &lt;em&gt;Resident Alien&lt;/em&gt; comic book series. It mentions that Peter Hogan and Steve Parkhouse previously collaborated on &lt;em&gt;The Dreaming&lt;/em&gt; for Vertigo comics. Parkhouse suggested an alien-themed project, and they worked closely on the plot, with Hogan primarily developing the story. Dark Horse Publisher Mike Richardson provided editorial input. Hogan wanted to offer a sympathetic portrayal of a nonhuman character and mix science fiction with mystery, drawing inspiration from &lt;em&gt;Twin Peaks&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Man Who Fell to Earth&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;My Favorite Martian&lt;/em&gt;. He requested that Parkhouse base the main character&amp;rsquo;s design on DC Comics aliens from the early 1960s. The title came from a conversation Hogan had with an English friend who showed him an ID that read &amp;ldquo;Resident Alien.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Parkhouse couldn&amp;rsquo;t maintain a monthly work pace, &lt;em&gt;Resident Alien&lt;/em&gt; was published as a series of four-issue miniseries. The first chapter of each of the first three miniseries was serialized in &lt;em&gt;Dark Horse Presents&lt;/em&gt; before being collected as issue zero. Subsequent issues were published monthly, followed by a trade paperback collection. The publication details of each miniseries are provided, including the serialization in &lt;em&gt;Dark Horse Presents&lt;/em&gt;, release dates, and sales figures. The third miniseries, &lt;em&gt;The Sam Hain Mystery&lt;/em&gt;, was conceived before the second miniseries began publication. Parkhouse got the idea for the detective name &amp;ldquo;Sam Hain&amp;rdquo; from Neil Gaiman. Later miniseries, such as &lt;em&gt;The Man With No Name&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;An Alien in New York&lt;/em&gt;, were numbered one through four instead of starting with a zero issue. &lt;em&gt;Your Ride&amp;rsquo;s Here&lt;/em&gt; was initially planned as the story&amp;rsquo;s conclusion. The success of the television adaptation led to additional miniseries, &lt;em&gt;The Book of Love&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Book of Life&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;collected-editions&#34;&gt;Collected Editions &lt;a href=&#34;#collected-editions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the &lt;em&gt;Resident Alien&lt;/em&gt; miniseries that have been collected into trade paperback releases. It provides a table with information on each miniseries, including the issues collected, release dates, ISBNs, and notes about serialization in &lt;em&gt;Dark Horse Presents&lt;/em&gt;. It also lists the &lt;em&gt;Resident Alien&lt;/em&gt; Omnibus editions and the material collected in each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the plot of the &lt;em&gt;Resident Alien&lt;/em&gt; comic book series. Flashbacks reveal that Captain Hah Re, an alien biologist, crashes in the Southwestern United States. He uses his empathic abilities to blend in and learns English and human anatomy. He takes the identity &amp;ldquo;Harry Vanderspeigle&amp;rdquo; and buys a remote cabin near Patience, Washington.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome to Earth!&lt;/em&gt; details how Harry becomes the town doctor after the previous doctor is murdered. He uses his mental abilities to solve crimes and befriends Asta Twelvetrees, who can partially see through his disguise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Suicide Blonde&lt;/em&gt; involves Harry investigating the death of a former lover of the mayor in Seattle. A picture of Harry and Asta is taken, which is seen by the men in black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Sam Hain Mystery&lt;/em&gt; focuses on the men in black investigating Patience and Harry learning about a pseudonymous mystery writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Man with No Name&lt;/em&gt; sees Harry befriending Dan Twelvetrees, Asta&amp;rsquo;s father, and helping a dying man&amp;rsquo;s daughter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An Alien in New York&lt;/em&gt; involves Harry discovering alien writing in paintings by a reclusive artist and deciding to live as though he will never be rescued. The men in black narrow their search for Asta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your Ride&amp;rsquo;s Here&lt;/em&gt; sees Harry dealing with a child who can see through his disguise and ultimately choosing to stay on Earth with Asta, allowing an agent to take his place among the rescuing aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Book of Love&lt;/em&gt; follows Harry as he attempts to navigate love with Asta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;critical-reception&#34;&gt;Critical Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the critical reception of the &lt;em&gt;Resident Alien&lt;/em&gt; comic book series. It provides a table with ratings from Comic Book Roundup for various miniseries. The series has received mostly positive reviews, with praise for its focus on small-town life and Parkhouse&amp;rsquo;s art style, particularly his ability to draw facial expressions. Some critics found the initial issue numbering confusing, while others appreciated the lack of focus on comedy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;television-adaptation&#34;&gt;Television Adaptation &lt;a href=&#34;#television-adaptation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the television adaptation of the &lt;em&gt;Resident Alien&lt;/em&gt; comic book series. It mentions that discussions for a television series began in March 2013. Syfy placed a pilot order in May 2018. The show is produced by Universal Cable Productions, Dark Horse Entertainment, and Amblin Television, with Chris Sheridan as the adapter and executive producer. Alan Tudyk stars as Harry, with Corey Reynolds and Alice Wetterlund in supporting roles. The setting was moved from Washington to Colorado. The premiere was delayed to January 27, 2021, due to the COVID-19 pandemic. The series was renewed for a second season in March 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resident_Alien_(comics)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resident_Alien_(comics)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
