<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conspiracy Theory on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/conspiracy-theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conspiracy Theory on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 20:42:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/conspiracy-theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ancient Aliens</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_80db310465ba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 20:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_80db310465ba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ancient-aliens&#34;&gt;Ancient Aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; is an American television series that explores the pseudoscientific ancient astronauts hypothesis. It presents unorthodox theories about extraterrestrial visitations in ancient times, often without critical analysis. The show has been criticized for promoting pseudoscience and pseudohistory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Genre:&lt;/strong&gt; Pseudoscience, Pseudohistory, Ufology, Conspiracy theory
&lt;strong&gt;Narrator:&lt;/strong&gt; Robert Clotworthy
&lt;strong&gt;Country of Origin:&lt;/strong&gt; United States
&lt;strong&gt;Original Language:&lt;/strong&gt; English
&lt;strong&gt;Number of Seasons:&lt;/strong&gt; 21
&lt;strong&gt;Number of Episodes:&lt;/strong&gt; 268&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series is produced by Prometheus Entertainment. Kevin Burns served as executive producer from 2009 to 2021. Giorgio A. Tsoukalos is a consulting producer and featured guest. UFO researcher C. Scott Littleton was a producing consultant until his death in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; began as a two-hour documentary special on the History Channel in 2009. It became a flagship series on History from 2010 to 2012, then moved to H2 from 2012 to 2014. In 2015, it returned to History after H2 was relaunched as Vice on TV. A fifteenth season premiered in 2020, with subsequent seasons following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;premise-and-cosmology&#34;&gt;Premise and cosmology &lt;a href=&#34;#premise-and-cosmology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series is based on the ancient astronauts hypothesis popularized by Erich von Däniken in &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; and Zecharia Sitchin in &lt;em&gt;The 12th Planet&lt;/em&gt;. This hypothesis suggests that extraterrestrial beings visited Earth in the distant past and influenced the development of human civilization, technology, and architecture. Ancient achievements like the Egyptian pyramids, Pumapunku, Teotihuacan, and Stonehenge are attributed to extraterrestrial influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series suggests that remnants of these visitations can be found in religious texts, ancient myths, and legendary histories, including those of Hinduism, Ancient Egyptian religion, Gnostic Christianity, and Mormonism. It also proposes that modern humans may be the result of genetic modification by or biological descendants of ancient astronauts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series often avoids precise dates, using terms like &amp;ldquo;the remote past&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;ancient times.&amp;rdquo; A common demarcation point is &amp;ldquo;before or after &amp;lsquo;The Ice Age&amp;rsquo;,&amp;rdquo; or approximately 12,000 years ago. Some guests, such as Graham Hancock and Robert Schoch, suggest that a sophisticated human civilization predated our own and was destroyed at the end of the Ice Age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series features guests who support these claims and promote the idea of a shared cosmogony and cosmology, with significance placed on Sirius, Orion, Pleiades, the Moon, and Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;presentation-style&#34;&gt;Presentation style &lt;a href=&#34;#presentation-style&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series presents claims made by guests in an uncritical and fast-paced manner. The narration often frames these claims as rhetorical questions, answered with &amp;ldquo;ancient alien theorists say yes.&amp;rdquo; After a claim is introduced, the narration often cuts away with, &amp;ldquo;Perhaps more evidence can be found&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; before introducing another location or event with a hypothetical connection. This presentation style has been described as a Gish gallop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geologist Robert Schoch has stated that his interviews for the series have been edited in a way that is out of context or disconnected from the questions asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writer David Childress frequently concludes his comments with the exclamation, &amp;ldquo;—probably extraterrestrials!&amp;rdquo; Childress and Giorgio Tsoukalos assert that prehistoric peoples lacked the vocabulary to describe advanced technology, and thus referred to extraterrestrial visitors as gods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terms such as &amp;ldquo;ancient astronauts,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;ancient aliens,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;alien visitors,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;extra-terrestrial beings,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;ancient gods,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;otherworldly beings&amp;rdquo; are used interchangeably. Guests often conflate the meaning of &amp;ldquo;theory&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;hypothesis,&amp;rdquo; or obscure the difference between mythology and verifiable archaeology, anthropology, or documented history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;frequent-guests&#34;&gt;Frequent guests &lt;a href=&#34;#frequent-guests&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series features a range of guests, including credentialed scientists and professionals, as well as proponents of the ancient astronaut hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some frequent guests include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sara Seager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michael Denning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jonathan Young&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert Schoch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erich von Däniken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;George Noory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Barry Downing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert Bauval&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graham Hancock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nick Pope&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travis S. Taylor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;evidence&#34;&gt;Evidence &lt;a href=&#34;#evidence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many episodes offer little empirical evidence to support the claims presented. Episodes often focus on out-of-place artifacts, such as the London Hammer, Antikythera mechanism, or the Aiud object. Guests discuss evidence in general or abstract terms. Some guests allege that professionals and government officials have suppressed evidence of ancient mysteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Season 12 onward, some episodes have included on-camera tests conducted by scientists and medical professionals on evidence that potentially supports the ancient astronauts hypothesis. However, none of the results have proven conclusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-claims&#34;&gt;Other claims &lt;a href=&#34;#other-claims&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series explores other claims linked to the ancient astronauts hypothesis, including UFOs, alien abductions, the Roswell incident, Rendlesham Forest incident, panspermia, and human space exploration. Guests have presented pseudohistorical and pseudoscientific hypotheses related to Atlantis, ley lines, cataclysmic pole shifts, creationism, and legendary history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other concepts explored include faith healing, remote viewing, psychic phenomena, and catastrophism. Guests have claimed that prominent historical figures were influenced by or were possibly &amp;ldquo;extra-terrestrial&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;otherworldly beings.&amp;rdquo; Guests have also discussed unrelated pseudoscientific claims, such as dinosaurs coexisting with humans, crystal healing, crystal skulls, Freemasonry, Rosicrucianism, and the New World Order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linda Moulton Howe appears in several episodes which explore alien abduction, animal mutilation, and conspiracies involving alleged military installations on Antarctica. The 2013 Citizen Hearing on Disclosure features prominently in numerous episodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to December 2012, several episodes explored aspects of the 2012 Mayan doomsday prophecy. Episodes focusing on Mesoamerica broadcast after 2012 make no mention of the 2012 phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series consists of 21 seasons, including a pilot episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program has attracted millions of viewers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;critical-response&#34;&gt;Critical response &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-response&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series has been criticized by historians, cosmologists, archaeologists, and other scientists for presenting pseudoscience, pseudohistory, and pseudoarchaeology as fact. Episodes are often characterized as &amp;ldquo;far-fetched&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;hugely speculative.&amp;rdquo; Many of the claims made by guests are not commonly accepted by the scientific community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brad Lockwood of &lt;em&gt;Forbes&lt;/em&gt; characterized &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; as an example of History&amp;rsquo;s channel drift toward &amp;ldquo;programs devoted to monsters, aliens, and conspiracies.&amp;rdquo; Alex Knapp, also of &lt;em&gt;Forbes&lt;/em&gt;, cited archaeologist Keith Fitzpatrick-Matthews&amp;rsquo; rebuke of History for treating &amp;ldquo;nonsense as though it were fact.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2011, &lt;em&gt;South Park&lt;/em&gt; parodied the series in the episode &amp;ldquo;A History Channel Thanksgiving.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Science writer Riley Black was critical of the series, accusing it of employing a Gish gallop technique to overwhelm the viewer with many &amp;ldquo;fictions and distortions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenneth Feder, Professor of Archaeology at Central Connecticut State University, stated that he was approached by producers with requests to appear in several episodes, but was not contacted again after stating his belief that the ancient astronaut hypothesis is &amp;ldquo;execrable bullshit.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, Vice on TV producer Jordan Kinley said of &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; claims: &amp;ldquo;You feel kind of lost when someone questions the historical narrative you&amp;rsquo;ve been taught. I don&amp;rsquo;t believe much of what&amp;rsquo;s talked about &amp;hellip; but I think it&amp;rsquo;s a good time for people to realize that some of our history is manufactured. Some of it is manufactured to be accurate, and some of it is manufactured to excuse horrible things that have happened.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 2019 issue of &lt;em&gt;Public Archaeology&lt;/em&gt;, Franco D. Rossi of Johns Hopkins University characterized &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; and its fans as a &amp;ldquo;science fiction fandom&amp;rdquo; which also trafficked in &amp;ldquo;misinformation&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;conspiracies.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2020, podcaster Brian Dunning challenged and debunked many of the claims featured on &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;critical-response-by-guests&#34;&gt;Critical response by guests &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-response-by-guests&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many guests featured in episodes of the series have publicly expressed skepticism of the series&amp;rsquo; premise or of the ancient astronaut hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a 2014 hearing of the House Committee on Science, Seth Shostak said that there is not any evidence which has convinced him &amp;ldquo;that we were visited in [historical] times.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a 2018 episode of &lt;em&gt;The Joe Rogan Experience&lt;/em&gt;, Robert Schoch said promoters of the ancient astronaut hypothesis &amp;ldquo;want everything to be &amp;lsquo;ancient aliens&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;, which in his view was &amp;ldquo;sort of a cop-out&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;William Shatner, who appeared in the Season 16 episode &amp;ldquo;William Shatner Meets &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, told &lt;em&gt;Inverse&lt;/em&gt;: &amp;ldquo;I had some spirited discussions with these experts who believe aliens were here, and like most people, I was dubious about the whole thing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;related-media&#34;&gt;Related media &lt;a href=&#34;#related-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many guests featured on &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; appear in other History channel series and specials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ancient-aliens-meme&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; meme &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-aliens-meme&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tsoukalos&amp;rsquo;s appearances in &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; inspired a meme highlighting his unusual hairstyle overlaid with the caption: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m not saying it was aliens &amp;hellip; but &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-con&#34;&gt;Alien Con &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-con&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2016 to 2018, A&amp;amp;E Networks co-produced several installments of Alien Con, a fan convention inspired by the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#heading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_Aliens&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_Aliens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
