<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Collectible on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/collectible/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Collectible on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 23:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/collectible/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Test Tube Aliens</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_278a8fc6376c/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 23:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_278a8fc6376c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;test-tube-aliens&#34;&gt;Test Tube Aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#test-tube-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry details the Test Tube Aliens toy line, including their fictional backstory, the toy&amp;rsquo;s features, and how it functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;story&#34;&gt;Story &lt;a href=&#34;#story&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The narrative revolves around two factions of aliens: the &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; aliens from the dying planet Naratuko, seeking a new home, and the &amp;ldquo;evil&amp;rdquo; aliens responsible for their planet&amp;rsquo;s destruction, pursuing them across the universe. The good aliens reverted to a pre-birth state to escape, sacrificing strength for intelligence. Initially, the story presents a clear good vs. evil dynamic. However, a later plot twist reveals that all the original aliens are actually evil, with the &amp;ldquo;X series&amp;rdquo; aliens being the true good guys. The evil aliens&amp;rsquo; plan involves being discarded in bins after appearing dead, allowing them to infiltrate and take over bodies of water. This led to the release of a &amp;ldquo;Pure Evil&amp;rdquo; series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-toy-itself&#34;&gt;The toy itself &lt;a href=&#34;#the-toy-itself&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The toy consists of a test tube containing a white cocoon or chrysalis. Adding water dissolves the cocoon, revealing an infant alien. The alien&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;heart,&amp;rdquo; indicated by flashing lights, begins to beat, signifying it is &amp;ldquo;alive.&amp;rdquo; The alien requires feeding with &amp;ldquo;Sloog&amp;rdquo; (a white powder mixed with water) for the first few days, after which it can survive on tap water. Maintaining the alien&amp;rsquo;s health involves a 12-hour light/dark cycle. The alien reacts to improper conditions, flashing green for too much water and orange for too little. If neglected, the alien will &amp;ldquo;die,&amp;rdquo; rendering the toy unusable. Some owners have reported lifespans of seven to nine months. The toy also interacted with a now-defunct website where users could induce coma or panic modes and check the alien&amp;rsquo;s age and health. A picture of Kurion, a good alien, is included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How it works &lt;a href=&#34;#how-it-works&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The alien&amp;rsquo;s body contains polyacrylamide, a polymer that expands when it absorbs water. The &amp;ldquo;Sloog&amp;rdquo; contains a weak acid that slows this expansion, creating the illusion of growth over several days. The alien senses the acid&amp;rsquo;s presence through conductivity measurements via electrodes on its antenna and head. These electrodes also detect water levels, with the alien being &amp;ldquo;healthy&amp;rdquo; only when the water is between the antenna and head electrodes. Website interaction was achieved through a light detector in the alien&amp;rsquo;s head, responding to flashes from the &amp;ldquo;web portal&amp;rdquo; on the Test Tube Aliens website. This light detector also tracked light and dark exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test_Tube_Aliens&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test_Tube_Aliens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
