<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Exoplanets on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/exoplanets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Exoplanets on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 05:26:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/exoplanets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial life</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7c53322651c6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 05:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7c53322651c6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-life&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial Life &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-life&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extraterrestrial life, often called alien life, refers to life that originates from a world other than Earth. While no such life has been conclusively detected, the possibility ranges from simple prokaryotes to intelligent beings and civilizations. The study of extraterrestrial life falls under the science of astrobiology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context &lt;a href=&#34;#context&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a framework for understanding the topic of life in the universe. It outlines the conditions necessary for life to arise, noting that the early universe was initially too hot and lacked the necessary elements. The formation of planetary systems and the emergence of organic compounds are discussed, along with the concepts of abiogenesis and panspermia. The section also touches on stellar evolution and the ubiquity of life&amp;rsquo;s raw components in the cosmos. The vastness of the universe and the challenges of studying extraterrestrial life due to immense distances are highlighted. The concept of the circumstellar habitable zone, or &amp;ldquo;Goldilocks zone,&amp;rdquo; is introduced, along with the factors that influence planetary habitability. The section concludes by emphasizing the fleeting nature of species&amp;rsquo; existence on a cosmic scale and the possibility of life arising and becoming extinct on other planets millions or billions of years ago. Avi Loeb&amp;rsquo;s concept of the &amp;ldquo;Habitable Epoch of the Early Universe&amp;rdquo; is mentioned, suggesting a period when liquid water could have existed if planets were present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;likelihood-of-existence&#34;&gt;Likelihood of Existence &lt;a href=&#34;#likelihood-of-existence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the debate over whether life in the cosmos is common or rare. It presents the argument for ubiquitous extraterrestrial life, based on the size and age of the universe, the ubiquity of life&amp;rsquo;s chemical elements, and the universality of physical laws. Scientists such as Carl Sagan and Stephen Hawking are mentioned as proponents of this view, which is embodied in the Copernican and mediocrity principles. The Rare Earth hypothesis, which posits that life on Earth is possible due to a unique series of factors, is also presented. The Drake equation, devised by Frank Drake, is introduced as a probabilistic argument to estimate the number of communicative extraterrestrial civilizations in the Milky Way galaxy. The section concludes by discussing the Fermi paradox, which highlights the apparent contradiction between high estimates of the probability of extraterrestrial civilizations and the lack of evidence for their existence. Dennis W. Sciama, Zhi-Wei Wang, and Samuel L. Braunstein are mentioned in connection with potential explanations for the Fermi paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;biochemical-basis&#34;&gt;Biochemical Basis &lt;a href=&#34;#biochemical-basis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section delves into the potential biochemical characteristics of extraterrestrial life. It considers the range of possibilities, from simple microorganisms to complex alien intelligences. The basic requirements for life, including non-equilibrium thermodynamics and a source of energy, are discussed. The importance of water as a solvent is emphasized, along with alternative solvents such as ammonia and hydrocarbons. The section also explores the potential for alternative chemical elements to form the basis of life, considering the requirements for creating complex molecules and storing information. Carbon is highlighted as a versatile element, but the possibility of silicon-based life is also considered. Norman Horowitz&amp;rsquo;s views on carbon-based life are mentioned. The section further discusses the potential for radically different biochemistries, even if based on carbon and water, and the role of natural selection in shaping life. The likelihood of cell membranes, the evolution from prokaryotes to eukaryotes, and the potential for convergent evolution are also explored. Simon Conway Morris&amp;rsquo;s ideas on convergent evolution leading to similar kingdoms and features in alien animals are mentioned. The section concludes by discussing the influence of planetary context on life and the research assessing the capacity of life for developing intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;harsh-environmental-conditions-on-earth-harboring-life&#34;&gt;Harsh Environmental Conditions on Earth Harboring Life &lt;a href=&#34;#harsh-environmental-conditions-on-earth-harboring-life&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section addresses the common perception that the harsh conditions on other planets make them unlikely to harbor life. It presents evidence that some of the earliest and most basic forms of life on Earth originated in extreme environments, such as hydrothermal vents and acidic hot springs. These environments are considered extreme compared to typical ecosystems, but they support diverse populations of bacteria. The section highlights the importance of chemical reactions, such as chemosynthesis, in these environments, allowing organisms to utilize energy through reduced chemical compounds that fix carbon. The reducing nature of early Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere is discussed, along with the possibility that similar carbon-fixing compounds could occur on other planets with reducing atmospheres, potentially leading to the origin of extraterrestrial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;planetary-habitability-in-the-solar-system&#34;&gt;Planetary Habitability in the Solar System &lt;a href=&#34;#planetary-habitability-in-the-solar-system&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines the potential for life on various bodies within the Solar System. Mars, Europa, and Enceladus are identified as the most likely candidates besides Earth. Venus is discussed as a terrestrial planet that may have once been similar to Earth. The possibility of microbial life in Venus&amp;rsquo;s high-altitude clouds is mentioned. Mars is described as a cold, airless desert, but its past abundance of water is noted, raising the possibility of past or present life. The gas giants and ice giants are considered unlikely to harbor life, but the potential for life on moons orbiting these planets is explored. Europa&amp;rsquo;s subsurface ocean is highlighted, along with the subsurface oceans of Ganymede and Callisto. Enceladus&amp;rsquo;s eruption columns, which release water into space, are discussed, along with the detection of complex organic molecules, salts, hydrogen, and methane by the Cassini probe. Titan, with its liquid hydrocarbon bodies and subsurface water ocean, is also considered, but its cold temperatures are noted as a limiting factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scientific-search&#34;&gt;Scientific Search &lt;a href=&#34;#scientific-search&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces astrobiology as the science that searches for and studies life in the universe. It describes how astrobiology seeks to understand the origin, evolution, and requirements for the continuous existence of life, using the combined perspectives of various scientific disciplines. The scientific search for extraterrestrial life is being carried out both directly and indirectly. The number of identified exoplanets is mentioned, along with the potential for other planets and moons in the Solar System to host primitive life. The section also mentions the reported status of studies considering the possible detection of lifeforms on Venus and Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;search-for-basic-life&#34;&gt;Search for Basic Life &lt;a href=&#34;#search-for-basic-life&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the search for biosignatures within the Solar System and beyond. Scientists study planetary surfaces and examine meteorites for evidence of past or present life. The controversial report of nanobacteria-like structures in the ALH84001 meteorite is mentioned, along with the experiment on the Viking Mars landers that reported gas emissions from heated Martian soil samples. The section also discusses the NASA scientists who claimed to have found evidence of extraterrestrial life on Mars based on methane signatures. The launch of the Mars Science Laboratory and the Curiosity rover&amp;rsquo;s mission to assess past and present habitability on Mars are highlighted. The catalog of microorganisms being compiled by scientists at Cornell University to aid in the search for similar organisms on exoplanets is mentioned. The discovery of adenine, guanine, hypoxanthine, and xanthine in meteorites found on Antarctica is discussed, suggesting that organic molecules may be generated within asteroids and comets. The detection of glycolaldehyde, a sugar molecule needed to form RNA, in a distant star system is also highlighted. The section concludes with the discovery of hydrogen cyanide and other organic molecules in the plumes of Enceladus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligences&#34;&gt;Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligences &lt;a href=&#34;#search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligences&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section shifts the focus to the search for extraterrestrial intelligence. It discusses the concept of technosignatures, which are effects on a planet that may not be caused by natural causes. The three main types of technosignatures considered are interstellar communications, effects on the atmosphere, and planetary-sized structures such as Dyson spheres. Organizations such as the SETI Institute search for potential forms of communication, such as radio waves and laser pulses. The challenges of distinguishing between natural and artificial signals are highlighted, along with the potential use of artificial intelligence in this search. The section also discusses the potential for detecting atmospheric technosignatures, such as nitrogen dioxide, chlorofluorocarbons, and light pollution. The Kardashev scale is introduced, along with the possibility of detecting Dyson spheres through excess infrared radiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;extrasolar-planets&#34;&gt;Extrasolar Planets &lt;a href=&#34;#extrasolar-planets&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the search for extrasolar planets that may be conducive to life. Astronomers narrow the search to terrestrial planets within the habitable zones of their stars. The number of discovered exoplanets is mentioned, along with the range of sizes from terrestrial planets to gas giants. The Kepler space telescope&amp;rsquo;s detection of thousands of candidate planets is highlighted. The section notes that there is at least one planet on average per star, and that about 1 in 5 Sun-like stars have an Earth-sized planet in the habitable zone. The nearest known exoplanet, Proxima Centauri b, is mentioned. The least massive and most massive exoplanets known are also identified. The section concludes by emphasizing the importance of considering a wide range of factors in determining the suitability of a planet for hosting life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-and-cultural-impact&#34;&gt;History and Cultural Impact &lt;a href=&#34;#history-and-cultural-impact&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the historical and cultural context of the search for extraterrestrial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cosmic-pluralism&#34;&gt;Cosmic Pluralism &lt;a href=&#34;#cosmic-pluralism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section traces the historical development of the concept of extraterrestrial life, beginning with the ideas of ancient Greek scholars. The section highlights the shift from mythological explanations to more rational inquiries about the nature of the universe. The debate between atomists and Aristotelians is discussed, with Epicurus advocating for the existence of other worlds and Aristotle arguing against it. The concept of cosmic pluralism, the belief in numerous worlds beyond Earth, is introduced. The section also mentions the support for cosmic pluralism in Jain scriptures and by medieval Muslim writers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-modern-period&#34;&gt;Early Modern Period &lt;a href=&#34;#early-modern-period&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the Copernican Revolution and its impact on the concept of extraterrestrial life. Nicolaus Copernicus&amp;rsquo;s heliocentric model, Johannes Kepler&amp;rsquo;s discovery of elliptical orbits, and Galileo Galilei&amp;rsquo;s use of the telescope are highlighted as key developments. The section also mentions the resistance to the new ideas from the Catholic Church and Galileo&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrials&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial liquid water</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_77e58d4d298b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 22:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_77e58d4d298b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-liquid-water&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial Liquid Water &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-liquid-water&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extraterrestrial liquid water refers to water in its liquid state that occurs naturally outside of Earth. Its presence is considered a key prerequisite for life as we know it, making it a central focus in the search for extraterrestrial life. While many celestial bodies in the Solar System have a hydrosphere, Earth is the only one known to have stable bodies of liquid water on its surface. Confirmation of liquid water relies on absorption spectroscopy and geochemistry, which are effective for detecting water vapor and ice. However, detecting liquid water, especially subsurface water, is more challenging. Scientists use habitable zone theory, gravitational and tidal theory, planetary differentiation models, and radiometry to assess the potential for liquid water. Volcanic activity, fluvial features, and the presence of antifreeze agents also provide indirect evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;significance&#34;&gt;Significance &lt;a href=&#34;#significance&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Water is essential for the biochemistry of all known life forms. While lifeforms on Earth have adapted to varying levels of water scarcity, no known lifeform can survive entirely without it. Water is a simple molecule, consisting of oxygen and hydrogen, found throughout the solar system. However, it is only useful for life in its liquid state, which is less common than water vapor or ice. Because the first life forms on Earth originated in liquid water, the search for extraterrestrial liquid water is closely linked to the search for extraterrestrial life. Liquid water&amp;rsquo;s unique properties, such as becoming less dense when solidifying, are also beneficial for life, as they allow aquatic ecosystems to survive in cold environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;liquid-water-in-the-solar-system&#34;&gt;Liquid Water in the Solar System &lt;a href=&#34;#liquid-water-in-the-solar-system&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of December 2015, the confirmed liquid water outside Earth in the Solar System is estimated to be 25-50 times the volume of Earth&amp;rsquo;s water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mars&#34;&gt;Mars &lt;a href=&#34;#mars&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mars ocean theory suggests that nearly a third of the surface of Mars was once covered by water. Today, water on Mars exists primarily as ice and underground, with a small amount present as vapor in the atmosphere. Liquid water may occur transiently under specific conditions. The low atmospheric pressure and temperature prevent large bodies of standing liquid water from existing. Recurring slope lineae are thought to be caused by flows of brine. In July 2018, scientists from the Italian Space Agency detected a subglacial lake 1.5 kilometers below the southern polar ice cap, providing the first evidence of a stable body of liquid water on Mars. The water is thought to remain liquid due to the presence of magnesium and calcium perchlorates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;europa&#34;&gt;Europa &lt;a href=&#34;#europa&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists generally agree that a layer of liquid water exists beneath the surface of Europa, a moon of Jupiter. Heat from tidal flexing allows the subsurface ocean to remain liquid. The outer crust of solid ice is estimated to be 10-30 km thick, while the liquid ocean underneath may be about 100 km deep, resulting in a volume slightly more than twice that of Earth&amp;rsquo;s oceans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;enceladus&#34;&gt;Enceladus &lt;a href=&#34;#enceladus&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enceladus, a moon of Saturn, has geysers of water, confirmed by the &lt;em&gt;Cassini&lt;/em&gt; spacecraft. Gravimetric data confirmed a subsurface ocean. Evidence suggests the subsurface ocean is global in nature. The geysers also contain small amounts of salt, nitrogen, carbon dioxide, and volatile hydrocarbons. The melting of the ocean water and the geysers appear to be driven by tidal flux from Saturn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mimas&#34;&gt;Mimas &lt;a href=&#34;#mimas&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mimas, another moon of Saturn, was found by &lt;em&gt;Cassini&lt;/em&gt; to have a &amp;ldquo;rocking&amp;rdquo; motion whose amplitude could only be explained by a large subsurface ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ganymede&#34;&gt;Ganymede &lt;a href=&#34;#ganymede&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A subsurface saline ocean is theorized to exist on Ganymede, a moon of Jupiter, following observation by the Hubble Space Telescope in 2015. Patterns in auroral belts and rocking of the magnetic field suggest the presence of an ocean. It is estimated to be 100 km deep with the surface lying below a crust of 150 km of ice. The precise quantity of liquid water on Ganymede is highly uncertain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ceres&#34;&gt;Ceres &lt;a href=&#34;#ceres&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ceres appears to be differentiated into a rocky core and icy mantle, and may have a remnant internal ocean of liquid water under the layer of ice. The surface is probably a mixture of water ice and hydrated minerals. Emissions of water vapor have been detected from several regions of Ceres. Ceres also features a mountain called Ahuna Mons that is thought to be a cryovolcanic dome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ice-giants&#34;&gt;Ice Giants &lt;a href=&#34;#ice-giants&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ice giant planets Uranus and Neptune are thought to have a supercritical water ocean beneath their clouds, which accounts for about two-thirds of their total mass, most likely surrounding small rocky cores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pluto&#34;&gt;Pluto &lt;a href=&#34;#pluto&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June 2020, astronomers reported evidence that the dwarf planet Pluto may have had a subsurface ocean, and consequently may have been habitable, when it was first formed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;indicators-methods-of-detection-and-confirmation&#34;&gt;Indicators, Methods of Detection and Confirmation &lt;a href=&#34;#indicators-methods-of-detection-and-confirmation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most known extrasolar planetary systems appear to have very different compositions to the Solar System.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;spectroscopy&#34;&gt;Spectroscopy &lt;a href=&#34;#spectroscopy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liquid water has a distinct absorption spectroscopy signature compared to other states of water due to the state of its hydrogen bonds. Despite the confirmation of extraterrestrial water vapor and ice, the spectral signature of liquid water is yet to be confirmed outside of Earth. Seasonal flows on warm Martian slopes, though strongly suggestive of briny liquid water, have yet to indicate this in spectroscopic analysis. Water vapor has been confirmed in numerous objects via spectroscopy, though it does not by itself confirm the presence of liquid water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;magnetic-fields&#34;&gt;Magnetic Fields &lt;a href=&#34;#magnetic-fields&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Jovian moons Ganymede and Europa, the existence of a sub-ice ocean is inferred from the measurements of the magnetic field of Jupiter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;geological-indicators&#34;&gt;Geological Indicators &lt;a href=&#34;#geological-indicators&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas Gold posited that many Solar System bodies could potentially hold groundwater below the surface. Liquid water may exist in the Martian subsurface. Research suggests that in the past there was liquid water flowing on the surface, creating large areas similar to Earth&amp;rsquo;s oceans. &amp;ldquo;Chaos terrain&amp;rdquo;, a common feature on Europa&amp;rsquo;s surface, is interpreted as regions where the subsurface ocean has melted through the icy crust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;volcanic-observation&#34;&gt;Volcanic Observation &lt;a href=&#34;#volcanic-observation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geysers have been found on Enceladus, a moon of Saturn, and Europa, moon of Jupiter. These contain water vapour and could be indicators of liquid water deeper down. In June 2009, researchers noticed that Enceladus wobbled in a certain way as it orbited Saturn, indicating that the moon&amp;rsquo;s icy crust didn&amp;rsquo;t extend all the way to its core — instead, it rested on a global ocean. On 3 April 2014, NASA reported that evidence for a large underground ocean of liquid water on Enceladus had been found by the &lt;em&gt;Cassini&lt;/em&gt; spacecraft. Emissions of water vapor have been detected from several regions of the dwarf planet Ceres, combined with evidence of ongoing cryovalcanic activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gravitational-evidence&#34;&gt;Gravitational Evidence &lt;a href=&#34;#gravitational-evidence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists used gravitational measurements from the &lt;em&gt;Cassini&lt;/em&gt; spacecraft to confirm a water ocean under the crust of Enceladus. Such tidal models have been used as theories for water layers in other Solar System moons. Anomalies in the orbital libration of Saturn&amp;rsquo;s moon Mimas combined with models of tidal mechanics led scientists in 2022 to propose that it harbours an internal ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ground-penetrating-radio&#34;&gt;Ground Penetrating Radio &lt;a href=&#34;#ground-penetrating-radio&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists have detected liquid water using radio signals. The radio detection and ranging (RADAR) instrument of the &lt;em&gt;Cassini&lt;/em&gt; probe was used to detect the existence of a layer of liquid water and ammonia beneath the surface of Saturn&amp;rsquo;s moon Titan. Ground penetrating radar and dielectric permittivity data from the MARSIS instrument on Mars Express indicates a 20-kilometer-wide stable body of briny liquid water in the Planum Australe region of planet Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;density-calculation&#34;&gt;Density Calculation &lt;a href=&#34;#density-calculation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planetary scientists can use calculations of density to determine the composition of planets and their potential to possess liquid water. Models of Saturn&amp;rsquo;s moon Titan density indicate the presence of a subsurface ocean layer. Similar density estimations are strong indicators of an subsurface ocean on Enceladus. GJ 1214 b was the second exoplanet to have an established mass and radius less than those of the giant Solar System planets. Its low density indicated that it is likely a mix of rock and water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;models-of-radioactive-decay&#34;&gt;Models of Radioactive Decay &lt;a href=&#34;#models-of-radioactive-decay&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Models of heat retention and heating via radioactive decay in smaller icy Solar System bodies suggest that Rhea, Titania, Oberon, Triton, Pluto, Eris, Sedna, and Orcus may have oceans underneath solid icy crusts approximately 100 km thick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;internal-differentiation-models&#34;&gt;Internal Differentiation Models &lt;a href=&#34;#internal-differentiation-models&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Models of Solar System objects indicate the presence of liquid water in their internal differentiation. Some models of the dwarf planet Ceres indicate the possibility of a wet interior layer. A global layer of liquid water thick enough to decouple the crust from the mantle is thought to be present on Titan, Europa and, with less certainty, Callisto, Ganymede and Triton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;habitable-zone&#34;&gt;Habitable Zone &lt;a href=&#34;#habitable-zone&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A planet&amp;rsquo;s orbit in the circumstellar habitable zone is a popular method used to predict its potential for surface water at its surface. Habitable zone theory has put forward several extrasolar candidates for liquid water. The Gliese 581 planetary system contains multiple planets that may be candidates for surface water, including Gliese 581c, Gliese 581d, and Gliese 581e. Gliese 667 C has three of them are in the habitable zone including Gliese 667 Cc is estimated to have surface temperatures similar to Earth and a strong chance of liquid water. Kepler-22b one of the first 54 candidates found by the Kepler telescope and reported is 2.4 times the size of the Earth, with an estimated temperature of 22 °C. It is described as having the potential for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_liquid_water&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_liquid_water&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kepler space telescope</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a440bb8d510b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 08:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a440bb8d510b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;kepler&#34;&gt;Kepler &lt;a href=&#34;#kepler&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kepler space telescope, a NASA mission from 2009 to 2018, was designed to discover Earth-sized exoplanets. Named after astronomer Johannes Kepler, it operated in a heliocentric orbit. The mission ended when its reaction control system fuel was depleted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mission-type&#34;&gt;Mission type &lt;a href=&#34;#mission-type&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kepler mission was a space telescope mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;operator&#34;&gt;Operator &lt;a href=&#34;#operator&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA and the Laboratory for Atmospheric and Space Physics (LASP) operated the Kepler mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cospar-id&#34;&gt;COSPAR ID &lt;a href=&#34;#cospar-id&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The COSPAR ID for Kepler is 2009-011A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;satcat-no&#34;&gt;SATCAT no. &lt;a href=&#34;#satcat-no&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SATCAT number for Kepler is 34380.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;website&#34;&gt;Website &lt;a href=&#34;#website&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The official website for the Kepler mission is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nasa.gov/kepler&#34;&gt;www.nasa.gov/kepler&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mission-duration&#34;&gt;Mission duration &lt;a href=&#34;#mission-duration&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kepler mission was initially planned for 3.5 years but ultimately lasted 9 years, 7 months, and 23 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;spacecraft-properties&#34;&gt;Spacecraft properties &lt;a href=&#34;#spacecraft-properties&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;manufacturer&#34;&gt;Manufacturer &lt;a href=&#34;#manufacturer&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ball Aerospace &amp;amp; Technologies manufactured the Kepler spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;launch-mass&#34;&gt;Launch mass &lt;a href=&#34;#launch-mass&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch mass of the Kepler spacecraft was 1,052.4 kg (2,320 lb).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dry-mass&#34;&gt;Dry mass &lt;a href=&#34;#dry-mass&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dry mass of the Kepler spacecraft was 1,040.7 kg (2,294 lb).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;payload-mass&#34;&gt;Payload mass &lt;a href=&#34;#payload-mass&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The payload mass of the Kepler spacecraft was 478 kg (1,054 lb).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dimensions&#34;&gt;Dimensions &lt;a href=&#34;#dimensions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kepler spacecraft&amp;rsquo;s dimensions were 4.7 m × 2.7 m (15.4 ft × 8.9 ft).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;power&#34;&gt;Power &lt;a href=&#34;#power&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kepler spacecraft had a power of 1100 watts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;start-of-mission&#34;&gt;Start of mission &lt;a href=&#34;#start-of-mission&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;launch-date&#34;&gt;Launch date &lt;a href=&#34;#launch-date&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kepler was launched on March 7, 2009, at 03:49:57 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rocket&#34;&gt;Rocket &lt;a href=&#34;#rocket&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Delta II (7925-10L) rocket was used to launch Kepler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;launch-site&#34;&gt;Launch site &lt;a href=&#34;#launch-site&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch site was Cape Canaveral Air Force Station SLC-17B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;contractor&#34;&gt;Contractor &lt;a href=&#34;#contractor&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Launch Alliance was the contractor for the launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;entered-service&#34;&gt;Entered service &lt;a href=&#34;#entered-service&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kepler entered service on May 12, 2009, at 09:01 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;end-of-mission&#34;&gt;End of mission &lt;a href=&#34;#end-of-mission&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;deactivated&#34;&gt;Deactivated &lt;a href=&#34;#deactivated&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kepler was deactivated on November 15, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;orbital-parameters&#34;&gt;Orbital parameters &lt;a href=&#34;#orbital-parameters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reference-system&#34;&gt;Reference system &lt;a href=&#34;#reference-system&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reference system for Kepler&amp;rsquo;s orbit is heliocentric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;regime&#34;&gt;Regime &lt;a href=&#34;#regime&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kepler&amp;rsquo;s orbital regime was Earth-trailing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;semi-major-axis&#34;&gt;Semi-major axis &lt;a href=&#34;#semi-major-axis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The semi-major axis of Kepler&amp;rsquo;s orbit was 1.0133 AU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;eccentricity&#34;&gt;Eccentricity &lt;a href=&#34;#eccentricity&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eccentricity of Kepler&amp;rsquo;s orbit was 0.036116.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;perihelion-altitude&#34;&gt;Perihelion altitude &lt;a href=&#34;#perihelion-altitude&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The perihelion altitude of Kepler&amp;rsquo;s orbit was 0.97671 AU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aphelion-altitude&#34;&gt;Aphelion altitude &lt;a href=&#34;#aphelion-altitude&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aphelion altitude of Kepler&amp;rsquo;s orbit was 1.0499 AU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;inclination&#34;&gt;Inclination &lt;a href=&#34;#inclination&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inclination of Kepler&amp;rsquo;s orbit was 0.4474 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;period&#34;&gt;Period &lt;a href=&#34;#period&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The orbital period of Kepler was 372.57 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;argument-of-perihelion&#34;&gt;Argument of perihelion &lt;a href=&#34;#argument-of-perihelion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The argument of perihelion of Kepler&amp;rsquo;s orbit was 294.04 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mean-anomaly&#34;&gt;Mean anomaly &lt;a href=&#34;#mean-anomaly&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mean anomaly of Kepler&amp;rsquo;s orbit was 311.67 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mean-motion&#34;&gt;Mean motion &lt;a href=&#34;#mean-motion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mean motion of Kepler&amp;rsquo;s orbit was 0.96626 deg/day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;epoch&#34;&gt;Epoch &lt;a href=&#34;#epoch&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The epoch for Kepler&amp;rsquo;s orbital parameters was January 1, 2018 (J2000: 2458119.5).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-telescope&#34;&gt;Main telescope &lt;a href=&#34;#main-telescope&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type &lt;a href=&#34;#type&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kepler telescope was a Schmidt camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;diameter&#34;&gt;Diameter &lt;a href=&#34;#diameter&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diameter of the Kepler telescope was 0.95 m (3.1 ft).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;collecting-area&#34;&gt;Collecting area &lt;a href=&#34;#collecting-area&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The collecting area of the Kepler telescope was 0.708 m2 (7.62 sq ft).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;wavelengths&#34;&gt;Wavelengths &lt;a href=&#34;#wavelengths&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kepler telescope operated at wavelengths of 430–890 nm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transponders&#34;&gt;Transponders &lt;a href=&#34;#transponders&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bandwidth&#34;&gt;Bandwidth &lt;a href=&#34;#bandwidth&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kepler&amp;rsquo;s bandwidth was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X band up: 7.8 bit/s – 2 kbit/s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X band down: 10 bit/s – 16 kbit/s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ka band down: Up to 4.3 Mbit/s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;discovery-program&#34;&gt;Discovery program &lt;a href=&#34;#discovery-program&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kepler is part of the Discovery Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pre-launch-development&#34;&gt;Pre-launch development &lt;a href=&#34;#pre-launch-development&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kepler space telescope was part of NASA&amp;rsquo;s Discovery Program. The Jet Propulsion Laboratory managed construction and initial operation, while Ball Aerospace developed the flight system. Budget cuts and consolidation at NASA delayed the launch. The high-gain antenna design was changed to reduce cost and complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;post-launch&#34;&gt;Post launch &lt;a href=&#34;#post-launch&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ames Research Center managed ground system development, mission operations, and data analysis. The initial mission lifetime was 3.5 years, but noise in the data required more time. Reaction wheel failures in 2012 and 2013 threatened the mission. NASA sought alternative mission plans, leading to the K2 &amp;ldquo;Second Light&amp;rdquo; proposal. By 2015, Kepler had found over 1,000 confirmed exoplanets and thousands of candidates. Astronomers estimated billions of rocky, Earth-sized exoplanets in habitable zones. NASA announced the 1,000th confirmed exoplanet in 2015. In 2016, 1,284 new exoplanets were verified. Kepler data also helped study supernovae. The mission ended on October 30, 2018, after running out of fuel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;spacecraft-design&#34;&gt;Spacecraft design &lt;a href=&#34;#spacecraft-design&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kepler telescope had a mass of 1,039 kg and used a Schmidt camera with a 0.95-meter corrector plate and a 1.4-meter primary mirror. It had a 115 deg2 field of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;camera&#34;&gt;Camera &lt;a href=&#34;#camera&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The camera&amp;rsquo;s focal plane consisted of forty-two 50 × 25 mm CCDs with a total resolution of 94.6 megapixels. The CCDs were read out every 6.5 seconds and co-added on board. Data from selected pixels was requantized, compressed, and stored in a 16 gigabyte solid-state recorder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;primary-mirror&#34;&gt;Primary mirror &lt;a href=&#34;#primary-mirror&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary mirror was 1.4 meters in diameter, made by Corning using ultra-low expansion (ULE) glass. It had a nine-layer silver coating to enhance reflection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;photometric-performance&#34;&gt;Photometric performance &lt;a href=&#34;#photometric-performance&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kepler&amp;rsquo;s photometric performance was good but fell short of design goals. The objective was 20 ppm CDPP for a magnitude 12 star for a 6.5-hour integration. The median obtained accuracy was 29 ppm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;orbit-and-orientation&#34;&gt;Orbit and orientation &lt;a href=&#34;#orbit-and-orientation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kepler orbits the Sun in an Earth-trailing orbit with a period of 372.5 days. The photometer pointed to a field in the constellations Cygnus, Lyra, and Draco. Orientation was three-axis stabilized using fine-guidance sensors and reaction wheels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;operations&#34;&gt;Operations &lt;a href=&#34;#operations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Laboratory for Atmospheric and Space Physics (LASP) operated Kepler from Boulder, Colorado. The spacecraft&amp;rsquo;s solar array was rotated at solstices and equinoxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;communications&#34;&gt;Communications &lt;a href=&#34;#communications&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA contacted Kepler using the X band communication link. Scientific data was downloaded monthly using the Ka band link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;data-management&#34;&gt;Data management &lt;a href=&#34;#data-management&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Science data was processed by the Kepler Data Management Center (DMC) at the Space Telescope Science Institute and the Science Operations Center (SOC) at NASA Ames Research Center. Calibrated data products and scientific results were archived and distributed to astronomers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;reaction-wheel-failures&#34;&gt;Reaction wheel failures &lt;a href=&#34;#reaction-wheel-failures&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reaction wheel failures in 2012 and 2013 were traced to pitting caused by arcing between steel ball bearings, triggered by coronal mass ejections (CMEs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;operational-timeline&#34;&gt;Operational timeline &lt;a href=&#34;#operational-timeline&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kepler observatory launched on March 7, 2009, aboard a Delta II rocket from Cape Canaveral Air Force Station. The telescope cover was jettisoned on April 7, 2009. The focus was optimized in April 2009. Kepler began its search for planets on May 13, 2009. The first science data was sent to Earth on June 19, 2009. Safe mode events occurred in June and July 2009 due to a processor reset. A low voltage power supply was identified as the cause. In January 2010, a problem occurred with focal plane MOD-3 module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;field-of-view&#34;&gt;Field of view &lt;a href=&#34;#field-of-view&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kepler had a fixed field of view (FOV) in the constellations Cygnus, Lyra, and Draco, covering 115 square degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;objectives-and-methods&#34;&gt;Objectives and methods &lt;a href=&#34;#objectives-and-methods&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kepler&amp;rsquo;s objective was to explore the structure and diversity of planetary systems. It aimed to determine the number of Earth-size planets in or near habitable zones, the range of orbit sizes and shapes, the number of planets in multiple-star systems, and the properties of stars with planetary systems. The transit method was used to detect planets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;planet-finding-process&#34;&gt;Planet finding process &lt;a href=&#34;#planet-finding-process&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;finding-planet-candidates&#34;&gt;Finding planet candidates &lt;a href=&#34;#finding-planet-candidates&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kepler collected data, constructed light curves, and used software&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kepler_(spacecraft)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kepler_(spacecraft)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial (TV program)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6ae4a656d588/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6ae4a656d588/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-tv-program&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial (TV program) &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-tv-program&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry details a British-American two-part television documentary miniseries, also known as &lt;em&gt;Alien Worlds&lt;/em&gt; in the UK, which aired in 2005. The program, produced by Big Wave Productions Ltd., explores the hypothetical evolution of alien life on extrasolar planets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;series-concept-and-scientific-basis&#34;&gt;Series concept and scientific basis &lt;a href=&#34;#series-concept-and-scientific-basis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentary speculates about life on extrasolar planets, prompted by the discovery of such planets starting in 1989. It highlights the importance of the habitable zone, where temperatures allow liquid water to exist. The program mentions exoplanets Gliese 667 Cc and Gliese 581g (disputed) as examples, noting the challenges in detecting smaller, terrestrial planets. The cancellation of NASA&amp;rsquo;s Terrestrial Planet Finder (TPF) project is discussed, along with the shift in focus towards red dwarf stars and binary systems as potential locations for life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episode-1-aurelia&#34;&gt;Episode 1: Aurelia &lt;a href=&#34;#episode-1-aurelia&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This episode focuses on Aurelia, a hypothetical Earth-sized extrasolar planet orbiting a red dwarf star.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;planetary-concept&#34;&gt;Planetary concept &lt;a href=&#34;#planetary-concept&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientists theorize that red dwarf stars, despite being dimmer, offer long lifespans suitable for life evolution. The close proximity required for habitability around a red dwarf would likely result in tidal locking. The program challenges traditional assumptions about tidally locked planets, suggesting they can retain an atmosphere, albeit with unusual characteristics. Aurelia would lack seasons and a day/night cycle, with one side in perpetual darkness and the other experiencing a constant hurricane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lifeforms-of-aurelia&#34;&gt;Lifeforms of Aurelia &lt;a href=&#34;#lifeforms-of-aurelia&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The episode speculates on potential lifeforms, assuming carbon-based biology. A plant-like creature called a Stinger Fan is presented as the primary autotroph, with six-legged, beaver-like Mudpods feeding on them. Gulphogs, large, emu-like predators, hunt the Mudpods. Hysteria, tiny, orange creatures similar to tadpoles and piranhas, can form super-organisms to paralyze and consume other animals. All organisms have adaptations to detect and avoid deadly solar flares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episode-2-blue-moon&#34;&gt;Episode 2: Blue Moon &lt;a href=&#34;#episode-2-blue-moon&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This episode explores the Blue Moon, a fictional moon orbiting a gas giant in a binary star system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;planetary-concept-1&#34;&gt;Planetary concept &lt;a href=&#34;#planetary-concept-1&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Blue Moon is covered in water and has a dense atmosphere, allowing for the evolution of enormous flying creatures. It orbits a Water Cloud Jovian planet in a binary star system. The moon&amp;rsquo;s thick atmosphere maintains constant temperatures, and a greenish haze is present due to floating moss and algae. The denser atmosphere allows for massive airborne creatures like Skywhales, which evolved from sea-going animals. High oxygen levels (30%) create a risk of spontaneous combustion during lightning storms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lifeforms-of-the-blue-moon&#34;&gt;Lifeforms of the Blue Moon &lt;a href=&#34;#lifeforms-of-the-blue-moon&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skywhales are preyed upon by insect-like Caped Stalkers, colony-living predators with specialized tasks. Giant Kites, parasol-like grazers, also inhabit the skies. The land is dominated by pagoda trees and balloon plants. The pagoda trees interconnect to reach great heights, collecting rainwater in their hollow leaves. Balloon plants release hydrogen-filled seeds for dispersal. The forest floor features a bioluminescent ecosystem with fungi and other creatures. Mass wildfires pose a threat to the Blue Moon&amp;rsquo;s ecosystem, with balloon plants exploding and releasing seeds during fires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;home-video-releases&#34;&gt;Home video releases &lt;a href=&#34;#home-video-releases&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Channel 4 released a DVD of the documentary in January 2005.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_(TV_program)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_(TV_program)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darwin (spacecraft)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_679d3f288d30/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 02:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_679d3f288d30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;darwin&#34;&gt;Darwin &lt;a href=&#34;#darwin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darwin was a proposed ESA Cornerstone mission involving a constellation of spacecraft designed to detect Earth-like planets orbiting nearby stars and search for evidence of life. The most recent design featured three free-flying space telescopes redirecting light to a fourth spacecraft containing beam combiners, spectrometers, and cameras. An earlier design included six 1.5-meter telescopes, a beam combiner, and a separate power and communications spacecraft. The study of this mission ended in 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points&lt;/strong&gt;: Detection of Earth-like planets and search for extraterrestrial life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operator&lt;/strong&gt;: ESA (European Space Agency)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: Sun-Earth L2 Lagrangian point in a Halo orbit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Major Events&lt;/strong&gt;: Study ended in 2007 with no further activities planned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;concept&#34;&gt;Concept &lt;a href=&#34;#concept&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The space telescopes were designed to observe in the infrared spectrum. This region was chosen because the difference in brightness between an Earth-like planet and its star is less pronounced in the infrared compared to the visible spectrum. The spacecraft components in the optical path would need to be passively cooled to 40 kelvins for infrared observations. The planet search would have used a nulling interferometer configuration to cancel out light from the central star, allowing for the detection of orbiting planets. If a suitable planet was detected, a detailed study of its atmosphere would be conducted by analyzing its infrared spectrum for evidence of life, such as the presence of oxygen and water vapor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points&lt;/strong&gt;: Infrared observation, nulling interferometer, atmospheric analysis for biosignatures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important People&lt;/strong&gt;: Mention of a 2000 ESA bulletin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Major Events&lt;/strong&gt;: Design considerations for infrared observations and planet detection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;candidate-planets&#34;&gt;Candidate planets &lt;a href=&#34;#candidate-planets&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planet Gliese 581 d, discovered in 2007, was considered a good candidate for the Darwin project because it orbits within the habitable zone of its star, potentially supporting life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points&lt;/strong&gt;: Gliese 581 d as a potential target for observation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Major Events&lt;/strong&gt;: Discovery of Gliese 581 d in 2007.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;similar-initiatives&#34;&gt;Similar initiatives &lt;a href=&#34;#similar-initiatives&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA&amp;rsquo;s Terrestrial Planet Finder (TPF) mission was similar in concept to Darwin. However, the TPF project was deferred indefinitely in 2006 and later cancelled in 2011. Antoine Labeyrie proposed a larger space-based astronomical interferometer called the Hypertelescope, which would be more expensive and complex than Darwin and TPF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points&lt;/strong&gt;: Comparison to NASA&amp;rsquo;s Terrestrial Planet Finder and the Hypertelescope project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important People&lt;/strong&gt;: Antoine Labeyrie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Major Events&lt;/strong&gt;: Deferral and cancellation of NASA&amp;rsquo;s Terrestrial Planet Finder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Darwin_(spacecraft)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Darwin_(spacecraft)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
