<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Channeling on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/channeling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Channeling on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 11:32:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/channeling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ashtar (extraterrestrial being)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f573308dd64c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 11:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f573308dd64c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ashtar-extraterrestrial-being&#34;&gt;Ashtar (Extraterrestrial Being) &lt;a href=&#34;#ashtar-extraterrestrial-being&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry focuses on Ashtar, an alleged extraterrestrial being or group of beings, primarily within the context of ufology and UFO religions. It notes the &amp;ldquo;unbalanced&amp;rdquo; tag, indicating potential bias in viewpoints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;folklore&#34;&gt;Folklore &lt;a href=&#34;#folklore&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section identifies the subject as belonging to the realm of ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-attested&#34;&gt;First Attested &lt;a href=&#34;#first-attested&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first recorded claim of contact with Ashtar dates back to 1952.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-names&#34;&gt;Other Name(s) &lt;a href=&#34;#other-names&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ashtar is also known by variations of the name, including Ashtar Sheran, Captain Ashtar, Commander Ashtar, and Lord Ashtar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;country&#34;&gt;Country &lt;a href=&#34;#country&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial claims and development of the Ashtar figure originated in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ashtar&#34;&gt;Ashtar &lt;a href=&#34;#ashtar&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces Ashtar as an alleged extraterrestrial being or group of beings that some people claim to have channeled. It mentions George Van Tassel as the first person to claim contact with Ashtar in 1952. It also notes that after Van Tassel&amp;rsquo;s initial claims, many other mediums began to claim contact, often presenting conflicting messages. The failure of predictions made through these channels, such as flourishing civilizations on other planets and imminent landings of spaceships, is also mentioned. Ashtar&amp;rsquo;s common depiction as a humanoid with blond hair and European features is noted, linking him to the Nordic alien archetype. The Ashtar movement is studied as a prominent form of UFO religion, with the Czech Universe People being an example of a religion that venerates Ashtar alongside figures like Jesus and Krishna.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces the historical context of the Ashtar figure within the broader history of UFO religions and esoteric teachings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the background of Ashtar within the context of UFO religions and the reappearance of &amp;ldquo;Ascended Masters&amp;rdquo; in spacesuits. It traces the concept back to Theosophy and Helena Blavatsky&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Secret Doctrine&lt;/em&gt;, where &amp;ldquo;ashtar-vidya&amp;rdquo; refers to advanced warfare technology in the &lt;em&gt;Mahabharata&lt;/em&gt;. George Van Tassel&amp;rsquo;s role in propagating the contactee movement is highlighted, particularly his establishment of a UFO Center at Giant Rock, California, which became a prominent meeting place. Van Tassel&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Ministry of Universal Wisdom,&amp;rdquo; founded in 1953, is mentioned as a key organization for investigating UFO phenomena and interviewing contactees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;purported-contact-with-van-tassel&#34;&gt;Purported contact with Van Tassel &lt;a href=&#34;#purported-contact-with-van-tassel&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details George Van Tassel&amp;rsquo;s claims of telepathic communication with Ashtar starting in 1952. Van Tassel interpreted the Bible in terms of extraterrestrial intervention and claimed Jesus was a being from space. He taught that humans could tap into the &amp;ldquo;Universal Mind of God&amp;rdquo; and receive messages from Ashtar and deceased individuals like Nikola Tesla. From Tesla, he claimed to receive instructions to build the &amp;ldquo;Integratron&amp;rdquo; machine. Van Tassel&amp;rsquo;s early messages from Ashtar focused on apocalyptic concerns regarding the hydrogen bomb, with Ashtar entering the Solar System as Commander in Chief of the Ashtar Galactic Command to warn humanity. The messages claimed the space command was helping humanity and that Ashtar provided messages for the U.S. government. Van Tassel claimed his method of communication was a new form of telepathy utilizing advanced alien technology, rather than traditional spiritual mediumship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;giant-rock-space-conventions&#34;&gt;Giant Rock Space Conventions &lt;a href=&#34;#giant-rock-space-conventions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the weekly channeling sessions held by Van Tassel at Giant Rock, which helped coalesce the contactee subculture. These gatherings led to the annual Giant Rock Spacecraft Convention, which began in 1953 and continued for at least 24 years. In 1959, up to 11,000 people attended these conventions and heard channeled messages claiming to come from space. Most of the well-known UFO contactees attended as speakers and channelers. J. Gordon Melton notes that almost all of the 1950s contactees became involved in the ecumenical structures founded by Van Tassel or Gabriel Green. Most of the early messages Van Tassel claimed to have received from Ashtar were first presented to the public at these events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ashtar-command&#34;&gt;Ashtar Command &lt;a href=&#34;#ashtar-command&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the appropriation of the &amp;ldquo;Ashtar Command&amp;rdquo; concept by other contactees and channelers, based on Van Tassel&amp;rsquo;s Ashtar figure. Robert Short (AKA Bill Rose), editor of &lt;em&gt;Interplanetary News Digest&lt;/em&gt;, popularized the messages but broke away from Van Tassel to form his own group called &amp;ldquo;Ashtar Command.&amp;rdquo; By the mid-1950s, the concept of Ashtar and a galactic law enforcement agency preparing to rescue humanity had become well-established, including channelers like Elouise Moeller and Adelaide J. Brown. The public failure of predictions had a negative impact on the movement due to the lack of a central authority. Dozens of Ashtar channelers presented conflicting messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;development-into-spiritual-religion-1990s-onward&#34;&gt;Development into spiritual religion (1990s onward) &lt;a href=&#34;#development-into-spiritual-religion-1990s-onward&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explains the evolution of the Ashtar message from an early contact account to a more spiritual message, with Ashtar taking on the role of an Ascended Master. The Ashtar Command evolved into a diffuse New Age Spiritualist milieu, with teachings varying immensely. Tuella founded Guardian Action International. Andreas Grunschloss describes much of the Ashtar channeling as akin to cargo cults, blending spiritual ascension with new alien technologies. Millenarian concepts involved a transformation of human beings via these technologies, who would then return to Earth to enjoy a golden millennium. Later, with the failure of these prophecies, teachings were modified to include a less material and more spiritual emphasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1970s-broadcasts&#34;&gt;1970s broadcasts &lt;a href=&#34;#1970s-broadcasts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions a 1971 British radio talk show that received a strange call-in claiming to originate from outer space. It also discusses the 1977 Southern Television broadcast interruption, when a voice calling itself &amp;ldquo;Vrillon&amp;rdquo; of the Ashtar Galactic Command temporarily took over a television transmitter in southern England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1986-prediction-of-1994-apocalypse&#34;&gt;1986 prediction of 1994 apocalypse &lt;a href=&#34;#1986-prediction-of-1994-apocalypse&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details Yvonne Cole&amp;rsquo;s predictions, claiming to channel Ashtar messages from 1986, of the destruction of all Earth civilizations and the arrival of alien cultures in 1994. Cole claimed governments were working with extraterrestrials to prepare for contact, which would be broadcast through the global media and include a message from the Ashtar Command. Ashtar followers would be needed as advisors, ambassadors, and peacekeepers. These prophecies furthered the continued fracturing and disappointment within the movement when they failed to occur. Despite these failures, during the 1980s, a number of individuals began to claim contact with the Ashtar Command through channeling, and various small groups were formed to receive and disseminate the messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-1994-pioneer-voyage-meditations&#34;&gt;The 1994 Pioneer Voyage meditations &lt;a href=&#34;#the-1994-pioneer-voyage-meditations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes a 1994 event where a small group of Ashtar Command members claimed to have had a &amp;ldquo;lift-off experience,&amp;rdquo; being placed aboard &amp;ldquo;ships of Light&amp;rdquo; circling the planet. &amp;ldquo;The Galactic Fifth Fleet&amp;rdquo; used &amp;ldquo;physical vibrational transfer&amp;rdquo; to raise human consciousness to the &amp;ldquo;Light ships.&amp;rdquo; A second event was predicted for December 1994, involving over 250 people, which was declared to have &amp;ldquo;opened a portal to the AC (Ashtar Command) ships for ever.&amp;rdquo; Participants&amp;rsquo; vibrations were raised through an eight-step contemplative procedure, and the Pioneer Voyage would occur during meditation. This evoked &amp;ldquo;memory recall&amp;rdquo; from a core group of Ashtar Command members meeting in Australia, who began providing accounts of their &amp;ldquo;time aboard the ships.&amp;rdquo; The time on the ships was claimed to be extensive, even though the member&amp;rsquo;s meditation period was short. The events are claimed to be occurring on a spiritual or etheric dimension, not a physical one. The purpose of the lift-off is for the ascension of the human race, aided by large electronic grids deployed around the planet by the guardian ships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;developments-after-the-mid-1990s&#34;&gt;Developments after the mid-1990s &lt;a href=&#34;#developments-after-the-mid-1990s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses how, by the mid-1990s, channeling groups began using the Internet to promulgate their beliefs and unify the movement by establishing a single &amp;ldquo;authoritative&amp;rdquo; source for all Ashtar messages. This led to more prominence in the religious scene and significant membership. This cohesive response addressed the problem of conflicting, negative, and failed prophecies, enabling the Ashtar Command to produce a single Ashtar worldview. Individual channelers espousing messages which differed and continued to focus on themes such as the destruction of Earth, conspiracies, extraterrestrial mass evacuations, and general fear-mongering were declared invalid. These channelers had been deceived by negative space beings who had rebelled from the Ashtar Command. The new, more unified movement declared that in the future, no new channels would be accepted unless they operated on the &amp;ldquo;level of the soul.&amp;rdquo; Channeled messages from Ashtar would be accepted as valid by the new orthodoxy if they complied with criteria consisting of a set of twelve guidelines which outlined what the movement stood for and how Ashtar would interact with society. The millions of spaceships believed to be constantly in the vicinity of Earth would never interfere on the planet&amp;rsquo;s surface unless there was a serious problem such as a third world war or an &amp;ldquo;astrophysical catastrophe.&amp;rdquo; The emergent group was &amp;ldquo;noticeably more spiritually focused and less concerned with extraterrestrial spaceships and visitors.&amp;rdquo; Very little distinguished the new Ashtar Command from other theosophically influenced groups, except that in 1994 a distinctive component, the Pioneer Voyage, was incorporated into the Ashtar worldview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;credibility&#34;&gt;Credibility &lt;a href=&#34;#credibility&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section addresses the credibility of Ashtar claims, pointing out the failure of the July 1952 prediction channeled through Van Tassel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ashtar_(extraterrestrial_being)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ashtar_(extraterrestrial_being)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
