<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Levelland on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/levelland/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Levelland on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 20:13:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/levelland/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Levelland UFO case</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_98577a913d6b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 20:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_98577a913d6b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;levelland-ufo-case&#34;&gt;Levelland UFO Case &lt;a href=&#34;#levelland-ufo-case&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Levelland UFO case occurred on November 2–3, 1957, around Levelland, Texas. It is considered a notable UFO incident due to the number of witnesses. The US Air Force attributed the sightings to ball lightning or a severe electrical storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reports&#34;&gt;Reports &lt;a href=&#34;#reports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the evening of November 2, 1957, Pedro Saucedo and Joe Salaz reported a UFO sighting to the Levelland police department, claiming their truck&amp;rsquo;s engine died when a blue flash of light and a rocket-shaped object approached. Motorist Jim Wheeler reported a large, egg-shaped object blocking the road, causing his vehicle to stall. A married couple reported a bright flash of light that caused their headlights and radio to fail temporarily. Texas Technological College student Newell Wright encountered a 100-foot-long egg-shaped object that caused his car engine to sputter and die. Farmer Frank Williams reported a glowing object that caused his car&amp;rsquo;s lights and motor to stop. Ronald Martin and James Long also reported similar encounters with a brightly lit object. Sheriff Weir Clem saw a red object moving across the sky, and Fire Chief Ray Jones experienced vehicle malfunctions. The Levelland police department received a total of 15 UFO-related reports during the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;us-air-force-investigation&#34;&gt;U.S. Air Force Investigation &lt;a href=&#34;#us-air-force-investigation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Levelland sightings were investigated by Project Blue Book. An Air Force sergeant spent seven hours investigating, interviewing Saucedo, Wheeler, and Wright. The Air Force concluded that a severe electrical storm, possibly ball lightning or St. Elmo&amp;rsquo;s fire, caused the sightings and auto failures, blaming engine failures on wet electrical circuits. Donald H. Menzel agreed with the Air Force explanation, attributing the events to ball lightning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufologists&#34;&gt;Ufologists &lt;a href=&#34;#ufologists&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James E. McDonald and J. Allen Hynek disputed the Air Force&amp;rsquo;s explanation, arguing that there was no electrical storm. McDonald testified that ten vehicles were stopped independently within a short area and time. Hynek concurred initially but later recognized the lack of evidence that ball lightning could stop cars and put out headlights. Ufologists also noted that the Air Force investigator did not interview nine of the fifteen witnesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;media-coverage&#34;&gt;Media Coverage &lt;a href=&#34;#media-coverage&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2002, KDFW aired a report about the Levelland UFO case, interviewing Sheriff Weir Clem&amp;rsquo;s widow and friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lubbock Lights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of UFO sightings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lists books and publications for further reading on the Levelland UFO case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lists the references cited in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Levelland_UFO_case&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Levelland_UFO_case&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
