<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cattle Mutilation on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/cattle-mutilation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cattle Mutilation on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 18:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/cattle-mutilation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cattle mutilation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_ee1c97534fee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 18:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_ee1c97534fee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;cattle-mutilation&#34;&gt;Cattle Mutilation &lt;a href=&#34;#cattle-mutilation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cattle mutilation refers to the killing and mutilation of cattle and other animals under unusual and often bloodless circumstances. The phenomenon has been linked to paranormal and supernatural explanations, as well as more mundane causes. Mutilations often involve the removal of specific body parts such as ears, eyeballs, jaw flesh, tongues, lymph nodes, genitals, and rectums. Various explanations have been proposed, ranging from natural decomposition and predation to the involvement of cults, government agencies, cryptids like the chupacabra, and extraterrestrials. The United States has seen two independent federal investigations into these incidents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;early-history&#34;&gt;Early History &lt;a href=&#34;#early-history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The earliest documented cases of unexplained livestock deaths occurred in England in 1606, with reports of sheep being slaughtered and specific parts removed. Charles Fort collected accounts of similar mutilations in England during the late 19th and early 20th centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-snippy-horse-death-of-1967&#34;&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Snippy&amp;rdquo; Horse Death of 1967 &lt;a href=&#34;#the-snippy-horse-death-of-1967&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unexplained livestock deaths gained wider attention in 1967 with the case of &amp;ldquo;Snippy,&amp;rdquo; a horse found mutilated in Alamosa, Colorado. The Pueblo Chieftain published a story about the incident, noting the precise cuts and lack of blood at the scene. Agnes King and her son Harry discovered the body. This case was the first to link mutilations to extraterrestrial beings and UFOs. Wadsworth Ayer investigated for the Condon Committee and found no evidence of abnormal causes. Sheriff Ben Phillips suggested a lightning strike as the cause. Later press coverage mentioned the horse had been shot. Two students from Alamosa State College confessed to shooting the horse weeks after the case was publicized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;cattle-mutilations-19731980&#34;&gt;Cattle Mutilations 1973–1980 &lt;a href=&#34;#cattle-mutilations-19731980&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This period saw a surge in reported cattle mutilations across Kansas, Nebraska, Colorado, and New Mexico. In April 1973, sheriffs in Western Iowa reported unidentified helicopters involved in cattle and pig rustling. Similar rustling was reported in Missouri in August, with authorities warning farmers against firing on the helicopters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;1973-kansas-wave&#34;&gt;1973 Kansas Wave &lt;a href=&#34;#1973-kansas-wave&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In June 1973, Cloud County sheriff Fred Modlin warned the public about suspicious phone calls from someone posing as a USDA official. A series of butchered cows were found on farms near Munden, Kansas, with right ears removed. Local press speculated about a &amp;ldquo;Mad Dog&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;phantom&amp;rdquo; butcher. By December, law enforcement reported investigating 40 mutilations across Kansas and Nebraska, primarily near US Highway 81. State Senator Ross Doyen reported a mutilation on his ranch. The Kansas Brand Commissioner&amp;rsquo;s office attributed most deaths to natural causes, but Modlin disagreed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;1974-nebraska-wave&#34;&gt;1974 Nebraska Wave &lt;a href=&#34;#1974-nebraska-wave&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reports of mutilations continued in April 1974, with a Nebraska cow found mutilated and drained of blood. The North American Newspaper Alliance reported on the 1973 mutilations and helicopter sightings. In May, mutilations were reported in Mills County, Iowa, with coyotes suggested as the cause. By June, Lancaster County, Nebraska, reported mutilations. Custer County reported helicopter sightings and armed patrols. In August, an unidentified helicopter was spotted hovering above a field where a mutilated cow was later found near Agnew, Nebraska. Knox County Sheriff Herbert Thompson reported armed civilian patrols. Cloud County Attorney William Walsh suggested devil-worshiping cultists were responsible. State Sen. John Decamp called for a coordinated investigation. By late August, 25 mutilations were reported across five Nebraska counties. A rancher near Hartington apparently thwarted a mutilation in progress when he spotted a helicopter. Authorities cautioned the public against shooting at aircraft. In September, an autopsy revealed a supposedly-mutilated cow died of a bacterial infection. Over 50 law enforcement officials attended a meeting in Center, Nebraska, to discuss the mutilations. Three cases of alleged mutilations were reported in South Dakota. Newsweek became the first national outlet to cover the story. South Dakota Attorney General Kermit Sande reported mutilations in the state. UFO conspiracy theorists considered a link to flying saucers, but J. Allen Hynek denied any connection. In December, Minnesota reported several mutilations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;1975-colorado&#34;&gt;1975 Colorado &lt;a href=&#34;#1975-colorado&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1975, the Colorado Associated Press voted the mutilations as the state&amp;rsquo;s top story. Senator Floyd K. Haskell contacted the FBI for help, claiming 130 mutilations in Colorado and reports across nine states. A 1979 FBI report estimated 8,000 mutilations in Colorado, causing $1 million in damages. Donald E. Flickinger of the Michigan ATF investigated possible links to a &amp;ldquo;Hell-oriented biker gang.&amp;rdquo; The Colorado Bureau of Investigation opened an investigation under Carl Whiteside. The New York Times published a story examining cattle mutilations across 11 states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;1976-dulce-new-mexico&#34;&gt;1976 Dulce, New Mexico &lt;a href=&#34;#1976-dulce-new-mexico&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On June 13, 1976, Dulce rancher Manuel Gomez reported a mutilation to Officer Gabe Valdez of the New Mexico State Patrol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;1979-public-meeting&#34;&gt;1979 Public Meeting &lt;a href=&#34;#1979-public-meeting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On April 20, 1979, U.S. Attorney R. E. Thompson and US Senator Harrison Schmidt held a public meeting about cattle mutilations, attended by about 80 people. Paul Bennewitz reported seeing unidentified lights over Kirtland Air Force Base. In May 1979, Valdez reported finding two drugs in a mutilated bull, including Chlorpromazine (Thorazine). On June 14, 1981, investigators found a mutilated cow at the Gomez ranch with radar chaff nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;later-incidents&#34;&gt;Later Incidents &lt;a href=&#34;#later-incidents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many cases of mutilation have been reported worldwide since 1967, particularly in the Americas and Australia. South America has seen an estimated 3,500 incidents since 2002. Investigators believe many cases go unreported. In 1993, photographic evidence surfaced of a mutilated human corpse found near the Guarapiranga reservoir of São Paulo, Brazil, in 1988. Theories ranged from homicide to alien abduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;characteristics&#34;&gt;Characteristics &lt;a href=&#34;#characteristics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cattle deaths due to natural causes are common. Unusual cattle deaths are characterized by the absence of sex organs, udders, tongues, anus, rectum, and sometimes ears or eyes. Cuts are described as &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;surgical.&amp;rdquo; Some animals are reported to have been drained of blood with no sign of blood in the area. Howard Burgess stated that nearly 90 percent of mutilated cattle are between four and five years old. Strange marks or imprints have been found near the sites. In the &amp;ldquo;Snippy&amp;rdquo; case, there was an absence of tracks near the carcass. In Rio Arriba County, New Mexico, a &amp;ldquo;trail of suction cup-like impressions&amp;rdquo; was found leading from a mutilated cow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;laboratory-reports&#34;&gt;Laboratory Reports &lt;a href=&#34;#laboratory-reports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Laboratory reports on some mutilated animals have shown unusual levels of vitamins or minerals in tissue samples and the presence of chemicals not normally found in animals. In one case documented by New Mexico police and the FBI, an 11-month-old bull belonging to Manuel Gomez of Dulce, New Mexico, was found mutilated in 1978. The animal&amp;rsquo;s heart and liver were found to be abnormal. Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory detected &lt;em&gt;Clostridium&lt;/em&gt; bacteria in the heart. Liver samples were found to be devoid of copper and to contain high levels of zinc, potassium, and phosphorus. Blood samples were reported to be light pink and did not clot. The animal&amp;rsquo;s hide was unusually brittle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;helicopter-sightings&#34;&gt;Helicopter Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#helicopter-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On July 15, 1974, two unregistered helicopters reportedly opened fire on Robert Smith Jr. in Honey Creek, Iowa. In August 1974, residents reported seeing unidentified helicopters shining spotlights into fields where mutilated cows were later found. Know County Sheriff Herbert Thompson claimed helicopter sightings had become a nightly occurrence. By 1975, some ranchers formed armed vigilante groups. Authorities ran ads urging ranchers not to shoot at survey helicopters. The National Guard warned its helicopter pilots to fly at higher altitudes. In 1976, two Cache County, Utah, police officers reportedly confronted men in an unmarked U.S. Army helicopter. In 1979, three police officers in Dulce, New Mexico, reported a mysterious aircraft resembling a U.S. military helicopter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;official-investigations&#34;&gt;Official Investigations &lt;a href=&#34;#official-investigations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The New Mexico Livestock Board sought assistance from the Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory. Colorado Bureau of Investigation agents went undercover. Oklahoma convened a task force. Federal authorities launched a comprehensive investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bureau-of-alcohol-tobacco-and-firearms&#34;&gt;Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms &lt;a href=&#34;#bureau-of-alcohol-tobacco-and-firearms&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In January 1975, the Minnesota field office of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms (ATF) launched an investigation headed by Agent Donald Flickinger. Flickinger investigated possible connections between cults and cattle mutilation. He recorded unusual incidents and circumstantial evidence but found insufficient evidence of cult involvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;colorado-bureau-of-investigation&#34;&gt;Colorado Bureau of Investigation &lt;a href=&#34;#colorado-bureau-of-investigation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In May 1975, the Colorado Bureau of Investigation opened an investigation under the leadership of Carl Whiteside. 19 animals underwent necropsies at Colorado State University, but no conclusive results emerged. A $40,000 reward was offered. The US Bureau of Land Management grounded all helicopters in Eastern Colorado. By December, the CBI had investigated 203 reports of cattle mutilations. The CBI investigation was closed after Colorado mutilation reports dwindled in Summer 1976.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;new-mexico-state-police&#34;&gt;New Mexico State Police &lt;a href=&#34;#new-mexico-state-police&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On June 13, 1976, the New Mexico State Police began an investigation headed by Officer Gabe Valdez. Valdez solicited the assistance of retired Sandia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle_mutilation&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle_mutilation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
