<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Government on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/government/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Government on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 05:26:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/government/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial life</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_9c80ff0dfe5c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 05:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_9c80ff0dfe5c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-life&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial Life &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-life&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extraterrestrial life, also known as alien life, refers to life that originates from a world other than Earth. While no such life has been conclusively detected, it could range from simple prokaryotes to intelligent beings and civilizations. The science dedicated to studying extraterrestrial life is astrobiology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context &lt;a href=&#34;#context&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a framework for understanding the topic of life in the universe. It outlines various aspects, including planetary habitability within and outside the Solar System, and lists celestial bodies like Venus, Mars, Europa, Enceladus, and Titan as potential locations for life. It also mentions the habitability of binary star systems, natural satellites, neutron star systems, red dwarf systems, K-type, yellow dwarf, and F-type main-sequence star systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;likelihood-of-existence&#34;&gt;Likelihood of Existence &lt;a href=&#34;#likelihood-of-existence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the debate on whether extraterrestrial life is common or rare. It presents the argument for ubiquitous life, citing the size and age of the universe, the abundance of life&amp;rsquo;s chemical elements, and the universality of physical laws. Scientists like Carl Sagan and Stephen Hawking are mentioned as proponents of this view, which is rooted in the Copernican and mediocrity principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversely, the Rare Earth hypothesis suggests that life on Earth is due to a unique combination of factors, making extraterrestrial life, especially multicellular life, rare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Drake equation, devised by Frank Drake, is introduced as a probabilistic argument to estimate the number of communicative extraterrestrial civilizations in the Milky Way galaxy. The equation considers factors like the rate of star formation, the fraction of stars with planets, and the likelihood of life evolving intelligence and developing communication technology. However, the section notes the controversy surrounding the Drake equation due to the speculative nature of its variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fermi paradox, the apparent contradiction between the high probability of extraterrestrial civilizations and the lack of evidence for them, is also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;biochemical-basis&#34;&gt;Biochemical Basis &lt;a href=&#34;#biochemical-basis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the potential biochemical requirements for extraterrestrial life. It states that life requires an environment with non-equilibrium thermodynamics, such as energy from stars, volcanoes, or hydrothermal vents. Liquid water is considered essential as a solvent for biochemical reactions, although alternatives like ammonia or liquid hydrocarbons are mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The section also explores alternative chemical elements that could form the basis of life, such as silicon, while acknowledging carbon&amp;rsquo;s versatility. It discusses the potential for radically different biochemistries, the role of natural selection, and the likelihood of cell membranes. Simon Conway Morris is mentioned for his views on convergent evolution leading to similar lifeforms as on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;harsh-environmental-conditions-on-earth-harboring-life&#34;&gt;Harsh Environmental Conditions on Earth Harboring Life &lt;a href=&#34;#harsh-environmental-conditions-on-earth-harboring-life&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights that while conditions on other planets may seem too extreme to harbor life, some of the earliest life forms on Earth originated in extreme environments. Hydrothermal vents and acidic hot springs are mentioned as possible origins of life on Earth. These environments support chemosynthetic processes, allowing organisms to utilize energy through reduced chemical compounds that fix carbon. The section suggests that similar processes could occur on other planets with reducing atmospheres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;planetary-habitability-in-the-solar-system&#34;&gt;Planetary Habitability in the Solar System &lt;a href=&#34;#planetary-habitability-in-the-solar-system&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines the potential for life on various bodies within our Solar System. Besides Earth, Mars, Europa, and Enceladus are identified as the most likely candidates. Venus is discussed as a terrestrial planet that evolved differently from Earth. Mars is considered potentially habitable in the past, with the possibility of fossilized remains or surviving microbes underground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europa, Ganymede, and Callisto are mentioned as having subsurface oceans, with Europa being the most promising due to contact between its ocean and rocky surface. Enceladus is noted for its eruption columns releasing water into space, containing complex organic molecules, salts, and evidence of hydrothermal activity. Titan is unique for having liquid bodies of hydrocarbons on its surface, raising speculation about lifeforms with different biochemistry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scientific-search&#34;&gt;Scientific Search &lt;a href=&#34;#scientific-search&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces astrobiology as the science dedicated to searching for and studying life in the universe. It mentions the direct and indirect methods used, including the identification of thousands of exoplanets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;search-for-basic-life&#34;&gt;Search for Basic Life &lt;a href=&#34;#search-for-basic-life&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the search for biosignatures within the Solar System and beyond. It mentions claims of evidence for microbial life on Mars, including structures resembling nanobacteria in the ALH84001 meteorite. The Viking Mars landers&amp;rsquo; gas emission experiments are discussed, along with NASA&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Curiosity&lt;/em&gt; rover&amp;rsquo;s mission to assess past and present habitability on Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists at Cornell University are creating a catalog of microorganisms and their reactions to sunlight to aid in the search for similar organisms on exoplanets. The discovery of organic molecules in meteorites found in Antarctica is also mentioned, suggesting that building blocks of life may be generated within asteroids and comets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The detection of glycolaldehyde, a sugar molecule needed to form RNA, in a distant star system is highlighted as evidence that complex organic molecules may form in stellar systems prior to planet formation. The discovery of hydrogen cyanide in the plumes of Enceladus is also mentioned as a possible chemical essential for life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligences&#34;&gt;Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligences &lt;a href=&#34;#search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligences&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the search for extraterrestrial intelligence (SETI) through the detection of technosignatures, such as interstellar communications, atmospheric effects, and planetary-sized structures. Organizations like the SETI Institute are searching for radio waves and laser pulses. The use of artificial intelligence to analyze data is also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Potential technosignatures include nitrogen dioxide in the atmosphere, chlorofluorocarbons, and light pollution. The Kardashev scale is introduced, suggesting that advanced civilizations may consume energy directly from their local star, creating detectable infrared radiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;extrasolar-planets&#34;&gt;Extrasolar Planets &lt;a href=&#34;#extrasolar-planets&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the search for exoplanets that may be conducive to life, particularly terrestrial planets within habitable zones. It mentions the discovery of thousands of exoplanets, ranging in size from Earth-like to gas giants. The Kepler space telescope&amp;rsquo;s role in detecting candidate planets is highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The section notes that there is at least one planet on average per star, and about 1 in 5 Sun-like stars have an Earth-sized planet in the habitable zone. Proxima Centauri b is mentioned as the nearest known exoplanet. The study of planetary habitability considers various factors in determining a planet&amp;rsquo;s suitability for hosting life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-and-cultural-impact&#34;&gt;History and Cultural Impact &lt;a href=&#34;#history-and-cultural-impact&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the historical and cultural context of the extraterrestrial life debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cosmic-pluralism&#34;&gt;Cosmic Pluralism &lt;a href=&#34;#cosmic-pluralism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the philosophical belief in numerous worlds beyond Earth that might harbor life. It traces the concept back to ancient Greek thinkers like Anaximander, Epicurus, and Aristotle. Epicurus believed that other worlds with their own animals and plants should exist, while Aristotle thought Earth was the only planet in the universe. Medieval Muslim writers like Fakhr al-Din al-Razi and Muhammad al-Baqir are mentioned for supporting cosmic pluralism based on the Qur&amp;rsquo;an.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-modern-period&#34;&gt;Early Modern Period &lt;a href=&#34;#early-modern-period&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the shift in understanding the cosmos during the Copernican Revolution. Nicolaus Copernicus proposed that planets revolve around the sun, Johannes Kepler discovered that orbits were ellipses, and Galileo Galilei&amp;rsquo;s telescope provided further evidence. Giordano Bruno argued for an infinite universe with every star surrounded by its own planetary system. Isaac Newton&amp;rsquo;s theory of gravity further strengthened the heliocentric model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;19th-century&#34;&gt;19th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#19th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the increased speculation about life on Mars in the late 19th century, fueled by telescopic observations of apparent Martian canals. Percival Lowell published books proposing that the canals were the work of a long-gone civilization. Spectroscopic analysis by William Wallace Campbell showed that neither water nor oxygen was present in the Martian atmosphere. Louis Pasteur disproved the theory of spontaneous generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recent-history&#34;&gt;Recent History &lt;a href=&#34;#recent-history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the emergence of astrobiology as a science. It mentions the influence of science fiction on popular perception and the emergence of pseudosciences like ufology and the ancient astronauts hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lewis White Beck&amp;rsquo;s analysis of philosophical thought on extraterrestrial life is mentioned. The section notes that while no extraterrestrial life has been found, scientific reasons and technological advances suggest that it can exist elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frank Drake&amp;rsquo;s optimism about finding alien life is contrasted with Jacques Monod&amp;rsquo;s pessimism. Peter Ward and Donald Brownlee&amp;rsquo;s Rare Earth hypothesis is introduced, claiming that Earth-like life is rare in the universe. Stephen Hawking warned against contacting alien life forms, citing the potential for exploitation. Yuri Milner and the SETI Institute launched the Breakthrough Initiatives to expand efforts to search for extraterrestrial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;government-responses&#34;&gt;Government Responses &lt;a href=&#34;#government-responses&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses government policies related to extraterrestrial life. The 1967 Outer Space Treaty and the 1979 Moon Agreement define rules of planetary protection. COSPAR also provides guidelines for planetary protection. The United Nations Office for Outer Space Affairs discussed strategies for interacting with extraterrestrial life, but ended without conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA&amp;rsquo;s Office of Safety and Mission Assurance (OSMA) is mentioned for its mission to prevent backward contamination of Earth by extraterrestrial life. The Chinese government&amp;rsquo;s space program includes the search for extraterrestrial life. Dmitry Rogozin, head of the Russian space agency, stated that the search for extraterrestrial life is a main goal of deep space research. The French space agency (CNES) has an office for the study of &amp;ldquo;non-identified aero spatial phenomena&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-fiction&#34;&gt;In Fiction &lt;a href=&#34;#in-fiction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the portrayal of extraterrestrials in fiction. Charles Darwin&amp;rsquo;s theory of evolution influenced science fiction authors to create bizarre aliens distinct from humans. The Barney and Betty Hill incident, the first recorded claim of an alien abduction, influenced the grey alien archetype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_life&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO Report (U.S. Intelligence)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8ceb16d973cd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 04:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8ceb16d973cd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;preliminary-assessment-unidentified-aerial-phenomena&#34;&gt;Preliminary Assessment: Unidentified Aerial Phenomena &lt;a href=&#34;#preliminary-assessment-unidentified-aerial-phenomena&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document summarizes the Wikipedia article on the &amp;ldquo;Preliminary Assessment: Unidentified Aerial Phenomena,&amp;rdquo; also known as the UAP Report or the Pentagon UFO Report, published by the Office of the Director of National Intelligence on June 25, 2021. It covers the background, content, and aftermath of the report, which assessed information regarding unidentified aerial phenomena (UAPs), including unidentified flying objects (UFOs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the events leading up to the report&amp;rsquo;s release. The Senate Intelligence Committee mandated the Director of National Intelligence to collaborate with the Secretary of Defense on a report detailing government knowledge of UAPs, commonly known as UFOs. This mandate was included in Senate Report 116-233 accompanying the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021. The report was to include detailed analysis of data and intelligence gathered by the Office of Naval Intelligence, the Unidentified Aerial Phenomena Task Force (UAPTF), and the FBI. It also required a description of an interagency process for data collection and analysis and identification of potential national security threats. The mandate followed articles confirming the existence of the Advanced Aerospace Threat Identification Program, a Department of Defense program that began in 2007. The Department of Defense released three videos recorded by US Navy pilots, known as the Pentagon UFO videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;report&#34;&gt;Report &lt;a href=&#34;#report&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the content of the nine-page preliminary assessment released on June 25, 2021. The UAPTF focused on 144 observations of &amp;ldquo;unidentified aerial phenomena&amp;rdquo; by the U.S. Armed Forces, mostly from U.S. Navy personnel, from 2004 to 2021. The report found that the UAPTF was unable to identify causes of the observations found in 143 reports, with only one identified as &amp;ldquo;a large, deflating balloon&amp;rdquo;. Eighteen incidents featured &amp;ldquo;unusual flight characteristics&amp;rdquo;. Some UAP released radio frequency energy picked up by U.S. military aircraft. The report did not link the sightings to extraterrestrial life. There were 11 reports of near misses between pilots and UAPs. The report established five potential explanatory categories: airborne clutter, natural atmospheric phenomena, U.S. government or American industry developmental programs, foreign adversary systems, and a catch-all &amp;ldquo;other&amp;rdquo; category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;classified-annex&#34;&gt;Classified Annex &lt;a href=&#34;#classified-annex&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the classified annex accompanying the public report. Lawmakers were given &amp;ldquo;little information beyond what&amp;rsquo;s publicly available&amp;rdquo; during the classified briefing, and the only videos shown had already been made public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;categories&#34;&gt;Categories &lt;a href=&#34;#categories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the five potential explanatory categories for UAPs observed between 2004 and 2021, as identified in the report:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Airborne Clutter:&lt;/strong&gt; Objects like birds, balloons, or debris.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natural Atmospheric Phenomena:&lt;/strong&gt; Ice crystals, moisture, and thermal fluctuations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;USG or Industry Developmental Programs:&lt;/strong&gt; Developments and classified programs by U.S. entities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foreign Adversary Systems:&lt;/strong&gt; Technologies deployed by China, Russia, or other nations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other:&lt;/strong&gt; Unidentified UAP due to limited data or challenges in collection, processing, or analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reactions-and-aftermath&#34;&gt;Reactions and Aftermath &lt;a href=&#34;#reactions-and-aftermath&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the responses to the report. The report was largely considered inconclusive. The UAPTF announced efforts to acquire additional reporting and standardize incident reporting across US military services and government agencies. Deputy Secretary of Defense Kathleen Hicks ordered the Pentagon&amp;rsquo;s top intelligence and security official to establish a more formal means of coordinating the collection, reporting, and analysis of UAP information. Senators Mark Warner and Marco Rubio commented on the report, emphasizing the need to understand and mitigate threats to pilots and national security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;response-and-analysis&#34;&gt;Response and Analysis &lt;a href=&#34;#response-and-analysis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents various perspectives on the report and the broader topic of UFOs. Adam Mann of Wired magazine traces the current interest in UFOs back to To the Stars, which made the Pentagon UFO videos available to the New York Times. Jim Semivan and Tom DeLonge of To the Stars reject the idea that Russian or Chinese technology is responsible for UAP reports. Mick West argues that advocates of alien disclosure are mischaracterizing UAPs. Ravi Kumar Kopparapu suggests that making the data informing the report publicly available would be helpful. Kathryn Dorsch sees parallels with Cold War-era interest in UFOs. Jeff Wise speculates that advanced Electronic Warfare techniques could deceive sensors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pentagon_UFO_Report&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pentagon_UFO_Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 United States Congress hearings on UFOs</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cacc9618f5eb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 13:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cacc9618f5eb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;2022-united-states-congressional-hearings-on-unexplained-aerial-phenomena&#34;&gt;2022 United States Congressional Hearings on Unexplained Aerial Phenomena &lt;a href=&#34;#2022-united-states-congressional-hearings-on-unexplained-aerial-phenomena&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the United States congressional hearings held on May 17, 2022, by the House Intelligence Subcommittee on Counterterrorism, Counterintelligence, and Counterproliferation to discuss military reports of Unexplained Aerial Phenomena (UAPs). It was the first public congressional hearing on UFO sightings in the US in over 50 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides the historical context leading up to the 2022 hearings. It mentions the last public congressional hearing on UAPs in 1969, initiated by then-congressman Gerald Ford in 1966. Project Blue Book, a U.S. Air Force program investigating UFOs, was disbanded in 1969. The section also notes the 2017 reports of Pentagon investigations into UAPs and the 2020 COVID-19 relief bill that mandated a report on UAPs from US intelligence agencies. The unclassified report released in June 2021 is highlighted, noting its conclusion that 144 incidents defied explanation and called for further investigation. Finally, the establishment of the Airborne Object Identification and Management Synchronization Group (AOIMSG) in November 2021 and the provisions in the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022 and the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2022, for a permanent agency to investigate UAPs are mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hearings&#34;&gt;Hearings &lt;a href=&#34;#hearings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the events of the May 17, 2022, congressional hearings. Rep. André Carson, chairman of the subcommittee, opened the hearing, expressing concerns about national security threats posed by UAPs and criticizing the Pentagon&amp;rsquo;s lack of updates and leadership for the AOIMSG. Testimony was given by Under Secretary of Defense for Intelligence and Security Ronald S. Moultrie and Deputy Director of Naval Intelligence Scott Bray. Bray stated that reported sightings had grown to about 400 since the previous year&amp;rsquo;s report and dismissed extraterrestrial origins. He also noted no collisions had been reported. The section mentions that other countries have similar reports and communicate with U.S. intelligence agencies. Moultrie emphasized the need for cooperation with the Federal Aviation Administration and other government agencies. Declassified images and footage of UFOs were shown, including a video of a &amp;ldquo;spherical object&amp;rdquo; and triangular objects seen through night-vision goggles. Concerns about potential Russian or Chinese hypersonic weapons programs were raised by lawmakers like Rick Crawford. The standardization of civilian reporting was discussed. The public portion of the hearing was followed by a private classified session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reactions&#34;&gt;Reactions &lt;a href=&#34;#reactions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the reactions to the congressional hearings. Rep. Tim Burchett criticized the Pentagon&amp;rsquo;s transparency and dismissiveness of extraterrestrial explanations. UFO skeptic Robert Sheaffer derided the footage shown at the hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external resources related to the hearings, including the event page on Congress.gov, the hearing on C-SPAN, and a YouTube video of the hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2022_United_States_Congress_hearings_on_UFOs&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2022_United_States_Congress_hearings_on_UFOs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
