<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ancient Astronauts on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ancient-astronauts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ancient Astronauts on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 08:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ancient-astronauts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ancient astronauts</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_96b21753a786/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 08:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_96b21753a786/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ancient-astronauts&#34;&gt;Ancient Astronauts &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-astronauts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ancient astronauts, also known as ancient aliens, is a pseudoscientific belief that intelligent extraterrestrial beings visited Earth in ancient times and influenced the development of human civilization. Proponents suggest that these aliens affected modern cultures, technologies, religions, and human biology. A common idea is that deities from religions are extraterrestrial in origin, with advanced technologies interpreted as divine status by early humans. Academics and archaeologists dismiss these claims as pseudoarchaeological or unscientific, lacking credible peer-reviewed studies. Some argue that ancient astronaut theories have racist undertones, diminishing the accomplishments of indigenous cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Various terms are used to describe claims about ancient astronauts, including ancient aliens, ancient ufonauts, ancient space pilots, paleocontact, astronaut- or alien gods, and paleo- or biblical-SETI. Believers maintain that humans are descendants or creations of extraterrestrial intelligence who landed on Earth in the past. They propose that human knowledge, religion, and culture originated from these visitors, who acted as a &amp;ldquo;mother culture.&amp;rdquo; Proponents also claim that extraterrestrials built structures like the Egyptian pyramids and the Moai stone heads of Easter Island or aided humans in their construction. Evidence is drawn from documentary gaps in historical and archaeological records, as well as archaeological artifacts considered anachronistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is featured in fringe media, such as the History Channel series &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;. The show mixes fact with fiction to spread theories of an alternate past, often aligning with white supremacist, nativist, imperialist, settler-colonial, and Christian Identity beliefs. Proponents portray themselves as an oppressed minority of academics, claiming a conspiracy by &amp;lsquo;big archaeology&amp;rsquo; to disenfranchise them. They focus on monumental archaeological structures, implying that non-white Indigenous people could not have built them without extraterrestrial intervention. However, some indigenous voices argue that the idea of extraterrestrials supports their own origin stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common feature in these stories portrays aliens as light-skinned or Aryan, as claimed by Erich von Däniken. Some proponents are associated with white supremacism, though their theories are sometimes applied to European cultures. Mainstream archaeologists largely ignored these claims until recently, while skeptics universally panned them. Carl Sagan noted that cases of interest have reasonable alternative explanations or are misreported, fabricated, or distorted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34;&gt;History of Ancient Aliens Beliefs and Their Proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paleocontact narratives first appeared in early science fiction of the late 19th and early 20th centuries, including &lt;em&gt;Edison&amp;rsquo;s Conquest of Mars&lt;/em&gt; (1898) and the works of H.P. Lovecraft. Harold T. Wilkins proposed the idea in earnest in 1954. It gained popularity in the 1960s due to the Space Race and Erich von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s works. Critics emerged in the 1970s, discrediting Von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s claims. Ufologists separated the idea from the UFO controversy, and by the early 1980s, little support remained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;shklovskii-and-sagan&#34;&gt;Shklovskii and Sagan &lt;a href=&#34;#shklovskii-and-sagan&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Carl Sagan co-authored &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Life in the Universe&lt;/em&gt; (1966) with Soviet astrophysicist Iosif Shklovsky. In &lt;em&gt;Broca&amp;rsquo;s Brain&lt;/em&gt; (1979), Sagan suggested that he and Shklovsky might have inspired the wave of 1970s ancient astronaut books, disapproving of &amp;ldquo;von Däniken and other uncritical writers&amp;rdquo; who built on these ideas as valid evidence. Sagan pointed out that many legends, artifacts, and purported out-of-place artifacts cited in support of ancient astronaut hypotheses could be easily explained with more conventional hypotheses. He reiterated that extraterrestrial visits to Earth were possible but unproven and improbable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;erich-von-däniken&#34;&gt;Erich von Däniken &lt;a href=&#34;#erich-von-d%c3%a4niken&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Erich von Däniken was a leading proponent in the late 1960s and early 1970s, gaining a large audience through his book &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; (1968) and its sequels. He argued that certain artifacts required more sophisticated technology than was available to ancient cultures, suggesting they were constructed by extraterrestrial visitors or humans who learned from them. Examples include Stonehenge, Pumapunku, the Moai of Easter Island, the Great Pyramid of Giza, and the ancient Baghdad electric batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Von Däniken wrote that ancient art and iconography illustrate air and space vehicles, non-human creatures, ancient astronauts, and advanced technology. He stated that geographically separated cultures share artistic themes, implying a common origin. He interpreted the sarcophagus lid of Maya ruler Pacal the Great as a seated astronaut, while the iconography identifies it as a portrait of the ruler with the World Tree of Maya mythology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He interpreted the origins of religions as reactions to encounters with an alien race, considering their technology supernatural and the aliens themselves as gods. He stated that religious traditions contain references to alien visitors in the way of descriptions of stars and vehicular objects traveling through air and space. One such is Ezekiel&amp;rsquo;s revelation, which Däniken interprets as a landing spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s hypotheses became popularized in the U.S. after the NBC-TV documentary &lt;em&gt;In Search of Ancient Astronauts&lt;/em&gt; and the film &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods&lt;/em&gt;. Critics argue that von Däniken misrepresented data, that many of his claims were unfounded, and that none of his core claims have been validated. The Christian creationist community is highly critical of his work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the Nazca Lines, von Däniken stated that they gave him the impression of an airfield. Kenneth L. Feder argues that readers seeing the Nazca Lines for the first time in a book about aliens would be more likely to associate those features with extraterrestrial origins. In 1970, von Däniken admitted that the Nazca markings &amp;ldquo;could have been laid out on their gigantic scale by working from a model using a system of coordinates.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;zecharia-sitchin&#34;&gt;Zecharia Sitchin &lt;a href=&#34;#zecharia-sitchin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zecharia Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s series &lt;em&gt;The Earth Chronicles&lt;/em&gt;, beginning with &lt;em&gt;The 12th Planet&lt;/em&gt;, revolves around his interpretation of ancient Sumerian and Middle Eastern texts, megalithic sites, and artifacts. He hypothesized that the gods of old Mesopotamia were astronauts from the planet &amp;ldquo;Nibiru,&amp;rdquo; which the Sumerians believed to be a remote &amp;ldquo;12th planet&amp;rdquo; associated with the god Marduk. According to Sitchin, Nibiru continues to orbit the Sun on a 3,600-year elongated orbit. Modern astronomy has found no evidence to support Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitchin argued that Sumerian texts tell the story that 50 Anunnaki, inhabitants of Nibiru, came to Earth approximately 400,000 years ago to mine raw materials, especially gold. They genetically engineered laborers to work the mines, creating &lt;em&gt;Homo sapiens sapiens&lt;/em&gt;: the &amp;ldquo;Adapa&amp;rdquo; or Adam of later mythology. Sitchin contended the Anunnaki were active in human affairs until their culture was destroyed by global catastrophes caused by the abrupt end of the last ice age some 12,000 years ago. Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s work has not received mainstream scholarly support. Semitic languages scholar Michael S. Heiser says that many of Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s translations are not consistent with Mesopotamian cuneiform bilingual dictionaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alan F. Alford, author of &lt;em&gt;Gods of the New Millennium&lt;/em&gt; (1996), was an adherent of the ancient astronaut hypothesis but now finds fault with Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s hypothesis, stating that the gods personified the falling sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;robert-temple&#34;&gt;Robert Temple &lt;a href=&#34;#robert-temple&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Robert K. G. Temple&amp;rsquo;s 1976 book, &lt;em&gt;The Sirius Mystery,&lt;/em&gt; argues that the Dogon people of northwestern Mali preserved an account of extraterrestrial visitation from around 5,000 years ago. He quotes evidence, including advanced astronomical knowledge inherited by the tribe, descriptions, and comparative belief systems with ancient civilizations. His work draws heavily on the studies of cultural anthropologists Marcel Griaule and Germaine Dieterlen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His conclusions have been criticized by scientists, who point out discrepancies within Temple&amp;rsquo;s account and suggested that the Dogon may have received some of their astronomical information recently from European sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufo-religions&#34;&gt;UFO Religions &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-religions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Various new religious movements, including some branches of Theosophy, Scientology, Raëlism, Aetherius Society, and Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate, believe in ancient and present-day contact with extraterrestrial intelligence. Many of these faiths see both ancient scriptures and recent revelations as connected with the action of aliens from other planetary systems. Psychologists have found that UFO religions have similarities which suggest that members of these groups consciously or subliminally associate enchantment with the memes of science fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;claims-of-proponents&#34;&gt;Claims of Proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#claims-of-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among scientists, the consensus is that the ancient astronaut hypothesis is not impossible, but unjustified and unnecessary. The &amp;ldquo;mysteries&amp;rdquo; cited as evidence can be explained without having to invoke ancient astronauts. Since ancient astronauts are unnecessary, Occam&amp;rsquo;s razor should be applied and the hypothesis rejected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ancient-religious-texts&#34;&gt;Ancient Religious Texts &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-religious-texts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Proponents cite ancient mythologies to support their viewpoints, based on the idea that ancient creation myths of gods who descend from the heavens to Earth to create or instruct humanity are representations of alien visitors, whose superior technology accounts for their perception as gods. Proponents draw an analogy to occurrences in modern time when isolated cultures are exposed to advanced technology, such as when, in the early 20th century, &amp;ldquo;cargo cults&amp;rdquo; were discovered in the South Pacific.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ancient Sumerian myth of &lt;em&gt;Enûma Eliš&lt;/em&gt;, inscribed on cuneiform tablets and part of the Library of Ashurbanipal, says humankind was created to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
