<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ancient Astronauts on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ancient-astronauts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ancient Astronauts on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 01:53:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ancient-astronauts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ancient Aliens Episodes</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_4ec78e5ef76d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 01:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_4ec78e5ef76d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ancient-aliens-episodes&#34;&gt;Ancient Aliens Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-aliens-episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; is an American television series that explores the ancient astronauts hypothesis and other pseudoscientific topics. It is narrated by Robert Clotworthy and produced by Prometheus Entertainment. The series has been criticized for promoting unproven hypotheses as fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;series-overview&#34;&gt;Series Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#series-overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a table summarizing the number of episodes per season and the original release dates for each season, starting with the pilot episode in 2009 and continuing through season 21, scheduled for 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;broadcast-episodes&#34;&gt;Broadcast Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#broadcast-episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists all episodes broadcast under the &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; title card. Episode availability varies by broadcast market and language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-1-200910&#34;&gt;Season 1 (2009–10) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-1-200910&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2009 &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; documentary was retitled &amp;ldquo;Chariots, Gods &amp;amp; Beyond&amp;rdquo; and packaged as the series pilot. All episodes, except the pilot, carry the &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens: The Series&lt;/em&gt; title card. The section lists the pilot episode and the five episodes of the first season, including their titles and original release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-2-2010&#34;&gt;Season 2 (2010) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-2-2010&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the ten episodes of the second season, including their titles and original release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-3-2011&#34;&gt;Season 3 (2011) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-3-2011&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sixteen episodes of the third season, including their titles and original release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-4-2012&#34;&gt;Season 4 (2012) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-4-2012&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the ten episodes of the fourth season, including their titles and original release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-5-201213&#34;&gt;Season 5 (2012–13) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-5-201213&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the twelve episodes of the fifth season, including their titles and original release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-6-2013&#34;&gt;Season 6 (2013) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-6-2013&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the eleven episodes of the sixth season, including their titles and original release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-7-2014&#34;&gt;Season 7 (2014) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-7-2014&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the eight episodes of the seventh season, including their titles and original release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-8-2014&#34;&gt;Season 8 (2014) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-8-2014&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the nine episodes of the eighth season, including their titles and original release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-9-201415&#34;&gt;Season 9 (2014–15) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-9-201415&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the twelve episodes of the ninth season, including their titles and original release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-10-2015&#34;&gt;Season 10 (2015) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-10-2015&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the ten episodes of the tenth season, including their titles and original release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-11-2016&#34;&gt;Season 11 (2016) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-11-2016&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the fifteen episodes of the eleventh season, including their titles and original release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-12-2017&#34;&gt;Season 12 (2017) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-12-2017&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sixteen episodes of the twelfth season, including their titles and original release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-13-201819&#34;&gt;Season 13 (2018–19) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-13-201819&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the fifteen episodes of the thirteenth season, including their titles and original release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-14-2019&#34;&gt;Season 14 (2019) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-14-2019&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the twenty-two episodes of the fourteenth season, including their titles and original release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-15-2020&#34;&gt;Season 15 (2020) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-15-2020&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the twelve episodes of the fifteenth season, including their titles and original release dates. It mentions the Nan Madol episode and the Skinwalker Ranch episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-16-202021&#34;&gt;Season 16 (2020–21) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-16-202021&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the ten episodes of the sixteenth season, including their titles, original release dates, and U.S. viewer numbers in millions. It mentions the episode featuring William Shatner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-17-2021&#34;&gt;Season 17 (2021) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-17-2021&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the seven episodes of the seventeenth season, including their titles and original release dates. It mentions the Mount Shasta episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-18-2022&#34;&gt;Season 18 (2022) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-18-2022&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the twenty episodes of the eighteenth season, including their titles and original release dates. Six episodes were broadcast as &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens on Location&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-19-2023&#34;&gt;Season 19 (2023) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-19-2023&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the twenty episodes of the nineteenth season, including their titles, original release dates, and U.S. viewer numbers in millions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-20-2024&#34;&gt;Season 20 (2024) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-20-2024&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the twenty episodes of the twentieth season, including their titles, original release dates, and U.S. viewer numbers in millions for the first eight episodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-21-2025&#34;&gt;Season 21 (2025) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-21-2025&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the first eight episodes of the upcoming twenty-first season, including their titles and original release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;special-episodes&#34;&gt;Special Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#special-episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details special episodes that include new footage in addition to selections from previously broadcast episodes. Availability varies by broadcast market and language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;special-edition-2014&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Special Edition&lt;/em&gt; (2014) &lt;a href=&#34;#special-edition-2014&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens: Special Edition&lt;/em&gt; features highlights from previously broadcast episodes, including extended interviews and new effects. The episodes were originally broadcast as part of Season 8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-ultimate-evidence-2015&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ultimate Evidence&lt;/em&gt; (2015) &lt;a href=&#34;#the-ultimate-evidence-2015&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens: The Ultimate Evidence&lt;/em&gt; is a repackage of previously broadcast episodes presented by Giorgio Tsoukalos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;special-presentation-20222024&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Special Presentation&lt;/em&gt; (2022–2024) &lt;a href=&#34;#special-presentation-20222024&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens: Special Presentation&lt;/em&gt; features highlights from previously broadcast episodes in a 90-minute format, with many segments presented in high-definition for the first time, along with new interview footage and special effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;season-1-202223&#34;&gt;Season 1 (2022–23) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-1-202223&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the thirteen episodes of the first season of &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens: Special Presentation&lt;/em&gt;, including their titles and original release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;season-2-202324&#34;&gt;Season 2 (2023–24) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-2-202324&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the twelve episodes of the second season of &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens: Special Presentation&lt;/em&gt;, including their titles and original release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;origins-202425&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Origins&lt;/em&gt; (2024–25) &lt;a href=&#34;#origins-202425&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens: Origins&lt;/em&gt; is a repackage of previously broadcast episodes in a 90-minute format, with new on-location segments and interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Ancient_Aliens_episodes&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Ancient_Aliens_episodes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancient astronauts</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_96b21753a786/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 08:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_96b21753a786/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ancient-astronauts&#34;&gt;Ancient Astronauts &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-astronauts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ancient astronauts, also known as ancient aliens, is a pseudoscientific belief that intelligent extraterrestrial beings visited Earth in ancient times and influenced human civilization. Proponents suggest that these aliens affected the development of cultures, technologies, religions, and even human biology. A common idea is that deities in many religions were actually extraterrestrials, and their advanced technologies were seen as divine powers by early humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This idea is rejected by academics and archaeologists, who consider it pseudoarchaeology and unscientific. Claims are often based on distorted or fabricated evidence. Some critics argue that ancient astronaut theories have racist implications, diminishing the achievements of indigenous cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notable proponents in the late 20th century include Robert Charroux, Jacques Bergier, Jean Sendy, Erich von Däniken, Alexander Kazantsev, Zecharia Sitchin, Robert K. G. Temple, Giorgio A. Tsoukalos, David Hatcher Childress, Peter Kolosimo, and Mauro Biglino.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various terms are used to describe claims about ancient astronauts, including ancient aliens, ancient ufonauts, ancient space pilots, paleocontact, astronaut- or alien gods, and paleo- or biblical-SETI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believers often claim that humans are descendants or creations of extraterrestrial intelligence that landed on Earth in the past. They suggest that human knowledge, religion, and culture originated from these ancient alien visitors, who acted as a &amp;ldquo;mother culture.&amp;rdquo; Proponents also claim that extraterrestrials built or helped humans build structures like the Egyptian pyramids and the Moai stone heads of Easter Island. Evidence is said to come from gaps in historical and archaeological records, as well as artifacts that are considered anachronistic and beyond the technical capabilities of ancient people. These &amp;ldquo;out-of-place artifacts&amp;rdquo; include artwork and legends reinterpreted to support extraterrestrial contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is featured in fringe media, such as the History Channel series &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;. The show mixes fact with fiction to promote theories of an alternate past, often incorporating white supremacist, nativist, imperialist, settler-colonial, and Christian Identity beliefs. Proponents portray themselves as an oppressed minority of academics challenging mainstream archaeology, despite lacking credentials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like past archaeological endeavors, the focus is on monumental structures, suggesting that indigenous people could not have built them without alien help. However, some indigenous voices argue that ancient alien theory supports their stories of extraterrestrial origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common theme is the portrayal of aliens as light-skinned or Aryan, as claimed by Erich von Däniken. Some proponents are associated with white supremacism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainstream archaeologists have largely ignored these claims, while popular science explainers and skeptics have criticized them. Carl Sagan noted that cases of apparent interest have reasonable alternative explanations, misreporting, or are hoaxes and distortions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34;&gt;History of Ancient Aliens Beliefs and Their Proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paleocontact narratives appeared in early science fiction of the late 19th and early 20th centuries, including &lt;em&gt;Edison&amp;rsquo;s Conquest of Mars&lt;/em&gt; (1898) and the works of H.P. Lovecraft. Harold T. Wilkins proposed the idea in earnest in 1954. It gained popularity in the 1960s due to the Space Race and Erich von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s works. Critics emerged in the 1970s, discrediting Von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s claims. By the early 1980s, support dwindled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;shklovskii-and-sagan&#34;&gt;Shklovskii and Sagan &lt;a href=&#34;#shklovskii-and-sagan&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Sagan co-authored &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Life in the Universe&lt;/em&gt; (1966) with Soviet astrophysicist Iosif Shklovsky. In &lt;em&gt;Broca&amp;rsquo;s Brain&lt;/em&gt; (1979), Sagan expressed disapproval of writers like von Däniken who treated speculations as valid evidence of extraterrestrial contact. Sagan noted that many legends, artifacts, and out-of-place artifacts cited in support of ancient astronaut hypotheses could be explained with conventional hypotheses. He reiterated that extraterrestrial visits were possible but unproven and improbable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;erich-von-däniken&#34;&gt;Erich von Däniken &lt;a href=&#34;#erich-von-d%c3%a4niken&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erich von Däniken became a leading proponent in the late 1960s and early 1970s with his book &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; (1968) and its sequels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Von Däniken argued that certain artifacts required more advanced technology than was available to ancient cultures. He claimed that these artifacts were constructed by extraterrestrial visitors or humans who learned from them. Examples include Stonehenge, Pumapunku, the Moai of Easter Island, the Great Pyramid of Giza, and the ancient Baghdad electric batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He wrote that ancient art and iconography depict air and space vehicles, intelligent non-human creatures, ancient astronauts, and advanced technology. He also stated that geographically separated cultures share artistic themes, implying a common origin. One example is his interpretation of the sarcophagus lid from the tomb of Pacal the Great in Palenque, which he saw as a seated astronaut, while Maya texts identify it as a portrait of the ruler with the World Tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Von Däniken interpreted the origins of many religions as reactions to encounters with an alien race, whose technology was seen as supernatural. He stated that religious traditions contain references to alien visitors, such as Ezekiel&amp;rsquo;s revelation, which he interpreted as a landing spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His hypotheses became popularized in the U.S. through the NBC-TV documentary &lt;em&gt;In Search of Ancient Astronauts&lt;/em&gt; and the film &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critics argue that von Däniken misrepresented data, made unfounded claims, and failed to validate his core claims. Christian creationists also criticized his work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the Nazca Lines, von Däniken stated that they resembled an airfield when seen from the air. Kenneth L. Feder argues that readers seeing the Nazca Lines in a book about aliens would be more likely to associate them with extraterrestrial origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1970, von Däniken admitted that the Nazca markings could have been laid out using a system of coordinates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;zecharia-sitchin&#34;&gt;Zecharia Sitchin &lt;a href=&#34;#zecharia-sitchin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zecharia Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Earth Chronicles&lt;/em&gt; series revolves around his interpretation of ancient Sumerian and Middle Eastern texts, megalithic sites, and artifacts. He hypothesized that the gods of Mesopotamia were astronauts from the planet Nibiru, which the Sumerians believed to be a remote &amp;ldquo;12th planet&amp;rdquo; associated with the god Marduk. According to Sitchin, Nibiru orbits the Sun on a 3,600-year elongated orbit. Modern astronomy has found no evidence to support these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitchin argued that Sumerian texts tell the story of 50 Anunnaki from Nibiru who came to Earth approximately 400,000 years ago to mine raw materials, especially gold. They genetically engineered laborers, creating &lt;em&gt;Homo sapiens sapiens&lt;/em&gt;: the &amp;ldquo;Adapa&amp;rdquo; or Adam of later mythology. Sitchin contended that the Anunnaki were active in human affairs until their culture was destroyed by global catastrophes caused by the end of the last ice age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His work has not received mainstream scholarly support and has been criticized by professionals. Semitic languages scholar Michael S. Heiser says that many of Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s translations are inconsistent with Mesopotamian cuneiform dictionaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alan F. Alford, author of &lt;em&gt;Gods of the New Millennium&lt;/em&gt;, initially adhered to Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s hypotheses but later found fault, stating that the gods personified the falling sky and that the descent of the gods was a poetic rendition of the cataclysm myth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;robert-temple&#34;&gt;Robert Temple &lt;a href=&#34;#robert-temple&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert K. G. Temple&amp;rsquo;s 1976 book, &lt;em&gt;The Sirius Mystery,&lt;/em&gt; argues that the Dogon people of northwestern Mali preserved an account of extraterrestrial visitation from around 5,000 years ago. He cites advanced astronomical knowledge, descriptions, and comparative belief systems with ancient civilizations. His work draws on the studies of cultural anthropologists Marcel Griaule and Germaine Dieterlen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His conclusions have been criticized by scientists, who point out discrepancies and suggest that the Dogon may have received their astronomical information recently from European sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ufo-religions&#34;&gt;UFO Religions &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-religions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various new religious movements, including some branches of Theosophy, Scientology, Raëlism, Aetherius Society, and Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate, believe in ancient and present-day contact with extraterrestrial intelligence. Many see ancient scriptures and recent revelations as connected with the action of aliens. Psychologists have found that UFO religions have similarities suggesting that members associate enchantment with science fiction memes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;claims-of-proponents&#34;&gt;Claims of Proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#claims-of-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientific consensus is that the ancient astronaut hypothesis is not impossible, but unjustified and unnecessary. The &amp;ldquo;mysteries&amp;rdquo; cited as evidence can be explained without invoking ancient astronauts. Since ancient astronauts are unnecessary, Occam&amp;rsquo;s razor should be applied and the hypothesis rejected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ancient-religious-texts&#34;&gt;Ancient Religious Texts &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-religious-texts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proponents cite ancient mythologies, suggesting that creation myths of gods descending from the heavens to create or instruct humanity are representations of alien visitors. They draw an analogy to cargo cults, where isolated cultures believed Western ships and cargo were sent from the gods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ancient Sumerian myth of &lt;em&gt;Enûma Eliš&lt;/em&gt; says humankind was created to serve gods called the &amp;ldquo;Annunaki.&amp;rdquo; Proponents believe that the Annunaki were aliens who came to Earth to mine gold and created the human race as slaves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;ramayana&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ramayana&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#ramayana&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Hindu mythology, the gods and their avatars travel in flying vehicles called Vimana. The &lt;em&gt;Ramayana&lt;/em&gt; mentions these flying objects, used by the Lankan king Ravana from Sri Lanka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples from the &lt;em&gt;Ramayana&lt;/em&gt; include descriptions of the Pushpak chariot, a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancient astronauts in popular culture</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_d6f5a5a50175/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 12:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_d6f5a5a50175/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ancient-astronauts-in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;Ancient Astronauts in Popular Culture &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-astronauts-in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article explores the presence of the ancient astronaut theory in various forms of fiction, including literature, comics, television, film, documentaries, music, and video games. The theory posits that extraterrestrial beings visited Earth in the distant past and influenced the development of human civilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;literature&#34;&gt;Literature &lt;a href=&#34;#literature&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details numerous literary works that incorporate the ancient astronaut theme. Some key examples include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Les Xipehuz (1887) by J.-H. Rosny aîné:&lt;/strong&gt; Features geometric aliens encountered by primitive humans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edison&amp;rsquo;s Conquest of Mars (1898) by Garrett P. Serviss:&lt;/strong&gt; Martians enslaved inhabitants of the Fertile Crescent and used them to build monuments in Egypt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Call of Cthulhu (1926) and At the Mountains of Madness (1931) by H.P. Lovecraft:&lt;/strong&gt; Deals with ancient aliens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2001: A Space Odyssey (1968) by Arthur C. Clarke:&lt;/strong&gt; Based on his short story &amp;ldquo;Encounter in the Dawn,&amp;rdquo; explores the idea of extraterrestrial influence on human evolution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Sirens of Titan (1959) by Kurt Vonnegut:&lt;/strong&gt; Human development is manipulated by aliens to relay messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Known Space (1964–present) by Larry Niven:&lt;/strong&gt; Humanity is descended from aliens called the Pak.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heechee Saga (1972–2004) by Frederik Pohl:&lt;/strong&gt; The Heechee are an ancient alien race that left behind futuristic technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uplift Universe (1980-&amp;hellip;) by David Brin:&lt;/strong&gt; Explores the idea that all species were brought to sapience through the intervention of a galactic &amp;ldquo;patron.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VALIS trilogy (1981) by Philip K. Dick:&lt;/strong&gt; An ancient astronaut race placed an information-streaming satellite in orbit around Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Encounter With Tiber (1996) by Buzz Aldrin and John Barnes:&lt;/strong&gt; Deals with the discovery of ancient alien encounters on Earth and Mars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outlanders novel series (1997-&amp;hellip;) by Mark Ellis:&lt;/strong&gt; The Anunnaki are revealed to have been behind a nuclear war and the Root Race of the Gray aliens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comics&#34;&gt;Comics &lt;a href=&#34;#comics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights comic books and series that feature ancient astronauts or related concepts. Some notable examples include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uncle Scrooge #34 (1961):&lt;/strong&gt; A Carl Barks story where Scrooge McDuck&amp;rsquo;s family discovers a planetoid inhabited by beings who were the basis for Roman and Norse gods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tales of Suspense #50 (1964):&lt;/strong&gt; Introduces the Mandarin&amp;rsquo;s rings, created by the alien Makluans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Adventures of Tintin: Flight 714 to Sydney (1968) by Hergé:&lt;/strong&gt; Features a temple built to honor ancient astronauts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Eternals:&lt;/strong&gt; Deals with advanced aliens (the Celestials) who experimented on early hominids, creating the Eternals and Deviants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thorgal series by Grzegorz Rosiński and Van Hamme:&lt;/strong&gt; The main protagonist is the son of ancient astronauts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karmatrón y los Transformables by Oscar González Loyo:&lt;/strong&gt; Relies heavily on the ancient astronaut theory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;television&#34;&gt;Television &lt;a href=&#34;#television&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details television shows that have explored the ancient astronaut theme. Some key examples include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quatermass and the Pit (1958–1959):&lt;/strong&gt; A miniseries that used a version of the ancient astronaut idea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Star Trek:&lt;/strong&gt; The franchise has numerous examples of extraterrestrials visiting Earth in past centuries, influencing pre-modern humans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctor Who: Pyramids of Mars (1975):&lt;/strong&gt; Features a conflict between aliens of a race named the Osirans forming the basis of Egyptian mythology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Space: 1999 (1975–1977):&lt;/strong&gt; Many alien species have controlled or visited Earth in the past.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battlestar Galactica:&lt;/strong&gt; Depicts humans as having originated on the planet Kobol and later settled thirteen colony planets, Earth being the last and most distant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Babylon 5 (1993–1998):&lt;/strong&gt; Many of the First Ones, particularly the Vorlons and Shadows, visited Earth at various times in history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The X-Files (1993–2002, 2016–2018):&lt;/strong&gt; Has borrowed the ancient astronaut theory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Earth: Final Conflict (1997–2002):&lt;/strong&gt; The Atavus species traveled to Earth in the distant past and ruled over it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Super Dimension Fortress Macross (1982):&lt;/strong&gt; Features an ancient alien civilization called The Protoculture, who created the human race on Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neon Genesis Evangelion:&lt;/strong&gt; Lilith and Adam were two extraterrestrial beings that landed on Earth and gave birth to humanity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;film&#34;&gt;Film &lt;a href=&#34;#film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists films that incorporate the ancient astronaut theory. Some notable examples include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2001: A Space Odyssey (1968):&lt;/strong&gt; The first act of the movie features paleocontact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Horror Express (1972):&lt;/strong&gt; An extraterrestrial is found frozen for millions of years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alien vs. Predator (2004):&lt;/strong&gt; The Predator race traveled to Earth at a prehistoric time and had a human culture serve them as Gods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prometheus (2012):&lt;/strong&gt; Themed around a group of scientists who set out to discover the origins of human life, which was seeded on Earth and influenced by an ancient race of aliens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hangar 18 (1980):&lt;/strong&gt; Involves a UFO whose symbols are found to match those used in ancient cultures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stargate (1994):&lt;/strong&gt; Features Ra, a member of the alien species Goa&amp;rsquo;uld that came to Earth around 8000 BC, enslaved the ancient Egyptians, adopting their culture and religion and posing as their God.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mission to Mars (2000):&lt;/strong&gt; Another movie with an &amp;ldquo;alien seeding&amp;rdquo; theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull (2008):&lt;/strong&gt; Links the existence of crystal skulls to beings that were perceived as gods by the Maya civilization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;documentaries&#34;&gt;Documentaries &lt;a href=&#34;#documentaries&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists documentaries that explore the ancient astronaut theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chariots of the Gods (1970)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Search of Ancient Astronauts (1973)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Search of Ancient Mysteries (1974)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Outer Space Connection (1975)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;Music &lt;a href=&#34;#music&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights musical works that deal with the ancient astronaut concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Spaceman Came Travelling by Chris de Burgh:&lt;/strong&gt; Deals with the concept of an ancient astronaut, in this case pertaining to the Christ story.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inca Roads by Frank Zappa:&lt;/strong&gt; Deals with Ancient Astronaut Theory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Several songs by The Lost Children of Babylon:&lt;/strong&gt; Explicitly state that &amp;ldquo;Jesus Christ was really an ancient astronaut.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God Is an Astronaut:&lt;/strong&gt; A post-rock musical group from Ireland with a name exploiting the theory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ayreon albums:&lt;/strong&gt; About ancient astronauts, that go by the name Forever, who traveled from the Andromeda Galaxy to earth long ago and influenced the development of science and technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-games&#34;&gt;Video Games &lt;a href=&#34;#video-games&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists video games that incorporate the ancient astronaut theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spore (2008):&lt;/strong&gt; Has many elements of ancient astronauts, even giving player the ability to manipulate other less developed species as a space travelling species.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Fantasy VII:&lt;/strong&gt; Features an ancient astronaut, Jenova, as the main antagonist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Halo series:&lt;/strong&gt; Ancient humanity was a spacefaring society technologically superior to modern humanity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dark Void:&lt;/strong&gt; Features a race of humanoid shape-shifters called Watchers, who ruled over ancient humans as gods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mass Effect:&lt;/strong&gt; Humanity discovers a cache of alien technology built by an alien species known as the Protheans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assassin&amp;rsquo;s Creed franchise:&lt;/strong&gt; Humanity was originally created as a slave race by the &amp;ldquo;First Civilization.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rise of Nations: Rise of Legends:&lt;/strong&gt; The Cuotl is a nation of Mesoamerica-inspired tribes subjugated by four extraterrestrial beings who install themselves as deities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts_in_popular_culture&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts_in_popular_culture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancient Aliens</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_80db310465ba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 20:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_80db310465ba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ancient-aliens&#34;&gt;Ancient Aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; is an American television series that explores the pseudoscientific ancient astronauts hypothesis. It presents unorthodox theories about extraterrestrial visitations in ancient times, often without critical analysis. The show has been criticized for promoting pseudoscience and pseudohistory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Genre:&lt;/strong&gt; Pseudoscience, Pseudohistory, Ufology, Conspiracy theory
&lt;strong&gt;Narrator:&lt;/strong&gt; Robert Clotworthy
&lt;strong&gt;Country of Origin:&lt;/strong&gt; United States
&lt;strong&gt;Original Language:&lt;/strong&gt; English
&lt;strong&gt;Number of Seasons:&lt;/strong&gt; 21
&lt;strong&gt;Number of Episodes:&lt;/strong&gt; 268&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series is produced by Prometheus Entertainment. Kevin Burns served as executive producer from 2009 to 2021. Giorgio A. Tsoukalos is a consulting producer and featured guest. UFO researcher C. Scott Littleton was a producing consultant until his death in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; began as a two-hour documentary special on the History Channel in 2009. It became a flagship series on History from 2010 to 2012, then moved to H2 from 2012 to 2014. In 2015, it returned to History after H2 was relaunched as Vice on TV. A fifteenth season premiered in 2020, with subsequent seasons following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;premise-and-cosmology&#34;&gt;Premise and cosmology &lt;a href=&#34;#premise-and-cosmology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series is based on the ancient astronauts hypothesis popularized by Erich von Däniken in &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; and Zecharia Sitchin in &lt;em&gt;The 12th Planet&lt;/em&gt;. This hypothesis suggests that extraterrestrial beings visited Earth in the distant past and influenced the development of human civilization, technology, and architecture. Ancient achievements like the Egyptian pyramids, Pumapunku, Teotihuacan, and Stonehenge are attributed to extraterrestrial influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series suggests that remnants of these visitations can be found in religious texts, ancient myths, and legendary histories, including those of Hinduism, Ancient Egyptian religion, Gnostic Christianity, and Mormonism. It also proposes that modern humans may be the result of genetic modification by or biological descendants of ancient astronauts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series often avoids precise dates, using terms like &amp;ldquo;the remote past&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;ancient times.&amp;rdquo; A common demarcation point is &amp;ldquo;before or after &amp;lsquo;The Ice Age&amp;rsquo;,&amp;rdquo; or approximately 12,000 years ago. Some guests, such as Graham Hancock and Robert Schoch, suggest that a sophisticated human civilization predated our own and was destroyed at the end of the Ice Age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series features guests who support these claims and promote the idea of a shared cosmogony and cosmology, with significance placed on Sirius, Orion, Pleiades, the Moon, and Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;presentation-style&#34;&gt;Presentation style &lt;a href=&#34;#presentation-style&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series presents claims made by guests in an uncritical and fast-paced manner. The narration often frames these claims as rhetorical questions, answered with &amp;ldquo;ancient alien theorists say yes.&amp;rdquo; After a claim is introduced, the narration often cuts away with, &amp;ldquo;Perhaps more evidence can be found&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; before introducing another location or event with a hypothetical connection. This presentation style has been described as a Gish gallop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geologist Robert Schoch has stated that his interviews for the series have been edited in a way that is out of context or disconnected from the questions asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writer David Childress frequently concludes his comments with the exclamation, &amp;ldquo;—probably extraterrestrials!&amp;rdquo; Childress and Giorgio Tsoukalos assert that prehistoric peoples lacked the vocabulary to describe advanced technology, and thus referred to extraterrestrial visitors as gods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terms such as &amp;ldquo;ancient astronauts,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;ancient aliens,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;alien visitors,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;extra-terrestrial beings,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;ancient gods,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;otherworldly beings&amp;rdquo; are used interchangeably. Guests often conflate the meaning of &amp;ldquo;theory&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;hypothesis,&amp;rdquo; or obscure the difference between mythology and verifiable archaeology, anthropology, or documented history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;frequent-guests&#34;&gt;Frequent guests &lt;a href=&#34;#frequent-guests&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series features a range of guests, including credentialed scientists and professionals, as well as proponents of the ancient astronaut hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some frequent guests include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sara Seager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michael Denning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jonathan Young&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert Schoch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erich von Däniken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;George Noory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Barry Downing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert Bauval&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graham Hancock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nick Pope&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travis S. Taylor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;evidence&#34;&gt;Evidence &lt;a href=&#34;#evidence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many episodes offer little empirical evidence to support the claims presented. Episodes often focus on out-of-place artifacts, such as the London Hammer, Antikythera mechanism, or the Aiud object. Guests discuss evidence in general or abstract terms. Some guests allege that professionals and government officials have suppressed evidence of ancient mysteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Season 12 onward, some episodes have included on-camera tests conducted by scientists and medical professionals on evidence that potentially supports the ancient astronauts hypothesis. However, none of the results have proven conclusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-claims&#34;&gt;Other claims &lt;a href=&#34;#other-claims&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series explores other claims linked to the ancient astronauts hypothesis, including UFOs, alien abductions, the Roswell incident, Rendlesham Forest incident, panspermia, and human space exploration. Guests have presented pseudohistorical and pseudoscientific hypotheses related to Atlantis, ley lines, cataclysmic pole shifts, creationism, and legendary history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other concepts explored include faith healing, remote viewing, psychic phenomena, and catastrophism. Guests have claimed that prominent historical figures were influenced by or were possibly &amp;ldquo;extra-terrestrial&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;otherworldly beings.&amp;rdquo; Guests have also discussed unrelated pseudoscientific claims, such as dinosaurs coexisting with humans, crystal healing, crystal skulls, Freemasonry, Rosicrucianism, and the New World Order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linda Moulton Howe appears in several episodes which explore alien abduction, animal mutilation, and conspiracies involving alleged military installations on Antarctica. The 2013 Citizen Hearing on Disclosure features prominently in numerous episodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to December 2012, several episodes explored aspects of the 2012 Mayan doomsday prophecy. Episodes focusing on Mesoamerica broadcast after 2012 make no mention of the 2012 phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series consists of 21 seasons, including a pilot episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program has attracted millions of viewers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;critical-response&#34;&gt;Critical response &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-response&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series has been criticized by historians, cosmologists, archaeologists, and other scientists for presenting pseudoscience, pseudohistory, and pseudoarchaeology as fact. Episodes are often characterized as &amp;ldquo;far-fetched&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;hugely speculative.&amp;rdquo; Many of the claims made by guests are not commonly accepted by the scientific community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brad Lockwood of &lt;em&gt;Forbes&lt;/em&gt; characterized &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; as an example of History&amp;rsquo;s channel drift toward &amp;ldquo;programs devoted to monsters, aliens, and conspiracies.&amp;rdquo; Alex Knapp, also of &lt;em&gt;Forbes&lt;/em&gt;, cited archaeologist Keith Fitzpatrick-Matthews&amp;rsquo; rebuke of History for treating &amp;ldquo;nonsense as though it were fact.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2011, &lt;em&gt;South Park&lt;/em&gt; parodied the series in the episode &amp;ldquo;A History Channel Thanksgiving.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Science writer Riley Black was critical of the series, accusing it of employing a Gish gallop technique to overwhelm the viewer with many &amp;ldquo;fictions and distortions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenneth Feder, Professor of Archaeology at Central Connecticut State University, stated that he was approached by producers with requests to appear in several episodes, but was not contacted again after stating his belief that the ancient astronaut hypothesis is &amp;ldquo;execrable bullshit.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, Vice on TV producer Jordan Kinley said of &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; claims: &amp;ldquo;You feel kind of lost when someone questions the historical narrative you&amp;rsquo;ve been taught. I don&amp;rsquo;t believe much of what&amp;rsquo;s talked about &amp;hellip; but I think it&amp;rsquo;s a good time for people to realize that some of our history is manufactured. Some of it is manufactured to be accurate, and some of it is manufactured to excuse horrible things that have happened.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 2019 issue of &lt;em&gt;Public Archaeology&lt;/em&gt;, Franco D. Rossi of Johns Hopkins University characterized &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; and its fans as a &amp;ldquo;science fiction fandom&amp;rdquo; which also trafficked in &amp;ldquo;misinformation&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;conspiracies.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2020, podcaster Brian Dunning challenged and debunked many of the claims featured on &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;critical-response-by-guests&#34;&gt;Critical response by guests &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-response-by-guests&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many guests featured in episodes of the series have publicly expressed skepticism of the series&amp;rsquo; premise or of the ancient astronaut hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a 2014 hearing of the House Committee on Science, Seth Shostak said that there is not any evidence which has convinced him &amp;ldquo;that we were visited in [historical] times.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a 2018 episode of &lt;em&gt;The Joe Rogan Experience&lt;/em&gt;, Robert Schoch said promoters of the ancient astronaut hypothesis &amp;ldquo;want everything to be &amp;lsquo;ancient aliens&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;, which in his view was &amp;ldquo;sort of a cop-out&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;William Shatner, who appeared in the Season 16 episode &amp;ldquo;William Shatner Meets &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, told &lt;em&gt;Inverse&lt;/em&gt;: &amp;ldquo;I had some spirited discussions with these experts who believe aliens were here, and like most people, I was dubious about the whole thing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;related-media&#34;&gt;Related media &lt;a href=&#34;#related-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many guests featured on &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; appear in other History channel series and specials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ancient-aliens-meme&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; meme &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-aliens-meme&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tsoukalos&amp;rsquo;s appearances in &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; inspired a meme highlighting his unusual hairstyle overlaid with the caption: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m not saying it was aliens &amp;hellip; but &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-con&#34;&gt;Alien Con &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-con&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2016 to 2018, A&amp;amp;E Networks co-produced several installments of Alien Con, a fan convention inspired by the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#heading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_Aliens&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_Aliens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
