<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Manga on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/manga/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Manga on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 16:02:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/manga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dover Demon</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_670cdf070164/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 16:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_670cdf070164/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;dover-demon&#34;&gt;Dover Demon &lt;a href=&#34;#dover-demon&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dover Demon is a creature reportedly sighted in Dover, Massachusetts, in April 1977.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sightings&#34;&gt;Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section details the reported sightings of the Dover Demon in April 1977. William &amp;ldquo;Bill&amp;rdquo; Bartlett, John Baxter, and Abby Brabham, all teenagers at the time, independently reported seeing a strange creature. Bartlett described it as about 4 feet tall with glowing orange eyes and no nose or mouth, with a watermelon-shaped head, on Farm Street in Dover. Baxter reported a similar creature on Miller Hill Road, and Brabham claimed to have seen it on Springdale Avenue the following night. The teenagers drew sketches of the creature, with Bartlett swearing on a stack of Bibles to the accuracy of his drawing. The locations of the sightings, when plotted on a map, formed a straight line over 2 miles. The sightings became public in May 1977, and a local investigator noted similarities to the creatures in the Kelly–Hopkinsville encounter. The Mutual UFO Network investigated the sightings, even though no UFOs were reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;possible-explanations&#34;&gt;Possible explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#possible-explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section explores potential explanations for the Dover Demon sightings. One suggestion is that the creature was a foal or a moose calf. Skeptic Joe Nickell proposes it was likely a snowy owl, citing its size, plumage reflecting yellow headlights, and the possibility that the &amp;ldquo;long spindly arms&amp;rdquo; were partially opened wings. Police suggested the sightings were a school vacation hoax. Ben Radford suggests the sightings were influenced by the release of &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt; in 1977.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the Dover Demon&amp;rsquo;s appearances in popular culture. It was featured in an episode of the television series &lt;em&gt;Lost Tapes&lt;/em&gt; on Animal Planet in 2009. The Dover Demon appears as a character in the comic book series &lt;em&gt;Proof&lt;/em&gt;, where it can see into the future, and in &lt;em&gt;The Perhapanauts&lt;/em&gt;. It also made appearances in &lt;em&gt;The Pound: Ghouls Night Out&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Hack/Slash: Entry Wound&lt;/em&gt;. A Dover Demon appears in the webcomic &lt;em&gt;Gunnerkrigg Court&lt;/em&gt;. In the manga series &lt;em&gt;Dandadan&lt;/em&gt;, an alien known as Dover Demon takes the form of a crustacean-like alien with the ability to transform into a stronger form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dover_Demon&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dover_Demon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
