<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Match-Three on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/match-three/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Match-Three on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 14:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/match-three/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Hive</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_4d3214fd7917/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_4d3214fd7917/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-hive&#34;&gt;Alien Hive &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-hive&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Hive&lt;/em&gt; is a puzzle video game developed and published by Malaysia-based studio Appxplore. It was released in March 2013 for iOS, Android, and Windows Phone platforms. The game combines match-three and sliding puzzle mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gameplay&#34;&gt;Gameplay &lt;a href=&#34;#gameplay&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The core gameplay involves swiping tiles to match eggs and aliens, with the goal of hatching, breeding, and evolving them into the Supreme Alien. Players aim to build the ultimate alien hive by matching resource tiles. Players must avoid Naughty Bots and use power-ups to eliminate them, while also trying to minimize the number of moves used. As players progress, they encounter more aliens and uncover their mysteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magic Fruit, collected by merging seeds into saplings, is essential for evolving Supreme Aliens. These fruits allow players to merge similar-level items using only two of a kind instead of three. Evolved Supreme Aliens can be activated using gold to provide special bonuses in future games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-app-purchase&#34;&gt;In App Purchase &lt;a href=&#34;#in-app-purchase&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Hive&lt;/em&gt; incorporates microtransactions, where players can exchange real money for in-game gold to purchase consumable items. This aspect of the game has faced criticism, with some reviewers suggesting that microtransactions are almost necessary to progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Hive&lt;/em&gt; received an average score of 70 out of 100 based on reviews aggregated by Metacritic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 2015, the game had achieved over 3 million downloads across all platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including links to the game&amp;rsquo;s page on Appxplore&amp;rsquo;s website, the Google Play Store, and reviews from sites like Gamezebo and Vulcan Post. These references provide verification for the information presented in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the official website of &lt;em&gt;Alien Hive&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Hive&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Hive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
