<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloning on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/cloning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloning on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:54:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/cloning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Resurrection (1997 Film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_73f8e3c7928a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_73f8e3c7928a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-resurrection-1997-film&#34;&gt;Alien Resurrection (1997 Film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-resurrection-1997-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry provides a detailed overview of the 1997 science fiction horror film &lt;em&gt;Alien Resurrection&lt;/em&gt;, directed by Jean-Pierre Jeunet and written by Joss Whedon. It covers various aspects of the film, including its plot, cast, production, release, reception, and related media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film&amp;rsquo;s story unfolds 200 years after &lt;em&gt;Alien 3&lt;/em&gt;. Military scientists aboard the USM &lt;em&gt;Auriga&lt;/em&gt; clone Ellen Ripley (Ripley 8) from pre-death blood samples to extract an Alien queen embryo. The scientists extract the embryo, raise it, and collect its eggs while keeping Ripley 8 alive for further study. Ripley 8 possesses enhanced abilities due to the Xenomorph queen&amp;rsquo;s DNA. A group of mercenaries, including Elgyn, Johner, Christie, Vriess, Hillard, and Call, arrives on the &lt;em&gt;Auriga&lt;/em&gt; with abducted humans for use as Alien hosts. The Aliens escape, and Ripley 8 and the mercenaries attempt to escape and destroy the &lt;em&gt;Auriga&lt;/em&gt; before it reaches Earth. Key plot points include Ripley 8&amp;rsquo;s discovery of failed cloning attempts, the Xenomorph queen giving birth to a human-Alien hybrid (the Newborn), and the &lt;em&gt;Auriga&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s collision course with Earth. The survivors escape on the &lt;em&gt;Betty&lt;/em&gt; as the &lt;em&gt;Auriga&lt;/em&gt; crashes into Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the main actors and their respective characters in &lt;em&gt;Alien Resurrection&lt;/em&gt;. Sigourney Weaver stars as Ripley 8, a clone of Ellen Ripley. Winona Ryder plays Annalee Call, a synthetic crew member of the &lt;em&gt;Betty&lt;/em&gt;. Other notable cast members include Dominique Pinon as Dom Vriess, Ron Perlman as Ron Johner, Gary Dourdan as Gary Christie, Michael Wincott as Frank Elgyn, Dan Hedaya as General Martin Perez, J. E. Freeman as Dr. Mason Wren, and Brad Dourif as Dr. Jonathan Gediman. Tom Woodruff Jr. is credited as the lead Alien, Alien queen, and the Newborn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the film&amp;rsquo;s production, including its origins, direction and design, creature design, filming, and visual effects. Joss Whedon was hired to write the script. Sigourney Weaver returned as Ripley and received a co-producer credit. Danny Boyle and Peter Jackson were considered to direct before Jean-Pierre Jeunet was chosen. The special effects company Amalgamated Dynamics Incorporated (ADI) was hired to design and modify the Alien creatures. Filming took place at Fox studios in Los Angeles, California. The underwater scene was filmed in a reconstructed tank at Fox Studios. Blue Sky Studios created the first CGI Aliens to appear on film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;Music &lt;a href=&#34;#music&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the film&amp;rsquo;s score, composed by John Frizzell. Frizzell was hired after Robert Kraft was impressed with his work on &lt;em&gt;The Empty Mirror&lt;/em&gt;. Jeunet requested a unique score, incorporating themes of romance and eroticism. The cue &amp;ldquo;They Swim&amp;rdquo; took one month to complete. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m Popeye the Sailor Man&amp;rdquo; is whistled by Dom Vriess and is acknowledged in the credits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the film&amp;rsquo;s theatrical and home media release. &lt;em&gt;Alien Resurrection&lt;/em&gt; premiered in Paris on November 6, 1997, before opening in France on November 12. It was released in the United States and Canada on November 26. The film was released on VHS, LaserDisc, and DVD on June 2, 1998. It was released on Blu-ray as part of the &lt;em&gt;Alien Anthology&lt;/em&gt; box set in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;special-editions&#34;&gt;Special Editions &lt;a href=&#34;#special-editions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the special editions of the film, including an alternate version included on the &lt;em&gt;Alien Quadrilogy&lt;/em&gt; DVD box set in 2003. The alternate version includes different opening and closing scenes, references to Newt, and scenes of the &lt;em&gt;Betty&lt;/em&gt; landing on Earth. Jeunet has stated that the theatrical cut is his preferred version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the film&amp;rsquo;s box office performance and critical reception. &lt;em&gt;Alien Resurrection&lt;/em&gt; grossed $161.4 million worldwide. It received mixed reviews from critics, who praised Weaver&amp;rsquo;s performance and Jeunet&amp;rsquo;s direction but criticized the screenplay. The film was nominated for six Saturn Awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-media&#34;&gt;Other Media &lt;a href=&#34;#other-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists other media related to the film, including a book titled &lt;em&gt;Making of Alien Resurrection&lt;/em&gt;, a novelization by A.C. Crispin, a comic book adaptation by Dark Horse Comics, and a video game for the PlayStation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;future&#34;&gt;Future &lt;a href=&#34;#future&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses potential sequels and related projects. Joss Whedon had written an Earth-set script for &lt;em&gt;Alien 5&lt;/em&gt;, but Sigourney Weaver was not interested. James Cameron had been collaborating on a fifth &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; film before 20th Century Fox greenlit &lt;em&gt;Alien vs. Predator&lt;/em&gt;. Ridley Scott expressed interest in a new &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; project. &lt;em&gt;Prometheus&lt;/em&gt; was released in 2012, followed by &lt;em&gt;Alien: Covenant&lt;/em&gt; in 2017. A new film, &lt;em&gt;Alien: Romulus&lt;/em&gt;, was released on August 16, 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Resurrection&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Resurrection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
