<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UFOs on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ufos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UFOs on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 18:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ufos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cattle mutilation</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ee1c97534fee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 18:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ee1c97534fee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;cattle-mutilation&#34;&gt;Cattle Mutilation &lt;a href=&#34;#cattle-mutilation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cattle mutilation refers to the killing and mutilation of cattle (and other animals) under unusual and often bloodless circumstances. The phenomenon is often linked to paranormal or supernatural explanations, including cults, government agencies, cryptids like the chupacabra, and extraterrestrials. Mutilations typically involve the removal of specific body parts such as ears, eyeballs, jaw flesh, tongues, lymph nodes, genitals, and rectums. Two independent federal investigations have been conducted in the United States to examine these incidents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;early-history&#34;&gt;Early History &lt;a href=&#34;#early-history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The earliest documented cases of unexplained livestock deaths occurred in England in 1606. Whole slaughters of sheep were reported, with only tallow and some inward parts taken. Charles Fort collected accounts of cattle mutilations in England during the late 19th and early 20th centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-snippy-horse-death-of-1967&#34;&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Snippy&amp;rdquo; Horse Death of 1967 &lt;a href=&#34;#the-snippy-horse-death-of-1967&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unexplained livestock deaths gained wider attention in 1967 with the case of &amp;ldquo;Snippy,&amp;rdquo; a horse found mutilated in Alamosa, Colorado. The Pueblo Chieftain published a story about the incident, noting the horse&amp;rsquo;s head and neck had been skinned and defleshed with precise cuts, and there was no blood at the scene. This case was the first to link extraterrestrial beings and UFOs to mutilations. Wadsworth Ayer investigated the case for the Condon Committee and concluded there was no evidence to support the assertion that the horse&amp;rsquo;s death was associated with abnormal causes. Alamosa County Sheriff Ben Phillips suggested a lightning strike as the cause. Later press coverage mentioned the horse had been shot. Two students from Alamosa State College confessed to shooting the horse several weeks after the case was publicized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;cattle-mutilations-19731980&#34;&gt;Cattle Mutilations 1973–1980 &lt;a href=&#34;#cattle-mutilations-19731980&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Waves of cattle mutilations were reported in Kansas, Nebraska, Colorado, and New Mexico during this period. In April 1973, sheriffs in Western Iowa reported unidentified helicopters involved in cattle and pig rustling. Similar rustling was reported in Missouri in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;1973-kansas-wave&#34;&gt;1973 Kansas Wave &lt;a href=&#34;#1973-kansas-wave&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In June 1973, Cloud County sheriff Fred Modlin warned the public about a caller posing as a USDA official conducting a survey of herd population and locations. A series of butchered cows were found on farms near Munden, Kansas. The right ear was often removed. Local press speculated about a &amp;lsquo;Mad Dog&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;phantom&amp;rsquo; Butcher. By December, law enforcement reported investigating 40 mutilations across Kansas and Nebraska. State Senator Ross Doyen reported a cattle mutilation on his ranch. The Kansas Brand Commissioner&amp;rsquo;s office determined that most of the deaths and removal of sex organs were the result of natural causes including predation, &amp;ldquo;[shipping fever](Shipping fever)&amp;rdquo; and [blackleg](Blackleg_(disease). Modlin disagreed with these conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;1974-nebraska-wave&#34;&gt;1974 Nebraska Wave &lt;a href=&#34;#1974-nebraska-wave&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reports resumed in April 1974, when a Nebraska cow was discovered mutilated and drained of blood. The North American Newspaper Alliance reported on the 1973 mutilations along with sightings of unidentified helicopters. In May, two mutilations were reported in Mills County, Iowa. By June 1974, mutilations were reported in Lancaster County, Nebraska. Custer Country reported similar helicopter sightings and armed patrols. On August 14, 1974, the Cascade County, Montana Sheriff&amp;rsquo;s Office received its first report of a mutilated cow. An unidentified helicopter was spotted hovering 400 feet above where a mutilated cow would later be discovered near Agnew, Nebraska. Knox County Sheriff Herbert Thompson reported that armed civilians had begun patrols in response to repeated helicopter sightings. Cloud County Attorney William Walsh told press of a jailhouse informant who claimed to be a former cult member and opined the mutilations were likely the result of devil-worshiping cultists. State Sen. John Decamp called on authorities to coordinate an investigation into the mutilations. A rancher near Hartington apparently thwarted a mutilation in progress when he found a helicopter above his field. Authorities cautioned the public not to shoot at aircraft. Over 50 law enforcement officials from 24 counties attended a meeting at the Knox County Courthouse in Center, Nebraska to discuss the mutilations. South Dakota Attorney General Kermit Sande told press that a number of mutilations had been reported in the state. UFO expert J. Allen Hynek released a statement denying any link between UFOs and cattle mutilations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;1975-colorado&#34;&gt;1975 Colorado &lt;a href=&#34;#1975-colorado&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1975, the Colorado Associated Press voted the mutilations as the state&amp;rsquo;s top story. Senator Floyd K. Haskell contacted the FBI asking for help due to public concern. He claimed there had been 130 mutilations in Colorado alone, and further reports across nine states. A 1979 FBI report indicated that, according to investigations by the New Mexico State Police, there had been an estimated 8,000 mutilations in Colorado, causing approximately $1 million in damages. In January 1975, the Michigan ATF tasked Donald E. Flickinger with investigating the mutilations. In May 1975, the Colorado Bureau of Investigation opened an investigation under the leadership of Carl Whiteside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;1976-dulce-new-mexico&#34;&gt;1976 Dulce, New Mexico &lt;a href=&#34;#1976-dulce-new-mexico&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On June 13, 1976, Dulce rancher Manuel Gomez reported a mutilation to Officer Gabe Valdez of the New Mexico State Patrol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;1979-public-meeting&#34;&gt;1979 Public Meeting &lt;a href=&#34;#1979-public-meeting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On April 20, 1979, U.S. Attorney R. E. Thompson and US Senator Harrison Schmidt held a public meeting about cattle mutilations. Paul Bennewitz approached Valdez and reported having seen unidentified lights over Kirtland Air Force Base. On May 2, 1979, Valdez told press that two drugs had been found in the remains of a mutilated bull found in Torrance County on February 15. On June 14, 1981, investigators found a mutilated cow at the Gomez ranch with a large amount of radar chaff nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;later-incidents&#34;&gt;Later Incidents &lt;a href=&#34;#later-incidents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many cases of mutilation have been reported worldwide since the 1967 Snippy incident, chiefly in the Americas and Australia. In South America, an estimated 3,500 incidents have occurred since 2002. In 1993, photographic evidence surfaced of a mutilated male human corpse that was found near the Guarapiranga reservoir of São Paulo, Brazil in 1988.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;characteristics&#34;&gt;Characteristics &lt;a href=&#34;#characteristics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cattle death due to natural causes are extremely common. Unusual cattle deaths are characterized by absence of sex organs, udders, tongues, anus, rectum, and sometimes ears or eyes. Cuts were described as &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;surgical&amp;rdquo;. Some animals were reported to have been drained of blood but with no sign of blood in the immediate area or even around their wounds. According to Howard Burgess, nearly 90 percent of mutilated cattle are between four and five years old. In some cases, strange marks or imprints near the site have been found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;laboratory-reports&#34;&gt;Laboratory Reports &lt;a href=&#34;#laboratory-reports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Laboratory reports carried out on some mutilated animals have shown unusually high or low levels of vitamins or minerals in tissue samples, and the presence of chemicals not normally found in animals. In one case documented by New Mexico police and the FBI, an 11-month-old cross Hereford-Charolais bull, belonging to a Mr. Manuel Gomez of Dulce, New Mexico, was found mutilated on March 24, 1978. Los Alamos detected the presence of naturally occurring &lt;em&gt;Clostridium&lt;/em&gt; bacteria in the heart. Samples from the animal&amp;rsquo;s liver were found to be completely devoid of copper and to contain 4 times the normal level of zinc, potassium and phosphorus. Blood samples taken at the scene were reported to be &amp;ldquo;light pink in color&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Did not clot after several days&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;helicopter-sightings&#34;&gt;Helicopter Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#helicopter-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On July 15, 1974, two unregistered helicopters were reported to have opened fire on Robert Smith Jr. while he was driving his tractor on his farm in Honey Creek, Iowa. On August 20, 1974, the &lt;em&gt;Lincoln Journal Star&lt;/em&gt; reported that residents had seen unidentified helicopters shining spotlights into fields where mutilated cows were later found. By 1975, some ranchers formed armed vigilante groups to patrol their fields at night. In 1976, two Cache County, Utah, police officers reportedly confronted several men in an unmarked U.S. Army helicopter at a small community airport in Cache County. On April 8, 1979, three police officers in Dulce, New Mexico, reported a mysterious aircraft which resembled a U.S. military helicopter hovering around a site following a wave of alleged mutilation which claimed 16 cows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;official-investigations&#34;&gt;Official Investigations &lt;a href=&#34;#official-investigations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The New Mexico Livestock Board sought assistance from the Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory. Colorado Bureau of Investigation agents went undercover to investigate. Oklahoma convened a task force. Federal authorities launched a comprehensive investigation of the mutilation phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bureau-of-alcohol-tobacco-and-firearms&#34;&gt;Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms &lt;a href=&#34;#bureau-of-alcohol-tobacco-and-firearms&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In January 1975, the Minnesota field office of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms (ATF) launched their own investigation into the phenomenon, headed by Agent Donald Flickinger. Flickinger was tasked with investigating the possible connections between cults and the mutilation of cattle. Flickinger recorded a number of &amp;ldquo;unusual&amp;rdquo; incidents and circumstantial evidence, but was unable to find sufficient evidence of cult involvement for the ATF to take further action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;colorado-bureau-of-investigation&#34;&gt;Colorado Bureau of Investigation &lt;a href=&#34;#colorado-bureau-of-investigation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In May 197&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle_mutilation&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle_mutilation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
