<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UFOs on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ufos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UFOs on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 09:29:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ufos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Area 51</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1bb36472371e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 09:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1bb36472371e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;area-51&#34;&gt;Area 51 &lt;a href=&#34;#area-51&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Area 51, officially called Homey Airport (KXTA) or Groom Lake, is a highly classified United States Air Force (USAF) facility located within the Nevada Test and Training Range. It&amp;rsquo;s a remote detachment administered by Edwards Air Force Base. While details of its operations are not public, it&amp;rsquo;s believed to support the development and testing of experimental aircraft and weapons systems. The USAF and CIA acquired the site in 1955, primarily for flight testing the Lockheed U-2 aircraft. The intense secrecy surrounding the base has made it a frequent subject of conspiracy theories and a central component of unidentified flying object (UFO) folklore. The CIA publicly acknowledged the base&amp;rsquo;s existence in 2013, following a Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) request. Area 51 is located in southern Nevada, 83 miles (134 km) north-northwest of Las Vegas. The surrounding area, including the town of Rachel, is a popular tourist destination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography &lt;a href=&#34;#geography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;area-51-1&#34;&gt;Area 51 &lt;a href=&#34;#area-51-1&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The original rectangular base is part of the &amp;ldquo;Groom box,&amp;rdquo; a rectangular area of restricted airspace. It&amp;rsquo;s connected to the Nevada Test Site (NTS) road network, with roads leading to Mercury and Yucca Flat. Groom Lake Road runs northeast through the Jumbled Hills, past a security checkpoint, and descends to the Tikaboo Valley, converging with State Route 375, the &amp;ldquo;Extraterrestrial Highway,&amp;rdquo; south of Rachel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;groom-lake&#34;&gt;Groom Lake &lt;a href=&#34;#groom-lake&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Groom Lake is a salt flat in Nevada used for runways of the Nellis Bombing Range Test Site airport (XTA/KXTA) on the north of the Area 51 USAF military installation. The lake is located within the Groom Lake Valley portion of the Tonopah Basin, south of Rachel, Nevada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The origin of the name &amp;ldquo;Area 51&amp;rdquo; is unclear. The correct names for the facility are Homey Airport (XTA/KXTA) and Groom Lake. The facility has also been referred to as &amp;ldquo;Dreamland&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Paradise Ranch&amp;rdquo;. Lead and silver were discovered in the Groom Range in 1864, and the English company &lt;em&gt;Groome Lead Mines Limited&lt;/em&gt; financed the Conception Mines in the 1870s. The airfield on the Groom Lake site began service in 1942 as Indian Springs Air Force Auxiliary Field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-2-program&#34;&gt;U-2 program &lt;a href=&#34;#u-2-program&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The CIA established the Groom Lake test facility in April 1955 for Project AQUATONE: the development of the Lockheed U-2 strategic reconnaissance aircraft. Project director Richard M. Bissell Jr. understood that the flight test and pilot training programs could not be conducted at Edwards Air Force Base or Lockheed&amp;rsquo;s Palmdale facility. Lockheed&amp;rsquo;s U-2 designer Kelly Johnson stated that Groom Lake was ideal due to the dry lake bed and the protection from visitors afforded by the Emigrant Valley&amp;rsquo;s mountain ranges and the NTS perimeter. The CIA asked the AEC to acquire the land, designated &amp;ldquo;Area 51&amp;rdquo; on the map, and to add it to the Nevada Test Site. Johnson named the area &amp;ldquo;Paradise Ranch&amp;rdquo; to encourage workers to move to the new facility. The Ranch initially consisted of little more than a few shelters, workshops, and trailer homes. The base received its first U-2 delivery on 24 July 1955.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;oxcart-program&#34;&gt;OXCART program &lt;a href=&#34;#oxcart-program&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Project OXCART was established in August 1959 for work on the Lockheed A-12. This included testing at Groom Lake, which had inadequate facilities. A-12 test facility construction began in September 1960, including a new runway. Reynolds Electrical and Engineering Company (REECo) began construction of &amp;ldquo;Project 51&amp;rdquo; on 1 October 1960. The contractor upgraded base facilities and built a new runway diagonally across the southwest corner of the lakebed. They marked an Archimedean spiral on the dry lake approximately two miles (three kilometers) across so that an A-12 pilot approaching the end of the overrun could abort instead of plunging into the sagebrush. Area 51 pilots called it &amp;ldquo;The Hook&amp;rdquo;. By August 1961, construction of the essential facilities was complete. Security was enhanced for the arrival of OXCART and the small mine was closed in the Groom basin. In January 1962, the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) expanded the restricted airspace in the vicinity of Groom Lake. The CIA facility received eight USAF F-101 Voodoos for training, two T-33 Shooting Star trainers, a C-130 Hercules for cargo transport, a U-3A for administrative purposes, a helicopter for search and rescue, and a Cessna 180 for liaison use, and Lockheed provided an F-104 Starfighter for use as a chase plane. The first A-12 test aircraft was covertly trucked from Burbank on 26 February 1962 and arrived at Groom Lake on 28 February. It made its first flight 26 April 1962 when the base had over 1,000 personnel. Groom was also the site of the first Lockheed D-21 drone test flight on 22 December 1964. By the end of 1963, nine A-12s were at Area 51, assigned to the CIA-operated &amp;ldquo;1129th Special Activities Squadron&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;d-21-tagboard&#34;&gt;D-21 Tagboard &lt;a href=&#34;#d-21-tagboard&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following the loss of Gary Powers&amp;rsquo; U-2 over the Soviet Union, there were several discussions about using the A-12 OXCART as an unpiloted drone aircraft. The Air Force agreed to fund the study of a high-speed, high-altitude drone aircraft in October 1962. The project designated &amp;ldquo;Q-12&amp;rdquo; was renamed the &amp;ldquo;D-21&amp;rdquo;. (The &amp;ldquo;12&amp;rdquo; was reversed to &amp;ldquo;21&amp;rdquo;). &amp;ldquo;Tagboard&amp;rdquo; was the project&amp;rsquo;s code name. The first D-21 was completed in the spring of 1964 by Lockheed. It was to be carried by a two-seat derivative of the A-12, designated the &amp;ldquo;M-21&amp;rdquo;. Difficulties were addressed throughout 1964 and 1965 at Groom Lake with various technical issues. The first D-21 launch was made on 5 March 1966 with a successful flight. An accident on 30 July 1966 with a fully fueled D-21, on a planned checkout flight, suffered from an unstart of the drone after its separation, causing it to collide with the M-21 launch aircraft. Kelly Johnson personally cancelled the entire program. A number of D-21s had already been produced, and rather than scrapping the whole effort, Johnson again proposed to the Air Force that they be launched from a B-52H bomber. The test missions were flown out of Groom Lake, with the actual launches over the Pacific. Several more tests were made, none of which met with success. On 15 July 1971, Kelly Johnson received a wire canceling the D-21B program. The remaining drones were transferred by a C-5A and placed in dead storage. The tooling used to build the D-21Bs was ordered destroyed. In 1993, the B-52/D-21B program was made public. That same year, the surviving D-21Bs were released to museums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;foreign-technology-evaluation&#34;&gt;Foreign technology evaluation &lt;a href=&#34;#foreign-technology-evaluation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the Cold War, one of the missions carried out by the United States was the test and evaluation of captured Soviet fighter aircraft. Beginning in the late 1960s, and for several decades, Area 51 played host to an assortment of Soviet-built aircraft. Munir Redfa&amp;rsquo;s defection with a Mikoyan-Gurevich MiG-21 from Iraq for Israel&amp;rsquo;s Mossad in Operation Diamond led to the HAVE DOUGHNUT, HAVE DRILL and HAVE FERRY programs. The first MiGs flown in the United States were used to evaluate the aircraft in performance, technical, and operational capabilities, pitting the types against U.S. fighters. In August 1966, Iraqi Air Force fighter pilot Captain Munir Redfa defected, flying his MiG-21 to Israel after being ordered to attack Iraqi Kurd villages with napalm. His aircraft was transferred to Groom Lake in late 1967 for study. Israel loaned the MiG-21 to the US Air Force from January 1968 to April 1968. In 1968, the US Air Force and Navy jointly formed a project known as HAVE DOUGHNUT in which Air Force Systems Command, Tactical Air Command, and the U.S. Navy&amp;rsquo;s Air Test and Evaluation Squadron Four (VX-4) flew this acquired Soviet-made aircraft in simulated air combat training. On 12 August 1968, two Syrian air force lieutenants, Walid Adham and Radfan Rifai, took off in a pair of MiG-17Fs on a training mission. They lost their way and, believing they were over Lebanon, landed at the Betzet Landing Field in northern Israel. Prior to the end of 1968 these MiG-17s were transferred from Israeli stocks and added to the Area 51 test fleet. The data from the HAVE DOUGHNUT and HAVE DRILL tests were provided to the newly formed Top Gun school at NAS Miramar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Area_51&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Area_51&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cattle mutilation</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ee1c97534fee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 18:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ee1c97534fee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;cattle-mutilation&#34;&gt;Cattle Mutilation &lt;a href=&#34;#cattle-mutilation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cattle mutilation refers to the killing and mutilation of cattle (and other animals) under unusual and anomalous circumstances, often described as bloodless. The phenomenon is frequently linked to paranormal or supernatural explanations, including cults, government agencies, cryptids like the chupacabra, and extraterrestrials. The article notes that it has been the subject of two independent federal investigations in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-history&#34;&gt;Early History &lt;a href=&#34;#early-history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The earliest documented cases of unexplained livestock deaths occurred in England in 1606. Charles Fort collected accounts of cattle mutilations in England during the late 19th and early 20th centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-snippy-horse-death-of-1967&#34;&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Snippy&amp;rdquo; Horse Death of 1967 &lt;a href=&#34;#the-snippy-horse-death-of-1967&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The unexplained death and mutilation of a horse named &amp;ldquo;Snippy&amp;rdquo; in Alamosa, Colorado, in 1967 brought the phenomenon to wider attention. The case involved precise cuts, a lack of blood, and a medicinal odor. This incident was the first to link mutilations to extraterrestrials and UFOs. Wadsworth Ayer&amp;rsquo;s investigation for the Condon Committee concluded there was no evidence of abnormal causes. Alamosa County Sheriff Ben Phillips suggested a lightning strike, but later reports mentioned the horse had been shot. Two students confessed to shooting the horse after the case gained publicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cattle-mutilations-19731980&#34;&gt;Cattle Mutilations 1973–1980 &lt;a href=&#34;#cattle-mutilations-19731980&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This period saw waves of cattle mutilations reported in Kansas, Nebraska, Colorado, and New Mexico. In April 1973, sheriffs in Western Iowa reported unidentified helicopters involved in cattle and pig rustling. Similar rustling was reported in Missouri in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1973-kansas-wave&#34;&gt;1973 Kansas Wave &lt;a href=&#34;#1973-kansas-wave&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In June 1973, Cloud County sheriff Fred Modlin warned the public about suspicious phone calls from someone posing as a USDA official. A series of butchered cows were found on farms in Cloud County, with right ears removed. Local press speculated about a &amp;ldquo;Mad Dog&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;phantom&amp;rdquo; Butcher. By December, law enforcement reported a wave of cattle deaths in seven counties across Kansas and Nebraska, with sexual organs removed. State Senator Ross Doyen reported a cattle mutilation on his ranch. The Kansas Brand Commissioner&amp;rsquo;s office attributed most deaths to natural causes, but Modlin and others disagreed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1974-nebraska-wave&#34;&gt;1974 Nebraska Wave &lt;a href=&#34;#1974-nebraska-wave&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reports resumed in April 1974, with a Nebraska cow found mutilated and drained of blood. The North American Newspaper Alliance reported on the 1973 mutilations and unidentified helicopter sightings. Mutilations were reported in Mills County, Iowa, and Lancaster County, Nebraska. Custer County reported helicopter sightings and armed patrols. In August, an unidentified helicopter was spotted hovering above a field where a mutilated cow was later found near Agnew, Nebraska. Knox County Sheriff Herbert Thompson reported armed civilian patrols. Cloud County Attorney William Walsh mentioned a jailhouse informant who claimed the mutilations were the result of devil-worshiping cultists. State Sen. John Decamp called for a coordinated investigation. A rancher near Hartington apparently thwarted a mutilation in progress when he found a helicopter above his field. Authorities cautioned the public not to shoot at aircraft. The University of Nebraska&amp;rsquo;s Department of Veterinary Science disproved three mutilations, attributing them to natural causes. Law enforcement officials from 24 counties attended a meeting in Center, Nebraska, to discuss the mutilations. Three cases of alleged mutilations were reported in South Dakota. Newsweek became the first national outlet to cover the story, reporting 100 cattle mutilated in Nebraska, Kansas, and Iowa since May. South Dakota Attorney General Kermit Sande reported mutilations in the state. UFO expert J. Allen Hynek denied any link between UFOs and mutilations. Two mutilations were reported in Kandiyohi County, six in Swift County, and one in Meeker County, Minnesota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1975-colorado&#34;&gt;1975 Colorado &lt;a href=&#34;#1975-colorado&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1975, the Colorado Associated Press voted the mutilations as the state&amp;rsquo;s top story. Senator Floyd K. Haskell contacted the FBI for help due to public concern, claiming 130 mutilations in Colorado and reports across nine states. A 1979 FBI report indicated an estimated 8,000 mutilations in Colorado, causing approximately $1 million in damages. Donald E. Flickinger of the Michigan ATF investigated possible links to a &amp;ldquo;Hell-oriented biker gang.&amp;rdquo; The Colorado Bureau of Investigation opened an investigation under Carl Whiteside. The New York Times published a story examining cattle mutilations across 11 states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1976-dulce-new-mexico&#34;&gt;1976 Dulce, New Mexico &lt;a href=&#34;#1976-dulce-new-mexico&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;On June 13, 1976, Dulce rancher Manuel Gomez reported a mutilation to Officer Gabe Valdez of the New Mexico State Patrol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1979-public-meeting&#34;&gt;1979 Public Meeting &lt;a href=&#34;#1979-public-meeting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;On April 20, 1979, U.S. Attorney R. E. Thompson and US Senator Harrison Schmidt held a public meeting about cattle mutilations. Paul Bennewitz reported seeing unidentified lights over Kirtland Air Force Base. On May 2, 1979, Valdez reported that two drugs had been found in the remains of a mutilated bull, one to tranquilize the animal and another to remove blood. On June 14, 1981, investigators found a mutilated cow at the Gomez ranch with radar chaff nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;later-incidents&#34;&gt;Later Incidents &lt;a href=&#34;#later-incidents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many cases of mutilation have been reported worldwide since 1967, chiefly in the Americas and Australia. In South America, an estimated 3,500 incidents have occurred since 2002.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1993, photographic evidence surfaced of a mutilated male human corpse found near the Guarapiranga reservoir of São Paulo, Brazil, in 1988.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;characteristics&#34;&gt;Characteristics &lt;a href=&#34;#characteristics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unusual cattle deaths are characterized by the absence of sex organs, udders, tongues, anus, rectum, and sometimes ears or eyes. Cuts are described as &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;surgical.&amp;rdquo; Some animals are reported to have been drained of blood with no sign of blood in the immediate area. Howard Burgess stated that nearly 90 percent of mutilated cattle are between four and five years old. Strange marks or imprints near the site have been found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;laboratory-reports&#34;&gt;Laboratory Reports &lt;a href=&#34;#laboratory-reports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Laboratory reports on some mutilated animals have shown unusual levels of vitamins or minerals in tissue samples and the presence of chemicals not normally found in animals. In one case in Dulce, New Mexico, a bull was found mutilated with the rectum and sex organs removed. The animal&amp;rsquo;s heart and liver were found to be inconsistent with a normal case of death followed by predation. The liver was found to be completely devoid of copper and to contain 4 times the normal level of zinc, potassium, and phosphorus. Blood samples were reported to be &amp;ldquo;light pink in color&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Did not clot after several days.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;helicopter-sightings&#34;&gt;Helicopter Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#helicopter-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;On July 15, 1974, two unregistered helicopters were reported to have opened fire on Robert Smith Jr. in Honey Creek, Iowa. On August 20, 1974, the &lt;em&gt;Lincoln Journal Star&lt;/em&gt; reported that residents had seen unidentified helicopters shining spotlights into fields where mutilated cows were later found. By 1975, some ranchers formed armed vigilante groups. In 1976, two Cache County, Utah, police officers reportedly confronted several men in an unmarked U.S. Army helicopter. On April 8, 1979, three police officers in Dulce, New Mexico, reported a mysterious aircraft resembling a U.S. military helicopter hovering around a site following a wave of alleged mutilation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;official-investigations&#34;&gt;Official Investigations &lt;a href=&#34;#official-investigations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The New Mexico Livestock Board sought assistance from the Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory. Colorado Bureau of Investigation agents went undercover to investigate. Oklahoma convened a task force. Federal authorities launched a comprehensive investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bureau-of-alcohol-tobacco-and-firearms&#34;&gt;Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms &lt;a href=&#34;#bureau-of-alcohol-tobacco-and-firearms&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In January 1975, the Minnesota field office of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms (ATF) launched an investigation, headed by Agent Donald Flickinger, into possible connections between cults and cattle mutilation. Flickinger recorded unusual incidents and circumstantial evidence but was unable to find sufficient evidence of cult involvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;colorado-bureau-of-investigation&#34;&gt;Colorado Bureau of Investigation &lt;a href=&#34;#colorado-bureau-of-investigation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In May 1975, the Colorado Bureau of Investigation opened an investigation under the leadership of Carl Whiteside. 19 animals underwent necropsies at Colorado State University but no conclusive results emerged. The US Bureau of Land Management was forced to ground all helicopters in Eastern Colorado. By December, the CBI had investigated 203 reports of cattle mutilations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-mexico-state-police&#34;&gt;New Mexico State Police &lt;a href=&#34;#new-mexico-state-police&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;On June 13, 1976, the New Mexico State Police began an investigation, headed by Officer Gabe Valdez, with the assistance of Cattle Inspector Jim Dyad and Officer Howard Johnston of the New Mexico Department of Game and Fish. On the night of July 5, Burgess and Valdez screened the Gomez herd; five animals were found to have been marked with a chemical that fluoresced under ultraviolet light. On June 14, 1981, intact radar chaff was found near a mutilated cow on the Gomez ranch. This investigation reported finding evidence that some mutilated animals had been tranquilized and treated with an anti-coagulant prior to their mutilation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rommel-investigation&#34;&gt;Rommel Investigation &lt;a href=&#34;#rommel-investigation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beginning in May 1979, an investigation was funded by a grant from the Law Enforcement Assistance Administration and was headed by recently-retired FBI agent Kenneth Rommel. Rommel&amp;rsquo;s final report, released in June 1980, concluded that the mutilations were predominantly the result of natural&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle_mutilation&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle_mutilation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
