<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UFOs on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ufos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UFOs on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 13:04:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ufos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_9c34e91b7ea9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 13:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_9c34e91b7ea9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;national-defense-authorization-act-for-fiscal-year-2024&#34;&gt;National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024 &lt;a href=&#34;#national-defense-authorization-act-for-fiscal-year-2024&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024 (NDAA 2024) is a United States federal law that outlines the budget, expenditures, and policies of the U.S. Department of Defense (DOD) for fiscal year 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Defense Authorization Act is an annual bill proposed in the United States Congress that redefines the United States military budget for the following fiscal year. Each chamber of Congress introduced a version of the NDAA: H.R. 2670 in the House and S. 2226 in the Senate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The House passed their version on July 14, 2023 by a vote of 219–210. Led by Chuck Schumer and Mike Rounds, the Senate passed theirs on July 27, 2023 by a vote of 86–11. The Senate then replaced H.R. 2670 with the text of S. 2226 and passed it by unanimous consent, and indefinitely postponed S. 2226. The House disagreed to the Senate amendment and asked to hold conference on September 19, with the Senate insisting on its amendment and agreeing to conference on November 15. The subsequent conference report was filed on December 6 (H. Rept. 118-301). The bill was approved by the Senate and House and sent to President Joe Biden on December 14. Biden signed it into law on December 22. In his signing statement, Biden expressed reservations about provisions that restrict the executive branch&amp;rsquo;s discretion in Guantanamo detainee transfers and raised constitutional concerns regarding congressional oversight and foreign policy authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;provisions&#34;&gt;Provisions &lt;a href=&#34;#provisions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section requires updating to reflect recent events or newly available information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;unidentified-flying-objects-ufos&#34;&gt;Unidentified flying objects (UFOs) &lt;a href=&#34;#unidentified-flying-objects-ufos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sections 1841 et seq. outline the creation and management of a comprehensive collection of government records on UFOs or unidentified anomalous phenomena (UAP) at the National Archives (NARA), detailing the processes for assembling, preserving, and providing public access to these records, along with specific protocols for their review, disclosure, and secure handling. NARA subsequently provided guidance to federal agencies to identify, organize, and disclose UAP records for the new collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sections 1687 and 7343 disallow use of funds or independent research and development (IRAD) indirect expenses for UFOs or UAP unless such material and information is made available the appropriate congressional committees and congressional leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Language on the topic of UFO/UAP was also included in the previous 2023 NDAA, the 2022 NDAA, the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022, as well as an accompanying Senate Select Committee on Intelligence report for the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;foreign-extortion-prevention-act&#34;&gt;Foreign Extortion Prevention Act &lt;a href=&#34;#foreign-extortion-prevention-act&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Foreign Extortion Prevention Act (FEPA) enables US authorities to prosecute foreign officials who demand or accept bribes from a US citizen, US company, or within a US jurisdiction. FEPA addresses a longstanding gap in US anti-bribery legislation by tackling the &amp;ldquo;demand&amp;rdquo; side of bribery. At the same time, the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act (FCPA) focuses on the &amp;ldquo;supply&amp;rdquo; side of bribery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;counter-extremist-working-group-defunded&#34;&gt;Counter-extremist working group defunded &lt;a href=&#34;#counter-extremist-working-group-defunded&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Republicans opposed the anti-extremism working group created by Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin. That working group had been created by Austin after it became apparent that some service members and veterans had participated in the attack on the US Capitol January 6, 2021. That working group released recommendations at the end of 2021. Implementation, however, appeared to stall as Republicans increasingly opposed diversity, equity, and inclusion efforts in the military, which Republicans derided as &amp;ldquo;wokeness&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, a recent inspector general report found dozens of troops, who appeared to be advocating violent overthrow of the US government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The seriousness of this issue seems apparent from the fact that military and veterans have participated in other violent extremist events. For example, the Oklahoma City bomber, Timothy McVeigh, had served with distinction in Operation Desert Storm but had earned a reputation as a sergeant for assigning undesirable work to black servicemen and using derogatory language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nato-withdrawal&#34;&gt;NATO withdrawal &lt;a href=&#34;#nato-withdrawal&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Section 1250A prevents the President from withdrawing the United States from NATO without the approval of a two-thirds Senate supermajority or an act of Congress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;original-proposals&#34;&gt;Original proposals &lt;a href=&#34;#original-proposals&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original House bill contained provisions to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Space Force Personnel Management Act: Disestablish the regular Space Force in order to integrate both active duty and reserve personnel into one Space Force entity. This is to allow for better flexibility for the Space Force by replacing &amp;ldquo;active duty&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;sustained duty&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;full-time&amp;rdquo; status, and replacing &amp;ldquo;reserve&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;part-time&amp;rdquo; status. This change would only pertain to the Space Force and not to the other armed services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elevate the position of vice chief of the National Guard Bureau to hold a statutory rank of general.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Permanently establish the titles of commissioned officer ranks of the Space Force to be the same as the Army, Marine Corps, and Air Force.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authorize a $886 billion spending budget for national defense programs including:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A 5.2% pay increase for service members of the armed forces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Procurement of up to 13 &lt;em&gt;Virginia&lt;/em&gt;-class submarines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authorize the sale and transfer of defense articles and services relating to the implementation of the AUKUS partnership, including:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Up to three &lt;em&gt;Virginia&lt;/em&gt;-class submarines, one year after this act is passed, however the Navy doesn&amp;rsquo;t intend implement this until 2032.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Senate amendment contained:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UAP Disclosure Act: The Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena Disclosure Act of 2023 would direct the National Archives and Records Administration to collect and disclose records on unidentified flying objects (UFOs) or unidentified anomalous phenomena (UAP) no later than 25 years after enactment with a presumption of immediate disclosure. The U.S. president can certify that continued postponement can be made necessary by an identifiable harm to military defense, intelligence operations, law enforcement or conduct of foreign relations. The federal government would have eminent domain over recovered technologies of unknown origin (TUO) and biological evidence of non-human intelligence (NHI) that may be controlled by private persons or entities, such as aerospace companies. Legislation was necessary in part because UAP records had not been subject to mandatory declassification review due to exemptions under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 as well as an over-broad interpretation of &amp;ldquo;transclassified foreign nuclear information&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Intelligence Authorization Act (IAA) requires people currently or formerly under contract with the federal government to make all UFO/UAP material and information and a comprehensive list of all extraterrestrial or exotic UAP material available to the All-domain Anomaly Resolution Office (AARO).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A provision that prevents the President of the United States from withdrawing the U.S. from NATO without approval of a two-thirds Senate supermajority or an act of Congress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unidentified_Anomalous_Phenomena_Disclosure_Act&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unidentified_Anomalous_Phenomena_Disclosure_Act&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of UFO religions</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_c138a4063c7d/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_c138a4063c7d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-religions&#34;&gt;UFO Religions &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-religions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFO religions are groups that incorporate beliefs about communication with extraterrestrial beings into their religious doctrines. These groups often interpret major religions as being based on supernatural beings from heaven. Communication methods include telepathy and astral projection. A common belief is that humanity can be saved through education provided by aliens, leading to societal improvement. Alien abduction experiences can also contribute to the formation of these religions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for understanding UFO religions. It highlights that these religions generally involve belief in communication with extraterrestrial beings, often through physical contact, telepathy, or astral projection. These groups typically believe that aliens will save humanity by teaching them a better way to live, sometimes by taking believers to a more positive location. UFO religions emphasize spiritual growth and the evolution of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. Gordon Melton is identified as considering the &amp;ldquo;I AM&amp;rdquo; Activity, founded by Guy Ballard, as the first UFO religion. However, Christopher Hugh Partridge views it as a theosophical religion rather than a UFO religion. Partridge emphasizes the belief within UFO religions that supreme beings originate from other planets or planes, not from Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Roswell incident of 1947 is identified as a key event in the history of UFO spirituality, marking the emergence of UFOs into public consciousness. UFO religion is placed within the context of theosophical esotericism and New Age thought, with many groups believing that extraterrestrial beings are heralds of a new era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Aetherius Society, founded by George King in 1955, is described as one of the first and most enduring UFO cults. Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate and the Order of the Solar Temple are mentioned as controversial groups combining UFO beliefs with contactee assertions. Scientology is also discussed as a UFO religion due to its Xenu cosmogony and space opera elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;list&#34;&gt;List &lt;a href=&#34;#list&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a table listing various UFO religions, their founders, and the year they were founded. The list includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aetherius Society:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by George King in 1955.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ashtar Galactic Command:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Thelma B. Terrill (&amp;ldquo;Tuella&amp;rdquo;) in 1977.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CEIRUS:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Jean Miguères in 1987.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chen Tao:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Hon-ming Chen in 1993.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christ Brotherhood:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Wallace C. Halsey in 1956.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cosmic Circle of Fellowship:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by William R. Ferguson in 1955.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fiat Lux:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Uriella in 1980.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freie Interessengemeinschaft für Grenz- und Geisteswissenschaften und Ufologiestudien:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Billy Meier in the 1970s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ground Crew Project:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Sheldon Nidle in the 1980s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Marshall Applewhite and Bonnie Nettles in the 1970s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;I AM&amp;rdquo; Activity:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Guy Ballard in the 1930s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industrial Church of the New World Comforter:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Allen Michael in 1973.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark-Age:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Charles Boyd Gentzel and Pauline Sharpe in 1962.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nation of Islam:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Wallace Fard Muhammad in 1930.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Néo-Phare:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Arnaud Mussy in 2001.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nuwaubian Nation:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Dwight York in the 1970s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Order of the Solar Temple:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Joseph Di Mambro and Luc Jouret in 1984.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raëlism:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Raël in 1974.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rational Culture:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Manoel Jacintho Coelho in the 1930s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sanctuary of Thought:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Truman Bethurum in the 1950s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Seekers:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Charles Laughead (aka &amp;ldquo;Dr. Armstrong&amp;rdquo;) or Dorothy Martin (aka &amp;ldquo;Marian Keech&amp;rdquo;) in 1953.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Siderella:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Jean-Paul Appel-Guéry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scientology:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by L. Ron Hubbard in 1952.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unarius:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Ernest Norman and Ruth Norman in 1954.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universe People:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Ivo A. Benda in 1997.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Urantia movement:&lt;/strong&gt; Authorship of &lt;em&gt;The Urantia Book&lt;/em&gt; is unknown and disputed. The book alleges it was written by celestial beings. Founded between 1924 and 1955.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vale do Amanhecer:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Neiva Chaves Zelaya in the 1960s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics and links for further exploration, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Religion portal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outer space portal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doomsday cult&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of new religious movements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of ufologists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of UFO organizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO_religions&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO_religions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cattle mutilation</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ee1c97534fee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 18:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ee1c97534fee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;cattle-mutilation&#34;&gt;Cattle Mutilation &lt;a href=&#34;#cattle-mutilation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cattle mutilation refers to the killing and mutilation of cattle and other animals under unusual and often bloodless circumstances. The phenomenon has been linked to paranormal and supernatural explanations, as well as more mundane causes. Mutilations typically involve the removal of organs such as the eyes, tongue, and genitals. Reports of such incidents span the globe, involving various livestock and wild animals. Explanations range from natural decomposition and predation to cults, government agencies, cryptids like the chupacabra, and extraterrestrials. The United States has conducted two federal investigations into the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-history&#34;&gt;Early History &lt;a href=&#34;#early-history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documented reports of unexplained livestock deaths date back to 1606 in England, where sheep were found slaughtered with only tallow and some inward parts removed. Charles Fort collected accounts of similar mutilations in England during the late 19th and early 20th centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-snippy-horse-death-of-1967&#34;&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Snippy&amp;rdquo; Horse Death of 1967 &lt;a href=&#34;#the-snippy-horse-death-of-1967&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unexplained death and mutilation of a horse named &amp;ldquo;Snippy&amp;rdquo; in Alamosa, Colorado, in 1967 brought the phenomenon to wider attention. The &lt;em&gt;Pueblo Chieftain&lt;/em&gt; published a story about the incident, detailing the horse&amp;rsquo;s skinned and defleshed head and neck, as well as precise cuts on the body. The lack of blood and a medicinal odor at the scene fueled speculation about extraterrestrial involvement. Wadsworth Ayer&amp;rsquo;s investigation for the Condon Committee concluded there was no evidence of abnormal causes. Sheriff Ben Phillips initially attributed the death to a lightning strike. Later, two students confessed to shooting the horse weeks after the incident gained publicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cattle-mutilations-19731980&#34;&gt;Cattle Mutilations 1973–1980 &lt;a href=&#34;#cattle-mutilations-19731980&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This period saw a surge in reported cattle mutilations across Kansas, Nebraska, Colorado, and New Mexico. Unidentified helicopters were reported in connection with cattle and pig rustling in Western Iowa (April 1973) and Missouri (August 1973).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1973-kansas-wave&#34;&gt;1973 Kansas Wave &lt;a href=&#34;#1973-kansas-wave&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June 1973, Cloud County sheriff Fred Modlin warned the public about suspicious phone calls from someone posing as a USDA official. Several butchered cows were subsequently found in the county, with right ears removed. Local press speculated about a &amp;ldquo;Mad Dog&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;phantom&amp;rdquo; butcher. By December, law enforcement reported a wave of cattle deaths in seven counties across Kansas and Nebraska, with sexual organs removed. State Senator Ross Doyen reported a mutilation on his ranch. The Kansas Brand Commissioner&amp;rsquo;s office attributed most deaths to natural causes, a conclusion disputed by Modlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1974-nebraska-wave&#34;&gt;1974 Nebraska Wave &lt;a href=&#34;#1974-nebraska-wave&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports continued in April 1974 with a mutilated and blood-drained cow in Nebraska. The North American Newspaper Alliance reported on the 1973 mutilations and helicopter sightings. Mutilations were reported in Mills County, Iowa, with coyotes blamed. By June, Lancaster County, Nebraska, reported mutilations. Custer County reported helicopter sightings and armed patrols. In August, an unidentified helicopter was spotted shining a spotlight over a field where a mutilated cow was later found near Agnew, Nebraska. Knox County Sheriff Herbert Thompson reported armed civilian patrols due to helicopter sightings. Cloud County Attorney William Walsh suggested devil-worshiping cultists were responsible. State Sen. John Decamp called for a coordinated investigation. By late August, 25 mutilations were reported across five Nebraska counties. A rancher near Hartington apparently thwarted a mutilation in progress when a helicopter was spotted above his field. Authorities cautioned against shooting at aircraft. In September, an autopsy revealed a supposedly-mutilated cow died of bacterial infection. Over 50 law enforcement officials attended a meeting in Center, Nebraska, estimating 27 out of 80 cow deaths were suspected mutilations. South Dakota also reported alleged mutilations. &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; became the first national outlet to cover the story, reporting 100 cattle mutilated in Nebraska, Kansas, and Iowa since May. South Dakota Attorney General Kermit Sande confirmed mutilation reports in the state. UFO expert J. Allen Hynek denied any link between UFOs and mutilations. Minnesota reported mutilations in Kandiyohi, Swift, and Meeker counties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1975-colorado&#34;&gt;1975 Colorado &lt;a href=&#34;#1975-colorado&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1975, the Colorado Associated Press voted the mutilations as the state&amp;rsquo;s top story. Senator Floyd K. Haskell contacted the FBI, claiming 130 mutilations in Colorado and reports across nine states. A 1979 FBI report estimated 8,000 mutilations in Colorado, causing $1 million in damages. Donald E. Flickinger of the Michigan ATF investigated possible links to a &amp;ldquo;Hell-oriented biker gang.&amp;rdquo; The Colorado Bureau of Investigation opened an investigation under Carl Whiteside. &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; published a story examining cattle mutilations across 11 states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1976-dulce-new-mexico&#34;&gt;1976 Dulce, New Mexico &lt;a href=&#34;#1976-dulce-new-mexico&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 13, 1976, Dulce rancher Manuel Gomez reported a mutilation to Officer Gabe Valdez of the New Mexico State Patrol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1979-public-meeting&#34;&gt;1979 Public Meeting &lt;a href=&#34;#1979-public-meeting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 20, 1979, U.S. Attorney R. E. Thompson and US Senator Harrison Schmidt held a public meeting about cattle mutilations, attended by about 80 people. Paul Bennewitz reported seeing unidentified lights over Kirtland Air Force Base. In May, Valdez reported finding two drugs in a mutilated bull&amp;rsquo;s remains: Chlorpromazine (Thorazine) to tranquilize the animal and another to clog the blood. In June 1981, investigators found a mutilated cow at the Gomez ranch with radar chaff nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;later-incidents&#34;&gt;Later Incidents &lt;a href=&#34;#later-incidents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many mutilation cases have been reported worldwide since 1967, primarily in the Americas and Australia. South America has seen an estimated 3,500 incidents since 2002. Investigators believe many cases go unreported. In 1993, photographic evidence surfaced of a mutilated human corpse found near the Guarapiranga reservoir of São Paulo, Brazil, in 1988. Theories ranged from homicide to alien abduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;characteristics&#34;&gt;Characteristics &lt;a href=&#34;#characteristics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cattle deaths due to natural causes are common. However, ranchers began reporting unusual deaths characterized by missing sex organs, udders, tongues, anus, and sometimes ears or eyes. Cuts were described as &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;surgical.&amp;rdquo; Some animals were reported drained of blood with no blood at the scene. Howard Burgess noted that nearly 90 percent of mutilated cattle are between four and five years old. Strange marks or imprints have been found near mutilation sites. The &amp;ldquo;Snippy&amp;rdquo; case featured an absence of tracks and small holes &amp;ldquo;punched&amp;rdquo; in the ground. In Rio Arriba County, New Mexico, a &amp;ldquo;trail of suction cup-like impressions&amp;rdquo; was found leading from a mutilated cow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;laboratory-reports&#34;&gt;Laboratory Reports &lt;a href=&#34;#laboratory-reports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laboratory reports on some mutilated animals have shown unusual levels of vitamins or minerals and the presence of chemicals not normally found in animals. However, these anomalies are not consistent across all cases. In a case documented by New Mexico police and the FBI involving a bull belonging to Manuel Gomez of Dulce, New Mexico, the animal displayed &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo; mutilation signs. The liver and heart were white and mushy, with the texture of peanut butter. Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory detected &lt;em&gt;Clostridium&lt;/em&gt; bacteria in the heart but could not draw conclusions. Liver samples were devoid of copper and contained high levels of zinc, potassium, and phosphorus. Blood samples were light pink and did not clot. The animal&amp;rsquo;s hide was brittle, and the flesh was discolored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;helicopter-sightings&#34;&gt;Helicopter Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#helicopter-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On July 15, 1974, two unregistered helicopters reportedly opened fire on Robert Smith Jr. in Honey Creek, Iowa. This followed a series of alleged mutilations in the area. In August 1974, residents reported seeing unidentified helicopters shining spotlights into fields where mutilated cows were later found. Know County Sheriff Herbert Thompson claimed helicopter sightings were nightly occurrences. By 1975, some ranchers formed armed vigilante groups. Authorities ran ads urging ranchers not to shoot at survey helicopters. The National Guard warned its helicopter pilots to fly at higher altitudes. In 1976, two Cache County, Utah, police officers reportedly confronted men in an unmarked U.S. Army helicopter. After this encounter, cattle mutilations in the region ceased for about five years. On April 8, 1979, three police officers in Dulce, New Mexico, reported a mysterious aircraft resembling a U.S. military helicopter hovering around a site following a wave of alleged mutilations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;official-investigations&#34;&gt;Official Investigations &lt;a href=&#34;#official-investigations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New Mexico Livestock Board sought assistance from the Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory. Colorado Bureau of Investigation agents went undercover. Oklahoma convened a task force. Federal authorities launched a comprehensive investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bureau-of-alcohol-tobacco-and-firearms&#34;&gt;Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms &lt;a href=&#34;#bureau-of-alcohol-tobacco-and-firearms&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January 1975, the Minnesota field office of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms (ATF) launched an investigation headed by Agent Donald Flickinger, tasked with investigating possible connections between cults and cattle mutilation. Flickinger recorded unusual incidents and circumstantial evidence but found insufficient evidence of cult involvement. His investigation was dropped when it was determined cattle deaths were not a prelude to a coordinated campaign against elected officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;colorado-bureau-of-investigation&#34;&gt;Colorado Bureau of Investigation &lt;a href=&#34;#colorado-bureau-of-investigation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May 1975, the Colorado Bureau of Investigation opened an investigation under Carl Whiteside. 19 animals underwent necropsies at Colorado State University, but no conclusive results emerged. A $40,000 reward was offered. The US Bureau of Land Management&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle_mutilation&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle_mutilation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of songs about close encounters with aliens</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a6f27fcf591b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 19:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a6f27fcf591b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-songs-about-close-encounters-with-aliens&#34;&gt;List of Songs About Close Encounters with Aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-songs-about-close-encounters-with-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a compilation of songs across various decades that explore lyrical themes related to close encounters with extraterrestrial aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1940s&#34;&gt;1940s &lt;a href=&#34;#1940s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights the earliest example on the list, &amp;ldquo;(When You See) Those Flying Saucers&amp;rdquo; by The Buchanan Brothers, released in July 1947. Its release coincided with the beginning of the flying saucer era, shortly after the Kenneth Arnold UFO sighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1950s&#34;&gt;1950s &lt;a href=&#34;#1950s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1950s saw a surge in songs about flying saucers and aliens. Notable entries include &amp;ldquo;The Flying Saucer Parts 1 &amp;amp; 2&amp;rdquo; by Bill Buchanan and Dickie Goodman, &amp;ldquo;My Flying Saucer&amp;rdquo; with lyrics by Woodie Guthrie, &amp;ldquo;The Purple People Eater&amp;rdquo; by Sheb Wooley, &amp;ldquo;Two Little Men In A Flying Saucer&amp;rdquo; by Ella Fitzgerald, and &amp;ldquo;Flyin&amp;rsquo; Saucers Rock &amp;amp; Roll&amp;rdquo; by Billy Lee Riley and Jerry Lee Lewis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1960s&#34;&gt;1960s &lt;a href=&#34;#1960s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists songs from the 1960s that touch on extraterrestrial themes. Key songs include &amp;ldquo;Let There Be More Light&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Set the Controls for the Heart of the Sun&amp;rdquo; by Pink Floyd, &amp;ldquo;Mr. Spaceman&amp;rdquo; by The Byrds, &amp;ldquo;Voices Green and Purple&amp;rdquo; by The Bees, &amp;ldquo;It Came Out of the Sky&amp;rdquo; by Creedence Clearwater Revival, &amp;ldquo;Have You Seen the Saucers&amp;rdquo; by Jefferson Airplane, and &amp;ldquo;U.F.O.&amp;rdquo; by Jim Sullivan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1970s&#34;&gt;1970s &lt;a href=&#34;#1970s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1970s brought a diverse range of songs exploring alien encounters. Highlights include &amp;ldquo;After the Gold Rush&amp;rdquo; by Neil Young, &amp;ldquo;Calling Occupants of Interplanetary Craft&amp;rdquo; by Klaatu (covered by The Carpenters), &amp;ldquo;Childhood&amp;rsquo;s End&amp;rdquo; by Pink Floyd, &amp;ldquo;Come Sail Away&amp;rdquo; by Styx, &amp;ldquo;Here Come the Martian Martians&amp;rdquo; by Jonathan Richman and the Modern Lovers, &amp;ldquo;Horsell Commons and the Heat Ray&amp;rdquo; by Jeff Wayne, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve Seen the Saucers&amp;rdquo; by Elton John, &amp;ldquo;Longer Boats&amp;rdquo; by Cat Stevens, &amp;ldquo;Martian Boogie&amp;rdquo; by Brownsville Station, &amp;ldquo;Mothership Connection&amp;rdquo; by Parliament, &amp;ldquo;Starman&amp;rdquo; by David Bowie, &amp;ldquo;Starship Trooper&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Arriving UFO&amp;rdquo; by Yes, &amp;ldquo;Waiting for the UFOs&amp;rdquo; by Graham Parker, &amp;ldquo;Silver Lights&amp;rdquo; by Sammy Hagar, &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; by Johnny Rivers, &amp;ldquo;Children of the Sun&amp;rdquo; by Billy Thorpe, &amp;ldquo;Starrider&amp;rdquo; by Foreigner, &amp;ldquo;Strange Ships&amp;rdquo; by Fox, and &amp;ldquo;Ships in the Sky&amp;rdquo; by Wishbone Ash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1980s&#34;&gt;1980s &lt;a href=&#34;#1980s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers songs from the 1980s with alien or UFO themes. Noteworthy songs include &amp;ldquo;Fire Of Unknown Origin&amp;rdquo; by Blue Öyster Cult, &amp;ldquo;Books about UFOs&amp;rdquo; by Hüsker Dü, &amp;ldquo;Flying Saucers&amp;rdquo; by Nina Hagen, &amp;ldquo;Love Walks In&amp;rdquo; by Van Halen, &amp;ldquo;Loving the Alien&amp;rdquo; by David Bowie, &amp;ldquo;No Doubt About It&amp;rdquo; by Hot Chocolate, &amp;ldquo;Nobody Told Me&amp;rdquo; by John Lennon, &amp;ldquo;Rapture&amp;rdquo; by Blondie, &amp;ldquo;Zero Zero UFO&amp;rdquo; by The Ramones, &amp;ldquo;I Ran (So Far Away)&amp;rdquo; by A Flock of Seagulls, &amp;ldquo;Caught in the Crossfire&amp;rdquo; by April Wine, and &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t Be Late&amp;rdquo; by Saga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1990s&#34;&gt;1990s &lt;a href=&#34;#1990s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1990s entries include &amp;ldquo;The Alien Song (For Those Who Listen)&amp;rdquo; by Mila Jovovich, &amp;ldquo;El Aparato (&amp;ldquo;The Apparatus&amp;rdquo;)&amp;rdquo; by Café Tacvba, &amp;ldquo;Alien (I Am)&amp;rdquo; by Hawkwind, &amp;ldquo;Aliens Exist&amp;rdquo; by Blink-182, &amp;ldquo;Alien Visitors&amp;rdquo; by Man or Astro-man?, &amp;ldquo;Another Sunday&amp;rdquo; by I Mother Earth, &amp;ldquo;Fell in Love with an Alien&amp;rdquo; by the Kelly Family, &amp;ldquo;Hangar 18&amp;rdquo; by Megadeth, &amp;ldquo;Hat Too Flat&amp;rdquo; by Walter Becker, &amp;ldquo;I Made Love to a Martian&amp;rdquo; by Mustard Plug, &amp;ldquo;Girl from Mars&amp;rdquo; by Ash, &amp;ldquo;Martian Dance Invasion&amp;rdquo; by Brainiac, &amp;ldquo;Motorway to Roswell&amp;rdquo; by Pixies, &amp;ldquo;Scent of a Mule&amp;rdquo; by Phish, &amp;ldquo;Shades of Grey&amp;rdquo; by Stuart Davis, &amp;ldquo;Spaceman&amp;rdquo; by Babylon Zoo, &amp;ldquo;Subterranean Homesick Alien&amp;rdquo; by Radiohead, &amp;ldquo;The Happening&amp;rdquo; by Pixies, &amp;ldquo;Who&amp;rsquo;s There?&amp;rdquo; by Smash Mouth, &amp;ldquo;Spaceman&amp;rdquo; by Bif Naked, &amp;ldquo;Is That You Mo-Dean?&amp;rdquo; by The B-52s, &amp;ldquo;Men in Black&amp;rdquo; by Will Smith, and &amp;ldquo;Calgone&amp;rdquo; by Incubus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2000s-to-present&#34;&gt;2000s to present &lt;a href=&#34;#2000s-to-present&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists songs from the 2000s to the present day. It includes &amp;ldquo;Fracture&amp;rdquo; by Edison&amp;rsquo;s Children (Neil Armstrong&amp;rsquo;s son&amp;rsquo;s band), &amp;ldquo;The Aliens Are Here&amp;rdquo; by The Hippos, &amp;ldquo;And You Thought the Doctor&amp;rsquo;s Probe Hurt&amp;rdquo; by Belvedere, &amp;ldquo;Jaadoo, Jaadoo&amp;rdquo; by Rajesh Roshan, &amp;ldquo;Concerning the UFO sighting near Highland, Illinois&amp;rdquo; by Sufjan Stevens, &amp;ldquo;Aliens&amp;rdquo; by Doctor Octagon, &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; by Sneaky Sound System, &amp;ldquo;Rosetta Stoned&amp;rdquo; by Tool, &amp;ldquo;Fallout of the 4th Kind&amp;rdquo; by Edison&amp;rsquo;s Children, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re Not Alone&amp;rdquo; by Nas, &amp;ldquo;Spaceman&amp;rdquo; by The Killers, &amp;ldquo;Venus Ambassador&amp;rdquo; by Bryan Scary &amp;amp; The Shredding Tears, &amp;ldquo;E.T.&amp;rdquo; by Katy Perry featuring Kanye West, &amp;ldquo;Zopilotes&amp;rdquo; by Café Tacuba, &amp;ldquo;A Million Miles Away (I Wish I Had A Time Machine)&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;The Awakening&amp;rdquo; by Edison&amp;rsquo;s Children, &amp;ldquo;Ancient Aliens&amp;rdquo; by Lemon Demon, &amp;ldquo;Decks Dark&amp;rdquo; by Radiohead, &amp;ldquo;Hey Aliens&amp;rdquo; by The Bouncing Souls, &amp;ldquo;Spaceship&amp;rdquo; by Kesha, &amp;ldquo;Herd Culling&amp;rdquo; by Porcupine Tree, &amp;ldquo;Silver Circles&amp;rdquo; by Upchurch, &amp;ldquo;End of the World&amp;rdquo; by Tom MacDonald, &amp;ldquo;Staring at the Stars&amp;rdquo; by Dan Marfisi and Glenn Jordan, &amp;ldquo;An Alien Abduction Story (The Probing)&amp;rdquo; by The Schnooks, and &amp;ldquo;Down Bad&amp;rdquo; by Taylor Swift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes &lt;a href=&#34;#notes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a note indicating that certain songs are used as bumper music on the &lt;em&gt;StarTalk&lt;/em&gt; podcast UFO episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the various sources used to compile the list of songs, including articles from publications like &lt;em&gt;The A.V. Club&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Huffington Post&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;NPR&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Salon.com&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, and books on UFOs and alien encounters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section suggests a book for further exploration of the topic: &lt;em&gt;Alien Rock: The Rock &amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo; Roll Extraterrestrial Connection&lt;/em&gt; by M. Luckman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/(When_You_See)_Those_Flying_Saucers&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/(When_You_See)_Those_Flying_Saucers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO religion</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_0a1958d0044c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 04:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_0a1958d0044c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-religion&#34;&gt;UFO Religion &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-religion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A UFO religion is a religion where belief in extraterrestrial entities operating unidentified flying objects (UFOs) is a core element. Adherents typically believe these ETs are interested in humanity&amp;rsquo;s welfare and that humanity will eventually join an existing ET civilization. Some UFO religions incorporate ETs into a supernatural worldview, blurring the lines between aliens and angels. These religions draw inspiration from early science fiction, ufology, UFO sightings, and alien abduction stories. The Aetherius Society, founded by George King, is considered the first UFO religion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary &lt;a href=&#34;#summary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adherents believe that the arrival or rediscovery of alien civilizations, technologies, and spirituality will enable humans to overcome ecological, spiritual, and social problems. Issues like hatred, war, bigotry, and poverty are believed to be resolvable through superior alien technology and spiritual abilities. These belief systems are often millenarian in their outlook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFO religions developed in countries like the United States, Canada, France, the United Kingdom, and Japan, where technology is advanced enough to conceive of ETs and where religion is not suppressed. The term &amp;ldquo;flying saucers&amp;rdquo; and the popular notion of the UFO originated in 1947. The study of UFO religions by sociologists, historians, theologians, scholars of religious studies, and new religious movements began in the 1950s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notable-ufo-religions&#34;&gt;Notable UFO Religions &lt;a href=&#34;#notable-ufo-religions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFO religions generally involve belief in communication with extraterrestrial beings through physical contact, telepathy, and astral projection. These groups often believe that humanity will be saved by aliens who will educate humans on a better way to live or take believers to a more positive location. Extraterrestrial beings are often seen pleading with humanity to improve itself and move away from greed and violence. UFO religions emphasize spiritual growth and the evolution of humanity. A UFO religion can form before or after an individual claims to have experienced an alien abduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. Gordon Melton identifies the &amp;ldquo;I AM&amp;rdquo; Activity, founded by Guy Ballard, as the first UFO religion, although Christopher Hugh Partridge views it as a theosophical religion. Partridge notes that UFO religions believe the supreme being or &amp;ldquo;evolved entity&amp;rdquo; came from another plane or planet. The 1947 Roswell incident is a key point in time within UFO spirituality. James R. Lewis notes that Ufologists see it as the date of the &amp;ldquo;emergence of UFOs into the public consciousness.&amp;rdquo; Partridge places UFO religion within the context of theosophical esotericism and asserts that it began to be associated as &amp;ldquo;UFO religion&amp;rdquo; after the Roswell incident. He notes that most UFO religions still have many of the key points associated with Theosophy, such as belief in the same Spiritual Hierarchy, and he also draws parallels to New Age thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen Hunt describes the Aetherius Society, founded by George King in 1955, as &amp;ldquo;probably the first and certainly the most enduring UFO cult.&amp;rdquo; Hunt places the Aetherius Society and Raëlism among the &amp;ldquo;most renowned&amp;rdquo; of the &amp;ldquo;flying saucer cults.&amp;rdquo; Melodie Campbell and Stephen A. Kent place the Aetherius Society and Unarius as among the &amp;ldquo;oldest and most studied&amp;rdquo; of the flying saucer cults. They describe Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate and Order of the Solar Temple as the &amp;ldquo;most controversial groups combining UFO belief with variations of contactee assertions.&amp;rdquo; Gregory L. Reece classes Scientology as a &amp;ldquo;UFO group,&amp;rdquo; discussing elements of the Xenu cosmogony and Space opera in Scientology doctrine. He compares Scientology to the Aetherius Society and Ashtar Command. Victoria Nelson writes that &amp;ldquo;[t]he most prominent current UFO religion is probably the science fiction writer L. Ron Hubbard&amp;rsquo;s Church of Scientology.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_religion&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_religion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
