<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UFOs on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ufos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UFOs on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 13:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ufos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO conspiracy theories</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_79b396660be9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 13:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_79b396660be9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;UFO Conspiracy Theories &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-conspiracy-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the various conspiracy theories surrounding UFOs, focusing on the idea that governments, particularly the United States government, are suppressing evidence of extraterrestrial life or technology. It also touches upon the alleged communication or cooperation between world governments and extraterrestrials, as well as claims of government involvement in cattle mutilations and alien abductions. The Committee for Skeptical Inquiry is cited as stating that there is little to no evidence to support these theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a historical context for UFO conspiracy theories, tracing their origins to pulp science fiction and &amp;ldquo;lost continent&amp;rdquo; myths. It mentions Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s 1947 sighting and the subsequent wave of UFO reports. Donald Keyhoe is credited with popularizing the idea of a government cover-up. The section also discusses the emergence of the &amp;ldquo;Men in Black&amp;rdquo; concept and the linking of UFOs to the Kennedy assassination. It notes the rise of theories involving malevolent aliens, alien abductions, and cattle mutilations in the 1980s, as well as Bill Moore&amp;rsquo;s confession of feeding fake evidence to UFO researchers. The popularity of UFO conspiracy theories in 1990s popular culture, with shows like &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt;, is also mentioned. The section concludes by noting the renewed interest in UFO conspiracy theories following Leslie Kean&amp;rsquo;s stories about a 21st-century Pentagon UFO program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;mainstream-views&#34;&gt;Mainstream Views &lt;a href=&#34;#mainstream-views&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents the mainstream scientific perspective on UFOs. It acknowledges the cultural prominence of UFOs after World War II and the Space Age, and mentions government investigations like Project Blue Book and Project Condign. It highlights that these investigations have not confirmed claims of extraterrestrial intelligence or other unconventional hypotheses. The section emphasizes that scientists and skeptical organizations offer prosaic explanations for UFOs, attributing them to natural phenomena, human technology, delusions, and hoaxes. It also notes that beliefs surrounding UFOs have inspired new religions and that social scientists view the ongoing interest in UFOs as a modern example of folklore and mythology. Benjamin Radford&amp;rsquo;s argument about the unlikelihood of a decades-long, international UFO cover-up is also presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;notable-proponents&#34;&gt;Notable Proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#notable-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section identifies key figures who have promoted UFO conspiracy theories. Donald Keyhoe, Jacque Vallee, J. Allen Hynek, and Stanton Friedman are mentioned as prominent proponents from the 1950s to the 1970s. The section also notes that some proponents, like Richard Shaver and Paul Bennewitz, had mental health issues, while others, like Gray Barker and Bill Moore, confessed to hoaxes or lies. Individuals who have suggested that UFO evidence is being suppressed, including Barry Goldwater, Lord Hill-Norton, Roscoe H. Hillenkoetter, Gordon Cooper, and Edgar Mitchell, are also listed. 21st-century proponents such as Paul Hellyer, Garry Nolan, Haim Eshed, Jim Semivan, Harold E. Puthoff, Tom DeLonge, Luis Elizondo, and David Grusch are also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;in-popular-fiction&#34;&gt;In Popular Fiction &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-fiction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the portrayal of government cover-ups of extraterrestrial contact in popular fiction. It mentions films like &lt;em&gt;2001: A Space Odyssey&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Easy Rider&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Flight of the Navigator&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Total Recall&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Independence Day&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Men in Black&lt;/em&gt;, as well as TV shows like &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Dark Skies&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Stargate&lt;/em&gt;. John Glenn&amp;rsquo;s appearance on &lt;em&gt;Frasier&lt;/em&gt;, where he confesses to a UFO cover-up, is also noted. The Sidney Sheldon novel &lt;em&gt;The Doomsday Conspiracy&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;American Horror Story: Double Feature&lt;/em&gt; series are also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;in-religion&#34;&gt;In Religion &lt;a href=&#34;#in-religion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines the connection between UFO conspiracy theories and new religious movements. The Nation of Islam, Scientology, and Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate are identified as examples. Mormon cosmology&amp;rsquo;s teachings about inhabited planets are also mentioned. Theosophists and occultists, as well as &amp;ldquo;contactees&amp;rdquo; like Meade Layne, George Adamski, and George Hunt Williamson, are discussed. The section also covers the Nation of Islam&amp;rsquo;s concept of The Mother Plane, the UFO religions of the 1950s, including Unarius and the Aetherius Society, and L. Ron Hubbard&amp;rsquo;s Scientology. The Raëlism movement and the Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate suicides are also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;chronology-of-ufo-conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;Chronology of UFO Conspiracy Theories &lt;a href=&#34;#chronology-of-ufo-conspiracy-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a detailed timeline of the development of UFO conspiracy theories, starting with Raymond Palmer&amp;rsquo;s pulp magazine in the 1940s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1940s-origin-in-raymond-palmers-pulp-magazine&#34;&gt;1940s Origin in Raymond Palmer&amp;rsquo;s Pulp Magazine &lt;a href=&#34;#1940s-origin-in-raymond-palmers-pulp-magazine&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection focuses on the role of Raymond Palmer and his &lt;em&gt;Amazing Stories&lt;/em&gt; magazine in the emergence of UFO conspiracy theories. It mentions Palmer&amp;rsquo;s publication of reports of strange craft and his hiring of Kenneth Arnold to investigate a UFO report near Maury Island, Washington. The subsection also notes Palmer&amp;rsquo;s magazine&amp;rsquo;s claims of a cover-up and his later linking of UFOs to the JFK assassination and Watergate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;spaceships-of-the-shaver-mystery&#34;&gt;Spaceships of &amp;ldquo;The Shaver Mystery&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#spaceships-of-the-shaver-mystery&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the &amp;ldquo;Shaver Mystery,&amp;rdquo; a series of stories published in &lt;em&gt;Amazing Stories&lt;/em&gt; based on the writings of Richard Shaver, who claimed to be in telepathic communication with a secret underground race. It mentions Shaver&amp;rsquo;s claims of ancient civilizations mastering space travel and Palmer&amp;rsquo;s argument that &amp;ldquo;responsible parties in world governments&amp;rdquo; were aware of spaceships visiting Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kenneth-arnold-ignites-flying-disc-craze&#34;&gt;Kenneth Arnold Ignites Flying Disc Craze &lt;a href=&#34;#kenneth-arnold-ignites-flying-disc-craze&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers the beginning of the flying disc craze with Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting and the subsequent spread of UFO reports. It mentions the Roswell incident and the Army&amp;rsquo;s initial press release about recovering a &amp;ldquo;flying disc.&amp;rdquo; The subsection also discusses Palmer&amp;rsquo;s contact with Arnold and their investigation of Fred Crisman&amp;rsquo;s claims near Maury Island, Washington.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aftermath&#34;&gt;Aftermath &lt;a href=&#34;#aftermath&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection describes the aftermath of the flying disc craze, including Palmer&amp;rsquo;s argument that the flap was proof of Richard Sharpe Shaver&amp;rsquo;s claims. It quotes Shaver&amp;rsquo;s prediction that the truth behind the discs would remain a secret. The subsection also notes Palmer&amp;rsquo;s later admission that Shaver had spent eight years in a mental institution and Palmer&amp;rsquo;s linking of UFOs to the Kennedy assassination and Watergate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;national-coverage-in-the-1950s&#34;&gt;National Coverage in the 1950s &lt;a href=&#34;#national-coverage-in-the-1950s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the increase in governmental and civilian investigative efforts and reports of public disinformation and suppression of evidence in the 1950s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aztec-alien-bodies-hoax&#34;&gt;Aztec &amp;ldquo;Alien Bodies&amp;rdquo; Hoax &lt;a href=&#34;#aztec-alien-bodies-hoax&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection focuses on the first &amp;ldquo;alien bodies&amp;rdquo; conspiracy theory, which emerged with Frank Scully&amp;rsquo;s columns in &lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt; and his book &lt;em&gt;Behind the Flying Saucers&lt;/em&gt;. It mentions Scully&amp;rsquo;s claims of dead extraterrestrial beings recovered from flying saucer crashes and the later revelation that Scully had been the victim of confidence artists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;air-force-accounts&#34;&gt;Air Force Accounts &lt;a href=&#34;#air-force-accounts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers the Air Force&amp;rsquo;s handling of UFO reports, including General John Samford&amp;rsquo;s press conference on the recent UFO sightings over the nation&amp;rsquo;s capital. It mentions the Robertson Panel&amp;rsquo;s recommendation of a public education campaign and the film &lt;em&gt;Unidentified Flying Objects: The True Story of Flying Saucers&lt;/em&gt;, which dramatized the events of the early 1950s. The subsection also discusses Captain Edward J. Ruppelt&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;em&gt;The Report on Unidentified Flying Objects&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;philadelphia-experiment-hoax&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Philadelphia Experiment&amp;rdquo; Hoax &lt;a href=&#34;#philadelphia-experiment-hoax&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the &amp;ldquo;Philadelphia Experiment&amp;rdquo; hoax, which involved claims of a navy ship being made invisible and teleporting from Philadelphia to Norfolk, Virginia. It mentions Morris K. Jessup&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;em&gt;The Case for the UFO&lt;/em&gt; and the letters he received from &amp;ldquo;Carlos Miguel Allende&amp;rdquo; (Carl Meredith Allen). The subsection also covers Jessup&amp;rsquo;s death by suicide and the promotion of the Philadelphia Experiment by Charles Berlitz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;men-in-black-legends&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Men in Black&amp;rsquo; Legends &lt;a href=&#34;#men-in-black-legends&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection focuses on the emergence of the &amp;ldquo;Men in Black&amp;rdquo; legend with Gray Barker&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;em&gt;They Knew Too Much About Flying Saucers&lt;/em&gt;. It discusses the speculation that the men in black are government agents who harass and threaten UFO witnesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1960-70s-growing-distrust-in-government&#34;&gt;1960-70s: Growing Distrust in Government &lt;a href=&#34;#1960-70s-growing-distrust-in-government&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the era of government skepticism that began in the 1960s, following the assassination of John F. Kennedy, the Pentagon Papers, and the Watergate scandal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fred-crisman-and-jfk-conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;Fred Crisman and JFK Conspiracy Theories &lt;a href=&#34;#fred-crisman-and-jfk-conspiracy-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers the linking of Fred Crisman to the Kennedy assassination and a supposed UFO cover-up. It mentions Jim Garrison&amp;rsquo;s prosecution of Clay Shaw and Crisman&amp;rsquo;s testimony before the New Orleans grand jury. The subsection also notes the United States House Select Committee on Assassinations&amp;rsquo; consideration of the possibility that Crisman may have been one of the &amp;ldquo;three tramps&amp;rdquo; detained and photographed in the aftermath of the JFK assassination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cosmic-watergate&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cosmic Watergate&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#cosmic-watergate&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the concept of a &amp;ldquo;Cosmic Watergate,&amp;rdquo; which refers to the idea of a government cover-up of UFO information. It mentions the novel and film &lt;em&gt;2001: A Space Odyssey&lt;/em&gt; and J. Allen Hynek&amp;rsquo;s claim that Bluebook was &amp;ldquo;a Cosmic Watergate.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-bodies-at-hangar-18&#34;&gt;Alien Bodies at &amp;ldquo;Hangar 18&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-bodies-at-hangar-18&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection focuses on the legends of alien bodies being stored in &amp;ldquo;Hangar 18&amp;rdquo; at Wright-Patterson Air Force Base. It mentions Robert Spencer Carr&amp;rsquo;s allegation that alien bodies recovered from the Aztec crash were stored in &amp;ldquo;Hangar 18&amp;rdquo; and the film *Hangar 18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interplanetary_Phenomenon_Unit&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interplanetary_Phenomenon_Unit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien abduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_039a17526655/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_039a17526655/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-abduction&#34;&gt;Alien Abduction &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-abduction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alien abduction, also known as abduction phenomenon, alien abduction syndrome, or UFO abduction, is the subjective experience of people reporting what they believe to be the real experience of being kidnapped by extraterrestrial beings and subjected to physical and psychological experimentation. Those who claim to have been abducted are called &amp;ldquo;abductees&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;experiencers.&amp;rdquo; Most scientists and mental health professionals attribute these experiences to suggestibility, sleep paralysis, deception, and psychopathology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainstream scientists generally reject claims that alien abduction literally occurs as reported. Some, like psychiatrist John E. Mack, argue that most abductees are sane and common people, with psychopathology associated only with some cases. Mack noted the detailed nature of some abduction reports and the existence of a subculture with support groups and a mythos explaining the roles, origins, and motivations of various alien types (Greys, Reptilians, Nordics, etc.). Some abductees explain the lack of wider awareness as a result of extraterrestrial or governmental cover-ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;paleo-abductions&#34;&gt;Paleo-abductions &lt;a href=&#34;#paleo-abductions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the term &amp;ldquo;alien abduction&amp;rdquo; gained widespread attention, some older stories were speculated to be possible cases, dubbed &amp;ldquo;paleo-abductions&amp;rdquo; by UFO researcher Jerome Clark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 1896, Colonel H. G. Shaw claimed he and a friend were harassed by tall, slender humanoids who tried to kidnap them in Stockton, California.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 1953, an article in &lt;em&gt;Man to Man Magazine&lt;/em&gt; questioned whether humans were being captured by flying saucers for zoological specimens or vivisection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 1955, Harold T. Wilkins&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Flying Saucers Uncensored&lt;/em&gt; reported the mysterious disappearance of Karl Hunrath and Wilbur Wilkinson, who claimed alien contact, with speculation that they were victims of abduction by flying saucers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;two-landmark-cases&#34;&gt;Two Landmark Cases &lt;a href=&#34;#two-landmark-cases&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Antônio Vilas-Boas case in Brazil in the mid-1950s was an early claim, but the Betty and Barney Hill abduction case of 1961 generated widespread publicity, including a 1975 television film. The Hill incident was the first in which the claimants described beings that later became widely known as the Greys and in which the beings were said to explicitly identify an extraterrestrial origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;later-developments&#34;&gt;Later Developments &lt;a href=&#34;#later-developments&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R. Leo Sprinkle, a psychologist at the University of Wyoming, became interested in the abduction phenomenon in the 1960s and suggested a link between abductions and cattle mutilation. Budd Hopkins became interested in abduction reports in the 1970s and used hypnosis to extract more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1980s brought mainstream attention to the subject through works by Hopkins, novelist Whitley Strieber, historian David M. Jacobs, and psychiatrist John E. Mack. Folklorist Thomas E. Bullard published a comparative analysis of nearly 300 alleged abductees. Jacobs and Hopkins argued that alien abduction was far more common than earlier suspected and that aliens were attempting to create human-alien hybrids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Boston Globe&lt;/em&gt; writer Linda Rodriguez McRobbie, abduction stories have declined in mainstream media. Skeptic Michael Shermer noted that the ubiquity of camera phones increases the burden of evidence for such claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;john-e-mack&#34;&gt;John E. Mack &lt;a href=&#34;#john-e-mack&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harvard psychiatry professor John E. Mack believed in the credibility of alien abduction claims. Niall Boyce writing in &lt;em&gt;The Lancet&lt;/em&gt; called him &amp;ldquo;a well-meaning man uncritically elaborating on tales of alien abduction, and potentially both cementing and constructing false memories&amp;rdquo;. Mack&amp;rsquo;s work in hypnotic regression of claimants helped spread the Grey aliens meme into the culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mack interviewed over 800 people and wrote two books on the subject. Due to Mack&amp;rsquo;s belief and subsequent promotion of the claims of those he interviewed, his professional reputation suffered, prompting Harvard to review his position in 1994. He retained tenure, but &amp;ldquo;was not taken seriously by his colleagues anymore”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abductees&#34;&gt;Abductees &lt;a href=&#34;#abductees&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The precise number of alleged abductees is uncertain. One of the earliest studies of abductions found 1,700 claimants, while contested surveys argued that 5–6 percent of the general population allege to have been abducted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;demographics&#34;&gt;Demographics &lt;a href=&#34;#demographics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although abduction reports are usually made by adults, sometimes young children report similar experiences. These child-reports often feature very specific details in common with reports of abduction made by adults, including the circumstances, narrative, entities and aftermaths of the alleged occurrences. Often, these young abductees have family members who have reported having abduction experiences. Family involvement in the military, or a residence near a military base is also common among child abduction claimants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mental-health&#34;&gt;Mental Health &lt;a href=&#34;#mental-health&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some studies show that abductees have psychological characteristics that render their testimony suspect, while others show that &amp;ldquo;as a group, abduction experients are not different from the general population in term of psychopathology prevalence&amp;rdquo;. Elizabeth Slater conducted a blind study of nine abduction claimants and found them to be prone to &amp;ldquo;mildly paranoid thinking&amp;rdquo;, nightmares and having a weak sexual identity, while Richard McNally of Harvard Medical School concluded in a similar study of 10 abductees that &amp;ldquo;none of them was suffering from any sort of psychiatric illness.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;political-conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;Political Conspiracy Theories &lt;a href=&#34;#political-conspiracy-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Political scientist Michael Barkun highlighted links between radical politics and conspiracy theories involving UFOs, alien visitation, environmental pollution, hidden groups, government and world takeover. He observed the rise of a form of eclectic and apocalyptic millenarism which he termed &amp;ldquo;improvisional millenarism&amp;rdquo;. UFO and abduction stories can often be part of stigmatized or suppressed knowledge narratives. UFO and alien-related conspiracy theories emerged in far-right politics from the 1980s onwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Barkun, in popular culture, TV shows like &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt; included aliens as part of coverup conspiracies, with militias and black helicopters but also featured demonization of FEMA. Political scientist Jodi Dean noted that the stigma of alien abduction stories is seductive to dismiss &amp;ldquo;consensus reality&amp;rdquo; in favor of deviant alternative realities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-described abduction victims often join self-help communities of victims and may resort to questionable regression therapy, similarly to other self-reported victims of child sexual abuse or satanic ritual abuse. Some espouse conspiracy theories of sophisticated technological mind control, including the use of implants, to force them to serve an alleged New World Order, or for the purposes of the antichrist, considering it important to warn the world of such imminent danger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abduction-narrative&#34;&gt;Abduction Narrative &lt;a href=&#34;#abduction-narrative&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various researchers have noted common points in report narratives. According to CUFOS&amp;rsquo;s definition of &lt;em&gt;abductee&lt;/em&gt;, the person must have been taken against their will by apparent non-human beings, taken to a special place perceived as extraterrestrial or to be a spaceship. They then must experience being subjected to an examination or to engage in some form of communication with the beings (or both). Communication may be perceived as telepathic rather than verbal. The memory of the experience may be conscious or &amp;ldquo;recovered&amp;rdquo; through means like hypnosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although different cases vary in detail, some UFO researchers, such as folklorist Thomas E. Bullard argue that there is a broad, fairly consistent sequence and description of events that make up the typical &amp;ldquo;close encounter of the fourth kind&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bullard argues most abduction accounts feature the following events:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capture&lt;/strong&gt;. The abductee is rendered incapable of resisting and taken to an alien spacecraft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Examination and Procedures&lt;/strong&gt;. Invasive physiological and psychological procedures, and on occasion simulated behavioral situations, training &amp;amp; testing, or sexual liaisons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conference&lt;/strong&gt;. The abductors communicate with the abductee or direct them to interact with specific individuals for some purpose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tour&lt;/strong&gt;. The abductees are given a tour of their captors&amp;rsquo; vessel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loss of Time&lt;/strong&gt;. Abductees often rapidly forget the majority of their experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Return&lt;/strong&gt;. The abductees are returned to earth, occasionally in a different location from where they were allegedly taken or with new injuries or disheveled clothing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theophany&lt;/strong&gt;. Coinciding with their immediate return, abductees may have a profound sense of love, a &amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo; similar to those induced by certain drugs, or a &amp;ldquo;mystical experience&amp;rdquo;, accompanied by a feeling of oneness with God, the universe, or their abductors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aftermath&lt;/strong&gt;. The abductee must cope with the psychological, physical, and social effects of the experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David M. Jacobs says: &amp;ldquo;The entire abduction event is precisely orchestrated. All the procedures are predetermined. There is no standing around and deciding what to do next. The beings are task-oriented and there is no indication whatsoever that we have been able to find of any aspect of their lives outside of performing the abduction procedures.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;capture&#34;&gt;Capture &lt;a href=&#34;#capture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abduction claimants report unusual feelings preceding the onset of an abduction experience. These feelings manifest as a compulsive desire to be at a certain place at a certain time or as expectations that something &amp;ldquo;familiar yet unknown&amp;rdquo; will soon occur. Abductees also report feeling severe, undirected anxiety at this point even though nothing unusual has actually occurred yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the experiencer will undergo an apparent &amp;ldquo;shift&amp;rdquo; into an altered state of consciousness. British abduction researchers have called this change in consciousness &amp;ldquo;the Oz Factor&amp;rdquo;. External sounds cease to have any significance to the experiencer and fall out of perception. They report feeling introspective and unusually calm. As consciousness shifts one or more lights are alleged to appear, occasionally accompanied by a strange mist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the alleged abduction proceeds, claimants say they will walk or be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_alien_abduction_claims&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_alien_abduction_claims&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_9c34e91b7ea9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 13:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_9c34e91b7ea9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;national-defense-authorization-act-for-fiscal-year-2024&#34;&gt;National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024 &lt;a href=&#34;#national-defense-authorization-act-for-fiscal-year-2024&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024 (NDAA 2024) is a United States federal law that outlines the budget, expenditures, and policies of the U.S. Department of Defense (DOD) for fiscal year 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Defense Authorization Act is an annual bill proposed in the United States Congress that redefines the United States military budget for the following fiscal year. Each chamber of Congress introduced a version of the NDAA: H.R. 2670 in the House and S. 2226 in the Senate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The House passed their version on July 14, 2023 by a vote of 219–210. Led by Chuck Schumer and Mike Rounds, the Senate passed theirs on July 27, 2023 by a vote of 86–11. The Senate then replaced H.R. 2670 with the text of S. 2226 and passed it by unanimous consent, and indefinitely postponed S. 2226. The House disagreed to the Senate amendment and asked to hold conference on September 19, with the Senate insisting on its amendment and agreeing to conference on November 15. The subsequent conference report was filed on December 6 (H. Rept. 118-301). The bill was approved by the Senate and House and sent to President Joe Biden on December 14. Biden signed it into law on December 22. In his signing statement, Biden expressed reservations about provisions that restrict the executive branch&amp;rsquo;s discretion in Guantanamo detainee transfers and raised constitutional concerns regarding congressional oversight and foreign policy authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;provisions&#34;&gt;Provisions &lt;a href=&#34;#provisions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section requires updating to reflect recent events or newly available information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;unidentified-flying-objects-ufos&#34;&gt;Unidentified flying objects (UFOs) &lt;a href=&#34;#unidentified-flying-objects-ufos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sections 1841 et seq. outline the creation and management of a comprehensive collection of government records on UFOs or unidentified anomalous phenomena (UAP) at the National Archives (NARA), detailing the processes for assembling, preserving, and providing public access to these records, along with specific protocols for their review, disclosure, and secure handling. NARA subsequently provided guidance to federal agencies to identify, organize, and disclose UAP records for the new collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sections 1687 and 7343 disallow use of funds or independent research and development (IRAD) indirect expenses for UFOs or UAP unless such material and information is made available the appropriate congressional committees and congressional leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Language on the topic of UFO/UAP was also included in the previous 2023 NDAA, the 2022 NDAA, the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022, as well as an accompanying Senate Select Committee on Intelligence report for the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;foreign-extortion-prevention-act&#34;&gt;Foreign Extortion Prevention Act &lt;a href=&#34;#foreign-extortion-prevention-act&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Foreign Extortion Prevention Act (FEPA) enables US authorities to prosecute foreign officials who demand or accept bribes from a US citizen, US company, or within a US jurisdiction. FEPA addresses a longstanding gap in US anti-bribery legislation by tackling the &amp;ldquo;demand&amp;rdquo; side of bribery. At the same time, the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act (FCPA) focuses on the &amp;ldquo;supply&amp;rdquo; side of bribery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;counter-extremist-working-group-defunded&#34;&gt;Counter-extremist working group defunded &lt;a href=&#34;#counter-extremist-working-group-defunded&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Republicans opposed the anti-extremism working group created by Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin. That working group had been created by Austin after it became apparent that some service members and veterans had participated in the attack on the US Capitol January 6, 2021. That working group released recommendations at the end of 2021. Implementation, however, appeared to stall as Republicans increasingly opposed diversity, equity, and inclusion efforts in the military, which Republicans derided as &amp;ldquo;wokeness&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, a recent inspector general report found dozens of troops, who appeared to be advocating violent overthrow of the US government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The seriousness of this issue seems apparent from the fact that military and veterans have participated in other violent extremist events. For example, the Oklahoma City bomber, Timothy McVeigh, had served with distinction in Operation Desert Storm but had earned a reputation as a sergeant for assigning undesirable work to black servicemen and using derogatory language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nato-withdrawal&#34;&gt;NATO withdrawal &lt;a href=&#34;#nato-withdrawal&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Section 1250A prevents the President from withdrawing the United States from NATO without the approval of a two-thirds Senate supermajority or an act of Congress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;original-proposals&#34;&gt;Original proposals &lt;a href=&#34;#original-proposals&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original House bill contained provisions to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Space Force Personnel Management Act: Disestablish the regular Space Force in order to integrate both active duty and reserve personnel into one Space Force entity. This is to allow for better flexibility for the Space Force by replacing &amp;ldquo;active duty&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;sustained duty&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;full-time&amp;rdquo; status, and replacing &amp;ldquo;reserve&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;part-time&amp;rdquo; status. This change would only pertain to the Space Force and not to the other armed services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elevate the position of vice chief of the National Guard Bureau to hold a statutory rank of general.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Permanently establish the titles of commissioned officer ranks of the Space Force to be the same as the Army, Marine Corps, and Air Force.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authorize a $886 billion spending budget for national defense programs including:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A 5.2% pay increase for service members of the armed forces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Procurement of up to 13 &lt;em&gt;Virginia&lt;/em&gt;-class submarines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authorize the sale and transfer of defense articles and services relating to the implementation of the AUKUS partnership, including:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Up to three &lt;em&gt;Virginia&lt;/em&gt;-class submarines, one year after this act is passed, however the Navy doesn&amp;rsquo;t intend implement this until 2032.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Senate amendment contained:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UAP Disclosure Act: The Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena Disclosure Act of 2023 would direct the National Archives and Records Administration to collect and disclose records on unidentified flying objects (UFOs) or unidentified anomalous phenomena (UAP) no later than 25 years after enactment with a presumption of immediate disclosure. The U.S. president can certify that continued postponement can be made necessary by an identifiable harm to military defense, intelligence operations, law enforcement or conduct of foreign relations. The federal government would have eminent domain over recovered technologies of unknown origin (TUO) and biological evidence of non-human intelligence (NHI) that may be controlled by private persons or entities, such as aerospace companies. Legislation was necessary in part because UAP records had not been subject to mandatory declassification review due to exemptions under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 as well as an over-broad interpretation of &amp;ldquo;transclassified foreign nuclear information&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Intelligence Authorization Act (IAA) requires people currently or formerly under contract with the federal government to make all UFO/UAP material and information and a comprehensive list of all extraterrestrial or exotic UAP material available to the All-domain Anomaly Resolution Office (AARO).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A provision that prevents the President of the United States from withdrawing the U.S. from NATO without approval of a two-thirds Senate supermajority or an act of Congress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unidentified_Anomalous_Phenomena_Disclosure_Act&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unidentified_Anomalous_Phenomena_Disclosure_Act&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ufology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_2c01afed379f/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_2c01afed379f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufology&#34;&gt;Ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology is the investigation of unidentified flying objects (UFOs) by individuals who believe they may have extraordinary origins, often extraterrestrial. While governments, private groups, and fringe science have investigated UFOs, ufology is generally considered pseudoscience by skeptics and science educators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;etymology&#34;&gt;Etymology &lt;a href=&#34;#etymology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;ufology&amp;rdquo; is a neologism derived from &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; and the suffix &amp;ldquo;-logy.&amp;rdquo; Edward J. Ruppelt is credited with coining the term UFO. Early uses of &amp;ldquo;ufology&amp;rdquo; appeared in a 1957 &lt;em&gt;Fantastic Universe&lt;/em&gt; article and a 1958 presentation for The Planetary Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-background&#34;&gt;Historical background &lt;a href=&#34;#historical-background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology&amp;rsquo;s roots trace back to various historical phenomena, including the mystery airships of the late 1890s, foo fighters reported during World War II, ghost fliers of the 1930s, ghost rockets of 1946 in Scandinavia, and the Kenneth Arnold sighting in 1947. The Arnold sighting popularized the concept of flying saucers. Increased UFO publicity after World War II coincided with Cold War tensions and concerns about Soviet aircraft. Official government involvement in ufology in the United States ended after the Condon Committee report and the termination of Project Blue Book. France maintains the GEIPAN program for UFO studies. In September 2023, NASA appointed Mark McInerney as the first Director of U.A.P. to study such occurrences scientifically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;as-a-field&#34;&gt;As a field &lt;a href=&#34;#as-a-field&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology is not recognized as a scientific field by academia and is generally considered pseudoscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;status-as-a-pseudoscience&#34;&gt;Status as a pseudoscience &lt;a href=&#34;#status-as-a-pseudoscience&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology is often listed as a pseudoscience due to its lack of adherence to the scientific method, supporting evidence, plausibility, and falsifiability. Social factors contribute to this status, including mistrust between ufology, the sciences, and government bodies. Poor science communication regarding the extraterrestrial intelligence (ETI) hypothesis hinders public understanding and discourages academic inquiry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-interest&#34;&gt;Current interest &lt;a href=&#34;#current-interest&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astronomer Avi Loeb launched The Galileo Project in 2021 to collect scientific evidence of extraterrestrial technology. The University of Würzburg is developing sensors for detecting and analyzing aerial objects. A 2021 Gallup poll indicated increased belief among Americans that some UFOs are extraterrestrial spacecraft. In 2022, NASA announced a study to investigate UAP. In 2023, the RAND Corporation published a study reviewing public reports of UAP sightings in the United States from 1998 to 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;methodological-issues&#34;&gt;Methodological issues &lt;a href=&#34;#methodological-issues&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific UFO research faces challenges due to the unpredictable nature of UFO phenomena, their lack of reproducibility, and tangible physicality. Most UFO sightings have mundane explanations, limiting the interpretive power of extraordinary events. Carl Sagan noted that reliable cases are uninteresting, and interesting cases are unreliable. J. Allen Hynek and Jacques Vallée developed descriptive systems for characterizing UFO sightings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;phenomena-linked-to-ufology&#34;&gt;Phenomena linked to ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#phenomena-linked-to-ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufologists are interested in phenomena related to UFO sightings, including crop circles, cattle mutilations, anomalous materials, alien abductions, and implants. Some ufologists promote UFO conspiracy theories, such as the Roswell Incident and the Majestic 12 documents. Robert Sheaffer has accused ufology of a &amp;ldquo;credulity explosion,&amp;rdquo; and James E. McDonald identified &amp;ldquo;cultism&amp;rdquo; as negatively impacting ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-posadism&#34;&gt;In Posadism &lt;a href=&#34;#in-posadism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the Cold War, ufology was combined with the ideas of the Trotskyist Posadism movement in South America. Juan Posadas, the main theorist, believed humanity should appeal to extraterrestrials to collaborate in suppressing poverty and creating a socialist system on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;governmental-and-private-ufology-studies&#34;&gt;Governmental and private ufology studies &lt;a href=&#34;#governmental-and-private-ufology-studies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the 1940s, governmental agencies and private groups have sponsored UFO investigations, studies, and conferences. These include Project Sign, Project Magnet, Project Blue Book, the Robertson Panel, and the Condon Committee in the United States; the Flying Saucer Working Party and Project Condign in Britain; GEIPAN in France; and Project Hessdalen in Norway. Private studies include those by the RAND Corporation, Harvey Rutledge, and the National Press Club&amp;rsquo;s Disclosure Project. The United Nations sponsored meetings and hearings on UFO sightings from 1977 to 1979. In August 2020, the United States Department of Defense established the Unidentified Aerial Phenomena Task Force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufo-organizations-and-events&#34;&gt;UFO organizations and events &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-organizations-and-events&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerous private organizations worldwide are dedicated to the study and discussion of ufology. Skeptic organizations emphasize the pseudoscientific nature of ufology. During World UFO Day (July 2), ufologists raise public awareness of ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ufologist&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ufologist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ufology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_7a24e854d947/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_7a24e854d947/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufology&#34;&gt;Ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology is the investigation of unidentified flying objects (UFOs) by individuals who believe they may have extraordinary origins, often extraterrestrial. While governments, private groups, and fringe science have investigated UFOs, ufology is generally considered pseudoscience by skeptics and science educators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;etymology&#34;&gt;Etymology &lt;a href=&#34;#etymology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;ufology&amp;rdquo; is a neologism derived from &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; and the suffix &amp;ldquo;-logy.&amp;rdquo; Edward J. Ruppelt is credited with coining the term UFO. Early uses of &amp;ldquo;ufology&amp;rdquo; appeared in a 1957 &lt;em&gt;Fantastic Universe&lt;/em&gt; article and a 1958 presentation for The Planetary Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-background&#34;&gt;Historical Background &lt;a href=&#34;#historical-background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology&amp;rsquo;s roots can be traced to several historical phenomena:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mystery Airships (late 1890s):&lt;/strong&gt; Unexplained aerial objects reported during this period.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foo Fighters (World War II):&lt;/strong&gt; Reports from Allied airmen of unusual objects during flight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ghost Fliers (1930s):&lt;/strong&gt; Sightings in Europe and North America.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ghost Rockets (1946):&lt;/strong&gt; Sightings in Scandinavia, particularly Sweden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenneth Arnold Sighting (1947):&lt;/strong&gt; Arnold&amp;rsquo;s report of &amp;ldquo;flying saucers&amp;rdquo; popularized the concept.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increased media attention to UFOs after World War II coincided with the Cold War and concerns about Soviet aircraft. Official government involvement in ufology in the United States ended in the late 1960s after the Condon Committee report and the termination of Project Blue Book. Other countries, such as the United Kingdom, Canada, Denmark, Italy, and Sweden, also ended government-sponsored UFO activities. France is an exception, maintaining the GEIPAN program. In September 2023, NASA appointed Mark McInerney as the Director of U.A.P. to study such occurrences scientifically and transparently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;as-a-field&#34;&gt;As a Field &lt;a href=&#34;#as-a-field&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;status-as-a-pseudoscience&#34;&gt;Status as a Pseudoscience &lt;a href=&#34;#status-as-a-pseudoscience&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology is not recognized as a scientific field by academia and is generally considered a pseudoscience. Pseudoscience lacks adherence to the scientific method, supporting evidence, plausibility, or falsifiability. Social factors contribute to this status, including mistrust between ufology, the sciences, and government investigative bodies. Poor science communication regarding the extraterrestrial intelligence (ETI) hypothesis also hinders public understanding and academic inquiry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-interest&#34;&gt;Current Interest &lt;a href=&#34;#current-interest&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interest in ufology persists. In 2021, Avi Loeb launched The Galileo Project to collect scientific evidence of extraterrestrial technology. The University of Würzburg in Germany is developing sensors to detect and analyze aerial objects. A 2021 Gallup poll indicated increased belief among Americans that some UFOs are extraterrestrial spacecraft. In 2022, NASA announced a study to investigate UAP. In 2023, the RAND Corporation published a study reviewing 101,151 public reports of UAP sightings in the United States from 1998 to 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;methodological-issues&#34;&gt;Methodological Issues &lt;a href=&#34;#methodological-issues&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific UFO research faces challenges due to the unpredictable nature of the phenomena, lack of reproducibility, and absence of tangible physicality. Most UFO sightings have mundane explanations, limiting the interpretive power of extraordinary events. Carl Sagan noted that reliable cases are uninteresting, and interesting cases are unreliable. J. Allen Hynek and Jacques Vallée developed descriptive systems for characterizing UFO sightings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;phenomena-linked-to-ufology&#34;&gt;Phenomena Linked to Ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#phenomena-linked-to-ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain phenomena are of interest to some ufologists:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crop circles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cattle mutilations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anomalous materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alien abductions and implants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ufologists promote UFO conspiracy theories, such as the Roswell Incident and Majestic 12 documents. Robert Sheaffer has accused ufology of a &amp;ldquo;credulity explosion,&amp;rdquo; while James E. McDonald identified &amp;ldquo;cultism&amp;rdquo; as negatively impacting ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-posadism&#34;&gt;In Posadism &lt;a href=&#34;#in-posadism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the Cold War, ufology was synthesized with the ideas of Posadism, a Trotskyist movement in South America. Juan Posadas, the main theorist, believed humanity should appeal to extraterrestrials to intervene and collaborate in suppressing poverty and creating a socialist system on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;governmental-and-private-ufology-studies&#34;&gt;Governmental and Private Ufology Studies &lt;a href=&#34;#governmental-and-private-ufology-studies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting in the 1940s, governmental agencies and private groups sponsored investigations, studies, and conferences related to ufology. These studies include Project Sign, Project Magnet, Project Blue Book, the Robertson Panel, and the Condon Committee in the United States; the Flying Saucer Working Party and Project Condign in Britain; GEIPAN in France; and Project Hessdalen in Norway. Private studies include those by the RAND Corporation, Harvey Rutledge of the University of Missouri, and the National Press Club&amp;rsquo;s Disclosure Project. The United Nations sponsored meetings and hearings concerning UFO sightings from 1977 to 1979. In August 2020, the United States Department of Defense established the Unidentified Aerial Phenomena Task Force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufo-organizations-and-events&#34;&gt;UFO Organizations and Events &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-organizations-and-events&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerous private organizations worldwide are dedicated to the study and discussion of ufology. Skeptic organizations also exist, emphasizing the pseudoscientific nature of ufology. During World UFO Day (July 2), ufologists raise public awareness of ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ufology&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ufology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ufology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_ca17bd06df71/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_ca17bd06df71/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufology&#34;&gt;Ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology is the investigation of unidentified flying objects (UFOs) by individuals who believe they may have extraordinary origins, often extraterrestrial. While governments, private groups, and fringe science may investigate UFOs, ufology is generally considered pseudoscience by skeptics and science educators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;etymology&#34;&gt;Etymology &lt;a href=&#34;#etymology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;ufology&amp;rdquo; is a neologism derived from &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; and the suffix &amp;ldquo;-logy.&amp;rdquo; Edward J. Ruppelt is credited with coining the term UFO. Early uses of &amp;ldquo;ufology&amp;rdquo; appeared in a 1957 &lt;em&gt;Fantastic Universe&lt;/em&gt; article and a 1958 presentation for The Planetary Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-background&#34;&gt;Historical background &lt;a href=&#34;#historical-background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology&amp;rsquo;s roots can be traced to several historical phenomena: the &amp;ldquo;mystery airships&amp;rdquo; of the late 1890s, &amp;ldquo;foo fighters&amp;rdquo; reported during World War II, &amp;ldquo;ghost fliers&amp;rdquo; of the 1930s, &amp;ldquo;ghost rockets&amp;rdquo; in Scandinavia in 1946, and the Kenneth Arnold &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; sighting in 1947. The Arnold sighting significantly popularized the concept of flying saucers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increased UFO publicity after World War II coincided with the Cold War and concerns about Soviet aircraft. Official government activities related to ufology in the United States ended in the late 1960s after the Condon Committee report and the termination of Project Blue Book. Similar government-sponsored activities in other countries, such as the United Kingdom, Canada, Denmark, Italy, and Sweden, also ended. France is an exception, maintaining the GEIPAN program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In September 2023, NASA appointed Mark McInerney as the Director of U.A.P. to study such occurrences scientifically and transparently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;as-a-field&#34;&gt;As a field &lt;a href=&#34;#as-a-field&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;status-as-a-pseudoscience&#34;&gt;Status as a pseudoscience &lt;a href=&#34;#status-as-a-pseudoscience&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology is not recognized as a scientific field by academia and is generally considered a pseudoscience by skeptics and science educators. Pseudoscience lacks adherence to the scientific method, supporting evidence, plausibility, or falsifiability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social factors contribute to ufology&amp;rsquo;s status as a pseudoscience. Some argue that mistrust between ufology, the sciences, and government bodies contributes to this status. Poor science communication regarding the extraterrestrial intelligence (ETI) hypothesis for UFOs hinders public understanding and discourages academic inquiry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-interest&#34;&gt;Current interest &lt;a href=&#34;#current-interest&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2021, Avi Loeb launched The Galileo Project to collect scientific evidence of extraterrestrials or their technology near Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Würzburg in Germany is developing sensors to detect and analyze aerial objects, potentially applicable to UAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2021 Gallup poll indicated an increase in the belief among Americans that some UFOs are extraterrestrial spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022, NASA announced a study to establish a roadmap for investigating UAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2023, the RAND Corporation published a study reviewing public reports of UAP sightings in the United States from 1998 to 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;methodological-issues&#34;&gt;Methodological issues &lt;a href=&#34;#methodological-issues&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific UFO research faces challenges due to the unpredictable nature of the phenomena, lack of reproducibility, and absence of tangible physicality. Most UFO sightings have mundane explanations, limiting the interpretive power of extraordinary events. Carl Sagan noted that reliable cases are uninteresting, and interesting cases are unreliable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. Allen Hynek and Jacques Vallée developed descriptive systems for characterizing UFO sightings and organizing ufology investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;phenomena-linked-to-ufology&#34;&gt;Phenomena linked to ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#phenomena-linked-to-ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain phenomena are of interest to some ufologists, including crop circles, cattle mutilations, anomalous materials, alien abductions, and implants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ufologists promote UFO conspiracy theories, including the Roswell Incident, Majestic 12 documents, and UFO disclosure advocates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Sheaffer has accused ufology of a &amp;ldquo;credulity explosion,&amp;rdquo; where increasingly outlandish stories gain traction. James E. McDonald identified &amp;ldquo;cultism&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;extreme subgroups&amp;rdquo; as negatively impacting ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-posadism&#34;&gt;In Posadism &lt;a href=&#34;#in-posadism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the Cold War, ufology was synthesized with Posadism, a Trotskyist movement in South America. Juan Posadas, the main theorist, believed humanity should appeal to extraterrestrials to collaborate in suppressing poverty and creating a socialist system on Earth. This belief contributed to the decline of Posadism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;governmental-and-private-ufology-studies&#34;&gt;Governmental and private ufology studies &lt;a href=&#34;#governmental-and-private-ufology-studies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting in the 1940s, governmental agencies and private groups sponsored investigations, studies, and conferences related to ufology. These studies include Project Sign, Project Magnet, Project Blue Book, the Robertson Panel, and the Condon Committee in the United States; the Flying Saucer Working Party and Project Condign in Britain; GEIPAN in France; and Project Hessdalen in Norway. Private studies include those by the RAND Corporation, Harvey Rutledge of the University of Missouri, and the National Press Club&amp;rsquo;s Disclosure Project. The United Nations sponsored meetings and hearings concerning UFO sightings from 1977 to 1979. In August 2020, the United States Department of Defense established the Unidentified Aerial Phenomena Task Force to detect, analyze, and catalog unidentified aerial phenomena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufo-organizations-and-events&#34;&gt;UFO organizations and events &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-organizations-and-events&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerous private organizations worldwide are dedicated to the study, discussion, and publicity of ufology. Skeptic organizations emphasize the pseudoscientific nature of ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During World UFO Day (July 2), ufologists raise public awareness of ufology, including group gatherings to search for and observe UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ufological&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ufological&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychological perspectives on UFO belief</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_0747aa33b15c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_0747aa33b15c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;psychological-perspectives-on-ufo-belief&#34;&gt;Psychological Perspectives on UFO Belief &lt;a href=&#34;#psychological-perspectives-on-ufo-belief&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Claims of sighting, visitation, and contact with unidentified flying objects (UFOs) have been the subject of medical and psychological research. Some research suggests psychopathological origins for these claims, while others propose that &amp;ldquo;experiencers&amp;rdquo; may simply have overactive imaginations. Treatment approaches include antipsychotic medication, psychotherapy, and lifestyle changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufo-belief-as-a-mental-health-disorder&#34;&gt;UFO Belief as a Mental Health Disorder &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-belief-as-a-mental-health-disorder&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines the idea that belief in UFOs and extraterrestrial contact may be linked to underlying mental health conditions. It highlights research suggesting that individuals claiming face-to-face contact with extraterrestrials (ETs) may have distinct psychological profiles compared to those without such experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;research&#34;&gt;Research &lt;a href=&#34;#research&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several studies are presented that explore the potential link between UFO beliefs and mental health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 1983 study in the &lt;em&gt;Canadian Journal of Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; examined six individuals claiming extraterrestrial contact and concluded that five suffered from a paranoid delusional state akin to paraphrenia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 1997 study by researchers at the University of Essex found an association between UFO-related beliefs and schizotypy, a construct that may indicate a risk of developing schizophrenia or other psychotic disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2008 study published in &lt;em&gt;Cortex&lt;/em&gt; found that individuals alleging alien abduction showed higher levels of dissociativity and a tendency to hallucinate compared to a control group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;individual-experiencers&#34;&gt;Individual Experiencers &lt;a href=&#34;#individual-experiencers&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents case studies of individuals whose belief in alien encounters was linked to mental health issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2000 case study at Boston University Medical Center described a married couple with shared psychotic disorder involving a belief in alien abductions. The husband had a history of mental health issues and suicide attempts, and the couple&amp;rsquo;s shared delusion reinforced their beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2008 case at the University of Louisville involved a woman with sleep paralysis who believed she was being abducted by aliens. Her belief was attributed to post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) resulting from the paralysis and cultural acclimation to the alien abduction phenomenon. Psychotherapy improved her condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2023 case study from Nova Southeastern University reported on a 17-year-old boy who felt &amp;ldquo;as if he is being chased by Martians.&amp;rdquo; He was diagnosed with schizophrenia and treated with risperidone, cognitive behavioral therapy, and counseling to stop using marijuana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufo-belief-as-a-personality-trait&#34;&gt;UFO Belief as a Personality Trait &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-belief-as-a-personality-trait&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the idea that belief in UFOs may be related to certain personality traits, particularly fantasy-prone personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Persons with a fantasy-prone personality spend a significant portion of their lives involved in fantasy and may confuse or mix their fantasies with their real life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medical sociologist Robert Bartholomew suggests that some individuals are prone to exceptionally vivid fantasies and have difficulty distinguishing between fantasy and reality. Science journalist Eric Smalley hypothesizes that &amp;ldquo;starseeds&amp;rdquo; may be experiencing the Barnum effect, with books providing a sense of authenticity to their beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychology professor Robert Baker proposed fantasy-prone personality as an explanation for UFO contacts, noting that individuals reporting such contacts are not necessarily psychotic or neurotic, just &amp;ldquo;a little different.&amp;rdquo; Armando Simon, a staff psychologist at the Texas Department of Corrections, argued that belief in UFOs is a cultural norm in North America and not necessarily a sign of mental illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 1991 study of 152 individuals reporting alien abductions found that 132 exhibited characteristics consistent with fantasy-prone personality. A 2001 study in the &lt;em&gt;European Journal of UFO and Abduction Studies&lt;/em&gt; found that persons who reported seeing UFOs tended &amp;ldquo;to have a richer fantasy life than those who do not report UFOs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufo-belief-as-faulty-perceptuality&#34;&gt;UFO Belief as Faulty Perceptuality &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-belief-as-faulty-perceptuality&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines how cognitive and perception psychology can explain UFO beliefs, focusing on how human perception, cognitive biases, and psychological tendencies shape beliefs about UAP stimuli. Joey Florez explored UAPs through comparative institutional psychology, focusing on the intuitive and conspiratorial mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Florez explains that understanding flawed perception entails considering anomalous phenomena from antiquity, given the over-reliance on superstition and illogical assumptions about the external world. Ancient Greeks interpreted bright flashes in the sky as Zeus firing lightning bolts, reinforcing divine authority and political legitimacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two central modes of information processing, intuitive and conspiratorial, can be used to identify modern UAP beliefs from a cognitive and perceptual perspective. Primary experiences with UAP stimuli often involve intuitive processing, while secondary experiences often involve conspiratorial processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pareidolia refers to anomalies in the brain&amp;rsquo;s initial perception of recognizable patterns in ambiguous visual stimuli, while apophenia is intentional and results in complex convictions of conspiratorial narratives. Research has suggested cognitive reflection and education may reduce narcissistic susceptibility to conspiratorial processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-studies-and-hypotheses&#34;&gt;Other Studies and Hypotheses &lt;a href=&#34;#other-studies-and-hypotheses&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents additional research and perspectives on UFO belief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 1993 study in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Abnormal Psychology&lt;/em&gt; found no difference in psychopathology and fantasy proneness between persons alleging abduction by UFOs and those with more mundane UFO experiences, concluding that UFO belief did not have a psychopathological origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research published in 2017 in &lt;em&gt;Motivation and Emotion&lt;/em&gt; found that paranormal beliefs related to extraterrestrial life were partly motivated by the need for meaning in life, with persons experiencing a lack of life meaning demonstrating a higher propensity for such beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harvard University psychiatrist John E. Mack suggested that some patients related actual encounters with non-humans or non-human controlled UFOs that were not explainable as mental illness. However, a Harvard review committee concluded that Mack was not using &amp;ldquo;rational and scholarly&amp;rdquo; research methods. Mack&amp;rsquo;s use of hypnosis to elicit purportedly repressed memories of abduction experiences has also been criticized. UCLA psychiatrist Fred Frankel and Michael D. Yapko criticized Mack&amp;rsquo;s use of hypnosis, explaining that fantasy and suggestion play a major role during hypnosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychological_perspectives_on_UFO_belief&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychological_perspectives_on_UFO_belief&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of UFO religions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_c138a4063c7d/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_c138a4063c7d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-religions&#34;&gt;UFO Religions &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-religions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFO religions are groups that incorporate beliefs about communication with extraterrestrial beings into their religious doctrines. These groups often interpret major religions as being based on supernatural beings from heaven. Communication methods include telepathy and astral projection. A common belief is that humanity can be saved through education provided by aliens, leading to societal improvement. Alien abduction experiences can also contribute to the formation of these religions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for understanding UFO religions. It highlights that these religions generally involve belief in communication with extraterrestrial beings, often through physical contact, telepathy, or astral projection. These groups typically believe that aliens will save humanity by teaching them a better way to live, sometimes by taking believers to a more positive location. UFO religions emphasize spiritual growth and the evolution of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. Gordon Melton is identified as considering the &amp;ldquo;I AM&amp;rdquo; Activity, founded by Guy Ballard, as the first UFO religion. However, Christopher Hugh Partridge views it as a theosophical religion rather than a UFO religion. Partridge emphasizes the belief within UFO religions that supreme beings originate from other planets or planes, not from Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Roswell incident of 1947 is identified as a key event in the history of UFO spirituality, marking the emergence of UFOs into public consciousness. UFO religion is placed within the context of theosophical esotericism and New Age thought, with many groups believing that extraterrestrial beings are heralds of a new era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Aetherius Society, founded by George King in 1955, is described as one of the first and most enduring UFO cults. Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate and the Order of the Solar Temple are mentioned as controversial groups combining UFO beliefs with contactee assertions. Scientology is also discussed as a UFO religion due to its Xenu cosmogony and space opera elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;list&#34;&gt;List &lt;a href=&#34;#list&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a table listing various UFO religions, their founders, and the year they were founded. The list includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aetherius Society:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by George King in 1955.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ashtar Galactic Command:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Thelma B. Terrill (&amp;ldquo;Tuella&amp;rdquo;) in 1977.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CEIRUS:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Jean Miguères in 1987.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chen Tao:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Hon-ming Chen in 1993.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christ Brotherhood:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Wallace C. Halsey in 1956.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cosmic Circle of Fellowship:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by William R. Ferguson in 1955.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fiat Lux:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Uriella in 1980.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freie Interessengemeinschaft für Grenz- und Geisteswissenschaften und Ufologiestudien:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Billy Meier in the 1970s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ground Crew Project:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Sheldon Nidle in the 1980s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Marshall Applewhite and Bonnie Nettles in the 1970s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;I AM&amp;rdquo; Activity:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Guy Ballard in the 1930s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industrial Church of the New World Comforter:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Allen Michael in 1973.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark-Age:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Charles Boyd Gentzel and Pauline Sharpe in 1962.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nation of Islam:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Wallace Fard Muhammad in 1930.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Néo-Phare:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Arnaud Mussy in 2001.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nuwaubian Nation:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Dwight York in the 1970s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Order of the Solar Temple:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Joseph Di Mambro and Luc Jouret in 1984.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raëlism:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Raël in 1974.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rational Culture:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Manoel Jacintho Coelho in the 1930s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sanctuary of Thought:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Truman Bethurum in the 1950s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Seekers:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Charles Laughead (aka &amp;ldquo;Dr. Armstrong&amp;rdquo;) or Dorothy Martin (aka &amp;ldquo;Marian Keech&amp;rdquo;) in 1953.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Siderella:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Jean-Paul Appel-Guéry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scientology:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by L. Ron Hubbard in 1952.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unarius:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Ernest Norman and Ruth Norman in 1954.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universe People:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Ivo A. Benda in 1997.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Urantia movement:&lt;/strong&gt; Authorship of &lt;em&gt;The Urantia Book&lt;/em&gt; is unknown and disputed. The book alleges it was written by celestial beings. Founded between 1924 and 1955.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vale do Amanhecer:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Neiva Chaves Zelaya in the 1960s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics and links for further exploration, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Religion portal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outer space portal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doomsday cult&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of new religious movements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of ufologists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of UFO organizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO_religions&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO_religions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cattle mutilation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_ee1c97534fee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 18:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_ee1c97534fee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;cattle-mutilation&#34;&gt;Cattle Mutilation &lt;a href=&#34;#cattle-mutilation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cattle mutilation refers to the killing and mutilation of cattle and other animals under unusual and often bloodless circumstances. The phenomenon has been linked to paranormal and supernatural explanations, as well as more mundane causes. Mutilations typically involve the removal of organs such as the eyes, tongue, and genitals. Reports of such incidents span the globe, involving various livestock and wild animals. Explanations range from natural decomposition and predation to cults, government agencies, cryptids like the chupacabra, and extraterrestrials. The United States has conducted two federal investigations into the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-history&#34;&gt;Early History &lt;a href=&#34;#early-history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documented reports of unexplained livestock deaths date back to 1606 in England, where sheep were found slaughtered with only tallow and some inward parts removed. Charles Fort collected accounts of similar mutilations in England during the late 19th and early 20th centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-snippy-horse-death-of-1967&#34;&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Snippy&amp;rdquo; Horse Death of 1967 &lt;a href=&#34;#the-snippy-horse-death-of-1967&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unexplained death and mutilation of a horse named &amp;ldquo;Snippy&amp;rdquo; in Alamosa, Colorado, in 1967 brought the phenomenon to wider attention. The &lt;em&gt;Pueblo Chieftain&lt;/em&gt; published a story about the incident, detailing the horse&amp;rsquo;s skinned and defleshed head and neck, as well as precise cuts on the body. The lack of blood and a medicinal odor at the scene fueled speculation about extraterrestrial involvement. Wadsworth Ayer&amp;rsquo;s investigation for the Condon Committee concluded there was no evidence of abnormal causes. Sheriff Ben Phillips initially attributed the death to a lightning strike. Later, two students confessed to shooting the horse weeks after the incident gained publicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cattle-mutilations-19731980&#34;&gt;Cattle Mutilations 1973–1980 &lt;a href=&#34;#cattle-mutilations-19731980&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This period saw a surge in reported cattle mutilations across Kansas, Nebraska, Colorado, and New Mexico. Unidentified helicopters were reported in connection with cattle and pig rustling in Western Iowa (April 1973) and Missouri (August 1973).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1973-kansas-wave&#34;&gt;1973 Kansas Wave &lt;a href=&#34;#1973-kansas-wave&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June 1973, Cloud County sheriff Fred Modlin warned the public about suspicious phone calls from someone posing as a USDA official. Several butchered cows were subsequently found in the county, with right ears removed. Local press speculated about a &amp;ldquo;Mad Dog&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;phantom&amp;rdquo; butcher. By December, law enforcement reported a wave of cattle deaths in seven counties across Kansas and Nebraska, with sexual organs removed. State Senator Ross Doyen reported a mutilation on his ranch. The Kansas Brand Commissioner&amp;rsquo;s office attributed most deaths to natural causes, a conclusion disputed by Modlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1974-nebraska-wave&#34;&gt;1974 Nebraska Wave &lt;a href=&#34;#1974-nebraska-wave&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports continued in April 1974 with a mutilated and blood-drained cow in Nebraska. The North American Newspaper Alliance reported on the 1973 mutilations and helicopter sightings. Mutilations were reported in Mills County, Iowa, with coyotes blamed. By June, Lancaster County, Nebraska, reported mutilations. Custer County reported helicopter sightings and armed patrols. In August, an unidentified helicopter was spotted shining a spotlight over a field where a mutilated cow was later found near Agnew, Nebraska. Knox County Sheriff Herbert Thompson reported armed civilian patrols due to helicopter sightings. Cloud County Attorney William Walsh suggested devil-worshiping cultists were responsible. State Sen. John Decamp called for a coordinated investigation. By late August, 25 mutilations were reported across five Nebraska counties. A rancher near Hartington apparently thwarted a mutilation in progress when a helicopter was spotted above his field. Authorities cautioned against shooting at aircraft. In September, an autopsy revealed a supposedly-mutilated cow died of bacterial infection. Over 50 law enforcement officials attended a meeting in Center, Nebraska, estimating 27 out of 80 cow deaths were suspected mutilations. South Dakota also reported alleged mutilations. &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; became the first national outlet to cover the story, reporting 100 cattle mutilated in Nebraska, Kansas, and Iowa since May. South Dakota Attorney General Kermit Sande confirmed mutilation reports in the state. UFO expert J. Allen Hynek denied any link between UFOs and mutilations. Minnesota reported mutilations in Kandiyohi, Swift, and Meeker counties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1975-colorado&#34;&gt;1975 Colorado &lt;a href=&#34;#1975-colorado&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1975, the Colorado Associated Press voted the mutilations as the state&amp;rsquo;s top story. Senator Floyd K. Haskell contacted the FBI, claiming 130 mutilations in Colorado and reports across nine states. A 1979 FBI report estimated 8,000 mutilations in Colorado, causing $1 million in damages. Donald E. Flickinger of the Michigan ATF investigated possible links to a &amp;ldquo;Hell-oriented biker gang.&amp;rdquo; The Colorado Bureau of Investigation opened an investigation under Carl Whiteside. &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; published a story examining cattle mutilations across 11 states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1976-dulce-new-mexico&#34;&gt;1976 Dulce, New Mexico &lt;a href=&#34;#1976-dulce-new-mexico&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 13, 1976, Dulce rancher Manuel Gomez reported a mutilation to Officer Gabe Valdez of the New Mexico State Patrol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1979-public-meeting&#34;&gt;1979 Public Meeting &lt;a href=&#34;#1979-public-meeting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 20, 1979, U.S. Attorney R. E. Thompson and US Senator Harrison Schmidt held a public meeting about cattle mutilations, attended by about 80 people. Paul Bennewitz reported seeing unidentified lights over Kirtland Air Force Base. In May, Valdez reported finding two drugs in a mutilated bull&amp;rsquo;s remains: Chlorpromazine (Thorazine) to tranquilize the animal and another to clog the blood. In June 1981, investigators found a mutilated cow at the Gomez ranch with radar chaff nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;later-incidents&#34;&gt;Later Incidents &lt;a href=&#34;#later-incidents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many mutilation cases have been reported worldwide since 1967, primarily in the Americas and Australia. South America has seen an estimated 3,500 incidents since 2002. Investigators believe many cases go unreported. In 1993, photographic evidence surfaced of a mutilated human corpse found near the Guarapiranga reservoir of São Paulo, Brazil, in 1988. Theories ranged from homicide to alien abduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;characteristics&#34;&gt;Characteristics &lt;a href=&#34;#characteristics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cattle deaths due to natural causes are common. However, ranchers began reporting unusual deaths characterized by missing sex organs, udders, tongues, anus, and sometimes ears or eyes. Cuts were described as &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;surgical.&amp;rdquo; Some animals were reported drained of blood with no blood at the scene. Howard Burgess noted that nearly 90 percent of mutilated cattle are between four and five years old. Strange marks or imprints have been found near mutilation sites. The &amp;ldquo;Snippy&amp;rdquo; case featured an absence of tracks and small holes &amp;ldquo;punched&amp;rdquo; in the ground. In Rio Arriba County, New Mexico, a &amp;ldquo;trail of suction cup-like impressions&amp;rdquo; was found leading from a mutilated cow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;laboratory-reports&#34;&gt;Laboratory Reports &lt;a href=&#34;#laboratory-reports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laboratory reports on some mutilated animals have shown unusual levels of vitamins or minerals and the presence of chemicals not normally found in animals. However, these anomalies are not consistent across all cases. In a case documented by New Mexico police and the FBI involving a bull belonging to Manuel Gomez of Dulce, New Mexico, the animal displayed &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo; mutilation signs. The liver and heart were white and mushy, with the texture of peanut butter. Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory detected &lt;em&gt;Clostridium&lt;/em&gt; bacteria in the heart but could not draw conclusions. Liver samples were devoid of copper and contained high levels of zinc, potassium, and phosphorus. Blood samples were light pink and did not clot. The animal&amp;rsquo;s hide was brittle, and the flesh was discolored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;helicopter-sightings&#34;&gt;Helicopter Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#helicopter-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On July 15, 1974, two unregistered helicopters reportedly opened fire on Robert Smith Jr. in Honey Creek, Iowa. This followed a series of alleged mutilations in the area. In August 1974, residents reported seeing unidentified helicopters shining spotlights into fields where mutilated cows were later found. Know County Sheriff Herbert Thompson claimed helicopter sightings were nightly occurrences. By 1975, some ranchers formed armed vigilante groups. Authorities ran ads urging ranchers not to shoot at survey helicopters. The National Guard warned its helicopter pilots to fly at higher altitudes. In 1976, two Cache County, Utah, police officers reportedly confronted men in an unmarked U.S. Army helicopter. After this encounter, cattle mutilations in the region ceased for about five years. On April 8, 1979, three police officers in Dulce, New Mexico, reported a mysterious aircraft resembling a U.S. military helicopter hovering around a site following a wave of alleged mutilations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;official-investigations&#34;&gt;Official Investigations &lt;a href=&#34;#official-investigations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New Mexico Livestock Board sought assistance from the Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory. Colorado Bureau of Investigation agents went undercover. Oklahoma convened a task force. Federal authorities launched a comprehensive investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bureau-of-alcohol-tobacco-and-firearms&#34;&gt;Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms &lt;a href=&#34;#bureau-of-alcohol-tobacco-and-firearms&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January 1975, the Minnesota field office of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms (ATF) launched an investigation headed by Agent Donald Flickinger, tasked with investigating possible connections between cults and cattle mutilation. Flickinger recorded unusual incidents and circumstantial evidence but found insufficient evidence of cult involvement. His investigation was dropped when it was determined cattle deaths were not a prelude to a coordinated campaign against elected officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;colorado-bureau-of-investigation&#34;&gt;Colorado Bureau of Investigation &lt;a href=&#34;#colorado-bureau-of-investigation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May 1975, the Colorado Bureau of Investigation opened an investigation under Carl Whiteside. 19 animals underwent necropsies at Colorado State University, but no conclusive results emerged. A $40,000 reward was offered. The US Bureau of Land Management&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle_mutilation&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle_mutilation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Close Encounters of the Third Kind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_c68085f81f67/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_c68085f81f67/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;close-encounters-of-the-third-kind&#34;&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind &lt;a href=&#34;#close-encounters-of-the-third-kind&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 1977 American science fiction drama film directed and written by Steven Spielberg. It tells the story of Roy Neary, an everyday blue-collar worker in Indiana, and Jillian, a single mother, whose lives are changed after encounters with unidentified flying objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1977, French scientist Claude Lacombe and his team examine Flight 19, found abandoned in the Sonoran Desert, and the SS Cotopaxi, found in the Gobi Desert. Near Indianapolis, Roy Neary has a close encounter with a UFO, becoming obsessed with a mountain shape. Jillian Guiler&amp;rsquo;s son, Barry, is abducted by a UFO. Lacombe&amp;rsquo;s team investigates increasing UFO activity, discovering a five-tone musical phrase. The coordinates point to Devils Tower in Wyoming. Roy and Jillian, along with others experiencing visions, head to Devils Tower, which is being evacuated by the US Army. They reach the site as UFOs appear. Scientists communicate with the UFOs using light and sound. A mothership arrives, releasing humans and animals, including Barry. Roy is chosen to join the extraterrestrials, entering the mothership as it departs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Dreyfuss stars as Roy Neary, an electrical lineman. François Truffaut plays Claude Lacombe, a French scientist. Teri Garr is Ronnie Neary, Roy&amp;rsquo;s wife, and Melinda Dillon portrays Jillian Guiler. Cary Guffey plays Barry Guiler, Jillian&amp;rsquo;s son. Bob Balaban appears as David Laughlin, Lacombe&amp;rsquo;s assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;development&#34;&gt;Development &lt;a href=&#34;#development&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film&amp;rsquo;s inspiration came from Steven Spielberg&amp;rsquo;s childhood experience watching a meteor shower. He developed a deal with Columbia Pictures in 1973. J. Allen Hynek, a UFO consultant, was hired. NASA declined to cooperate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;filming&#34;&gt;Filming &lt;a href=&#34;#filming&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Principal photography began in May 1976. Filming locations included Burbank, California; Devils Tower National Monument in Wyoming; airship hangars in Mobile, Alabama; and a railroad depot in Bay Minette, Alabama. The Sonora Desert sequence was filmed at the Dumont Dunes, California, and the Dharmsala-India exteriors were filmed near Mumbai, India. Technical and budgetary problems arose during filming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;visual-effects&#34;&gt;Visual effects &lt;a href=&#34;#visual-effects&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Douglas Trumbull served as the visual effects supervisor, and Carlo Rambaldi designed the extraterrestrials. The mothership was designed by Ralph McQuarrie and built by Greg Jein. The look of the ship was inspired by an oil refinery Spielberg saw at night in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;post-production&#34;&gt;Post-production &lt;a href=&#34;#post-production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Kahn was the film editor. Pick-ups were commissioned, with John A. Alonzo, László Kovács, and Douglas Slocombe working on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;Music &lt;a href=&#34;#music&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Williams composed the film score, including the iconic five-tone motif. Spielberg called Williams&amp;rsquo;s work &amp;ldquo;When You Wish Upon a Star meets science fiction.&amp;rdquo; Phillip Dodds from ARP Instruments installed the synthesizer on set and was cast as Jean Claude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes &lt;a href=&#34;#themes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film explores themes of humanity&amp;rsquo;s readiness to join the cosmos, the impact of new technologies, and spiritual yearning. Judeo-Christian analogies are present, with Devils Tower paralleling Mount Sinai. Communication and tolerance are also highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release-and-reception&#34;&gt;Release and reception &lt;a href=&#34;#release-and-reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;box-office&#34;&gt;Box office &lt;a href=&#34;#box-office&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film premiered in New York City on November 16, 1977, and was released nationally in December. It became a box office success, grossing over $300 million worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;critical-reception&#34;&gt;Critical reception &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviews were mostly positive, with praise for Spielberg&amp;rsquo;s vision and the film&amp;rsquo;s climax. Some critics noted a lack of warmth compared to &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reissues-and-home-media&#34;&gt;Reissues and home media &lt;a href=&#34;#reissues-and-home-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several versions of the film have been released, including the original theatrical version, the Special Edition (1980), and the Director&amp;rsquo;s Cut (1998). The Special Edition added scenes, including the interior of the mothership, while the Director&amp;rsquo;s Cut removed the mothership interior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;accolades&#34;&gt;Accolades &lt;a href=&#34;#accolades&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received numerous awards and nominations, including Academy Awards, British Academy Film Awards, and Golden Globe Awards. It was selected for preservation in the National Film Registry in 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legacy&#34;&gt;Legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Close Encounters&lt;/em&gt; is credited with launching the reemergence of science fiction films in the 1980s. Spielberg donated to the Planetary Society for extraterrestrial research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Close_Encounters_of_the_Third_Kind&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Close_Encounters_of_the_Third_Kind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdimensional UFO hypothesis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_cdc9008149f9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_cdc9008149f9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;interdimensional-ufo-hypothesis&#34;&gt;Interdimensional UFO Hypothesis &lt;a href=&#34;#interdimensional-ufo-hypothesis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interdimensional UFO hypothesis (IUH) proposes that unidentified flying object (UFO) sightings result from encounters with other &amp;ldquo;dimensions&amp;rdquo; that coexist alongside our own. This idea is supported by ufologists who suggest that UFOs are a modern manifestation of phenomena throughout human history, previously attributed to mythological or supernatural beings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the historical context of the interdimensional UFO hypothesis, tracing its roots from pre-modern concepts to modern ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pre-modern-history&#34;&gt;Pre-modern history &lt;a href=&#34;#pre-modern-history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concepts similar to &amp;ldquo;other dimensions&amp;rdquo; exist in various religious and mystical traditions. Islamic mysticism, known as Sufism, includes the concept of &lt;em&gt;al-ghayb&lt;/em&gt;, referring to the hidden and unseen. Within this tradition, &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;ālam al-mithāl&lt;/em&gt;, or &amp;ldquo;the world of similitude,&amp;rdquo; is considered an intermediary realm between the physical and spiritual worlds, inhabited by intelligent non-human entities such as jinn and angels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;theorists&#34;&gt;Theorists &lt;a href=&#34;#theorists&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces key figures who have advanced the interdimensional UFO hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 19th century, spiritualists believed in &amp;ldquo;other dimensions.&amp;rdquo; H.P. Blavatsky popularized the term &amp;ldquo;planes,&amp;rdquo; proposing a cosmology of seven planes. The term &amp;ldquo;ether&amp;rdquo; was adopted from ancient Greek and incorporated into occult writings. Charles Webster Leadbeater and Annie Besant introduced the &amp;ldquo;etheric plane&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;etheric body&amp;rdquo; in Theosophy. The first use of the word, as &lt;em&gt;inter-dimensional&lt;/em&gt;, is in a novel by Z Gale of 1906.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;meade-layne-and-ether-ships&#34;&gt;Meade Layne and &amp;lsquo;Ether Ships&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#meade-layne-and-ether-ships&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meade Layne, an occultist, claimed in 1947 that flying discs were &amp;ldquo;etheric.&amp;rdquo; Layne claimed telepathic communication with &amp;ldquo;people in the saucers,&amp;rdquo; arguing that objects could pass from an etheric to a dense level of matter. He stated that these visitors were human beings living in their own world with good intentions. Layne is regarded as the earliest proponent of the interdimensional hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;john-keel-and-ultraterrestrials&#34;&gt;John Keel and &amp;lsquo;Ultraterrestrials&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#john-keel-and-ultraterrestrials&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Keel coined the term &amp;ldquo;ultraterrestrials&amp;rdquo; to describe UFO occupants as non-human entities existing in a wavelength of energy undetectable to us. In his book &lt;em&gt;UFOs: Operation Trojan Horse&lt;/em&gt;, Keel argued that a non-human intelligence has staged events to propagate erroneous belief systems, including monsters, ghosts, demons, fairies, vampires, mystery airships, anomalous creatures, poltergeists, and UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hynek-and-vallée&#34;&gt;Hynek and Vallée &lt;a href=&#34;#hynek-and-vall%c3%a9e&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. Allen Hynek, an astronomer and scientific advisor to the U.S. Air Force UFO studies, pioneered the &amp;ldquo;Close Encounter&amp;rdquo; classification system. Jacques Vallée, a student of Hynek, served as the inspiration for a character in the film &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt;. In &lt;em&gt;The Edge of Reality&lt;/em&gt;, Vallée and Hynek considered the possibility of &amp;ldquo;interlocking universes.&amp;rdquo; Vallée argued for a &amp;ldquo;parallel universe co-existing with our own&amp;rdquo; in his book &lt;em&gt;Passport to Magonia&lt;/em&gt;. Vallée&amp;rsquo;s 1990 paper &amp;ldquo;Five Arguments Against the Extraterrestrial Origin of Unidentified Flying Objects&amp;rdquo; summarized his objections to the extraterrestrial hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the presence of the interdimensional UFO hypothesis in popular culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2008 film &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull&lt;/em&gt; utilizes the interdimensional hypothesis, describing ancient aliens traveling into &amp;ldquo;the space between the spaces.&amp;rdquo; The 2014 movie &lt;em&gt;Interstellar&lt;/em&gt; employs a mix of the interdimensional and time-traveler hypotheses, with future humans evolving to exist in five dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-contrasting-hypothesis&#34;&gt;Other contrasting hypothesis &lt;a href=&#34;#other-contrasting-hypothesis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contrasts the IUH with other hypotheses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IUH contrasts with the extraterrestrial hypothesis, which suggests UFO sightings are caused by visitations from outside Earth, and the psychosocial hypothesis, which argues UFO sightings are best explained as psychological or social phenomena. Other contrasting hypotheses include the cryptoterrestrial hypothesis, space animal hypothesis, and time-traveler hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists related topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fallen angel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiverse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spiritualism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;String theory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interdimensional_hypothesis&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interdimensional_hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO reports and atomic sites</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_415176c4b3ae/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 07:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_415176c4b3ae/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;correlation-between-ufo-reports-and-atomic-sites&#34;&gt;Correlation between UFO reports and atomic sites &lt;a href=&#34;#correlation-between-ufo-reports-and-atomic-sites&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article explores the historical and statistical connections between reports of Unidentified Flying Objects (UFOs) and locations associated with atomic technology, primarily in the United States. It examines how early speculation linked UFO sightings to atomic sites, the influence of the Cold War, and various incidents and studies that have fueled this correlation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section establishes the context for the link between UFO reports and atomic sites. It highlights the increased scrutiny of US airspace due to national security concerns in 1947, coinciding with increased media coverage of UFO reports. It notes that the development of atomic weapons and long-range vehicles meant that even a small number of adversarial overflights could have significant national security implications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1940s-weapons-development&#34;&gt;1940s weapons development &lt;a href=&#34;#1940s-weapons-development&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the development of atomic weapons by the US during World War II as part of the Manhattan Project. Key locations mentioned are Oak Ridge, Tennessee (uranium enrichment), Hanford, Washington (plutonium production), and Los Alamos, New Mexico (bomb design and construction). It also discusses the increased lethality and range of air power during the war and Japan&amp;rsquo;s deployment of intercontinental balloon bombs, one of which interfered with plutonium production at Hanford. The US&amp;rsquo;s Project Mogul, inspired by the Japanese balloons, aimed to detect Soviet atomic tests. The section also mentions German advancements in rockets, jet fighters, and bomber designs, which both the US and Soviet governments learned about and utilized after the war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;increased-scrutiny-of-us-airspace&#34;&gt;Increased scrutiny of US airspace &lt;a href=&#34;#increased-scrutiny-of-us-airspace&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explains how the possibility of a Soviet atomic attack led to increased surveillance of US airspace, particularly around atomic facilities. It mentions the development of the first intercontinental bomber, the Convair B-36 Peacemaker, which could reach the Soviet Union from American soil. Atomic sites were among the first locations in the US to operate radar, supported by visual spotters and fighter squadrons. The start of the Cold War in 1947 influenced media coverage of UFO reports, treating them as potential national security threats rather than folklore or tall tales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chronology&#34;&gt;Chronology &lt;a href=&#34;#chronology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents a timeline of notable UFO incidents and their connection to atomic sites, starting in 1947.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;supposed-flying-discs-allegedly-break-sound-barrier&#34;&gt;Supposed flying discs allegedly break sound barrier &lt;a href=&#34;#supposed-flying-discs-allegedly-break-sound-barrier&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the Kenneth Arnold sighting in June 1947, where he reported seeing nine objects flying at supersonic speeds near Mount Rainier and Mount Adams in Washington state. The proximity of this sighting to the Hanford plutonium plant led to media speculation about a connection. The section also notes that the sound barrier was not officially broken until October 1947 by Chuck Yeager, and the Air Force initially denied the achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;roswell-and-atomic-weapons&#34;&gt;Roswell and atomic weapons &lt;a href=&#34;#roswell-and-atomic-weapons&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the Roswell incident in July 1947, where debris was found on a ranch near Corona, New Mexico. The 509th at Roswell was the Army&amp;rsquo;s atomic bomb group. The initial explanation of a weather balloon was later questioned, and the Air Force eventually concluded the debris came from a Project Mogul balloon designed to detect Soviet atomic tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;public-claims-of-link-to-atomic-sites&#34;&gt;Public claims of link to atomic sites &lt;a href=&#34;#public-claims-of-link-to-atomic-sites&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the public&amp;rsquo;s perception of a link between flying discs and atomic weaponry in 1947. It mentions headlines claiming a connection between &amp;ldquo;discs&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;atom products,&amp;rdquo; citing an unnamed scientist from the Manhattan Project who suggested experiments in atomic energy transmutation were responsible for the sightings. The Hanford works were also mentioned as a location with numerous UFO reports. Atomic scientists Harold Urey and David E. Lilienthal dismissed these claims as &amp;ldquo;gibberish.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mantell-crash-near-oak-ridge&#34;&gt;Mantell crash near Oak Ridge &lt;a href=&#34;#mantell-crash-near-oak-ridge&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the Mantell incident in January 1948, where Captain Thomas F. Mantell, a pilot from Fort Knox, Kentucky, crashed while pursuing a UFO near Oak Ridge, Tennessee. The Air Force later attributed the UFO to a Skyhook balloon, a classified project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;green-fireballs-near-hanford&#34;&gt;Green Fireballs near Hanford &lt;a href=&#34;#green-fireballs-near-hanford&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses reports of green fireballs near Hanford, Washington, starting in December 1948. It mentions Lincoln LaPaz&amp;rsquo;s investigation of these reports and the issuance of orders to fire on potentially hostile aircraft over Hanford and Oak Ridge. The section also notes UFO reports over Hanford and Oak Ridge during the early days of the Korean War and a 1952 Life Magazine article reporting unusual radar returns near an atomic installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;contactees-and-nuclear-war&#34;&gt;Contactees and nuclear war &lt;a href=&#34;#contactees-and-nuclear-war&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the theme of nuclear war in UFO culture. The 1951 film &lt;em&gt;The Day the Earth Stood Still&lt;/em&gt; featured a benevolent spaceman warning about atomic weapons. George Adamski began claiming contact with &amp;ldquo;space brothers&amp;rdquo; concerned about atomic weapons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;big-sur-missile-test&#34;&gt;Big Sur missile test &lt;a href=&#34;#big-sur-missile-test&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes a reported UFO incident during a 1964 Air Force missile test near Big Sur, California. Robert Jacobs, who oversaw the team, claimed a UFO interfered with the test. Kingston George, the project engineer, argued the team had actually recorded the release of decoy warheads and chaff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;malmstrom-missile-malfunction&#34;&gt;Malmstrom missile malfunction &lt;a href=&#34;#malmstrom-missile-malfunction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses UFO reports over a missile complex in March 1967 during a routine malfunction. Retired Air Force personnel later claimed the weapons failure was caused by a UFO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hynek-suggests-atomic-link&#34;&gt;Hynek suggests atomic link &lt;a href=&#34;#hynek-suggests-atomic-link&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section notes that astronomer J. Allen Hynek, initially hired by the Air Force to debunk UFO reports, began speculating in 1968 that UFOs might be related to an unknown phenomenon connected to nuclear energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rendelsham&#34;&gt;Rendelsham &lt;a href=&#34;#rendelsham&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the Rendlesham Forest incident in December 1980, a series of reported sightings of unexplained lights near RAF Woodbridge in England, which was used by the United States Air Force (USAF). USAF personnel, including Lieutenant Colonel Charles I. Halt, claimed to see things they described as a UFO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;21st-century&#34;&gt;21st century &lt;a href=&#34;#21st-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers more recent developments, including a legend that the 1945 Trinity atomic bomb test brought down an alien spacecraft. It mentions Robert Hastings&amp;rsquo; book &lt;em&gt;UFOs &amp;amp; Nukes: Extraordinary Encounters at Nuclear Weapons Sites&lt;/em&gt; and claims by former AATIP director Luis Elizondo and former U.S. Air Force personnel that UAPs have interfered with nuclear capabilities. It also notes reports of UFOs interfering with other major powers&amp;rsquo; nuclear weapons systems. The section mentions the U.S. National Defense Authorization Act requesting more information on UAP incidents associated with military nuclear assets and claims by Robert L. Salas and Robert Hastings of alien abduction. Finally, it mentions that the Canadian Nuclear Safety Commission will raise the issue of UAP with its United States counterpart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statistical-studies&#34;&gt;Statistical studies &lt;a href=&#34;#statistical-studies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines the statistical evidence for a correlation between UFO reports and atomic sites, considering the possibility of observational bias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It introduces the concept of the &amp;ldquo;streetlight effect,&amp;rdquo; where observations are more likely to be reported where observations are most likely to occur. Mainstream experts argue that increased scrutiny of airspace around strategically important facilities explains the correlation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The section mentions a rudimentary spatial analysis conducted by Air Force officers in the 1950s, which found that UFOs were seen more frequently around areas vital to US defense, such as Los Alamos-Albuquerque, Oak Ridge, and White Sands Proving Ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2015 study of UFO reports in France concluded that there was a statistically significant link between nuclear activities and unexplained UFO reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2021 document from the Office of the Director of National Intelligence suggested that clustering of UFO reports around US training and testing grounds might be due to &amp;ldquo;collection bias as a result of focused attention.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2023 study examined a National UFO Reporting Center dataset and found that UFO reports are more frequent in areas with darker nighttime skies and &amp;ldquo;wide-open spaces.&amp;rdquo; Additionally, analysis suggested that proximity to airports and military installations was linked to increased UFO reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_reports_and_atomic_sites&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_reports_and_atomic_sites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial intelligence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_d19b9c3cea60/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 13:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_d19b9c3cea60/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial Intelligence &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extraterrestrial intelligence (ETI) refers to hypothetical intelligent life beyond Earth. It emphasizes that no such life has been verifiably observed. The concept&amp;rsquo;s modern form arose with the Copernican Revolution, which positioned Earth as one of many planets. The possibility of inhabited worlds beyond Earth is a major question in science, science fiction, and popular culture. An alternative term, &amp;ldquo;Extraterrestrial Technological Instantiations&amp;rdquo; (ETI), avoids potentially ambiguous terms like &amp;ldquo;civilizations&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;species.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intelligence&#34;&gt;Intelligence &lt;a href=&#34;#intelligence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section defines intelligence in the context of extraterrestrial life, linking it to human-like cognitive abilities. It introduces &amp;ldquo;sapience&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sophoncy&amp;rdquo; as related terms. Karen and Poul Anderson are credited with coining the term sophoncy. The section clarifies that &amp;ldquo;sentience&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;consciousness&amp;rdquo; are broader terms that don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily imply intelligence or sapience. The term &amp;ldquo;extraterrestrial civilization&amp;rdquo; is presented as a specific case of extraterrestrial intelligence, representing the potential long-term result of intelligent extraterrestrial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;probability&#34;&gt;Probability &lt;a href=&#34;#probability&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the likelihood of extraterrestrial intelligence. It mentions the Copernican principle, suggesting humans aren&amp;rsquo;t privileged observers. Stephen Hawking is noted as one of many scientists who believe the universe&amp;rsquo;s scale makes extraterrestrial life probable. Fermi&amp;rsquo;s Paradox is introduced, highlighting the contradiction between high probability estimates and the lack of evidence. The section reiterates the absence of observed extraterrestrial life. The Kardashev scale, a method for measuring a civilization&amp;rsquo;s technological advancement based on energy use, is mentioned. The Drake equation, a probabilistic framework for estimating the number of communicative extraterrestrial civilizations in the Milky Way, is also noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34;&gt;Search for extraterrestrial intelligence &lt;a href=&#34;#search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the search for ETI, noting the lack of significant results despite decades of effort. It defines Active SETI as the attempt to send messages to potential extraterrestrial civilizations, usually via radio signals, and mentions the Pioneer plaque as a physical example. Communication with Extraterrestrial Intelligence (CETI) is described as focusing on composing and deciphering messages. Frank Drake and Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s Arecibo message is cited as a well-known CETI experiment. It mentions that multiple independent organizations and individuals are engaged in CETI research. The U.S. government&amp;rsquo;s stance, reflecting expert consensus, is that the chances of contact are extremely small. The possibility of first contact being with extraterrestrial artificial intelligence is raised. The Wow! signal is mentioned as the best candidate for an extraterrestrial radio signal, but its uniqueness makes attribution difficult. The section concludes with the report of possible artificial signals detected by China&amp;rsquo;s FAST telescope in June 2022, followed by the caution from Dan Werthimer that these signals are likely radio interference from Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;potential-cultural-impact-of-extraterrestrial-contact&#34;&gt;Potential cultural impact of extraterrestrial contact &lt;a href=&#34;#potential-cultural-impact-of-extraterrestrial-contact&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the potential consequences of contact with extraterrestrial intelligence. It notes that the impact could vary based on the extraterrestrial civilization&amp;rsquo;s technological advancement, intentions, and mutual comprehension with humanity. It mentions the possibility of contact with a civilization that has transcended biology and exists within advanced computers. The medium of contact (e.g., electromagnetic radiation, physical interaction) could also influence the results. The section draws parallels between extraterrestrial contact and historical encounters between vastly different human cultures, citing the Columbian Exchange as an example. It notes that such encounters have often led to the destruction of the less advanced civilization, raising the possibility of a similar outcome for humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufology&#34;&gt;UFOlogy &lt;a href=&#34;#ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section connects extraterrestrial intelligence to UFOs. The extraterrestrial hypothesis, which posits that some UFOs are vehicles from extraterrestrial beings, is introduced. The section contrasts ETI with EDI (extradimensional intelligence) as explanations for UFOs, referencing J. Allen Hynek. It mentions a 2023 House hearing examining the executive branch&amp;rsquo;s handling of UFO reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-culture&#34;&gt;In culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section briefly mentions the cultural impact of theories about intelligent life, particularly in popular culture since the advent of spaceflight. It notes that New Mexico declared February 14th as Extraterrestrial Culture Day in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_intelligence&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychosocial UFO hypothesis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_89f0f0eb48db/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 07:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_89f0f0eb48db/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;psychosocial-hypothesis-in-ufology&#34;&gt;Psychosocial Hypothesis in Ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#psychosocial-hypothesis-in-ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psychosocial hypothesis (PSH) in ufology posits that psychological and social factors best explain some UFO reports. It contrasts with the extraterrestrial hypothesis (ETH). This perspective is favored by UFO researchers in the UK, including David Clarke and Hilary Evans, and in France, following Michel Monnerie&amp;rsquo;s 1977 book. PSH researchers distinguish themselves from debunkers by maintaining a serious, albeit skeptical, interest in UFOs. The hypothesis suggests that mundane explanations combined with emotional climates distort perceptions, and that claims of contact with extraterrestrials from uninhabitable planets point to psychological processes like dreams and hallucinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;origin&#34;&gt;Origin &lt;a href=&#34;#origin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;psychosocial hypothesis&amp;rdquo; gained prominence in English UFO literature in 1984, with Jacques Scornaux and Peter Rogerson&amp;rsquo;s article in &lt;em&gt;Magonia&lt;/em&gt;. Scornaux&amp;rsquo;s use of the term originated from French UFO controversies sparked by Michel Monnerie&amp;rsquo;s challenge to the ETH. Rogerson&amp;rsquo;s adoption of the term marked a shift from paranormal explanations to normal psychological processes influenced by cultural myths and social conditioning. Writers for &lt;em&gt;Magonia&lt;/em&gt; had been exploring alternatives to the ETH since 1968, noting the failure of the ETH to account for high strangeness cases. Roger Sandell&amp;rsquo;s research on a 1905 Welsh UFO wave led him to believe that UFO reports were part of a larger complex of ghost stories and religious visions. Peter Rogerson advocated for a search for historical antecedents of UFO rumors and the social factors driving UFO flaps and social panics, noting a relationship between UFO waves and times of radical social change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;science-fiction-aspects-of-the-ufo-mythos&#34;&gt;Science Fiction Aspects of the UFO Mythos &lt;a href=&#34;#science-fiction-aspects-of-the-ufo-mythos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bertrand Méheust&amp;rsquo;s discovery of parallels between UFO experience narratives and pre-1947 science fiction literature led to a study of the science fiction aspects of UFO mythology. Méheust found numerous parallels, including wondrous effects and humanoid motives. Michel Monnerie integrated Meheust&amp;rsquo;s study into his historical critique of UFO mythology. Michel Meurger expanded Meheust&amp;rsquo;s thesis into a compendium of parallels. Jacques Vallee noted electromagnetic effects associated with UFOs in earlier fiction. Researchers have explored the cultural back-stories to various alien types, including Grays, insectoids, and reptoids. Other studies explore science fictional saucer esoterica along psychosocial and historical lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-saucer-rumor&#34;&gt;The Saucer Rumor &lt;a href=&#34;#the-saucer-rumor&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mystery of why flying saucers are the dominant shape in UFO reports was addressed by Martin Kottmeyer, who discovered that Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s initial sighting in 1947 was misinterpreted. Arnold&amp;rsquo;s description of the objects&amp;rsquo; motion, rather than their shape, led to the &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; label. This mistake shaped the UFO phenomenon for decades, influencing film imagery, saucer photography, UFO illustration, contactee tales, and abduction experiences. Kottmeyer&amp;rsquo;s findings, first reported in 1988, suggest a cultural origin for the flying saucer phenomenon. The principal counterargument is that flying saucers were seen before Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s story, but Kottmeyer argues that the dominance of the saucer shape after 1947 is the key issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flaps-of-flying-phantoms&#34;&gt;Flaps of Flying Phantoms &lt;a href=&#34;#flaps-of-flying-phantoms&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early researchers attempted to correlate UFO flaps with Mars&amp;rsquo; proximity, but these predictions failed. British researchers shifted focus to pre-1947 &amp;ldquo;waves,&amp;rdquo; examining social, religious, political, and scientific backgrounds. Roger Sandell&amp;rsquo;s work on a 1905 Welsh UFO outbreak revealed odd facets and high strangeness material. Nigel Watson reported on a 1909 panic involving German airships spying on Britain. Phantom airship flaps were catalogued from various locations, involving cigar-shaped craft and rumors of foreign spies. By the 1930s, phantom airships were replaced by phantom aeroplanes. Researchers have experimented with variations in these explanations, such as the 1905 Wales flap occurring during a time of social change. Researchers generally reject explanations involving mass hysteria, preferring to discuss flaps as collective delusions maintained by rumor and gossip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-modern-myth-of-jung&#34;&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Modern Myth&lt;/em&gt; of Jung &lt;a href=&#34;#the-modern-myth-of-jung&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Gustav Jung&amp;rsquo;s essay &lt;em&gt;Flying Saucers: A Modern Myth of Things Seen in the Skies&lt;/em&gt; is considered a foundational work for the PSH. Jung&amp;rsquo;s use of synchronicity has also led some to see him as a proponent of paranormal explanations. While Jung acknowledged the possibility of some UFOs being physical objects, he clarified that he was uncommitted on the issue of their reality. He expressed concern that news affirming the existence of UFOs was more welcome than skepticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychosocial_hypothesis&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychosocial_hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychosocial UFO hypothesis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_a235c7fbdf9b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 07:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_a235c7fbdf9b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;psychosocial-hypothesis-in-ufology&#34;&gt;Psychosocial Hypothesis in Ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#psychosocial-hypothesis-in-ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psychosocial hypothesis (PSH) in ufology suggests that some UFO reports are best explained by psychological or social factors rather than extraterrestrial origins. It contrasts with the extraterrestrial hypothesis (ETH) and is favored by UFO researchers in the UK and France. Proponents view UFOs as an interesting subject for study, even with skepticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;origin&#34;&gt;Origin &lt;a href=&#34;#origin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;psychosocial hypothesis&amp;rdquo; gained prominence in English UFO literature in 1984, influenced by French UFO controversies sparked by Michel Monnerie&amp;rsquo;s challenge to the ETH. &lt;em&gt;Magonia&lt;/em&gt; magazine played a key role in popularizing the term. Peter Rogerson&amp;rsquo;s adoption of the term marked a shift away from paranormal explanations towards normal psychological processes influenced by cultural myths and social conditioning. Writers associated with &lt;em&gt;Magonia&lt;/em&gt; had been exploring alternatives to the ETH since 1968, driven by the belief that it failed to account for high strangeness cases. Roger Sandell&amp;rsquo;s research on a 1905 Welsh UFO wave led him to conclude that UFO reports were part of a larger complex of ghost stories and religious visions. Peter Rogerson advocated for a search for historical antecedents of UFO rumors and the social factors driving UFO flaps and social panics, noting a relationship between UFO waves and times of radical social change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;science-fiction-aspects-of-the-ufo-mythos&#34;&gt;Science Fiction Aspects of the UFO Mythos &lt;a href=&#34;#science-fiction-aspects-of-the-ufo-mythos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bertrand Méheust&amp;rsquo;s study of science fiction parallels to UFO mythology revealed numerous similarities between UFO experience narratives and pre-1947 science fiction literature. These parallels include wondrous effects like invisible force-fields, teleportation, and engine-stopping rays, as well as humanoid motives for visiting Earth. Michel Monnerie integrated Meheust&amp;rsquo;s study into his historical critique of UFO mythology. Michel Meurger expanded Meheust&amp;rsquo;s thesis with a compendium of parallels. Jacques Vallee noted electromagnetic effects associated with UFOs in earlier fiction. Researchers have explored the cultural backstories to various alien types, including Grays, insectoids, and reptoids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-saucer-rumor&#34;&gt;The Saucer Rumor &lt;a href=&#34;#the-saucer-rumor&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psychosocial approach helped solve the mystery of why flying saucers are the dominant shape in UFO reports. Martin Kottmeyer discovered that the &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; label originated from a misinterpretation of Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s 1947 sighting. Arnold described the objects&amp;rsquo; motion as erratic, &amp;ldquo;like a saucer if you skip it across the water,&amp;rdquo; but the reporter misinterpreted this as describing the objects&amp;rsquo; shape. This mistake shaped the UFO phenomenon for decades, influencing film imagery, saucer photography, UFO illustration, contactee tales, and abduction experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flaps-of-flying-phantoms&#34;&gt;Flaps of Flying Phantoms &lt;a href=&#34;#flaps-of-flying-phantoms&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early researchers attempted to correlate UFO flaps with Mars&amp;rsquo; proximity, but these predictions failed. British researchers shifted focus to pre-1947 &amp;ldquo;waves,&amp;rdquo; examining social, religious, political, and scientific backgrounds. Nigel Watson researched a March–May 1909 panic involving German airships spying on Britain. Phantom airship flaps were cataloged in various locations, often accompanied by rumors of foreign spies. By the 1930s, phantom airships were replaced by phantom aeroplanes. Researchers have experimented with variations in these explanations, such as the 1905 Wales flap occurring during a time of rapid social change. Researchers generally reject explanations involving mass hysteria, preferring to discuss flaps as collective delusions maintained by rumor and gossip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-modern-myth-of-jung&#34;&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Modern Myth&lt;/em&gt; of Jung &lt;a href=&#34;#the-modern-myth-of-jung&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Gustav Jung&amp;rsquo;s essay &lt;em&gt;Flying Saucers: A Modern Myth of Things Seen in the Skies&lt;/em&gt; is considered a foundational work of the PSH. While some argue that Jung also considered the ETH, Jung himself refuted claims that he believed UFOs were physically real. He emphasized the psychological significance of the UFO phenomenon, regardless of its objective reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychosocial_UFO_hypothesis&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychosocial_UFO_hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time-traveler UFO hypothesis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_4666fb28cb0a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 17:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_4666fb28cb0a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;time-traveler-ufo-hypothesis&#34;&gt;Time-traveler UFO hypothesis &lt;a href=&#34;#time-traveler-ufo-hypothesis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time-traveler hypothesis, also known as chrononaut UFO, future humans, extratempestrial model, and Terminator theory, proposes that unidentified flying objects (UFOs) are humans traveling from the future using advanced technology. This concept has gained recent attention from figures like retired NASA aerospace engineer Larry Lemke, Wisconsin congressman Mike Gallagher, and filmmaker Steven Spielberg. Mainstream scholars consider this hypothesis extremely implausible, and it&amp;rsquo;s generally viewed as unorthodox even among fringe conspiracy theorists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;antecedents&#34;&gt;Antecedents &lt;a href=&#34;#antecedents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the origins of the ideas that led to the time-traveler UFO hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;origins-of-time-travel-speculation&#34;&gt;Origins of time travel speculation &lt;a href=&#34;#origins-of-time-travel-speculation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection traces the concept of time travel from the future to the past back to its literary origins. Pierre Boitard&amp;rsquo;s 1861 book &lt;em&gt;Paris avant les hommes&lt;/em&gt; is credited with introducing the idea, featuring a man sent back to prehistoric Earth. Camille Flammarion&amp;rsquo;s 1887 novel &lt;em&gt;Lumen&lt;/em&gt; also explored the theme of a soul traveling through different historical periods. The section also notes that while time travel is considered physically impossible by most, theoretical research continues to explore its potential feasibility, with scientists like J. Richard Gott and Ronald Mallet speculating on the possibility of future human time travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;speculation-of-future-human-evolution&#34;&gt;Speculation of future human evolution &lt;a href=&#34;#speculation-of-future-human-evolution&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the history of speculation about the future evolution of mankind. It highlights H.G. Wells&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;The Time Machine&lt;/em&gt; as an early example of both time travel and speculative evolution. Other authors mentioned include Edgar Rice Burroughs, Olaf Stapledon, Kurt Vonnegut, Stephen Baxter, and Cevdet Mehmet Kösemen. The section also identifies climate change, the technological singularity, space travel, and genetic enhancement as potential factors that could alter human evolution, leading to transhuman and posthuman scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ufos-and-initial-explanations&#34;&gt;UFOs and initial explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#ufos-and-initial-explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection provides a brief overview of the history of UFO sightings. It mentions reports of unknown objects in the skies dating back to antiquity, as well as the mystery airship sightings of the 1890s and the Foo fighters and ghost rockets during World War II. The modern UFO era is said to have begun in the summer of 1947, following Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting. Initial explanations for these sightings ranged from novel US or Soviet technology to misidentification of mundane objects and mass hysteria. Fringe theories included extraterrestrial or interdimensional origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;formation-and-spread&#34;&gt;Formation and spread &lt;a href=&#34;#formation-and-spread&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the development and popularization of the time-traveler UFO hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;implausibility-of-humanoid-aliens&#34;&gt;Implausibility of humanoid aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#implausibility-of-humanoid-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection addresses the common depiction of aliens as humanoids in contactee and alien abduction folklore. It cites George Gaylord Simpson&amp;rsquo;s 1964 article &lt;em&gt;The Nonprevalence of Humanoids&lt;/em&gt;, which argues that it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely for extraterrestrial intelligence to exist and even more unlikely for it to be humanoid. The section also mentions Stephen Jay Gould&amp;rsquo;s thought experiment about rewinding evolution, suggesting that humans would likely not evolve again. Biologist Jack Cohen&amp;rsquo;s view on the implausibility of Grey aliens evolving a physiology similar to humans is also included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;modern-popularization&#34;&gt;Modern popularization &lt;a href=&#34;#modern-popularization&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explores the modern resurgence of the time-traveler hypothesis. It mentions Jacques Vallée&amp;rsquo;s 1975 book &lt;em&gt;The Invisible College&lt;/em&gt; as an early example. Other figures and works mentioned include David S. Anderson, Jenny Randles, James Herbert Brennan, and Philip J. Corso and William J. Birnes&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;The Day After Roswell&lt;/em&gt;, which reported Hermann Oberth&amp;rsquo;s belief that the Roswell craft could have been a time machine. The History channel series &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; is also mentioned for its episodes exploring the concept. Michael P. Masters&amp;rsquo; book &lt;em&gt;Identified Flying Objects&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Extratempestrial Model&lt;/em&gt; are highlighted for their in-depth exploration of the hypothesis. Tim Peake and Steven Spielberg are mentioned for their recent public comments on the theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection lists examples of the time-traveler hypothesis in popular culture. It includes the TV series &lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s About Time&lt;/em&gt;, Gregory Benford&amp;rsquo;s novel &lt;em&gt;Timescape&lt;/em&gt;, David Drake&amp;rsquo;s novel &lt;em&gt;Birds of Prey&lt;/em&gt;, Michael Crichton&amp;rsquo;s novel &lt;em&gt;Sphere&lt;/em&gt;, the TV film &lt;em&gt;Official Denial&lt;/em&gt;, the comic book series &lt;em&gt;Blake and Mortimer&lt;/em&gt;, the band Yes, Jordan Peele&amp;rsquo;s movie &lt;em&gt;Nope&lt;/em&gt;, and the movie &lt;em&gt;Interstellar&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;terminology-and-connection-to-other-theories&#34;&gt;Terminology and connection to other theories &lt;a href=&#34;#terminology-and-connection-to-other-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection clarifies the terminology used to describe the hypothesis, noting that while Michael P. Masters uses the term &amp;ldquo;extratempestrial,&amp;rdquo; the overall idea is often referred to as &amp;ldquo;the time-traveler hypothesis.&amp;rdquo; It also discusses the overlap between the time-traveler hypothesis and the interdimensional hypothesis, with figures like John Ventre and Harold E. Puthoff using the terms interchangeably. The section also notes that the time-traveler hypothesis provides an alternative explanation for the absence of future time travelers, similar to how the extraterrestrial hypothesis addresses Fermi&amp;rsquo;s paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;criticism&#34;&gt;Criticism &lt;a href=&#34;#criticism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents criticisms of the time-traveler hypothesis. It notes that the hypothesis is considered pseudoscientific. Neil deGrasse Tyson is quoted as calling the hypothesis illogical, and Robert Sheaffer criticizes Michael P. Masters&amp;rsquo; work for relying on the belief that time travel is possible. David J. Darling argues that the extraterrestrial and time-travel hypotheses are equally unlikely and unnecessary. Ian Ridpath suggests that Jim Penniston&amp;rsquo;s claims about time-traveling UFOs may have been influenced by the film &lt;em&gt;Official Denial&lt;/em&gt;. Isaac Arthur is mentioned for debunking the concept as presented in &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;. Fabio Costa is quoted as saying that time travel requires two doors, one in the future and one in the past, raising the question of where the time machine is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics, including Time travel, Posthumanism, Transhumanism, Timeline of the far future, Longtermism, Speculative Evolution, Cryptoterrestrial hypothesis, Psychosocial hypothesis, Interdimensional hypothesis, and Space animal hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time-traveller_UFO_hypothesis&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time-traveller_UFO_hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO (Television Documentary Series)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_9913cf9600c1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 06:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_9913cf9600c1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-television-documentary-series&#34;&gt;UFO (Television Documentary Series) &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-television-documentary-series&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A four-part television documentary series about unidentified flying objects (UFOs). It was produced by J.J. Abrams&amp;rsquo; production company, Bad Robot, and aired on Showtime in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces the documentary series, stating its genre as a television documentary, its subject matter as unidentified flying objects, the number of episodes (4), the production company (Bad Robot), and the original network (Showtime). It also mentions J.J. Abrams as the producer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a link to the &amp;ldquo;List of Showtime original programming&amp;rdquo; Wikipedia page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the citations used in the article. These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; article by Alexis Soloski, titled &amp;ldquo;How Much Watching Time Do You Have This Weekend?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;Daily Beast&lt;/em&gt; article by Nick Schager, titled &amp;ldquo;J.J. Abrams&amp;rsquo; Mission to Expose the Truth About UFOs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;Paste&lt;/em&gt; article titled &amp;ldquo;Showtime&amp;rsquo;s Compelling UFO Docuseries Deserves to Be on Your Radar.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the series&amp;rsquo; page on IMDb (Internet Movie Database).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_(American_TV_series)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_(American_TV_series)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial UFO hypothesis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_526895167195/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 23:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_526895167195/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-ufo-hypothesis&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial UFO Hypothesis &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-ufo-hypothesis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the extraterrestrial hypothesis (ETH), which suggests that some unidentified flying objects (UFOs) are best explained as spacecraft or probes from intelligent extraterrestrial civilizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;usage-of-the-term&#34;&gt;Usage of the Term &lt;a href=&#34;#usage-of-the-term&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section traces the use of the term &amp;ldquo;extraterrestrial hypothesis&amp;rdquo; in UFO literature. It notes that the term gained traction in the latter half of the 1960s, with early usage attributed to French ufologist Jacques Vallée in his 1966 book. Other figures who used the term in the late 1960s include Aimé Michel, James E. McDonald, and James Harder. Physicist Edward Condon is credited with popularizing the term and its abbreviation &amp;ldquo;ETH&amp;rdquo; in 1969 when presenting the findings of the Condon Report. Skeptic Philip J. Klass also used the term in his 1968 book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chronology&#34;&gt;Chronology &lt;a href=&#34;#chronology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the historical context leading up to the modern ETH. It traces the origins of the idea of extraterrestrial life and visitation to earlier concepts, including Percival Lowell&amp;rsquo;s theories about Martian canals and ancient Martian civilizations, the science fiction writings of H. G. Wells and Edgar Rice Burroughs, and the works of Emanuel Swedenborg, who linked other worlds to the afterlife. It also mentions Charles Fort, who collected accounts of anomalous aerial phenomena in the early 20th century and theorized about visitors from other worlds. The modern ETH, linking unidentified aircraft to alien life, took root in the late 1940s and 1950s, influenced by pseudoscience and popular culture, and bolstered by unexplained sightings investigated by governments and civilian groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-reports-of-extraterrestrial-visits&#34;&gt;Historical Reports of Extraterrestrial Visits &lt;a href=&#34;#historical-reports-of-extraterrestrial-visits&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents examples of early speculation about extraterrestrial visitors. It mentions a French newspaper story from 1864 about the discovery of an alien-like creature inside an egg-shaped structure. It also discusses H. G. Wells&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;The War of the Worlds&amp;rdquo; (1898), which popularized the idea of Martian visitation and invasion. The section notes a surge in &amp;ldquo;mystery airship&amp;rdquo; reports in the late 19th century, with some speculating about Martian origins. It also mentions the influence of comic strips, radio shows, and movies like Buck Rogers and Flash Gordon in popularizing the idea of alien visitation in spaceships. Orson Welles&amp;rsquo; 1938 radio broadcast of &amp;ldquo;The War of the Worlds&amp;rdquo; caused some public panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-1947-flying-saucer-wave-in-america&#34;&gt;The 1947 Flying Saucer Wave in America &lt;a href=&#34;#the-1947-flying-saucer-wave-in-america&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the events surrounding the Kenneth Arnold sighting in 1947 and the subsequent &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; craze. It details Arnold&amp;rsquo;s initial report of seeing unidentified disk-shaped aircraft near Mount Rainier and his consideration of the possibility of extraterrestrial origins. The section notes the widespread speculation in newspapers about the nature of the &amp;ldquo;saucers,&amp;rdquo; including theories about secret military projects, Russian spy devices, hoaxes, optical illusions, and mass hysteria. It mentions Senator Glen Taylor&amp;rsquo;s comment about wishing the saucers were spaceships from another planet and R. DeWitt Miller&amp;rsquo;s suggestion that they could be vehicles from Mars or other dimensions. The section also cites journalist Edward R. Murrow&amp;rsquo;s observation that the ETH did not gain widespread attention until about 18 months after Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;evolution-of-public-opinion&#34;&gt;Evolution of Public Opinion &lt;a href=&#34;#evolution-of-public-opinion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines how public opinion regarding UFOs and the ETH evolved. It mentions the release of the first U.S. poll of public UFO perceptions by Gallup in August 1947, which showed that most people either had no opinion or believed there was a mundane explanation for the sightings. The section also discusses the influence of movies depicting flying saucers and aliens in the early 1950s. It cites a poll published in Popular Science magazine in 1951, which reported that most UFO witnesses believed they had seen a man-made aircraft. By 1957, 25% of Americans were willing to believe in the ETH. A Roper poll in 2002 reported that 56% of respondents thought UFOs were real, with 48% believing that UFOs had visited Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;religion&#34;&gt;Religion &lt;a href=&#34;#religion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section briefly mentions the connection between UFOs and religion, citing the Aetherius Society, founded by George King in 1955, as one of the first and most enduring UFO cults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nasa&#34;&gt;NASA &lt;a href=&#34;#nasa&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses NASA&amp;rsquo;s evolving stance on UAPs. In June 2021, NASA Administrator Bill Nelson directed NASA scientists to investigate Unidentified Aerial Phenomenon, exploring the possibility that UAP could represent extraterrestrial technology. NASA scientist Ravi Kopparapu advocates studying UAP with an agnostic approach, involving experts from various fields to collect data and deduce the identity of such UAP. In August 2021, Kopparapu presented a paper supporting ETH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;private-or-government-studies&#34;&gt;Private or Government Studies &lt;a href=&#34;#private-or-government-studies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents examples of private or government studies that have concluded in favor of the ETH or have had members who disagreed with official conclusions. It mentions a 1948 Top Secret USAF Europe document citing Swedish air intelligence&amp;rsquo;s conclusion that some UFOs had extraterrestrial origins. It also discusses the USAF Project Sign&amp;rsquo;s 1948 Top Secret Estimate of the Situation, which concluded that the ETH was the most likely explanation for the most perplexing unexplained cases. The section mentions a secret West German study from 1951 to 1954, headed by Hermann Oberth, which also concluded that UFOs were extraterrestrial. It also discusses the CIA&amp;rsquo;s internal scientific review of UFOs in the early 1950s, noting that some CIA scientists were seriously considering the ETH. The section mentions extraterrestrial &amp;ldquo;believers&amp;rdquo; within Project Blue Book, including Major Dewey Fournet and consultant J. Allen Hynek, who later became a staunch supporter of the ETH. It also cites statements from former CIA Director Roscoe H. Hillenkoetter, who urged Congressional action to reduce the dangers from secrecy about unidentified flying objects. The section mentions Greek physicist Paul Santorini&amp;rsquo;s claim that a 1947 Greek government investigation into the European Ghost rockets concluded that they were extraterrestrial. It also discusses the 1968 Condon Report, noting that many members of the study disagreed with Condon&amp;rsquo;s methods and biases. The section mentions the 1999 private French COMETA report, which concluded that the hypothesis of extraterrestrial visitors best accounted for the facts. It also discusses Jean-Jacques Velasco, the head of the official French UFO investigation SEPRA, who stated that 14% of the cases studied by SEPRA were &amp;lsquo;utterly inexplicable and extraterrestrial&amp;rsquo; in origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;critical-responses-and-positions-of-the-eth&#34;&gt;Critical Responses and Positions of the ETH &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-responses-and-positions-of-the-eth&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents critical responses to the ETH. It notes that there is no scientific proof to back up assertions of alien encounters. It states that despite ardent believers, no rigorous analysis has ever concluded that various UFO sightings are verifiable evidence for the ETH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;us-military-investigation-and-debunkery&#34;&gt;U.S. Military Investigation and Debunkery &lt;a href=&#34;#us-military-investigation-and-debunkery&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the U.S. military&amp;rsquo;s investigation of UFOs and its efforts to debunk the ETH. It mentions the formation of Project Sign in 1947, the first official U.S. military UFO study. It notes that Project Sign concluded without endorsing any unified explanation for all UFO reports, and the ETH was rejected by USAF Chief of Staff General Hoyt Vandenberg. The section also discusses the CIA&amp;rsquo;s Robertson Panel, which was organized in 1953 to review the Blue Book&amp;rsquo;s best evidence and recommend an official policy of public debunkery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;involvement-of-scientists&#34;&gt;Involvement of Scientists &lt;a href=&#34;#involvement-of-scientists&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines the scientific community&amp;rsquo;s response to the ETH. It notes that the scientific community has shown very little support for the ETH, largely accepting the explanation that UFO reports are the result of misinterpretations or hoaxes. It mentions Stephen Hawking&amp;rsquo;s skepticism about the ETH. The section cites Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s observation about the emotional nature of the idea of extraterrestrial visitation and the potential for self-deception. It also quotes Peter A. Sturrock&amp;rsquo;s statement about the narrow polarization of the UFO debate around the ETH. The section presents the results of a 1973 poll of American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics members, which found that about 10% believed that UFOs were vehicles from outer space. It also presents the results of a 1977 poll of American Astronomical Society members, which asked them to assign probabilities to eight possible explanations for UFOs. The section summarizes the primary scientific arguments against ETH, as outlined by J. Allen Hynek, including the failure of surveillance systems to detect UFOs, gravitational and atmospheric considerations, statistical considerations, the behavior of UFOs and their occupants, the isolation of the UFO phenomenon in time and space, the space unworthiness of UFOs, and the problem of astronomical distances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fewer-sightings-despite-camera-phone-technology&#34;&gt;Fewer Sightings Despite Camera Phone Technology &lt;a href=&#34;#fewer-sightings-despite-camera-phone-technology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the argument that the proliferation of smartphone camera technology has not led to a significant increase in recorded UFO sightings, calling into question the claimed phenomenology of UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nasa-1&#34;&gt;NASA &lt;a href=&#34;#nasa-1&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents NASA&amp;rsquo;s official standpoint on the ETH, which is that it lacks empirical evidence. It quotes David Morrison&amp;rsquo;s statements that no one has ever found a single artifact or any other convincing evidence for alien visits and that no claims of UFOs as being alien craft have any validity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cia&#34;&gt;CIA &lt;a href=&#34;#cia&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions the CIA&amp;rsquo;s organization of the January 1953 Robertson Panel of scientists to debunk the data collected by the Air Force&amp;rsquo;s Project Blue Book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;official-white&#34;&gt;Official White &lt;a href=&#34;#official-white&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_hypothesis&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of songs about close encounters with aliens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_a6f27fcf591b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 19:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_a6f27fcf591b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-songs-about-close-encounters-with-aliens&#34;&gt;List of Songs About Close Encounters with Aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-songs-about-close-encounters-with-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a compilation of songs across various decades that explore lyrical themes related to close encounters with extraterrestrial aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1940s&#34;&gt;1940s &lt;a href=&#34;#1940s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights the earliest example on the list, &amp;ldquo;(When You See) Those Flying Saucers&amp;rdquo; by The Buchanan Brothers, released in July 1947. Its release coincided with the beginning of the flying saucer era, shortly after the Kenneth Arnold UFO sighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1950s&#34;&gt;1950s &lt;a href=&#34;#1950s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1950s saw a surge in songs about flying saucers and aliens. Notable entries include &amp;ldquo;The Flying Saucer Parts 1 &amp;amp; 2&amp;rdquo; by Bill Buchanan and Dickie Goodman, &amp;ldquo;My Flying Saucer&amp;rdquo; with lyrics by Woodie Guthrie, &amp;ldquo;The Purple People Eater&amp;rdquo; by Sheb Wooley, &amp;ldquo;Two Little Men In A Flying Saucer&amp;rdquo; by Ella Fitzgerald, and &amp;ldquo;Flyin&amp;rsquo; Saucers Rock &amp;amp; Roll&amp;rdquo; by Billy Lee Riley and Jerry Lee Lewis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1960s&#34;&gt;1960s &lt;a href=&#34;#1960s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists songs from the 1960s that touch on extraterrestrial themes. Key songs include &amp;ldquo;Let There Be More Light&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Set the Controls for the Heart of the Sun&amp;rdquo; by Pink Floyd, &amp;ldquo;Mr. Spaceman&amp;rdquo; by The Byrds, &amp;ldquo;Voices Green and Purple&amp;rdquo; by The Bees, &amp;ldquo;It Came Out of the Sky&amp;rdquo; by Creedence Clearwater Revival, &amp;ldquo;Have You Seen the Saucers&amp;rdquo; by Jefferson Airplane, and &amp;ldquo;U.F.O.&amp;rdquo; by Jim Sullivan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1970s&#34;&gt;1970s &lt;a href=&#34;#1970s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1970s brought a diverse range of songs exploring alien encounters. Highlights include &amp;ldquo;After the Gold Rush&amp;rdquo; by Neil Young, &amp;ldquo;Calling Occupants of Interplanetary Craft&amp;rdquo; by Klaatu (covered by The Carpenters), &amp;ldquo;Childhood&amp;rsquo;s End&amp;rdquo; by Pink Floyd, &amp;ldquo;Come Sail Away&amp;rdquo; by Styx, &amp;ldquo;Here Come the Martian Martians&amp;rdquo; by Jonathan Richman and the Modern Lovers, &amp;ldquo;Horsell Commons and the Heat Ray&amp;rdquo; by Jeff Wayne, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve Seen the Saucers&amp;rdquo; by Elton John, &amp;ldquo;Longer Boats&amp;rdquo; by Cat Stevens, &amp;ldquo;Martian Boogie&amp;rdquo; by Brownsville Station, &amp;ldquo;Mothership Connection&amp;rdquo; by Parliament, &amp;ldquo;Starman&amp;rdquo; by David Bowie, &amp;ldquo;Starship Trooper&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Arriving UFO&amp;rdquo; by Yes, &amp;ldquo;Waiting for the UFOs&amp;rdquo; by Graham Parker, &amp;ldquo;Silver Lights&amp;rdquo; by Sammy Hagar, &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; by Johnny Rivers, &amp;ldquo;Children of the Sun&amp;rdquo; by Billy Thorpe, &amp;ldquo;Starrider&amp;rdquo; by Foreigner, &amp;ldquo;Strange Ships&amp;rdquo; by Fox, and &amp;ldquo;Ships in the Sky&amp;rdquo; by Wishbone Ash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1980s&#34;&gt;1980s &lt;a href=&#34;#1980s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers songs from the 1980s with alien or UFO themes. Noteworthy songs include &amp;ldquo;Fire Of Unknown Origin&amp;rdquo; by Blue Öyster Cult, &amp;ldquo;Books about UFOs&amp;rdquo; by Hüsker Dü, &amp;ldquo;Flying Saucers&amp;rdquo; by Nina Hagen, &amp;ldquo;Love Walks In&amp;rdquo; by Van Halen, &amp;ldquo;Loving the Alien&amp;rdquo; by David Bowie, &amp;ldquo;No Doubt About It&amp;rdquo; by Hot Chocolate, &amp;ldquo;Nobody Told Me&amp;rdquo; by John Lennon, &amp;ldquo;Rapture&amp;rdquo; by Blondie, &amp;ldquo;Zero Zero UFO&amp;rdquo; by The Ramones, &amp;ldquo;I Ran (So Far Away)&amp;rdquo; by A Flock of Seagulls, &amp;ldquo;Caught in the Crossfire&amp;rdquo; by April Wine, and &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t Be Late&amp;rdquo; by Saga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1990s&#34;&gt;1990s &lt;a href=&#34;#1990s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1990s entries include &amp;ldquo;The Alien Song (For Those Who Listen)&amp;rdquo; by Mila Jovovich, &amp;ldquo;El Aparato (&amp;ldquo;The Apparatus&amp;rdquo;)&amp;rdquo; by Café Tacvba, &amp;ldquo;Alien (I Am)&amp;rdquo; by Hawkwind, &amp;ldquo;Aliens Exist&amp;rdquo; by Blink-182, &amp;ldquo;Alien Visitors&amp;rdquo; by Man or Astro-man?, &amp;ldquo;Another Sunday&amp;rdquo; by I Mother Earth, &amp;ldquo;Fell in Love with an Alien&amp;rdquo; by the Kelly Family, &amp;ldquo;Hangar 18&amp;rdquo; by Megadeth, &amp;ldquo;Hat Too Flat&amp;rdquo; by Walter Becker, &amp;ldquo;I Made Love to a Martian&amp;rdquo; by Mustard Plug, &amp;ldquo;Girl from Mars&amp;rdquo; by Ash, &amp;ldquo;Martian Dance Invasion&amp;rdquo; by Brainiac, &amp;ldquo;Motorway to Roswell&amp;rdquo; by Pixies, &amp;ldquo;Scent of a Mule&amp;rdquo; by Phish, &amp;ldquo;Shades of Grey&amp;rdquo; by Stuart Davis, &amp;ldquo;Spaceman&amp;rdquo; by Babylon Zoo, &amp;ldquo;Subterranean Homesick Alien&amp;rdquo; by Radiohead, &amp;ldquo;The Happening&amp;rdquo; by Pixies, &amp;ldquo;Who&amp;rsquo;s There?&amp;rdquo; by Smash Mouth, &amp;ldquo;Spaceman&amp;rdquo; by Bif Naked, &amp;ldquo;Is That You Mo-Dean?&amp;rdquo; by The B-52s, &amp;ldquo;Men in Black&amp;rdquo; by Will Smith, and &amp;ldquo;Calgone&amp;rdquo; by Incubus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2000s-to-present&#34;&gt;2000s to present &lt;a href=&#34;#2000s-to-present&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists songs from the 2000s to the present day. It includes &amp;ldquo;Fracture&amp;rdquo; by Edison&amp;rsquo;s Children (Neil Armstrong&amp;rsquo;s son&amp;rsquo;s band), &amp;ldquo;The Aliens Are Here&amp;rdquo; by The Hippos, &amp;ldquo;And You Thought the Doctor&amp;rsquo;s Probe Hurt&amp;rdquo; by Belvedere, &amp;ldquo;Jaadoo, Jaadoo&amp;rdquo; by Rajesh Roshan, &amp;ldquo;Concerning the UFO sighting near Highland, Illinois&amp;rdquo; by Sufjan Stevens, &amp;ldquo;Aliens&amp;rdquo; by Doctor Octagon, &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; by Sneaky Sound System, &amp;ldquo;Rosetta Stoned&amp;rdquo; by Tool, &amp;ldquo;Fallout of the 4th Kind&amp;rdquo; by Edison&amp;rsquo;s Children, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re Not Alone&amp;rdquo; by Nas, &amp;ldquo;Spaceman&amp;rdquo; by The Killers, &amp;ldquo;Venus Ambassador&amp;rdquo; by Bryan Scary &amp;amp; The Shredding Tears, &amp;ldquo;E.T.&amp;rdquo; by Katy Perry featuring Kanye West, &amp;ldquo;Zopilotes&amp;rdquo; by Café Tacuba, &amp;ldquo;A Million Miles Away (I Wish I Had A Time Machine)&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;The Awakening&amp;rdquo; by Edison&amp;rsquo;s Children, &amp;ldquo;Ancient Aliens&amp;rdquo; by Lemon Demon, &amp;ldquo;Decks Dark&amp;rdquo; by Radiohead, &amp;ldquo;Hey Aliens&amp;rdquo; by The Bouncing Souls, &amp;ldquo;Spaceship&amp;rdquo; by Kesha, &amp;ldquo;Herd Culling&amp;rdquo; by Porcupine Tree, &amp;ldquo;Silver Circles&amp;rdquo; by Upchurch, &amp;ldquo;End of the World&amp;rdquo; by Tom MacDonald, &amp;ldquo;Staring at the Stars&amp;rdquo; by Dan Marfisi and Glenn Jordan, &amp;ldquo;An Alien Abduction Story (The Probing)&amp;rdquo; by The Schnooks, and &amp;ldquo;Down Bad&amp;rdquo; by Taylor Swift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes &lt;a href=&#34;#notes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a note indicating that certain songs are used as bumper music on the &lt;em&gt;StarTalk&lt;/em&gt; podcast UFO episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the various sources used to compile the list of songs, including articles from publications like &lt;em&gt;The A.V. Club&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Huffington Post&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;NPR&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Salon.com&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, and books on UFOs and alien encounters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section suggests a book for further exploration of the topic: &lt;em&gt;Alien Rock: The Rock &amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo; Roll Extraterrestrial Connection&lt;/em&gt; by M. Luckman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/(When_You_See)_Those_Flying_Saucers&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/(When_You_See)_Those_Flying_Saucers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO religion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_0a1958d0044c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 04:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_0a1958d0044c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-religion&#34;&gt;UFO Religion &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-religion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A UFO religion is a religion where belief in extraterrestrial entities operating unidentified flying objects (UFOs) is a core element. Adherents typically believe these ETs are interested in humanity&amp;rsquo;s welfare and that humanity will eventually join an existing ET civilization. Some UFO religions incorporate ETs into a supernatural worldview, blurring the lines between aliens and angels. These religions draw inspiration from early science fiction, ufology, UFO sightings, and alien abduction stories. The Aetherius Society, founded by George King, is considered the first UFO religion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary &lt;a href=&#34;#summary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adherents believe that the arrival or rediscovery of alien civilizations, technologies, and spirituality will enable humans to overcome ecological, spiritual, and social problems. Issues like hatred, war, bigotry, and poverty are believed to be resolvable through superior alien technology and spiritual abilities. These belief systems are often millenarian in their outlook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFO religions developed in countries like the United States, Canada, France, the United Kingdom, and Japan, where technology is advanced enough to conceive of ETs and where religion is not suppressed. The term &amp;ldquo;flying saucers&amp;rdquo; and the popular notion of the UFO originated in 1947. The study of UFO religions by sociologists, historians, theologians, scholars of religious studies, and new religious movements began in the 1950s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notable-ufo-religions&#34;&gt;Notable UFO Religions &lt;a href=&#34;#notable-ufo-religions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFO religions generally involve belief in communication with extraterrestrial beings through physical contact, telepathy, and astral projection. These groups often believe that humanity will be saved by aliens who will educate humans on a better way to live or take believers to a more positive location. Extraterrestrial beings are often seen pleading with humanity to improve itself and move away from greed and violence. UFO religions emphasize spiritual growth and the evolution of humanity. A UFO religion can form before or after an individual claims to have experienced an alien abduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. Gordon Melton identifies the &amp;ldquo;I AM&amp;rdquo; Activity, founded by Guy Ballard, as the first UFO religion, although Christopher Hugh Partridge views it as a theosophical religion. Partridge notes that UFO religions believe the supreme being or &amp;ldquo;evolved entity&amp;rdquo; came from another plane or planet. The 1947 Roswell incident is a key point in time within UFO spirituality. James R. Lewis notes that Ufologists see it as the date of the &amp;ldquo;emergence of UFOs into the public consciousness.&amp;rdquo; Partridge places UFO religion within the context of theosophical esotericism and asserts that it began to be associated as &amp;ldquo;UFO religion&amp;rdquo; after the Roswell incident. He notes that most UFO religions still have many of the key points associated with Theosophy, such as belief in the same Spiritual Hierarchy, and he also draws parallels to New Age thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen Hunt describes the Aetherius Society, founded by George King in 1955, as &amp;ldquo;probably the first and certainly the most enduring UFO cult.&amp;rdquo; Hunt places the Aetherius Society and Raëlism among the &amp;ldquo;most renowned&amp;rdquo; of the &amp;ldquo;flying saucer cults.&amp;rdquo; Melodie Campbell and Stephen A. Kent place the Aetherius Society and Unarius as among the &amp;ldquo;oldest and most studied&amp;rdquo; of the flying saucer cults. They describe Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate and Order of the Solar Temple as the &amp;ldquo;most controversial groups combining UFO belief with variations of contactee assertions.&amp;rdquo; Gregory L. Reece classes Scientology as a &amp;ldquo;UFO group,&amp;rdquo; discussing elements of the Xenu cosmogony and Space opera in Scientology doctrine. He compares Scientology to the Aetherius Society and Ashtar Command. Victoria Nelson writes that &amp;ldquo;[t]he most prominent current UFO religion is probably the science fiction writer L. Ron Hubbard&amp;rsquo;s Church of Scientology.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_religion&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_religion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Moore (ufologist)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_c8e39d7b02ff/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 13:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_c8e39d7b02ff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;william-l-moore-ufologist&#34;&gt;William L. Moore (Ufologist) &lt;a href=&#34;#william-l-moore-ufologist&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;William Leonard Moore, born October 31, 1943, is an author and former UFO researcher who gained prominence from the late 1970s to the late 1980s. He is best known for co-authoring two books with Charles Berlitz, including &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;career&#34;&gt;Career &lt;a href=&#34;#career&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moore&amp;rsquo;s interest in UFOs began in his teenage years. He graduated from Thiel College in Greenville, Pennsylvania, in 1965. After teaching language and humanities at various high schools, he became the Arizona state section director of the Mutual UFO Network (MUFON). He then transitioned to a career as a freelance writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He co-authored &lt;em&gt;The Philadelphia Experiment - Project Invisibility&lt;/em&gt; with Charles Berlitz in 1979, which explored the alleged naval military experiment aboard the USS &lt;em&gt;Eldridge&lt;/em&gt; in 1943. In 1980, Moore and Berlitz co-wrote &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt;, which claimed that the Roswell UFO incident involved the crash of an extraterrestrial spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May 1987, Moore, along with ufologists Jaime Shandera and Stanton Friedman, circulated the Majestic 12 documents, which purported the existence of a high-level policy-making group overseeing UFOs and extraterrestrials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a 1989 MUFON conference, Moore admitted to engaging in &amp;ldquo;disinformation&amp;rdquo; activities against Paul Bennewitz on behalf of the Air Force Office of Special Investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;critical-reception&#34;&gt;Critical Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Philadelphia Experiment - Project Invisibility&lt;/em&gt; has been largely dismissed as an unsubstantiated urban myth. &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt; has been criticized as a collection of hearsay and unwarranted speculation. Critics have also pointed fingers at Moore regarding the fraudulent nature of the Majestic 12 documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;books&#34;&gt;Books &lt;a href=&#34;#books&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Philadelphia Experiment Project Invisibility&lt;/em&gt; (1979)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt; (1980)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFO conspiracy theory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bill_Moore_(ufologist)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bill_Moore_(ufologist)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
