<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Extraterrestriality on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/extraterrestriality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Extraterrestriality on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 04:26:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/extraterrestriality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Culture of extraterrestriality</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_446ae6ad1e1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 04:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_446ae6ad1e1a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;culture-of-extraterrestriality&#34;&gt;Culture of Extraterrestriality &lt;a href=&#34;#culture-of-extraterrestriality&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The culture of extraterrestriality encompasses the cultural imagination and depiction of otherworldliness, alienness, or outer space. It characterizes &amp;ldquo;the other&amp;rdquo; through extraterrestrial space, going beyond mere extraterritoriality or periphery. It involves the space imagined or described as extraterrestrial, or any space outside a described land, creating conditions of spatially set apart otherness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extraterrestriality has been a feature of many past and contemporary cultures. Politically, it has been an element of utopianism and colonialism, particularly in the formation of colonies as products in extraterrestrial space. These histories inform contemporary cultures of extraterrestriality, influencing space exploration, the reception of its findings, space colonization, and the search for extraterrestrial life. Colonialism was associated with extraterrestrial space as early as the 17th century when John Wilkins suggested that future adventurers like Francis Drake and Christopher Columbus might reach the Moon and people to live there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists related topics for further exploration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extraterrestrials in fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search for extraterrestrial intelligence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potential cultural impact of extraterrestrial contact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expatriate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anthropocentrism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of citations used in the article, including links to external sources. Some of the sources include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Britain&amp;rsquo;s Extraterrestrial Empire: Colonial Ambition, Anxiety, and Ambivalence in Early Modern Literature&amp;rdquo; by Mark Edward Wisniewski, discussing colonial ambition in early modern literature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Where do aliens come from?&amp;rdquo; by Justin Smith-Ruiu, exploring the origins of aliens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Conditio extraterrestris&amp;rdquo; from UZH, a German-language resource.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Extraterrestrial culture: How we express ourselves through space…&amp;rdquo; from The Planetary Society, discussing how we express ourselves through space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Other Worlds: The Cultural Significance of the Extraterrestrial Life Debate&amp;rdquo; by Steven J. Dick, discussing the cultural significance of the extraterrestrial life debate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;THE RACIST LANGUAGE OF SPACE EXPLORATION&amp;rdquo; by Caroline Haskins, discussing the racist language of space exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Culture_of_extraterrestriality&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Culture_of_extraterrestriality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
