<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>India on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/india/</link>
    <description>Recent content in India on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 17:58:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/india/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in India</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b797cb110fac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 17:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b797cb110fac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-india&#34;&gt;List of Alleged UFO Sightings in India &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-india&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article catalogs reported UFO sightings in India, spanning from 1951 to 2023. Each entry includes the date, location, and a brief description of the event, often with links to news sources or related articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1951&#34;&gt;1951 &lt;a href=&#34;#1951&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details a report from New Delhi where members of a flying club observed a cigar-shaped object, estimated to be around one hundred feet long, in the sky. The source cited is NICAP (National Investigations Committee On Aerial Phenomena).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2004&#34;&gt;2004 &lt;a href=&#34;#2004&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section recounts an incident on September 27, 2004, where scientists in Samudra Tapu (Chandra Taal) spotted a white, &amp;ldquo;snowman&amp;rdquo;-like object on a nearby mountain ridge. &lt;em&gt;India Today&lt;/em&gt; speculated it could have been a spy drone or balloon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2007&#34;&gt;2007 &lt;a href=&#34;#2007&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions a &amp;ldquo;fireball&amp;rdquo; photographed in the skies of Kolkata in October, which was claimed to be shape-shifting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2013&#34;&gt;2013 &lt;a href=&#34;#2013&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists two separate incidents. The first involves residents of Chennai observing five specks of bright orange light in the night sky in June. The second details how troops of the Indian Army spotted several UFOs near the Ladakh border in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2015&#34;&gt;2015 &lt;a href=&#34;#2015&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes two separate incidents in Uttar Pradesh. In Gorakhpur, a resident claimed to have photographed a large UFO, but the photo was suspected to be digitally altered. In Kanpur, a boy reportedly captured a flying saucer in a photo of clouds taken with his father&amp;rsquo;s phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2023&#34;&gt;2023 &lt;a href=&#34;#2023&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details a recent event in November where a UFO was spotted over Imphal airport, causing a three-hour disruption to flight services. Two Indian Air Force Rafale fighter jets were scrambled, but the search was unsuccessful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the main &amp;ldquo;List of reported UFO sightings&amp;rdquo; Wikipedia page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists all the sources cited in the article, including news articles from &lt;em&gt;India Today&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Hindu&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Times of India&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Daily Express&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Indian Express&lt;/em&gt;, as well as a link to the NICAP website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the MUFON (Mutual UFO Network) website, specifically to a page displaying the last 20 UFO sightings and pictures reported to the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_India&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_India&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
