<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ancient Aliens on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ancient-aliens/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ancient Aliens on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 06:34:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ancient-aliens/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mantis Overlords  Ancient Aliens or Earth’s Hidden Rulers?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_2bbf18bbf848/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 06:34:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_2bbf18bbf848/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;mantis-overlords-ancient-aliens-or-earths-hidden-rulers&#34;&gt;Mantis Overlords: Ancient Aliens or Earth’s Hidden Rulers? &lt;a href=&#34;#mantis-overlords-ancient-aliens-or-earths-hidden-rulers&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;encounters-along-the-musconetcong-river&#34;&gt;Encounters Along the Musconetcong River &lt;a href=&#34;#encounters-along-the-musconetcong-river&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on reported sightings of Mantis beings along the Musconetcong River in New Jersey, starting around 2006. Key elements include the consistency of the experiences reported by multiple witnesses: a sudden silence in the forest, electronic malfunctions, and the appearance of a tall, insectoid figure. Specific individuals mentioned are Paul Jax, a fisherman who claimed to have made eye contact with a seven-foot-tall Mantis being, and Joe Pari, who reported telepathic contact, memory extraction, and paralysis. The section suggests that these beings are not merely aliens but hold a position of power within an extraterrestrial hierarchy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;patterns-in-abduction-testimonies&#34;&gt;Patterns in Abduction Testimonies &lt;a href=&#34;#patterns-in-abduction-testimonies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This part explores the commonalities found in numerous alien abduction accounts involving Mantis beings. It highlights the consistent descriptions of these entities: triangular heads, large black eyes, thin insect-like bodies, and a commanding presence. The section also notes that Mantis beings are often reported to be in charge of smaller gray aliens during abduction procedures. The Terry Lovelace case from Devil’s Den State Park is mentioned as an example where witnesses observed gray aliens working under the direction of Mantis beings. The Mantis beings are often described as overseeing medical procedures, communicating telepathically, and maintaining a cold, efficient control over the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ancient-evidence-in-stone&#34;&gt;Ancient Evidence in Stone &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-evidence-in-stone&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section delves into the possibility that ancient civilizations documented the existence of Mantis-like beings in their art and mythology. It cites examples such as a petroglyph in Tamura, Iran, depicting a humanoid figure with mantis-like features, dated between 4,000 and 40,000 years old. It also mentions the San people (Khoisan) of Africa, who included mantis-headed figures in their rock art, often portraying them as creator gods. The section emphasizes the widespread nature of these depictions across continents and cultures, suggesting a global presence of Mantis beings that predates recorded history, referencing Mesopotamian, Egyptian, and Native American cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-portal-in-new-jersey&#34;&gt;A Portal in New Jersey? &lt;a href=&#34;#a-portal-in-new-jersey&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This portion presents the theory that certain geographic locations, such as the area around the Musconetcong River, may act as interdimensional gateways. It suggests that fault lines in the area could produce unusual electromagnetic fields, similar to NASA&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;X-points&amp;rdquo; or magnetic portals. The section proposes that these locations could serve as doorways for interdimensional beings like the Mantis to enter our reality. It also notes that witnesses often describe the presence of these beings as distorting time, disabling electronics, and overwhelming the senses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-they-after&#34;&gt;What Are They After? &lt;a href=&#34;#what-are-they-after&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the potential motives and purposes of the Mantis beings. It contrasts the idea of curious extraterrestrial explorers with the notion that Mantis beings have a specific agenda. Theories mentioned include the possibility that these entities have guided human development from behind the scenes, influenced civilizations, or are conducting long-term genetic experiments and harvesting knowledge and energy from humanity. The section emphasizes the consistent theme that the Mantis beings are not new to Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-overlords-among-us&#34;&gt;The Overlords Among Us? &lt;a href=&#34;#the-overlords-among-us&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This concluding section discusses the credibility of abduction accounts and the implications of the consistent descriptions of Mantis beings. It references the work of Harvard psychiatrist Dr. John Mack, who extensively documented abduction cases and concluded that many could not be dismissed as delusions. The section poses the question of who these entities are, given the consistency of the reports. It suggests that the idea of &amp;ldquo;Earth&amp;rsquo;s Mantis Overlords&amp;rdquo; may seem like science fiction, but for those who have encountered them, the experience is profoundly real. The section concludes by suggesting that the Mantis beings may have been present on Earth for millennia, hidden in the shadows, recorded in stone, and potentially still observing humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latest-ufo-sightings.net/2025/05/mantis-overlords-ancient-aliens-or-earths-hidden-rulers.html&#34;&gt;https://www.latest-ufo-sightings.net/2025/05/mantis-overlords-ancient-aliens-or-earths-hidden-rulers.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
