<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kenneth Arnold on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/kenneth-arnold/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kenneth Arnold on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 23:06:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/kenneth-arnold/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kenneth Arnold UFO sighting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_cf6ec7935450/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 23:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_cf6ec7935450/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alleged-1947-sighting-in-washington-us-kenneth-arnold-ufo-sighting&#34;&gt;Alleged 1947 Sighting in Washington, US: Kenneth Arnold UFO Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#alleged-1947-sighting-in-washington-us-kenneth-arnold-ufo-sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the alleged UFO sighting by private pilot Kenneth Arnold on June 24, 1947, near Mount Rainier, Washington. This sighting is considered a seminal event in the modern history of UFOs, as it garnered nationwide news coverage and popularized the terms &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;flying disc.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sighting&#34;&gt;Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 24, 1947, Kenneth Arnold, while flying from Chehalis to Yakima, Washington, detoured to search for a crashed U.S. Marine Corps C-46 transport plane near Mount Rainier. Near Mineral, Washington, at approximately 9,200 feet, Arnold observed nine shiny objects flying in formation past Mount Rainier. He estimated their speed to be over 1,200 miles per hour. Arnold described the objects as thin, flat, and convex, with one being crescent-shaped. He likened their movement to saucers skipping on water. The objects traveled from Mount Rainier to Mount Adams in 1 minute and 42 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;arnold-shares-the-story&#34;&gt;Arnold Shares the Story &lt;a href=&#34;#arnold-shares-the-story&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After landing in Yakima, Arnold shared his experience with fellow pilots. He was interviewed by reporters from the &lt;em&gt;East Oregonian&lt;/em&gt; in Pendleton, Oregon, the next day. The reporters found Arnold to be a credible witness. Arnold expressed his desire to speak with the FBI due to the widespread attention and skepticism surrounding his account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;corroboration&#34;&gt;Corroboration &lt;a href=&#34;#corroboration&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several other individuals reported similar sightings around the same time as Arnold. L.G. Bernier of Richland, Washington, saw three objects flying towards Mount Rainier about half an hour before Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting. Ethel Wheelhouse in Yakima, Washington, also reported seeing flying discs moving at high speeds. A member of the Washington State forest service reported seeing flashes over Mount Rainier at the same time as Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting. Ten days later, a United Airlines crew over Idaho also spotted similar objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;arnold-talks-of-possible-non-earthly-origins&#34;&gt;Arnold Talks of Possible Non-Earthly Origins &lt;a href=&#34;#arnold-talks-of-possible-non-earthly-origins&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In early July 1947, Arnold discussed the possibility of extraterrestrial origins for the objects. He mentioned receiving fan mail with various interpretations, including visitations from another planet. Arnold expressed his hope that the devices were U.S. Army creations but also stated that if the government knew anything, the public should be informed. He also noted the objects&amp;rsquo; abrupt turns, suggesting they might be controlled from elsewhere, possibly another planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publicity-and-origins-of-term-flying-saucer&#34;&gt;Publicity and Origins of Term &amp;ldquo;Flying Saucer&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#publicity-and-origins-of-term-flying-saucer&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arnold&amp;rsquo;s account received widespread media coverage, appearing in numerous U.S. and Canadian newspapers. The terms &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;flying disc&amp;rdquo; became popular descriptors for UFOs following the sighting. While the exact origin of the terms is debated, it&amp;rsquo;s believed they emerged from early news stories about Arnold&amp;rsquo;s experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-term-appears&#34;&gt;The Term Appears &lt;a href=&#34;#the-term-appears&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newspapers began using the terms &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;flying disc&amp;rdquo; to describe the objects starting on June 26 and 27. The Arnold sighting is credited with popularizing these terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bequette-interview&#34;&gt;Bequette Interview &lt;a href=&#34;#bequette-interview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years later, Arnold claimed he told Bill Bequette that the objects &amp;ldquo;flew erratic, like a saucer if you skip it across the water,&amp;rdquo; emphasizing the motion rather than the shape. Bequette&amp;rsquo;s initial articles described the objects as &amp;ldquo;saucer-like&amp;rdquo; and their motion as &amp;ldquo;like fish flipping in the sun.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;military-investigation-of-arnold-story&#34;&gt;Military Investigation of Arnold Story &lt;a href=&#34;#military-investigation-of-arnold-story&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first investigation of Arnold&amp;rsquo;s claims was conducted by Lt. Frank Brown and Capt. William Davidson of Hamilton Field, California, on July 12. They concluded that Arnold likely saw what he reported. However, First Lt. Hal L. Eustace of the Army Air Corps described Arnold as &amp;ldquo;excitable&amp;rdquo; and his report as a &amp;ldquo;silly season episode.&amp;rdquo; The Army Air Force&amp;rsquo;s official conclusion was that the objects were due to a mirage. AAF intelligence, with FBI assistance, initiated a secret investigation of the best sightings, including Arnold&amp;rsquo;s. This led to the formation of Project Sign at the end of 1947, the first publicly acknowledged USAF UFO investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;widespread-ufo-reports-after-arnold-sighting&#34;&gt;Widespread UFO Reports After Arnold Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#widespread-ufo-reports-after-arnold-sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the weeks following Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting, numerous reports of similar objects flooded in from the U.S. and around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;skeptical-explanations&#34;&gt;Skeptical Explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#skeptical-explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officials at McChord Army Air Field suggested the objects could have been fast P-80 jets. Lieutenant Colonel Harry R. Turner of the White Sands Proving Ground also stated that Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting was consistent with jet airplanes. Steuart Campbell proposed that the objects were mirages of snow-capped peaks in the Cascade Range. Philip J. Klass argued that Arnold might have misidentified meteors. James Easton suggested that Arnold may have misidentified pelicans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;donald-menzels-explanations&#34;&gt;Donald Menzel&amp;rsquo;s Explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#donald-menzels-explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donald Menzel, a Harvard astronomer and UFO debunker, offered several explanations for Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting, including clouds of snow, orographic clouds, wave clouds, and spots of water on his airplane&amp;rsquo;s windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kenneth_Arnold_UFO_sighting&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kenneth_Arnold_UFO_sighting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
