<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Biocontainment on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/biocontainment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Biocontainment on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 06:11:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/biocontainment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial sample curation</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_97f8be919529/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 06:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_97f8be919529/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-sample-curation&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial Sample Curation &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-sample-curation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the specialized facilities and procedures required for handling and preserving samples returned from space, with a focus on planetary protection and sample integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section emphasizes the importance of bringing extraterrestrial materials to Earth for in-depth scientific analysis due to the limitations of spacecraft instruments. It highlights the need for specialized biocontainment facilities that also function as cleanrooms to prevent contamination of the samples and protect Earth from potential biohazards. The section differentiates between non-restricted samples (e.g., from the Moon, asteroids) and restricted samples (from potentially habitable bodies like Mars), which require more stringent containment measures. It mentions the Biosafety Levels (BSL) required for each type of sample, with restricted samples needing BSL-4 facilities. A key challenge is the need to both contain the samples and allow researchers to analyze them without compromising their integrity or Earth&amp;rsquo;s safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;non-restricted-materials&#34;&gt;Non-restricted Materials &lt;a href=&#34;#non-restricted-materials&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the curation of samples from celestial bodies not considered to pose a biohazard risk, such as the Moon, asteroids, and comets. It mentions that as of 2019, only JAXA (Japan) and NASA (United States) operate BSL-3 laboratories dedicated to curating these samples. The Extraterrestrial Sample Curation Center at JAXA is highlighted for its ability to handle samples without atmospheric exposure. The Vernadsky Institute of Geochemistry and Analytical Chemistry at the Russian Academy of Sciences is mentioned as the location where Luna Soviet mission samples are studied and stored. The &lt;em&gt;OSIRIS-REx&lt;/em&gt; mission&amp;rsquo;s sample return to Earth is also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;restricted-materials&#34;&gt;Restricted Materials &lt;a href=&#34;#restricted-materials&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section addresses the handling of samples from planets or moons suspected of harboring past or present life, which are classified as Category V bodies. It emphasizes that these samples require BSL-4 facilities, but existing BSL-4 labs are not adequate for both sample preservation and Earth protection. Two proposed facilities are discussed: the European Sample Curation Facility (ESCF) in Vienna and NASA&amp;rsquo;s Mars Sample-Return Receiving Facility (MSRRF). The MSRRF had multiple designs submitted in 2009, and its construction is estimated to take 7-10 years, with an additional 2 years for staff training. A mobile BSL-4 facility for preliminary biohazard analysis at the landing site is also being considered. The section outlines stringent containment requirements, including filtering particles as small as 0.01 μm to prevent the release of potential biohazards, including gene transfer agents (GTAs) and ultramicrobacteria. The section also notes that some advocate for robotic systems within BSL-4 facilities to minimize human contamination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_sample_curation&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_sample_curation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
