<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cattle Mutilation on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/cattle-mutilation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cattle Mutilation on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 18:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/cattle-mutilation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cattle mutilation</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ee1c97534fee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 18:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ee1c97534fee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;cattle-mutilation&#34;&gt;Cattle Mutilation &lt;a href=&#34;#cattle-mutilation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cattle mutilation refers to the killing and mutilation of cattle and other animals under unusual and often bloodless circumstances. The phenomenon has been linked to paranormal and supernatural explanations, as well as more mundane causes. Mutilations typically involve the removal of organs such as the eyes, tongue, and genitals. Reports of such incidents span the globe, involving various livestock and wild animals. Explanations range from natural decomposition and predation to cults, government agencies, cryptids like the chupacabra, and extraterrestrials. The United States has conducted two federal investigations into the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-history&#34;&gt;Early History &lt;a href=&#34;#early-history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documented reports of unexplained livestock deaths date back to 1606 in England, where sheep were found slaughtered with only tallow and some inward parts removed. Charles Fort collected accounts of similar mutilations in England during the late 19th and early 20th centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-snippy-horse-death-of-1967&#34;&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Snippy&amp;rdquo; Horse Death of 1967 &lt;a href=&#34;#the-snippy-horse-death-of-1967&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unexplained death and mutilation of a horse named &amp;ldquo;Snippy&amp;rdquo; in Alamosa, Colorado, in 1967 brought the phenomenon to wider attention. The &lt;em&gt;Pueblo Chieftain&lt;/em&gt; published a story about the incident, detailing the horse&amp;rsquo;s skinned and defleshed head and neck, as well as precise cuts on the body. The lack of blood and a medicinal odor at the scene fueled speculation about extraterrestrial involvement. Wadsworth Ayer&amp;rsquo;s investigation for the Condon Committee concluded there was no evidence of abnormal causes. Sheriff Ben Phillips initially attributed the death to a lightning strike. Later, two students confessed to shooting the horse weeks after the incident gained publicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cattle-mutilations-19731980&#34;&gt;Cattle Mutilations 1973–1980 &lt;a href=&#34;#cattle-mutilations-19731980&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This period saw a surge in reported cattle mutilations across Kansas, Nebraska, Colorado, and New Mexico. Unidentified helicopters were reported in connection with cattle and pig rustling in Western Iowa (April 1973) and Missouri (August 1973).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1973-kansas-wave&#34;&gt;1973 Kansas Wave &lt;a href=&#34;#1973-kansas-wave&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June 1973, Cloud County sheriff Fred Modlin warned the public about suspicious phone calls from someone posing as a USDA official. Several butchered cows were subsequently found in the county, with right ears removed. Local press speculated about a &amp;ldquo;Mad Dog&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;phantom&amp;rdquo; butcher. By December, law enforcement reported a wave of cattle deaths in seven counties across Kansas and Nebraska, with sexual organs removed. State Senator Ross Doyen reported a mutilation on his ranch. The Kansas Brand Commissioner&amp;rsquo;s office attributed most deaths to natural causes, a conclusion disputed by Modlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1974-nebraska-wave&#34;&gt;1974 Nebraska Wave &lt;a href=&#34;#1974-nebraska-wave&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports continued in April 1974 with a mutilated and blood-drained cow in Nebraska. The North American Newspaper Alliance reported on the 1973 mutilations and helicopter sightings. Mutilations were reported in Mills County, Iowa, with coyotes blamed. By June, Lancaster County, Nebraska, reported mutilations. Custer County reported helicopter sightings and armed patrols. In August, an unidentified helicopter was spotted shining a spotlight over a field where a mutilated cow was later found near Agnew, Nebraska. Knox County Sheriff Herbert Thompson reported armed civilian patrols due to helicopter sightings. Cloud County Attorney William Walsh suggested devil-worshiping cultists were responsible. State Sen. John Decamp called for a coordinated investigation. By late August, 25 mutilations were reported across five Nebraska counties. A rancher near Hartington apparently thwarted a mutilation in progress when a helicopter was spotted above his field. Authorities cautioned against shooting at aircraft. In September, an autopsy revealed a supposedly-mutilated cow died of bacterial infection. Over 50 law enforcement officials attended a meeting in Center, Nebraska, estimating 27 out of 80 cow deaths were suspected mutilations. South Dakota also reported alleged mutilations. &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; became the first national outlet to cover the story, reporting 100 cattle mutilated in Nebraska, Kansas, and Iowa since May. South Dakota Attorney General Kermit Sande confirmed mutilation reports in the state. UFO expert J. Allen Hynek denied any link between UFOs and mutilations. Minnesota reported mutilations in Kandiyohi, Swift, and Meeker counties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1975-colorado&#34;&gt;1975 Colorado &lt;a href=&#34;#1975-colorado&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1975, the Colorado Associated Press voted the mutilations as the state&amp;rsquo;s top story. Senator Floyd K. Haskell contacted the FBI, claiming 130 mutilations in Colorado and reports across nine states. A 1979 FBI report estimated 8,000 mutilations in Colorado, causing $1 million in damages. Donald E. Flickinger of the Michigan ATF investigated possible links to a &amp;ldquo;Hell-oriented biker gang.&amp;rdquo; The Colorado Bureau of Investigation opened an investigation under Carl Whiteside. &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; published a story examining cattle mutilations across 11 states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1976-dulce-new-mexico&#34;&gt;1976 Dulce, New Mexico &lt;a href=&#34;#1976-dulce-new-mexico&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 13, 1976, Dulce rancher Manuel Gomez reported a mutilation to Officer Gabe Valdez of the New Mexico State Patrol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1979-public-meeting&#34;&gt;1979 Public Meeting &lt;a href=&#34;#1979-public-meeting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 20, 1979, U.S. Attorney R. E. Thompson and US Senator Harrison Schmidt held a public meeting about cattle mutilations, attended by about 80 people. Paul Bennewitz reported seeing unidentified lights over Kirtland Air Force Base. In May, Valdez reported finding two drugs in a mutilated bull&amp;rsquo;s remains: Chlorpromazine (Thorazine) to tranquilize the animal and another to clog the blood. In June 1981, investigators found a mutilated cow at the Gomez ranch with radar chaff nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;later-incidents&#34;&gt;Later Incidents &lt;a href=&#34;#later-incidents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many mutilation cases have been reported worldwide since 1967, primarily in the Americas and Australia. South America has seen an estimated 3,500 incidents since 2002. Investigators believe many cases go unreported. In 1993, photographic evidence surfaced of a mutilated human corpse found near the Guarapiranga reservoir of São Paulo, Brazil, in 1988. Theories ranged from homicide to alien abduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;characteristics&#34;&gt;Characteristics &lt;a href=&#34;#characteristics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cattle deaths due to natural causes are common. However, ranchers began reporting unusual deaths characterized by missing sex organs, udders, tongues, anus, and sometimes ears or eyes. Cuts were described as &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;surgical.&amp;rdquo; Some animals were reported drained of blood with no blood at the scene. Howard Burgess noted that nearly 90 percent of mutilated cattle are between four and five years old. Strange marks or imprints have been found near mutilation sites. The &amp;ldquo;Snippy&amp;rdquo; case featured an absence of tracks and small holes &amp;ldquo;punched&amp;rdquo; in the ground. In Rio Arriba County, New Mexico, a &amp;ldquo;trail of suction cup-like impressions&amp;rdquo; was found leading from a mutilated cow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;laboratory-reports&#34;&gt;Laboratory Reports &lt;a href=&#34;#laboratory-reports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laboratory reports on some mutilated animals have shown unusual levels of vitamins or minerals and the presence of chemicals not normally found in animals. However, these anomalies are not consistent across all cases. In a case documented by New Mexico police and the FBI involving a bull belonging to Manuel Gomez of Dulce, New Mexico, the animal displayed &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo; mutilation signs. The liver and heart were white and mushy, with the texture of peanut butter. Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory detected &lt;em&gt;Clostridium&lt;/em&gt; bacteria in the heart but could not draw conclusions. Liver samples were devoid of copper and contained high levels of zinc, potassium, and phosphorus. Blood samples were light pink and did not clot. The animal&amp;rsquo;s hide was brittle, and the flesh was discolored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;helicopter-sightings&#34;&gt;Helicopter Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#helicopter-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On July 15, 1974, two unregistered helicopters reportedly opened fire on Robert Smith Jr. in Honey Creek, Iowa. This followed a series of alleged mutilations in the area. In August 1974, residents reported seeing unidentified helicopters shining spotlights into fields where mutilated cows were later found. Know County Sheriff Herbert Thompson claimed helicopter sightings were nightly occurrences. By 1975, some ranchers formed armed vigilante groups. Authorities ran ads urging ranchers not to shoot at survey helicopters. The National Guard warned its helicopter pilots to fly at higher altitudes. In 1976, two Cache County, Utah, police officers reportedly confronted men in an unmarked U.S. Army helicopter. After this encounter, cattle mutilations in the region ceased for about five years. On April 8, 1979, three police officers in Dulce, New Mexico, reported a mysterious aircraft resembling a U.S. military helicopter hovering around a site following a wave of alleged mutilations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;official-investigations&#34;&gt;Official Investigations &lt;a href=&#34;#official-investigations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New Mexico Livestock Board sought assistance from the Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory. Colorado Bureau of Investigation agents went undercover. Oklahoma convened a task force. Federal authorities launched a comprehensive investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bureau-of-alcohol-tobacco-and-firearms&#34;&gt;Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms &lt;a href=&#34;#bureau-of-alcohol-tobacco-and-firearms&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January 1975, the Minnesota field office of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms (ATF) launched an investigation headed by Agent Donald Flickinger, tasked with investigating possible connections between cults and cattle mutilation. Flickinger recorded unusual incidents and circumstantial evidence but found insufficient evidence of cult involvement. His investigation was dropped when it was determined cattle deaths were not a prelude to a coordinated campaign against elected officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;colorado-bureau-of-investigation&#34;&gt;Colorado Bureau of Investigation &lt;a href=&#34;#colorado-bureau-of-investigation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May 1975, the Colorado Bureau of Investigation opened an investigation under Carl Whiteside. 19 animals underwent necropsies at Colorado State University, but no conclusive results emerged. A $40,000 reward was offered. The US Bureau of Land Management&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle_mutilation&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle_mutilation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
