<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Soviet Union on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/soviet-union/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Soviet Union on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 07:48:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/soviet-union/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Voronezh UFO incident</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_345e43d72a87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 07:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_345e43d72a87/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;voronezh-ufo-incident&#34;&gt;Voronezh UFO incident &lt;a href=&#34;#voronezh-ufo-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Voronezh UFO incident refers to an alleged UFO and extraterrestrial sighting reported by children in Voronezh, Soviet Union, on September 27, 1989. The area became a tourist attraction for UFO enthusiasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tass-reports&#34;&gt;TASS reports &lt;a href=&#34;#tass-reports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the account of the incident as reported by TASS. Children playing football in a park claimed to have witnessed a pink glow, followed by a red ball-shaped object. They further reported seeing a three-eyed alien and a robot exiting the object. The alien was said to have used a ray gun to make a boy disappear temporarily. A local police lieutenant claimed to have seen a flying object. TASS also reported that a correspondent spoke with youths who claimed to have seen a flying saucer, and Dr. Silanov of the Voronezh Geophysical Laboratory confirmed the landing location using &amp;ldquo;biolocation&amp;rdquo;. The reports were part of the government&amp;rsquo;s new &amp;ldquo;openness&amp;rdquo; policy. A reporter from Komsomolskaya Pravda claimed to have an interview with aliens. Sovietskaya Kultura, a Communist Party paper, defended its coverage of the children&amp;rsquo;s claims. Following the publicity, tours of Voronezh, &amp;ldquo;land of the aliens&amp;rdquo;, were offered. The description of the incident was similar to stories in the American magazine Saga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufologists&#34;&gt;Ufologists &lt;a href=&#34;#ufologists&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions A. Kuzovkin, a UFOlogist, who believed a scorched patch of ground near Moscow was caused by a UFO landing. However, TASS reported that firefighters attributed the scorched ground to an ignited haystack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;response&#34;&gt;Response &lt;a href=&#34;#response&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the official response to the alleged incident. The Soviet Scientific Commission launched an inquiry. Scientists, including members of the &amp;ldquo;Voronezh Amateur Section for the Study of Abnormal Phenomena,&amp;rdquo; investigated the site. Genrikh Silanov of the Voronezh Geophysical Lab later clarified that the extraterrestrial rock was a common form of hematite. Igor Sarotsev of the University of Voronezh stated that the presence of cesium was insignificant and could be attributed to the Chernobyl disaster. A French Press Agency report found no verifiable proof of a landing. Vladimir Posner sent a film crew to Voronezh but could only find the children as &amp;ldquo;witnesses&amp;rdquo;. The section concludes by citing a Time magazine article that viewed the state sponsorship of psychic and UFO claims as a new &amp;ldquo;opiate for the masses&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voronezh_UFO_incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voronezh_UFO_incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
