<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alien on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/alien/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alien on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 21:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/alien/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Lockdown (2004 Film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_24b53a15d205/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 21:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_24b53a15d205/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-lockdown-2004-film&#34;&gt;Alien Lockdown (2004 Film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-lockdown-2004-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry details the 2004 American science fiction horror television film &lt;em&gt;Alien Lockdown&lt;/em&gt;, directed by Tim Cox. It also goes by the names &lt;em&gt;Creature&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Predatorman&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a brief introduction to the film, highlighting its genre as science fiction horror and its alternative titles. It names Tim Cox as the director and Ross Helford and T.M. Van Ostrand as the screenwriters, based on a story by John Thompson, Boaz Davidson, and Kenneth M. Badish. The lead actors, John Savage, James Marshall, and Michelle Goh, are also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot centers around an ancient alien life force that awakens and threatens humanity. A SWAT team, led by a skilled assassin, must prevent the alien from consuming humans. The alien had been dormant for centuries, waiting for human knowledge to advance enough to unlock its potential. A mad scientist unlocks the genetic code, leading to the creation of mutant creatures. The military attempts to eliminate the creatures within a top-secret base, but the creature grows stronger with each kill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the actors and the characters they portray in the film:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John Savage as Dr. Alan Woodman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Marshall as Charlie Dryfus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michelle Goh as Commander Rita Talon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T.M. Van Ostrand as Lieutenant Raymond Green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nathan Perez as Sal Meyer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Kallaway as Kerns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Martin Kove as Colonel Anslow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atanas Srebrev as Temple&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stanimir Stamatov as Hoog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raicho Vasilev as Monie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stanislav Dimitrov as Creature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is a placeholder indicating that the article needs citations for verification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the film&amp;rsquo;s page on IMDb (Internet Movie Database).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Lockdown&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Lockdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial (1982 film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e4b54ac7181b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 12:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e4b54ac7181b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;et-the-extra-terrestrial-1982-film&#34;&gt;E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial (1982 film) &lt;a href=&#34;#et-the-extra-terrestrial-1982-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive overview of the 1982 American science fiction film produced and directed by Steven Spielberg and written by Melissa Mathison. The film tells the story of a boy, Elliott, who befriends an extraterrestrial stranded on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A race of alien botanists visits Earth, but one of them gets separated from the group and is left behind. The alien takes shelter in a shed belonging to the family of ten-year-old Elliott Taylor. Elliott lures the alien back to his home with Reese&amp;rsquo;s Pieces, and he hides the creature in his room. Elliott introduces E.T. to his older brother, Michael, and five-year-old sister Gertie, who agree to keep E.T. hidden from their mother, Mary. Elliott and the creature begin to bond, they start to share thoughts and emotions. E.T. displays telekinetic abilities and revives a dead chrysanthemum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At school, Elliott becomes intoxicated because E.T. is drinking beer and watching television at home. Inspired by a Buck Rogers comic strip, E.T. builds a makeshift device to &amp;ldquo;phone home&amp;rdquo;, using various parts around the Taylor home. On Halloween, the children disguise E.T. as a ghost and Elliott sneaks E.T. into the forest, where they set up the device to call E.T.&amp;rsquo;s people. Elliott begs E.T. to stay on Earth with him, before falling asleep and waking alone in the forest the next day. He returns home to his worried family, while Michael searches for E.T., finding him pale and weakened in a culvert. He takes E.T. home, where Elliott is also growing weaker, and reveal the creature to Mary just before government agents invade and quarantine the house. The lead agent, Keys, asks for Elliott&amp;rsquo;s help to save E.T., stating that meeting aliens was his childhood dream and he considers E.T&amp;rsquo;s arrival a genuine miracle. However, E.T. dies while Elliott rapidly recovers. Left alone to say goodbye, Elliott tells E.T. that he loves him, but E.T.&amp;rsquo;s heart begins to glow and he is revived and restored to health. E.T. tells Elliott that his people are returning for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elliott and Michael flee with E.T. on their bikes, flanked by Michael&amp;rsquo;s friends who help them evade the pursuing authorities. Heading towards a roadblock, E.T. levitates the boys to safety and lands them in the forest. E.T.&amp;rsquo;s ship arrives, and he says goodbye to Michael and Gertie, who gifts him the chrysanthemum he previously revived. Elliott tearfully asks E.T. to stay, but E.T. places his glowing finger on Elliott&amp;rsquo;s head and tells him that he will always be there. The children, Mary, and Keys observe as the ship blasts off into space, leaving a rainbow in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main cast includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dee Wallace as Mary Taylor, the single mother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Henry Thomas as Elliott Taylor, the boy who befriends E.T.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peter Coyote as Keys, the government agent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert MacNaughton as Michael Taylor, Elliott&amp;rsquo;s older brother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drew Barrymore as Gertie Taylor, Elliott&amp;rsquo;s younger sister.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other cast members include K.C. Martel, Sean Frye, C. Thomas Howell, Erika Eleniak, David O&amp;rsquo;Dell, Richard Swingler, Frank Toth, Robert Barton, Michael Darrell, and Pat Welsh as the voice of E.T.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details the development, pre-production, casting, filming, and music of the movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;development&#34;&gt;Development &lt;a href=&#34;#development&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film&amp;rsquo;s concept originated from an imaginary friend Steven Spielberg created after his parents&amp;rsquo; divorce. He initially planned a darker project called &lt;em&gt;Night Skies&lt;/em&gt; but developed a subplot into what became &lt;em&gt;E.T.&lt;/em&gt; Melissa Mathison wrote the first draft, titled &lt;em&gt;E.T. and Me&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pre-production&#34;&gt;Pre-production &lt;a href=&#34;#pre-production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carlo Rambaldi designed the animatronics for E.T., inspired by his painting &lt;em&gt;Women of Delta&lt;/em&gt; and the faces of Carl Sandburg, Albert Einstein, and Ernest Hemingway. Kathleen Kennedy visited the Jules Stein Eye Institute to study eyes for E.T. Four heads were created for filming, one as the main animatronic and the others for facial expressions, as well as a costume. Tamara De Treaux, Pat Bilon, and Matthew DeMeritt took turns wearing the costume. Mars, Incorporated refused to allow M&amp;amp;M&amp;rsquo;s to be used in the film, so The Hershey Company was asked if Reese&amp;rsquo;s Pieces could be used, and it agreed. Henry Feinberg created E.T.&amp;rsquo;s communicator device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;casting&#34;&gt;Casting &lt;a href=&#34;#casting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spielberg cast Henry Thomas as Elliott after an impressive improvised audition scene. Robert MacNaughton played Michael, and Drew Barrymore was cast as Gertie. Pat Welsh provided the major voice work for E.T., with additional sounds from Debra Winger, Spielberg, and various animals. A scene featuring Harrison Ford as the school principal was cut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;filming&#34;&gt;Filming &lt;a href=&#34;#filming&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Principal photography began on September 8, 1981, in Los Angeles County and the San Fernando Valley, under the cover name &lt;em&gt;A Boy&amp;rsquo;s Life&lt;/em&gt;. Filming locations included Culver City High School, Northridge, Tujunga, Laird International Studios in Culver City, and a redwood forest near Crescent City in Northern California. The exterior Halloween scene and the &amp;ldquo;flying bicycle&amp;rdquo; chase scenes were filmed in Porter Ranch. The film was shot in roughly chronological order to achieve convincing emotional performances from the young cast. Sean Frye revealed how the visual effect close-up shots for the climax of the &amp;ldquo;flying bicycle&amp;rdquo; chase scene were filmed. BMX riders Robert Cardoza, Greg Maes, and David Lee served as stunt doubles for the scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;Music &lt;a href=&#34;#music&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Williams composed the score, taking a modernist approach with polytonality and the Lydian mode. Spielberg edited the final chase sequence to suit Williams&amp;rsquo; music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes &lt;a href=&#34;#themes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film explores themes of divorce, alienation, growing up, and communication. Critics have noted parallels between E.T. and Elliott, as well as religious parallels between E.T. and Jesus. Some see the movie as a modern fairy tale, drawing comparisons to Peter Pan and The Wizard of Oz. Kathleen Kennedy highlighted tolerance as an important theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details the film&amp;rsquo;s release, sales, critical response, and accolades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;release-and-sales&#34;&gt;Release and sales &lt;a href=&#34;#release-and-sales&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;E.T.&lt;/em&gt; premiered at the 1982 Cannes Film Festival and was released in the United States on June 11, 1982. It opened at number one at the US box office and stayed at the top for six weeks. In 1983, &lt;em&gt;E.T.&lt;/em&gt; surpassed &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; to become the highest-grossing film of all time. The film was also a merchandising success, with dolls selling 15 million units by September 1982 and becoming the best-selling toy that Christmas season. The film was re-released in 1985 and 2002, earning another $60 million and $68 million respectively. It was re-released in IMAX on August 12, 2022, to commemorate the film&amp;rsquo;s 40th anniversary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;home-media&#34;&gt;Home media &lt;a href=&#34;#home-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;E.T.&lt;/em&gt; was released on VHS and LaserDisc on October 27, 1988. The videos were priced with a recommended retail price of $24.95, the lowest initial price at the time for a major movie compared to the normal price of $89.95. The film doubled the record pre-orders of &lt;em&gt;Cinderella&lt;/em&gt; released the same month and went on to sell over 15 million VHS units in the United States, and grossed over $250 million in video sales revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;critical-response&#34;&gt;Critical response &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-response&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received near-universal acclaim. Roger Ebert gave it four out of four stars, and Michael Sragow of &lt;em&gt;Rolling Stone&lt;/em&gt; called Spielberg &amp;ldquo;a space age Jean Renoir.&amp;rdquo; George Will was one of few to pan the film. The film holds a 99% approval rating on Rotten Tomatoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;accolades&#34;&gt;Accolades &lt;a href=&#34;#accolades&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film was nominated for nine Oscars at the 55th Academy Awards, winning four: Best Original Score, Best Sound, Best Sound Effects Editing, and Best Visual Effects. It also won Golden Globe Awards for Best Picture (Drama) and Best Original Score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legacy&#34;&gt;Legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film has been voted one of the greatest films of all time by the American Film Institute. The line &amp;ldquo;E.T. phone home&amp;rdquo; was ranked 15th on AFI&amp;rsquo;s 100 Years&amp;hellip;100 Movie Quotes list. In 1994, it was selected for preservation in the U.S. National Film Registry. In 2023, actress Rita Moreno named &lt;em&gt;E.T.&lt;/em&gt; as one of her top five favorite films. Many people in the world of entertainment have cited &lt;em&gt;E.T.&lt;/em&gt; as among their favorite films, including filmmakers Stanley Kubrick, Sidney Lumet, Edgar Wright, J. A. Bayona, Dustin Lance Black, Spenser Cohen, Dustin Guy Defa, Gareth Edwards, Michael Giacchino, Sarah Greenwood, Chad Hartigan, Max Hechtman, Jordan Horowitz, Phil Joanou, Travis Knight, David Lowery, Rod Roddenberry, Céline Sciamma, Ed Solomon, Goran Stolevski, Clement Virgo and Molly Manning Walker, actors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/E.T._the_Extra-Terrestrial&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/E.T._the_Extra-Terrestrial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extra Terrestrial Visitors</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6524ca714fe7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 01:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6524ca714fe7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extra-terrestrial-visitors&#34;&gt;Extra Terrestrial Visitors &lt;a href=&#34;#extra-terrestrial-visitors&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry details the 1983 French-Spanish science fiction film &lt;em&gt;Extra Terrestrial Visitors&lt;/em&gt; (also known as &lt;em&gt;Los nuevos extraterrestres&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Pod People&lt;/em&gt;). It covers the film&amp;rsquo;s production, plot, cast, release, and reception, including its later cult status due to being featured on &lt;em&gt;Mystery Science Theater 3000&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story unfolds in the woods of New England, where egg poachers stumble upon a cave containing alien eggs. After one poacher destroys the eggs, a vengeful alien begins targeting the poachers and a rock band camping nearby. Meanwhile, a young boy named Tommy discovers the remaining egg, which hatches into a creature he names Trumpy. Tommy and Trumpy become friends, and Trumpy develops telekinetic powers. The alien mother searches for her offspring, leading to encounters with the rock band and Tommy&amp;rsquo;s family. The film culminates in a confrontation between the humans and the alien mother, with tragic consequences for some characters. Tommy and Trumpy say goodbye before Tommy returns to his family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cast includes Ian Serra as Rick, Nina Ferrer as Sharon, Susana Bequer as Lara Stapleton, Sara Palmer as Kathy, Óscar Martín as Tommy Stevens, Maria Albert as Tracy, Emilio Linder as Brian, Concha Cuetos as Molly Stevens, Manuel Pereiro as Bill Stevens, and Frank Braña as Burt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Extra Terrestrial Visitors&lt;/em&gt; was a co-production between France and Spain, filmed in Madrid. The cast consisted largely of Spanish actors, and the film was shot in both Spanish and French, later dubbed in post-production. Juan Piquer Simón directed the film. Faruk Alatan, Dick Randall, and Edward L. Montoro produced the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film was initially released in France. In the United States, it was sometimes shown on television under the title &lt;em&gt;The Unearthling&lt;/em&gt;. Film Ventures International later acquired the film and re-titled it &lt;em&gt;Pod People&lt;/em&gt; for U.S. television distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception-and-legacy&#34;&gt;Reception and legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#reception-and-legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received negative reviews, with some finding it unintentionally funny. Its legacy is largely tied to its appearance on &lt;em&gt;Mystery Science Theater 3000&lt;/em&gt; (MST3K), which lampooned the &lt;em&gt;Pod People&lt;/em&gt; version of the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mystery-science-theater-3000&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mystery Science Theater 3000&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#mystery-science-theater-3000&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film gained popularity after being featured on &lt;em&gt;Mystery Science Theater 3000&lt;/em&gt; in 1991. The MST3K episode used a print of the film re-titled &lt;em&gt;Pod People&lt;/em&gt; by Film Ventures International. The opening and ending credits of &lt;em&gt;Pod People&lt;/em&gt; are superimposed over footage from &lt;em&gt;The Galaxy Invader&lt;/em&gt;. The fictional pop band&amp;rsquo;s song &amp;ldquo;Hear the Engines Roll&amp;rdquo; became a recurring joke on the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;home-media&#34;&gt;Home media &lt;a href=&#34;#home-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film has been released on VHS under various titles, including &lt;em&gt;The Unearthling&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;E. T.: The Second Coming&lt;/em&gt;. The MST3K version of the film has been released on DVD and Blu-ray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extra_Terrestrial_Visitors&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extra_Terrestrial_Visitors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Alien</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_73e88702e51c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 13:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_73e88702e51c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-alien&#34;&gt;The Alien &lt;a href=&#34;#the-alien&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the history of &lt;em&gt;The Alien&lt;/em&gt;, an unproduced science fiction film conceived by Indian filmmaker Satyajit Ray in the late 1960s. The film was a joint venture between India and the United States, with Columbia Pictures slated to produce it. Despite the involvement of notable actors like Peter Sellers and Marlon Brando, the film was ultimately shelved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story centers around an alien spaceship that lands in a rural village in Bengal, India. The villagers, awestruck by the craft, begin to worship it. The alien, named &amp;ldquo;Mr. Ang,&amp;rdquo; communicates with a young boy named Haba through dreams and engages in playful pranks within the village. The narrative also includes an Indian businessman, a journalist from Calcutta (now Kolkata), and an American engineer. A specific scene is highlighted, describing the alien&amp;rsquo;s interaction with plant life, showcasing its gentle and curious nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Columbia Pictures was the producer for this planned US–India co-production, and Peter Sellers and Marlon Brando were slated to play lead roles. However, Ray discovered that his script had been copyrighted by Michael Wilson, his representative in Hollywood, who claimed co-writer credit without contributing to the writing. Marlon Brando later left the project, and although James Coburn was considered as a replacement, Ray became discouraged and returned to Calcutta. Columbia Pictures expressed interest in reviving the project in the 1970s and 1980s, but it never materialized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legacy&#34;&gt;Legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses the similarities between &lt;em&gt;The Alien&lt;/em&gt; and Steven Spielberg&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial&lt;/em&gt;, released in 1982. Satyajit Ray pointed out the parallels between his script and Spielberg&amp;rsquo;s film, suggesting that &lt;em&gt;E.T.&lt;/em&gt; would not have been possible without his script being available in Hollywood. Spielberg denied these claims. The article also mentions the Hindi film &lt;em&gt;Koi&amp;hellip; Mil Gaya&lt;/em&gt;, directed by Rakesh Roshan, as another film that appears to be based on &lt;em&gt;The Alien&lt;/em&gt;, particularly in its focus on an intellectually disabled person interacting with a friendly alien. In 2003, Satyajit Ray&amp;rsquo;s son, Sandip Ray, began adapting Ray&amp;rsquo;s original 1962 story &lt;em&gt;Bankubabur Bandhu&lt;/em&gt; into a Bengali television movie of the same name, which was eventually broadcast in India in 2006.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Alien_(unproduced_film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Alien_(unproduced_film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien Hunter (2003 Film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ef89d1d65030/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 11:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ef89d1d65030/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-hunter-2003-film&#34;&gt;Alien Hunter (2003 Film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-hunter-2003-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry provides information about the 2003 American-Bulgarian science fiction thriller film &lt;em&gt;Alien Hunter&lt;/em&gt;. It includes details about the film&amp;rsquo;s production, plot, cast, and links to external resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot summary details a series of events triggered by a mysterious signal. In 1947, a radio operator disappears while investigating a signal from Roswell, New Mexico. In the present day, the same signal reappears, originating from the South Pole. Cryptologist Julian Rome (played by James Spader) is recruited to investigate an alien object discovered in Antarctica. The object, emitting the signal, contains a deadly virus and an alien. The virus kills members of the research team and threatens a global pandemic. A nuclear strike is ordered to contain the threat. Julian communicates with the alien before it is killed, discovering the virus&amp;rsquo;s potential to destroy all life on Earth. Julian and three others are rescued by an alien spacecraft moments before the nuclear strike. The government covers up the incident, claiming a nuclear reactor meltdown. The film concludes with the alien spacecraft carrying the survivors leaving the solar system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the actors and the characters they portray in the film. Key actors include James Spader as Julian Rome, John Lynch as Dr. Michael Straub, Leslie Stefanson as Nyla Olson, and Carl Lewis as Grisham. Other notable cast members include Roy Dotrice and Keir Dullea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a reference to &lt;em&gt;The Thing&lt;/em&gt; (1982 film), suggesting a thematic similarity or influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is empty, indicating a lack of citations within the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to the film&amp;rsquo;s entry on IMDb, the TCM Movie Database, and a full film on YouTube via Crackle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Hunter&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Hunter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phil the Alien (2004 Film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_5687ae60a5c3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 16:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_5687ae60a5c3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;phil-the-alien-2004-film&#34;&gt;Phil the Alien (2004 Film) &lt;a href=&#34;#phil-the-alien-2004-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry provides information about the 2004 Canadian comedy film &lt;em&gt;Phil the Alien&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phil the Alien&lt;/em&gt; is a Canadian comedy film released in 2004. It was written and directed by Rob Stefaniuk, who also stars in the titular role. The film features a blend of science fiction and comedy elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot-summary&#34;&gt;Plot Summary &lt;a href=&#34;#plot-summary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot revolves around Phil, an extraterrestrial with shape-shifting and telekinetic abilities, who crash-lands in Northern Ontario. He befriends a local child, his father, and a talking beaver. Phil adopts the persona of a stereotypical Canadian small-town alcoholic while hiding from a military general. His telekinetic powers lead some to believe he is the Christian messiah, and he joins a local rock band. A Quebecois assassin attempts to kill him while he&amp;rsquo;s on tour with the band. The ending involves suspense, treachery, and dolphins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film stars:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rob Stefaniuk as Phil the Alien&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nicole de Boer as Madame Madame&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graham Greene as Wolf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boyd Banks as Slim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christopher Barry as Thomas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article cites two references:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;Sudbury Star&lt;/em&gt; article from September 24, 2004, titled &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;When a spaceship crashes in Northern Ontario, it&amp;rsquo;s funny&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;CityNews Toronto&lt;/em&gt; article from April 2, 2024, reporting the death of Joe Flaherty, noting this film as his final role.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External Links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article provides a link to the film&amp;rsquo;s IMDb page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stubs&#34;&gt;Stubs &lt;a href=&#34;#stubs&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article is marked as a stub for both Canadian films of the 2000s and 2000s comedy films, indicating that it requires expansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phil_the_Alien&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phil_the_Alien&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Alien Factor (1978 film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_2f46e1b40adc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 23:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_2f46e1b40adc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-alien-factor-1978-film&#34;&gt;The Alien Factor (1978 film) &lt;a href=&#34;#the-alien-factor-1978-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a description of the 1978 science fiction horror film &lt;em&gt;The Alien Factor&lt;/em&gt;, directed, written, and produced by Don Dohler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot centers around a spaceship crash in a sparsely populated area of Earth. Three grotesque aliens survive the crash and begin terrorizing the local residents. A character named Ben Zachary steps forward to fight back against the extraterrestrial threat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main cast includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don Leifert as Ben Zachary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tom Griffith as Sheriff Cinder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Richard Dyszel as Mayor Wicker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mary Mertens as Edie Martin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Richard Geiwitz as Pete&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;George Stover as Steven&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eleanor Herman as Mary Jane Carter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anne Frith as Dr. Ruth Sherman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Larry Schlechter and John Cosentino played the aliens Inferbyce and Zagatile, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Alien Factor&lt;/em&gt; marked Don Dohler&amp;rsquo;s directorial debut after he was laid off from his job as a payroll manager. The initial script was a comedy with 15 monsters, but it was changed to a straight horror film with only three monsters. Larry Schlechter and John Cosentino built the creature suits for the Inferbyce and Zagtile, respectively. Ernest D. Farino created the Leemoid through stop motion animation. Filming took place in and around Baltimore, Maryland, from October 1976 to April 1977.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film was released on DVD by Retromedia Entertainment on February 26, 2002. Image Entertainment released it on November 15, 2005, as part of the Don Dohler Collection. Mill Creek Entertainment released it on July 19, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received generally negative reviews. &lt;em&gt;TV Guide&lt;/em&gt; gave it two out of five stars, calling it &amp;ldquo;silly.&amp;rdquo; Dave Sindelar criticized the acting and direction. &lt;em&gt;Critical Outcast&lt;/em&gt; acknowledged the film&amp;rsquo;s flaws but admired Dohler&amp;rsquo;s initiative. &lt;em&gt;VideoHound&amp;rsquo;s Golden Movie Retriever&lt;/em&gt; awarded it one and a half out of four bones, noting the decent special effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sequels&#34;&gt;Sequels &lt;a href=&#34;#sequels&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Alien Factor 2: Alien Rampage&lt;/em&gt; was not a direct sequel. Fred Olen Ray, the Retromedia distributor, used the sequel-sounding title for marketing purposes. The original title was &lt;em&gt;Alien Rampage&lt;/em&gt;, filmed in 1999 as Don Dohler&amp;rsquo;s comeback movie after an 11-year hiatus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Alien_Factor&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Alien_Factor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roswell, New Mexico (TV series)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b2d5bbb29704/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 07:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b2d5bbb29704/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;roswell-new-mexico-tv-series&#34;&gt;Roswell, New Mexico (TV series) &lt;a href=&#34;#roswell-new-mexico-tv-series&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry provides an overview of the American science fiction drama television series &lt;em&gt;Roswell, New Mexico&lt;/em&gt;, a reboot of the &lt;em&gt;Roswell High&lt;/em&gt; book series by Melinda Metz. It highlights the show&amp;rsquo;s development, plot, cast, production details, episode information, reception, and availability on home media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the premise of the show. Liz Ortecho returns to her hometown of Roswell, New Mexico, and discovers that her teenage crush, Max Evans, is an alien. As they reconnect, they must protect his secret while facing threats from a greater alien presence and the politics of fear and hatred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast-and-characters&#34;&gt;Cast and characters &lt;a href=&#34;#cast-and-characters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the main and recurring cast members and their characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;main&#34;&gt;Main &lt;a href=&#34;#main&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jeanine Mason&lt;/strong&gt; as Liz Ortecho, a biomedical researcher and daughter of undocumented immigrants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nathan Dean&lt;/strong&gt; as Max Evans, a Roswell deputy sheriff and alien.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michael Vlamis&lt;/strong&gt; as Michael Guerin, a troubled alien drifter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lily Cowles&lt;/strong&gt; as Isobel Evans, Max&amp;rsquo;s sister and an alien.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tyler Blackburn&lt;/strong&gt; as Alex Manes, an Air Force veteran.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heather Hemmens&lt;/strong&gt; as Maria DeLuca, Liz&amp;rsquo;s best friend and a bartender.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michael Trevino&lt;/strong&gt; as Kyle Valenti, a doctor and son of the town sheriff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trevor St. John&lt;/strong&gt; as Jesse Manes (seasons 1–2), Alex&amp;rsquo;s father.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karan Oberoi&lt;/strong&gt; as Noah Bracken (season 1; guest season 2), Isobel&amp;rsquo;s husband.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amber Midthunder&lt;/strong&gt; as Rosa Ortecho (seasons 2–4; recurring season 1), Liz&amp;rsquo;s older sister.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recurring&#34;&gt;Recurring &lt;a href=&#34;#recurring&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists recurring characters, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carlos Compean as Arturo Ortecho, Liz&amp;rsquo;s father.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peter Diseth as Grant/Graham Green, an alien theorist and museum proprietor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kayla Ewell as Nora Truman, Michael&amp;rsquo;s biological mother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rosa Arredondo as Michelle Valenti, Kyle&amp;rsquo;s mother and sheriff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dylan McTee as Wyatt Long, the brother of one of Rosa&amp;rsquo;s victims.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Riley Voelkel as Jenna Cameron, Max&amp;rsquo;s deputy partner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sherri Saum as Mimi DeLuca, Maria&amp;rsquo;s mother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claudia Black as Ann Evans, Max and Isobel&amp;rsquo;s adoptive mother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kiowa Gordon as Flint Manes, Alex Manes&amp;rsquo; older brother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Justina Adorno as Steph, Kyle&amp;rsquo;s love interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jason Behr as Tripp Manes, Alex Manes&amp;rsquo; great-uncle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cassandra Jean Amell as Louise Truman, Isobel&amp;rsquo;s biological mother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaius Charles as Roy Bronson, a farmer from 1947.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jamie Clayton as Grace Powell / Charlie Cameron, Jenna Cameron&amp;rsquo;s sister.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cleo Anthony as Diego, Liz&amp;rsquo;s ex-fiancé.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christian Antidormi as Forrest Long, Alex Manes&amp;rsquo; love interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tanner Novlan as Gregory Manes, Alex Manes&amp;rsquo; older brother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;La&amp;rsquo;Charles Trask as Bert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steven Krueger as Heath, Liz&amp;rsquo;s colleague.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sibongile Mlambo as Anatsa, an investigative journalist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David DeSantos as Edgar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michael Grant Terry as Jordan Bernhardt, the son of Roswell&amp;rsquo;s mayor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gillian Vigman as Brooke Taylor, the town sheriff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quentin Plair as Dallas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrew Lees as Clyde.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoe Cipres as Bonnie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rekha Sharma as Dr. Shivani Sen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the production aspects of the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;development&#34;&gt;Development &lt;a href=&#34;#development&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CW ordered the show to pilot in January 2018, with Julie Plec directing. Production companies involved include Amblin Television, Bender Brown Productions, CBS Television Studios, and Warner Bros. Television. The show was ordered to series on May 11, 2018. It was renewed for a second season on April 24, 2019, a third season on January 7, 2020, and a fourth season on February 3, 2021. The series was canceled after four seasons on May 12, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;casting&#34;&gt;Casting &lt;a href=&#34;#casting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeanine Mason was cast as Liz Ortecho on February 16, 2018. The rest of the main cast, including Nathan Parsons, Lily Cowles, Michael Vlamis, Tyler Blackburn, Heather Hemmens, and Michael Trevino, was cast in early March 2018. Karan Oberoi was cast as Noah Bracken on March 27, 2018. Trevor St. John was cast as Alex&amp;rsquo;s father on March 12, 2018. Amber Midthunder was promoted to the main cast for the second season in April 2019. Tanner Novlan was cast in a recurring role as Alex&amp;rsquo;s brother, Gregory, in May 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;filming&#34;&gt;Filming &lt;a href=&#34;#filming&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Filming for the pilot took place in Albuquerque and Santa Fe, New Mexico, beginning on March 14, 2018, and ending on March 30, 2018. The rest of the first-season episodes began filming on August 13, 2018, in Las Vegas, New Mexico, and Santa Fe, New Mexico. Filming for the third season began on October 15, 2020, and the fourth and final season started in August 2021 and concluded in January 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides an overview of the series&amp;rsquo; episodes, including a series overview and detailed information for each season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;series-overview&#34;&gt;Series overview &lt;a href=&#34;#series-overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents a table summarizing the number of episodes, first released date, and last released date for each of the four seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-1-2019&#34;&gt;Season 1 (2019) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-1-2019&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists each episode of the first season, including the title, director, writer(s), original release date, U.S. viewers (in millions), and a brief summary of the plot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-2-2020&#34;&gt;Season 2 (2020) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-2-2020&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists each episode of the second season, including the title, director, writer(s), original release date, U.S. viewers (in millions), and a brief summary of the plot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-3-2021&#34;&gt;Season 3 (2021) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-3-2021&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists each episode of the third season, including the title, director, writer(s), original release date, and U.S. viewers (in millions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-4-2022&#34;&gt;Season 4 (2022) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-4-2022&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists each episode of the fourth season, including the title, director, writer(s), original release date, and U.S. viewers (in millions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the critical reception and ratings of the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;critical-reception&#34;&gt;Critical reception &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series has a 55% approval rating on Rotten Tomatoes, with an average rating of 6.22/10, and a critic consensus stating that the reboot hews too closely to its predecessor. Metacritic assigned the series a score of 58 out of 100, indicating &amp;ldquo;mixed or average reviews.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ratings&#34;&gt;Ratings &lt;a href=&#34;#ratings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides viewership and ratings information for each season and episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;overall&#34;&gt;Overall &lt;a href=&#34;#overall&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents a table summarizing the timeslot, number of episodes, first aired date and viewership, last aired date and viewership, TV season, viewership rank, average viewers (in millions), and 18–49 rank for each of the four seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;season-1&#34;&gt;Season 1 &lt;a href=&#34;#season-1&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents a table summarizing the title, air date, rating/share (18–49), viewers (in millions), DVR (18–49), DVR viewers (in millions), total (18–49), and total viewers (in millions) for each episode of the first season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;season-2&#34;&gt;Season 2 &lt;a href=&#34;#season-2&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents a table summarizing the title, air date, rating (18–49), viewers (in millions), DVR (18–49), DVR viewers (in millions), total (18–49), and total viewers (in millions) for each episode of the second season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;season-3&#34;&gt;Season 3 &lt;a href=&#34;#season-3&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents a table summarizing the title, air date, rating/share (18–49), viewers (in millions), DVR (18–49), DVR viewers (in millions), total (18–49), and total viewers (in millions) for each episode of the third season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;season-4&#34;&gt;Season 4 &lt;a href=&#34;#season-4&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents a table summarizing the title, air date, rating (18–49), and viewers (in millions) for each episode of the fourth season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;home-media&#34;&gt;Home media &lt;a href=&#34;#home-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section notes that Warner Archive Collection released a manufacture-on-demand DVD of the first season on January 28, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes &lt;a href=&#34;#notes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides clarifying notes, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CBS Television Studios was credited as CBS Television Studios from 2019 to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell,_New_Mexico_(TV_series)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell,_New_Mexico_(TV_series)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien Terminator (1988 film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_4f7a24b4b007/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 16:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_4f7a24b4b007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-terminator-1988-film&#34;&gt;Alien Terminator (1988 film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-terminator-1988-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the 1988 Italian film &lt;em&gt;Alien Terminator&lt;/em&gt;, also known as &lt;em&gt;Top Line&lt;/em&gt;. It distinguishes it from the 1995 film of the same name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-line&#34;&gt;Top Line &lt;a href=&#34;#top-line&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides the original Italian title of the film, which is &lt;em&gt;Top Line&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;film-details&#34;&gt;Film Details &lt;a href=&#34;#film-details&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents key information about the film in a table format:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Director:&lt;/strong&gt; Nello Rossati (also credited as Ted Archer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writers:&lt;/strong&gt; Roberto Gianviti and Nello Rossati&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stars:&lt;/strong&gt; Franco Nero and George Kennedy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cinematography:&lt;/strong&gt; Mario DiLeo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor:&lt;/strong&gt; Adalberto Ceccarelli&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Music:&lt;/strong&gt; Maurizio Dami&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 1988&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Country:&lt;/strong&gt; Italy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language:&lt;/strong&gt; Italian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot revolves around Ted Angelo, an alcoholic writer who discovers a 16th-century Spanish ship inside a mountain cave in Cartagena, Colombia. He learns the cave is actually the inside of a crashed UFO. He is pursued by hitmen, a Nazi fugitive named Heinrich Holzmann, and CIA operatives. He teams up with art historian June and eventually involves his ex-wife Maureen. Maureen is revealed to be an alien who has been disguising herself as a human and manipulating world events. She is killed by June. Ted and June go into hiding with an indigenous tribe, where Ted continues to write about his experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the main actors and their respective roles in the film:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Franco Nero as Ted Angelo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;George Kennedy as Heinrich Holzmann&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deborah Moore (credited as Deborah Barrymore) as June&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mary Stavin as Maureen De Havilland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;William Berger as Alonso Kintero&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shirley Hernandez as Juanita&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Larry Dolgin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert Redcross&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the film&amp;rsquo;s release information. It was released theatrically in Germany on September 22, 1988. It was released on Region 1 DVD on May 25, 2004. It is also available for streaming on platforms like Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes critical reception of the film. Sci-Fi 100 noted the initial lack of science fiction elements but found the last 30 minutes more engaging. Film Authority described the film as a mix of &lt;em&gt;Romancing the Stone&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Terminator&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists a related film:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull&lt;/em&gt; (2008)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of Italian films of 1988&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of citations used in the article, including books, websites, and databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the film&amp;rsquo;s IMDb page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Terminator_(1988_film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Terminator_(1988_film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of UFO-related hoaxes</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_345d7fc33b75/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 14:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_345d7fc33b75/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-ufo-related-hoaxes&#34;&gt;List of UFO-related Hoaxes &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-ufo-related-hoaxes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article provides a compilation of various hoaxes related to unidentified flying objects (UFOs). It categorizes these hoaxes into different types, including airship hoaxes, crashed UFO hoaxes, sighting hoaxes, and photographic hoaxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;airship-hoaxes&#34;&gt;Airship Hoaxes &lt;a href=&#34;#airship-hoaxes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details several instances of airship hoaxes, primarily from the late 19th century. Key events include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April Fool&amp;rsquo;s Day 1897, Omaha, Nebraska:&lt;/strong&gt; Two practical jokers launched a helium balloon with a burning wicker basket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 17, 1897, Dallas, Texas:&lt;/strong&gt; Three boys created a &amp;ldquo;mystery airship&amp;rdquo; sighting using a kerosene-soaked cotton ball attached to a turkey vulture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 19, 1897, Leroy, Kansas:&lt;/strong&gt; Alexander Hamilton reported an airship lassoing a heifer, which was later published in the &lt;em&gt;Yates Center Farmer’s Advocate&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1909 Airship Sighting Wave:&lt;/strong&gt; Wallace Tillinghast claimed to have built and flown an airship extensively over the Northeastern United States.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crashed-ufo-hoaxes&#34;&gt;Crashed UFO Hoaxes &lt;a href=&#34;#crashed-ufo-hoaxes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on hoaxes involving purported crashed UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1884, Dundy County, Nebraska:&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;em&gt;Nebraska State Journal&lt;/em&gt; published two hoax articles about a crashed UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-autopsy&#34;&gt;Alien Autopsy &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-autopsy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection details the Ray Santilli &amp;ldquo;Alien Autopsy&amp;rdquo; film hoax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1993:&lt;/strong&gt; Ray Santilli presented film footage allegedly showing an autopsy of an alien from the Roswell UFO incident in 1947.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1995:&lt;/strong&gt; The American Fox Broadcasting Company broadcast the footage in &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy: Fact or Fiction&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The footage was later revealed to be a hoax involving latex dummies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Santilli claimed he bought the film from Jack Barnett, who falsely claimed to be a commander in the US army.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1967-flying-saucer-hoax-in-england&#34;&gt;1967 Flying Saucer Hoax in England &lt;a href=&#34;#1967-flying-saucer-hoax-in-england&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes a hoax involving the placement of six &amp;lsquo;flying saucers&amp;rsquo; in southern England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 1967:&lt;/strong&gt; Apprentices from the Royal Aircraft Establishment at Farnborough placed six &amp;lsquo;flying saucers&amp;rsquo; between the Thames Estuary and the Bristol Channel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hoax was part of Rag Week and intended to raise money for charity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;british-roswell&#34;&gt;British Roswell &lt;a href=&#34;#british-roswell&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses a &amp;ldquo;miniature UFO&amp;rdquo; discovered in Sipho Moor near Scarborough, North Yorkshire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1957:&lt;/strong&gt; A small piece of metal with hieroglyphs was found.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experts deemed it most likely a hoax.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sighting-hoaxes&#34;&gt;Sighting Hoaxes &lt;a href=&#34;#sighting-hoaxes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists sighting hoaxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maury Island Incident (1947)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morristown UFO Hoax (2009)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;photographic-hoaxes&#34;&gt;Photographic Hoaxes &lt;a href=&#34;#photographic-hoaxes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on photographic hoaxes related to UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;photograph-of-an-alien-taken-at-ilkley-moor-1987&#34;&gt;Photograph of &amp;ldquo;an alien&amp;rdquo; taken at Ilkley Moor (1987) &lt;a href=&#34;#photograph-of-an-alien-taken-at-ilkley-moor-1987&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection details a photograph alleged to be of an alien taken in West Yorkshire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 1, 1987:&lt;/strong&gt; A photograph taken on Ilkley Moor was claimed to depict an alien.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Daily Star&lt;/em&gt; claimed to expose it as a hoax in 1989, identifying the &amp;ldquo;alien&amp;rdquo; as an insurance broker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Belgian investigators questioned how experienced investigators could have been misled by such a hoax.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to related Wikipedia articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of hoaxes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photograph of Petit-Rechain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO-related_hoaxes&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO-related_hoaxes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joe Alien</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_76dd0cdfb364/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 23:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_76dd0cdfb364/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;joe-alien&#34;&gt;Joe Alien &lt;a href=&#34;#joe-alien&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe Alien is a British comic book character who appeared in strips published by Fleetway Publications. He debuted in the preview issue of the science fiction anthology &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; in October 1988. The character&amp;rsquo;s strip was one of four linked serials in &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; and was later briefly featured in &lt;em&gt;Eagle&lt;/em&gt; after &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; was canceled. Joe Alien is the last survivor of the planet Xgangbe-4 and joins the &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; mission to help humanity find a new home, commanding the &lt;em&gt;Wildcat 2&lt;/em&gt; exploration shuttle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;creation&#34;&gt;Creation &lt;a href=&#34;#creation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barrie Tomlinson created Joe Alien as part of a new science fiction anthology, &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt;, for Fleetway Publications. The concept involved linking all five features in the comic to form an overall narrative centered on the spaceship &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt;. Tomlinson created four lead characters, including Joe Alien, to head exploration teams. Massimo Belardinelli was the initial artist for &amp;ldquo;Joe Alien,&amp;rdquo; with Tomlinson praising his ability to bring the story to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publishing-history&#34;&gt;Publishing history &lt;a href=&#34;#publishing-history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; began publication in October 1988, featuring &amp;ldquo;Joe Alien&amp;rdquo; as the color strip. Ron Smith took over as the artist from the third issue. &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; was canceled after 12 issues and merged with &lt;em&gt;Eagle&lt;/em&gt; in March 1989. &amp;ldquo;Joe Alien&amp;rdquo; continued in &lt;em&gt;Eagle&lt;/em&gt; for four weeks in May 1989 to complete the story arc and also featured in three episodes of &amp;ldquo;The Wildcat Complete&amp;rdquo; anthology. Rebellion Developments purchased the rights to &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; in 2016 and announced plans to reprint the contents in collected editions. As of 2025, only &amp;ldquo;Turbo Jones&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Loner&amp;rdquo; have been released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot-summary&#34;&gt;Plot summary &lt;a href=&#34;#plot-summary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe Alien joins the &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; mission after Turbo Jones realizes Earth is doomed. Joe, the last survivor of Xgangbe-4, possesses vast knowledge stored in an external brain-pack. He is selected for his intelligence and physical attributes. After the &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; launches, Joe&amp;rsquo;s sensors locate a potential new home for the refugees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He leads the &lt;em&gt;Wildcat Two&lt;/em&gt; shuttle to scout Area 17, where his team encounters carnivorous vegetation and a two-headed alien. They discover that the plants are controlled by a mad human astronaut from a 2079 Mars mission, who is now worshipped as a god. Joe brokers an alliance with giant insects to escape and later participates in other expeditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe shares the story of the Xgangbe&amp;rsquo;s destruction by the Kargroz and his revenge. He is later chosen to find an alien shapeshifter on board the &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt;. Joe, along with Jones, Loner, and Magee, is kidnapped by a Gamemaster of the Glarzon race but is released after defeating the Glarzon&amp;rsquo;s troops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graham Kibble-White described Joe Alien as &amp;ldquo;dopily designed.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joe_Alien&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joe_Alien&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
