<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alien Adventure on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/alien-adventure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alien Adventure on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 23:42:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/alien-adventure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aliens Stole My Body (film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_3eb2fb7aab7c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 23:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_3eb2fb7aab7c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;aliens-stole-my-body-film&#34;&gt;Aliens Stole My Body (film) &lt;a href=&#34;#aliens-stole-my-body-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry focuses on the 2020 American adventure science fiction comedy film &lt;em&gt;Aliens Stole My Body&lt;/em&gt;, directed by Sean McNamara. It is based on the novel of the same name by Bruce Coville and serves as a sequel to the 2018 film &lt;em&gt;Aliens Ate My Homework&lt;/em&gt;. The film features a cast including Jayden Greig, George Takei, and Dan Payne. It premiered on Netflix on August 4, 2020, in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crew of the &lt;em&gt;Ferkel&lt;/em&gt; returns to Earth to enlist Rod Allbright and Elspeth McMasters to stop BKR, who has escaped from prison. Rod&amp;rsquo;s friend Mickey joins them as they travel to Mentat to rescue Rod&amp;rsquo;s father. BKR needs Rod&amp;rsquo;s father&amp;rsquo;s knowledge to trap the entire galaxy in a single moment in time. The Allbright family confronts BKR near a black hole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film stars Jayden Greig as Rod Allbright, George Takei as the voice of Phil the Plant, and Dan Payne as Grakker. Other cast members include Tristan Risk as Madame Pong, Alex Zahara as Tar Gibbons, Lauren McNamara as Elspeth McMasters, Sean Quan as Mickey, Ty Consiglio as Billy Becker, Sandy Robson as Art Allbright, Kirsten Robeck as Gwen Allbright, Christian Convery as Eric Allbright, Carmela Guizzo as Linda Allbright, and Travis Turner as Lackey. Bruce Coville makes a cameo appearance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;differences-from-the-book&#34;&gt;Differences from the book &lt;a href=&#34;#differences-from-the-book&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film combines plot elements from &lt;em&gt;The Search for Snout&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Aliens Stole My Body&lt;/em&gt;, the third and fourth books in the Rod Allbright Alien Adventures series, while also introducing original elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aliens_Stole_My_Body_(film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aliens_Stole_My_Body_(film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
