<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>France on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/france/</link>
    <description>Recent content in France on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 17:54:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/france/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in France</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_1d9666650b2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 17:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_1d9666650b2b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-france&#34;&gt;List of Alleged UFO Sightings in France &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-france&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article documents alleged UFO sightings within France, spanning from the 9th century to the 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;815&#34;&gt;815 &lt;a href=&#34;#815&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details an account from 815 AD in Lyons, Auvergne-Rhône-Alpes. Archbishop Agobard of Lyons wrote about people believing in a region called Magonia, from which ships came in the clouds. These ships supposedly transported fruits lost through hail and storms, with &amp;ldquo;aeronauts&amp;rdquo; paying weather witches. The account also mentions a crowd attempting to stone four people believed to have fallen from these ships, who were eventually saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1952&#34;&gt;1952 &lt;a href=&#34;#1952&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers an event on October 17, 1952, in Oloron-Sainte-Marie. Multiple witnesses reported a cigar-shaped UFO accompanied by 30 disc-shaped objects. The smaller UFOs allegedly dropped a white siliceous cotton-like substance. Skeptics proposed alternative explanations, such as optical phenomena and spider migrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1954&#34;&gt;1954 &lt;a href=&#34;#1954&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on a sighting on September 10, 1954, in Quarouble, Nord. A railway worker, Marius Dewilde, claimed to have seen two small beings boarding a UFO. The case garnered significant media attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1965&#34;&gt;1965 &lt;a href=&#34;#1965&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details two separate incidents. The first, on July 1, 1965, in Valensole, Alpes-de-Haute-Provence, involves farmer Maurice Masse&amp;rsquo;s alleged close encounter. Masse claimed to have encountered two small beings near a spherical vehicle. He said he was paralyzed by one of the beings and watched them examining plants. UFOlogists consider this case significant, citing &amp;ldquo;landing gear impressions&amp;rdquo; found in the soil. The second incident occurred in September 1965 in Fort-de-France, Martinique, where hundreds of witnesses observed a ball or disk of light moving slowly across the sky, leaving a glowing trail. Michel Figuet, a helmsman in the French fleet, reported the sighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1967&#34;&gt;1967 &lt;a href=&#34;#1967&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the &amp;ldquo;Close encounter of Cussac&amp;rdquo; on August 29, 1967, in Cussac, Cantal. Two children claimed to have witnessed a UFO and its occupants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1976&#34;&gt;1976 &lt;a href=&#34;#1976&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section recounts an event on November 5, 1976, near Rives/Voreppe, Isère. A French physicist, Dr. S., reported seeing a luminous disk in the sky, brighter than the full moon. The same phenomenon was observed by multiple people over a 250-kilometer stretch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1978&#34;&gt;1978 &lt;a href=&#34;#1978&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details an incident on June 19, 1978, in Gujan-Mestras, Gironde. Several people witnessed a UAP that allegedly caused a city-wide power outage. The local police and GEPAN investigated the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1981&#34;&gt;1981 &lt;a href=&#34;#1981&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the Trans-en-Provence Case on January 8, 1981, in Trans-en-Provence, Var. UFOlogists consider this case significant due to alleged material traces left by a UFO. Critics suggest the traces were a hoax or caused by tires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1982&#34;&gt;1982 &lt;a href=&#34;#1982&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes an event on October 21, 1982, in Nancy, France. A biologist witnessed an ovoid object descending into a garden and hovering above the ground. After the object departed, the witness noted that nearby amaranth plants had withered leaves. The Gendarmerie investigated, and GEPAN analyzed plant samples, finding dehydration but no radiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to related Wikipedia articles, including &amp;ldquo;List of reported UFO sightings.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including books, news articles, and websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external websites, including the CNES (French Space Agency) UFO data website and the MUFON (Mutual UFO Network) website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Valensole_UFO_incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Valensole_UFO_incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in France</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_2b7da8d75dba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 17:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_2b7da8d75dba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-france&#34;&gt;List of Alleged UFO Sightings in France &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-france&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article catalogues alleged UFO sightings within France, spanning from the early Middle Ages to the late 20th century. It provides brief descriptions of each event, including locations, dates, and key witnesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;815&#34;&gt;815 &lt;a href=&#34;#815&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details an account from 815 in Lyons, Auvergne-Rhône-Alpes, referencing the writings of Carolingian archbishop Agobard of Lyons. Agobard&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;De Grandine et Tonitruis&lt;/em&gt; describes beliefs in a region called Magonia, from which ships supposedly came in the clouds, transporting fruits lost to hail and storms. The account also mentions people who claimed to have captured individuals who fell from these ships and were about to be stoned before the truth prevailed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1952&#34;&gt;1952 &lt;a href=&#34;#1952&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on an event in Oloron-Sainte-Marie on October 17, 1952. Multiple witnesses reported seeing a cigar-shaped UFO accompanied by approximately 30 disc-shaped objects. These objects allegedly dropped a white siliceous cotton-like substance that covered trees and roofs. The event was met with skepticism, with some suggesting it was an optical phenomenon or caused by migrating spiders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1954&#34;&gt;1954 &lt;a href=&#34;#1954&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights the Marius Dewilde case from September 10, 1954, in Quarouble, Nord. Railway worker Marius Dewilde claimed to have witnessed two small beings boarding a UFO before it flew into the sky. The incident garnered significant media attention, and strange occurrences were reported in the area in the days following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1965&#34;&gt;1965 &lt;a href=&#34;#1965&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details two separate incidents. The first is the Valensole incident on July 1, 1965, in Alpes-de-Haute-Provence, involving farmer Maurice Masse. Masse claimed to have encountered two small beings near a spherical vehicle that had landed in his field. He said he was paralyzed by one of the beings and observed them making grunting sounds while examining plants. Masse considered the encounter a spiritual experience. UFOlogists cite &amp;ldquo;landing gear impressions&amp;rdquo; as evidence. The second incident occurred in Fort-de-France, Martinique, in late September 1965. Hundreds of witnesses saw a ball or disk of light moving slowly across the sky, leaving a glowing trail. Michel Figuet, a helmsman in the French fleet, reported the sighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1967&#34;&gt;1967 &lt;a href=&#34;#1967&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the Close encounter of Cussac on August 29, 1967, in Cantal. Two young children claimed to have witnessed a UFO and its occupants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1976&#34;&gt;1976 &lt;a href=&#34;#1976&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section recounts an event on November 5, 1976, near Rives/Voreppe, Isère. A French physicist, Dr. S., reported seeing a luminous disk moving in the sky, brighter than the full moon. The object&amp;rsquo;s distance was estimated between 9 and 36 kilometers. The same phenomenon was observed by multiple people over a 250-kilometer stretch from Clermont-Ferrand to Grenoble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1978&#34;&gt;1978 &lt;a href=&#34;#1978&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details an incident on June 19, 1978, in Gujan-Mestras, Gironde. Several people witnessed a UAP that allegedly caused a city-wide blackout. The local police and GEPAN investigated the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1981&#34;&gt;1981 &lt;a href=&#34;#1981&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the Trans-en-Provence Case from January 8, 1981, in Var. This case is considered significant by UFOlogists due to alleged material traces left by a UFO. Skeptics dismiss the event as a joke and attribute the traces to tires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1982&#34;&gt;1982 &lt;a href=&#34;#1982&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes an event on October 21, 1982, in Nancy, France. A biologist witnessed an ovoid object descending into a garden and hovering above the ground. After 20 minutes, the object silently ascended. The witness reported that the grass under the object stood up straight and nearby amaranth plants withered. The Gendarmerie investigated and took samples, which GEPAN analyzed, finding dehydration but no radiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to other relevant Wikipedia articles, including the &amp;ldquo;List of reported UFO sightings.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited within the article, including books, news articles, and online resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external websites, including the CNES-GEIPAN (French government UFO research organization) website and the MUFON (Mutual UFO Network) website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_France&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_France&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Close encounter of Cussac</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_014e76193abe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 01:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_014e76193abe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;close-encounter-incident-in-cussac-cantal-france&#34;&gt;Close encounter incident in Cussac, Cantal, France &lt;a href=&#34;#close-encounter-incident-in-cussac-cantal-france&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the alleged close encounter that occurred in Cussac, Cantal, France in 1967.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary &lt;a href=&#34;#summary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces the topic as a claimed close encounter with alien beings by a young brother and sister in Cussac, Cantal, France. It cites a source that refers to the incident as a &amp;ldquo;close encounter of the third kind,&amp;rdquo; comparing its fame in France to the Kelly-Hopkinsville encounter in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;details-of-the-incident&#34;&gt;Details of the Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#details-of-the-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the events of August 29, 1967, when a 13-year-old boy and his 9-year-old sister reported seeing four small, black beings about 47 inches tall while watching cows in a field. The children claimed the beings rose into the air and entered a round spaceship, about 15 feet in diameter, that was hovering over the field. Police noted a sulfur odor and dried grass at the alleged takeoff site. The incident is mentioned as one of the UFO sightings investigated by the French government and made public in a mass release of documents in March 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a link to the &amp;ldquo;UFO sightings in France&amp;rdquo; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources used in the article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rossini, David; Maillot, Eric; Déguillaume, Eric (February 2009). &amp;ldquo;UFOs: an Assessment of Thirty Years of Official Studies in France&amp;rdquo;. &lt;em&gt;Skeptical Inquirer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moore, Molly (March 23, 2007). &amp;ldquo;French Get a Look at Nation&amp;rsquo;s UFO Files&amp;rdquo;. &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of additional resources for readers interested in learning more about the Cussac incident:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report on the Scientific Council - GEPAN, t. 4, National Centre for Space Studies, 140, June 1978 No. 68.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thierry Pinvidic, &amp;ldquo;Witnesses to a&amp;rdquo; legend &amp;ldquo;: a case of UFO sighting &amp;lsquo;in&amp;rsquo; Communications&amp;rsquo;, No. 52, October 1990, p. 311-335.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thierry Pinvidic, &amp;ldquo;A classic that has a hard time&amp;rdquo; in Pinvindic Thiery (ed). &amp;lsquo;UFO: towards an anthropology of contemporary myth&amp;rsquo;, Editions Heimdal, Paris, 1993, p. 199-209.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Close_encounter_of_Cussac&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Close_encounter_of_Cussac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
