<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Incident on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/incident/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Incident on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 10:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/incident/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ilkley Moor UFO incident</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6b0a3cf135d2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 10:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6b0a3cf135d2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ilkley-moor-ufo-incident&#34;&gt;Ilkley Moor UFO Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#ilkley-moor-ufo-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the alleged UFO incident that occurred on Ilkley Moor in West Yorkshire, England, on December 1, 1987. A retired police officer, using the pseudonym Philip Spencer, claimed to have been abducted by aliens during a morning walk. He purportedly took a photograph of one of the aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ilkley Moor, located between Ilkley and Keighley in West Yorkshire, England, is known for inspiring the song &amp;ldquo;On Ilkla Moor Baht &amp;lsquo;at&amp;rdquo; and for its carved rocks, including the Swastika Stone. The area has a history of UFO sightings, which some skeptics attribute to the proximity of Menwith Hill airforce base and Leeds Bradford Airport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philip Spencer, a retired police officer, had moved to West Yorkshire with his family. On the morning of the incident, he was walking across Ilkley Moor to visit his father-in-law, carrying a camera and compass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;incident&#34;&gt;Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spencer reported encountering a four-foot tall, dark green creature with an oversized head and long, thin arms. He claimed the creature gestured at him, but he took a photograph before it ran away. Spencer followed the creature but lost it in the fog. He then witnessed a whitish, two-part saucer-shaped craft rising from the moor and disappearing into the sky, accompanied by a loud hum. He did not photograph the craft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the encounter, Spencer found himself in a different town, two hours later than expected, and his compass was pointing in the opposite direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-aftermath&#34;&gt;Initial Aftermath &lt;a href=&#34;#initial-aftermath&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spencer contacted UFO researchers Jenny Randles and Peter Hough, handing over the copyright of the photo to Hough. Hough initially skeptical, later came to believe Spencer&amp;rsquo;s account. Spencer remained anonymous and did not profit from the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hough had the photograph examined by experts. A wildlife photographer ruled out known animals, and Kodak experts found no evidence of tampering. US Navy optics expert and ufologist Bruce Maccabee deemed the photo too grainy for proper testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufologist Nick Redfern claims that Spencer was harassed by the Ministry of Defence and visited by Men in Black who tried to intimidate him into silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;account-changed-under-hypnosis&#34;&gt;Account Changed Under Hypnosis &lt;a href=&#34;#account-changed-under-hypnosis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spencer experienced strange dreams after the incident. On Hough&amp;rsquo;s advice, he underwent regressive hypnotherapy with Jim Singleton on March 16, 1988. Under hypnosis, Spencer&amp;rsquo;s account changed. Singleton considered it a &amp;ldquo;genuine recall.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spencer now recalled being paralyzed upon seeing the creature, lifted into the craft, and told to remain calm. Green aliens performed medical experiments on him, inserting items into his nose and mouth. He was given a tour of the craft and shown two films. The first film depicted apocalyptic imagery, including nuclear explosions, famines, and floods. He has never revealed the contents of the second film, claiming the aliens do not want humanity to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterward, Spencer was returned to Ilkley Moor and took the photograph. He now claimed the alien was waving goodbye, not telling him to stay away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legacy&#34;&gt;Legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ilkley Moor incident became a major news story in the UK and remains a famous UFO sighting. Nick Pope, a former Ministry of Defence &amp;lsquo;UFO desk&amp;rsquo; journalist, included it in his &amp;ldquo;Top 10 UFO incidents in the UK&amp;rdquo; list in 2011. It is considered by some as one of the most persuasive UFO incidents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skeptics dismiss the incident as a hoax. They argue the photograph is too blurry to prove alien visitation and that the &amp;ldquo;alien&amp;rdquo; could be a person or cardboard cutout. They also question why Spencer didn&amp;rsquo;t photograph the craft and point out that compasses can be easily damaged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the &amp;ldquo;UFO sightings in the United Kingdom&amp;rdquo; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the various news articles, books, and websites used as sources for the information presented in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ilkley_Moor_UFO_incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ilkley_Moor_UFO_incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
