<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UFO on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ufo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UFO on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 13:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/ufo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien abduction</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_85a477e6d898/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_85a477e6d898/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-abduction&#34;&gt;Alien Abduction &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-abduction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alien abduction, also known as abduction phenomenon, alien abduction syndrome, or UFO abduction, is the subjective experience of individuals reporting being kidnapped by extraterrestrial beings and subjected to physical and psychological experimentation. These individuals are often referred to as &amp;ldquo;abductees&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;experiencers.&amp;rdquo; While most scientists and mental health professionals attribute these experiences to factors like suggestibility, sleep paralysis, deception, and psychopathology, some researchers give credence to the claims. Typical claims involve forced medical examinations, often focusing on reproductive systems, warnings about environmental abuses and nuclear weapons, or interspecies breeding. The content of these narratives often varies with the abductee&amp;rsquo;s cultural background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainstream scientists generally reject the literal interpretation of alien abduction claims. However, some, like psychiatrist John E. Mack, argue that many abductees are sane individuals, with psychopathology only present in some cases. Detailed abduction reports have led to the development of a subculture with support groups and a complex mythos explaining the roles, origins, and motivations of various alien types, such as Greys, Reptilians, and Nordics. Some abductees engage in independent research and attribute the lack of wider awareness to extraterrestrial or governmental cover-ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;paleo-abductions&#34;&gt;Paleo-abductions &lt;a href=&#34;#paleo-abductions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the widespread attention to alien abduction in the 1960s, some older stories have been reinterpreted as possible early cases, termed &amp;ldquo;paleo-abductions&amp;rdquo; by UFO researcher Jerome Clark. One example is Colonel H. G. Shaw&amp;rsquo;s 1896 claim of being harassed by tall, slender humanoids. An article from 1953 asked if flying saucers were kidnapping humans for zoological specimens or vivisection. The 1955 publication of Harold T. Wilkins&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Flying Saucers Uncensored&lt;/em&gt; reported speculation that Karl Hunrath and Wilbur Wilkinson, who claimed alien contact, disappeared due to abduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;two-landmark-cases&#34;&gt;Two landmark cases &lt;a href=&#34;#two-landmark-cases&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Antônio Vilas-Boas case in Brazil during the mid-1950s was an early claim but received limited attention initially. The Betty and Barney Hill abduction in 1961 gained widespread publicity, including a 1975 television film. The Hill incident is considered a prototypical abduction case, possibly the first to describe beings later known as the Greys and explicitly identify an extraterrestrial origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;later-developments&#34;&gt;Later developments &lt;a href=&#34;#later-developments&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R. Leo Sprinkle, a psychologist at the University of Wyoming, became interested in the phenomenon in the 1960s and linked abductions to cattle mutilation. Budd Hopkins became a key figure in the abductee subculture in the 1970s, using hypnosis to uncover details of remembered events. The 1980s saw increased mainstream attention, with works by Hopkins, Whitley Strieber, David M. Jacobs, and John E. Mack presenting alien abduction as a plausible experience. Thomas E. Bullard&amp;rsquo;s comparative analysis of nearly 300 alleged abductees was also published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jacobs and Hopkins argued that alien abduction was more common than previously thought, estimating tens of thousands of North Americans had been abducted. They also proposed an alien effort to create human-alien hybrids. While anecdotal reports of phantom pregnancies related to UFO encounters existed earlier, Hopkins and Jacobs popularized the idea of widespread interbreeding efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Boston Globe&lt;/em&gt; writer Linda Rodriguez McRobbie, alien abduction stories have declined in mainstream media. Michael Shermer suggests that the ubiquity of camera phones has increased the burden of evidence, contributing to the decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;john-e-mack&#34;&gt;John E. Mack &lt;a href=&#34;#john-e-mack&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harvard psychiatry professor John E. Mack believed in the credibility of alien abduction claims. Niall Boyce, writing in &lt;em&gt;The Lancet&lt;/em&gt;, suggested that Mack&amp;rsquo;s work in hypnotic regression helped spread the Grey aliens meme. Mack interviewed over 800 people and wrote two books on the subject. His professional reputation suffered due to his belief and promotion of abduction claims, leading to a Harvard review in 1994.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abductees&#34;&gt;Abductees &lt;a href=&#34;#abductees&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The precise number of alleged abductees is uncertain. Early studies found 1,700 claimants, while contested surveys suggested 5–6 percent of the general population claim to have been abducted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;demographics&#34;&gt;Demographics &lt;a href=&#34;#demographics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While abduction reports are usually made by adults, children sometimes report similar experiences. These reports often share specific details with adult reports, including circumstances, narrative, entities, and aftermaths. Young abductees often have family members who have reported abduction experiences, and family involvement in the military or residence near a military base is also common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mental-health&#34;&gt;Mental health &lt;a href=&#34;#mental-health&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some studies suggest that abductees have psychological characteristics that render their testimony suspect, while others show that abductees are not different from the general population in terms of psychopathology prevalence. Elizabeth Slater&amp;rsquo;s blind study found abductees prone to &amp;ldquo;mildly paranoid thinking,&amp;rdquo; nightmares, and weak sexual identity, while Richard McNally&amp;rsquo;s study concluded that none of the abductees suffered from psychiatric illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;political-conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;Political conspiracy theories &lt;a href=&#34;#political-conspiracy-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Political scientist Michael Barkun highlights links between radical politics and conspiracy theories involving UFOs, alien visitation, environmental pollution, hidden groups, and government takeover. He observed the rise of &amp;ldquo;improvisional millenarism.&amp;rdquo; UFO and abduction stories can be part of stigmatized knowledge narratives. UFO and alien-related conspiracy theories emerged in far-right politics from the 1980s onwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Barkun, TV shows like &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt; included aliens as part of coverup conspiracies, with militias and black helicopters, and demonized FEMA. Political scientist Jodi Dean noted that the stigma of alien abduction stories is seductive to dismiss &amp;ldquo;consensus reality&amp;rdquo; in favor of deviant alternative realities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-described abduction victims often join self-help communities and may resort to questionable regression therapy. Some espouse conspiracy theories of technological mind control, including implants, to force them to serve a New World Order or for the purposes of the antichrist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abduction-narrative&#34;&gt;Abduction narrative &lt;a href=&#34;#abduction-narrative&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various researchers have noted common points in report narratives. CUFOS defines an abductee as someone taken against their will by non-human beings to an extraterrestrial place or spaceship, subjected to examination or communication, with memories that may be conscious or recovered through hypnosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although cases vary, some UFO researchers argue that there is a fairly consistent sequence and description of events that make up the typical &amp;ldquo;close encounter of the fourth kind.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bullard argues most abduction accounts feature the following events:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capture&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductee is rendered incapable of resisting and taken to an alien spacecraft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Examination and Procedures&lt;/strong&gt;: Invasive physiological and psychological procedures, and on occasion simulated behavioral situations, training &amp;amp; testing, or sexual liaisons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conference&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductors communicate with the abductee or direct them to interact with specific individuals for some purpose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tour&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductees are given a tour of their captors&amp;rsquo; vessel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loss of Time&lt;/strong&gt;: Abductees often rapidly forget the majority of their experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Return&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductees are returned to earth, occasionally in a different location or with new injuries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theophany&lt;/strong&gt;: Abductees may have a profound sense of love, a &amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo; similar to those induced by certain drugs, or a &amp;ldquo;mystical experience&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aftermath&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductee must cope with the psychological, physical, and social effects of the experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David M. Jacobs says that the entire abduction event is precisely orchestrated, with predetermined procedures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;capture&#34;&gt;Capture &lt;a href=&#34;#capture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abduction claimants report unusual feelings preceding the onset of an abduction experience, such as a compulsive desire to be at a certain place or expectations that something &amp;ldquo;familiar yet unknown&amp;rdquo; will occur. They also report feeling severe anxiety. Eventually, the experiencer will undergo an apparent &amp;ldquo;shift&amp;rdquo; into an altered state of consciousness. External sounds cease to have any significance, and they report feeling introspective and unusually calm. As consciousness shifts, lights are alleged to appear, occasionally accompanied by a strange mist. As the alleged abduction proceeds, claimants say they will walk or be levitated into an alien craft, often through solid objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;examination&#34;&gt;Examination &lt;a href=&#34;#examination&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The examination phase is characterized by medical procedures and examinations by alien beings against the will of the experiencer. Such procedures often focus on sex and reproductive biology. The entity in charge of the operation is often taller than the others and may appear to be of a different species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miller notes different areas of emphasis between human medicine and what is reported as being practiced by the abductors. The abductors&amp;rsquo; areas of interest appear to be the cranium, nervous system, skin, reproductive system, and joints. Systems given less attention include the cardiovascular system, the respiratory system below the pharynx, and the lymphatic system. The abductors also appear to ignore the upper region of the abdomen in favor of the lower one. The abductors do not appear to wear gloves during the &amp;ldquo;examination.&amp;rdquo; Other constants of terrestrial medicine like pills and tablets are missing from abduction narratives, although sometimes abductees are asked to drink liquids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;subsequent-procedures&#34;&gt;Subsequent procedures &lt;a href=&#34;#subsequent-procedures&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the medical exam, the alleged abductees often report other procedures being performed with the entities. Common among these post-examination procedures are imaging, envisioning, staging, and testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Imaging&amp;rdquo; procedures consist of an abductee being made to view screens displaying images and scenes that appear to be specially chosen with the intent to provoke certain emotional responses in the abductee. &amp;ldquo;Envisioning&amp;rdquo; is a similar procedure, with the primary difference being that the images being viewed, rather than being on a screen, actually seem to be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_abduction&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_abduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in the United States</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8d3b71993ef9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 17:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8d3b71993ef9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-the-united-states&#34;&gt;List of alleged UFO sightings in the United States &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-the-united-states&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a list of alleged UFO sightings in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;table-of-sightings&#34;&gt;Table of Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#table-of-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This table lists alleged UFO sightings in the United States, organized by date, city, and state. It includes a link to a main article for some sightings and a brief description of each event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;september-1865&#34;&gt;September 1865 &lt;a href=&#34;#september-1865&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Cadotte Pass, Montana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Trapper James Lumley reported seeing a craft and its subsequent crash, noting sulfur smells and hieroglyphics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;18961897&#34;&gt;1896–1897 &lt;a href=&#34;#18961897&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Multiple locations across the United States&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Alleged sightings of airship-like vehicles, known as the Mystery airships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;april-17-1897&#34;&gt;April 17, 1897 &lt;a href=&#34;#april-17-1897&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Aurora, Texas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Local residents claimed an airship crashed, and the dead alien pilot was buried in the local cemetery. This is known as the Aurora, Texas, UFO incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;february-24-1942&#34;&gt;February 24, 1942 &lt;a href=&#34;#february-24-1942&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Los Angeles, California&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The &amp;ldquo;Battle of Los Angeles,&amp;rdquo; involved an alleged enemy attack and subsequent anti-aircraft artillery barrage. Initially thought to be an attack from Japan, Secretary of the Navy Frank Knox called it a &amp;ldquo;false alarm.&amp;rdquo; The US Office of Air Force History attributed it to &amp;ldquo;war nerves&amp;rdquo; triggered by a lost weather balloon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;august-1945&#34;&gt;August 1945 &lt;a href=&#34;#august-1945&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Jornada del Muerto, New Mexico&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Two boys reported seeing an &amp;ldquo;avocado-shaped&amp;rdquo; object fall from the sky, alleging it was a crashed vehicle containing three insect-like alien creatures. This is known as the Trinity UFO Case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;june-21-1947&#34;&gt;June 21, 1947 &lt;a href=&#34;#june-21-1947&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Maury Island, Washington&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; An incident reported before the Kenneth Arnold sighting, involving an alleged encounter with &amp;ldquo;men in black suits.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;june-24-1947&#34;&gt;June 24, 1947 &lt;a href=&#34;#june-24-1947&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Mount Rainier, Washington&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Kenneth Arnold reported seeing nine unusual objects flying in a chain near Mount Rainier. He described them as bright, erratic, and flying at tremendous speed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;july-1947&#34;&gt;July 1947 &lt;a href=&#34;#july-1947&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Roswell, New Mexico&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The Roswell UFO Incident involved the recovery of materials near Roswell. The United States military claims it was a crashed research balloon, while ufologists believe it was a crashed alien craft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;january-7-1948&#34;&gt;January 7, 1948 &lt;a href=&#34;#january-7-1948&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Maysville, Kentucky&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The Mantell Incident involved the crash and death of Captain Thomas F. Mantell, a Kentucky Air National Guard pilot, while in pursuit of a UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;july-24-1948&#34;&gt;July 24, 1948 &lt;a href=&#34;#july-24-1948&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Montgomery, Alabama&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The Chiles-Whitted UFO Encounter involved two commercial pilots reporting that their Douglas DC-3 nearly collided with a strange torpedo-shaped object.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;october-1-1948&#34;&gt;October 1, 1948 &lt;a href=&#34;#october-1-1948&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Fargo, North Dakota&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The Gorman Dogfight involved a US Air Force pilot sighting and pursuing a UFO for 27 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;may-11-1950&#34;&gt;May 11, 1950 &lt;a href=&#34;#may-11-1950&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; McMinnville, Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Paul and Evelyn Trent took the McMinnville UFO photographs on their farm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;may-29-1950&#34;&gt;May 29, 1950 &lt;a href=&#34;#may-29-1950&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Mount Vernon, Maryland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Captain Willis Sperry and crewmembers on an American Airlines DC-6 reported a &amp;ldquo;brilliant, diffused, bluish light of fluorescent type.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;august-15-1950&#34;&gt;August 15, 1950 &lt;a href=&#34;#august-15-1950&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Great Falls, Montana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The Mariana UFO incident garnered national media attention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;august-25-1951&#34;&gt;August 25, 1951 &lt;a href=&#34;#august-25-1951&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Lubbock, Texas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The Lubbock Lights were a v-shaped formation of lights seen over the town.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;may-24-1952&#34;&gt;May 24, 1952 &lt;a href=&#34;#may-24-1952&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Burbank, California&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Orfeo Angelucci claimed to encounter flying saucers and their friendly human-appearing pilots during his drives home from an aircraft plant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;july-13-1952&#34;&gt;July 13, 1952 &lt;a href=&#34;#july-13-1952&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Washington, D.C.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The 1952 Washington, D.C. UFO incident involved a series of unidentified flying object reports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;september-12-1952&#34;&gt;September 12, 1952 &lt;a href=&#34;#september-12-1952&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Flatwoods, West Virginia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Six local boys and a local woman reported sighting a UFO landing and later discovered a bizarre-looking creature near the site, known as the Flatwoods monster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;november-23-1953&#34;&gt;November 23, 1953 &lt;a href=&#34;#november-23-1953&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Felix Moncla, Jr., a United States Air Force pilot, disappeared with 2nd Lt. Robert Wilson while pursuing an unidentified flying object over Lake Superior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;november-2-1957&#34;&gt;November 2, 1957 &lt;a href=&#34;#november-2-1957&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Levelland, Texas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The Levelland UFO case involved multiple sightings of a UFO in the small town.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;september-19-1961&#34;&gt;September 19, 1961 &lt;a href=&#34;#september-19-1961&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Lancaster, New Hampshire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Betty and Barney Hill claimed to have been abducted by extraterrestrials, in what is known as the Hill Abduction or Zeta Reticuli Incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;april-24-1964&#34;&gt;April 24, 1964 &lt;a href=&#34;#april-24-1964&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Socorro, New Mexico&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Lonnie Zamora, a New Mexico police officer, reported a UFO close encounter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;september-3-1965&#34;&gt;September 3, 1965 &lt;a href=&#34;#september-3-1965&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Exeter, New Hampshire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The Exeter incident involved a UFO the size of a barn seen by a teenager and two police officers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;december-9-1965&#34;&gt;December 9, 1965 &lt;a href=&#34;#december-9-1965&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Kecksburg, Pennsylvania&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The Kecksburg UFO incident involved a large, brilliant fireball seen by thousands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1969&#34;&gt;1969 &lt;a href=&#34;#1969&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Leary, Georgia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Jimmy Carter claimed that he had seen a UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;october-11-1973&#34;&gt;October 11, 1973 &lt;a href=&#34;#october-11-1973&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Pascagoula, Mississippi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The abduction of Charles Hickson and Calvin Parker, also known as the Pascagoula Abduction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;january-12-1975&#34;&gt;January 12, 1975 &lt;a href=&#34;#january-12-1975&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; North Bergen, New Jersey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The Stonehenge incident occurred in the North Hudson Park near the Stonehenge apartment building.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;november-5-1975&#34;&gt;November 5, 1975 &lt;a href=&#34;#november-5-1975&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Snowflake, Arizona&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Travis Walton claims to have been abducted by a UFO while working on a logging crew.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;december-17-1977&#34;&gt;December 17, 1977 &lt;a href=&#34;#december-17-1977&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Council Bluffs, Iowa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Local residents reported seeing a reddish fireball falling and disappearing behind trees, followed by a grass fire and molten metal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;august-27-1979&#34;&gt;August 27, 1979 &lt;a href=&#34;#august-27-1979&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Stephen, Minnesota&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Deputy Sheriff Val Johnson&amp;rsquo;s patrol car was struck by a blinding ball of light.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;december-29-1980&#34;&gt;December 29, 1980 &lt;a href=&#34;#december-29-1980&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Dayton, Texas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The Cash-Landrum Incident involved a reported UFO sighting and subsequent health damage to the witnesses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;november-11-1987&#34;&gt;November 11, 1987 &lt;a href=&#34;#november-11-1987&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Gulf Breeze, Florida&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The Gulf Breeze UFO incident occurred.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;march-8-1994&#34;&gt;March 8, 1994 &lt;a href=&#34;#march-8-1994&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Multiple locations in Michigan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Over 100 witnesses reported five or six objects across West Michigan, known as the 1994 Lake Michigan UFO event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;march-13-1997&#34;&gt;March 13, 1997 &lt;a href=&#34;#march-13-1997&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Phoenix, Arizona&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The Phoenix Lights involved a series of optical phenomena seen by thousands of people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;january-5-2000&#34;&gt;January 5, 2000 &lt;a href=&#34;#january-5-2000&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Highland, Illinois&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The &amp;ldquo;St. Clair Triangle&amp;rdquo; sighting involved five on-duty Illinois police officers and other witnesses reporting a massive, silent, triangular aircraft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;august-21-2004&#34;&gt;August 21, 2004 &lt;a href=&#34;#august-21-2004&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Chicago, Illinois&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; A triangular formation of reddish lights were seen at low to intermediate altitude.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;november-7-2006&#34;&gt;November 7, 2006 &lt;a href=&#34;#november-7-2006&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Chicago, Illinois&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Federal authorities at Chicago O&amp;rsquo;Hare International Airport received a report of a metallic, saucer-shaped craft hovering over gate C-17.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;january-5-2009&#34;&gt;January 5, 2009 &lt;a href=&#34;#january-5-2009&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Morristown, New Jersey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Five unidentified red objects were seen. It was later admitted to be a hoax.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;february-1&#34;&gt;February 1 &lt;a href=&#34;#february-1&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_the_United_States&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_the_United_States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien Terminator (1988 film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_4f7a24b4b007/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 16:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_4f7a24b4b007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-terminator-1988-film&#34;&gt;Alien Terminator (1988 film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-terminator-1988-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the 1988 Italian film &lt;em&gt;Alien Terminator&lt;/em&gt;, also known as &lt;em&gt;Top Line&lt;/em&gt;. It distinguishes it from the 1995 film of the same name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-line&#34;&gt;Top Line &lt;a href=&#34;#top-line&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides the original Italian title of the film, which is &lt;em&gt;Top Line&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;film-details&#34;&gt;Film Details &lt;a href=&#34;#film-details&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents key information about the film in a table format:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Director:&lt;/strong&gt; Nello Rossati (also credited as Ted Archer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writers:&lt;/strong&gt; Roberto Gianviti and Nello Rossati&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stars:&lt;/strong&gt; Franco Nero and George Kennedy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cinematography:&lt;/strong&gt; Mario DiLeo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor:&lt;/strong&gt; Adalberto Ceccarelli&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Music:&lt;/strong&gt; Maurizio Dami&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 1988&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Country:&lt;/strong&gt; Italy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language:&lt;/strong&gt; Italian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot revolves around Ted Angelo, an alcoholic writer who discovers a 16th-century Spanish ship inside a mountain cave in Cartagena, Colombia. He learns the cave is actually the inside of a crashed UFO. He is pursued by hitmen, a Nazi fugitive named Heinrich Holzmann, and CIA operatives. He teams up with art historian June and eventually involves his ex-wife Maureen. Maureen is revealed to be an alien who has been disguising herself as a human and manipulating world events. She is killed by June. Ted and June go into hiding with an indigenous tribe, where Ted continues to write about his experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the main actors and their respective roles in the film:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Franco Nero as Ted Angelo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;George Kennedy as Heinrich Holzmann&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deborah Moore (credited as Deborah Barrymore) as June&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mary Stavin as Maureen De Havilland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;William Berger as Alonso Kintero&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shirley Hernandez as Juanita&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Larry Dolgin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert Redcross&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the film&amp;rsquo;s release information. It was released theatrically in Germany on September 22, 1988. It was released on Region 1 DVD on May 25, 2004. It is also available for streaming on platforms like Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes critical reception of the film. Sci-Fi 100 noted the initial lack of science fiction elements but found the last 30 minutes more engaging. Film Authority described the film as a mix of &lt;em&gt;Romancing the Stone&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Terminator&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists a related film:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull&lt;/em&gt; (2008)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of Italian films of 1988&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of citations used in the article, including books, websites, and databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the film&amp;rsquo;s IMDb page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Terminator_(1988_film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Terminator_(1988_film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Harder</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ed1204981fce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 16:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ed1204981fce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;james-a-harder&#34;&gt;James A. Harder &lt;a href=&#34;#james-a-harder&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James Albert Harder was a professor of civil and hydraulic engineering at the University of California, Berkeley, and later a professor emeritus. He also had a notable interest in ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;engineering&#34;&gt;Engineering &lt;a href=&#34;#engineering&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harder taught civil engineering at various levels, emphasizing practical aspects like lab experiments and model testing. While he didn&amp;rsquo;t publish extensively, his work was recognized for its quality. He made significant contributions to flow simulations before computers were widely used. A paper he co-authored, &lt;em&gt;Sea Water Intrusion in California&lt;/em&gt;, received an award in 1957. His work was applied in Suisun Bay and the Mekong Delta, and he also studied fish protection facilities. Later in his career, he studied fluid mechanics in a medical context, working on artificial hearts, endoscopes, and colostomy equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufology&#34;&gt;Ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harder believed that unidentified flying objects were extraterrestrial beings. He testified before the House of Representatives Committee on Science and Astronautics and was involved with the Aerial Phenomena Research Organization (APRO).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education &lt;a href=&#34;#education&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harder&amp;rsquo;s education included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;B.S. from the California Institute of Technology in 1948.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M.S. in Civil Engineering from UC Berkeley in 1952.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ph.D. in Fluid Mechanics from UC Berkeley in 1957.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;career&#34;&gt;Career &lt;a href=&#34;#career&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harder&amp;rsquo;s career included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;U.S. Navy as an electronics technician (1944-45).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design Engineer for the soil conservation service, U.S. Department of Agriculture (1948–50).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resident engineer at UC Berkeley (1952–57).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assistant professor of hydraulic engineering at UC Berkeley (1957–62).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Associate professor of civil engineering at UC Berkeley (1962–70).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professor of civil engineering at UC Berkeley (1970–91).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professor emeritus at UC Berkeley (1991).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;organizations&#34;&gt;Organizations &lt;a href=&#34;#organizations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harder was a Fellow of the American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS) and the American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE). He was also a founding member of the Society for Scientific Exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Harder_(ufologist)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Harder_(ufologist)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
