<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pseudoscience on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/pseudoscience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pseudoscience on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 12:27:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/pseudoscience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ufology</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7a24e854d947/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7a24e854d947/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufology&#34;&gt;Ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology is the investigation of unidentified flying objects (UFOs) by individuals who believe they may have extraordinary origins, often extraterrestrial. While governments, private groups, and fringe science have investigated UFOs, ufology is generally considered pseudoscience by skeptics and science educators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;etymology&#34;&gt;Etymology &lt;a href=&#34;#etymology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;ufology&amp;rdquo; is a neologism derived from &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; and the suffix &amp;ldquo;-logy.&amp;rdquo; Edward J. Ruppelt is credited with coining the term UFO. Early uses of &amp;ldquo;ufology&amp;rdquo; appeared in a 1957 &lt;em&gt;Fantastic Universe&lt;/em&gt; article and a 1958 presentation for The Planetary Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-background&#34;&gt;Historical Background &lt;a href=&#34;#historical-background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology&amp;rsquo;s roots can be traced to several historical phenomena:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mystery Airships (late 1890s):&lt;/strong&gt; Unexplained aerial objects reported during this period.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foo Fighters (World War II):&lt;/strong&gt; Reports from Allied airmen of unusual objects during flight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ghost Fliers (1930s):&lt;/strong&gt; Sightings in Europe and North America.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ghost Rockets (1946):&lt;/strong&gt; Sightings in Scandinavia, particularly Sweden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenneth Arnold Sighting (1947):&lt;/strong&gt; Arnold&amp;rsquo;s report of &amp;ldquo;flying saucers&amp;rdquo; popularized the concept.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increased media attention to UFOs after World War II coincided with the Cold War and concerns about Soviet aircraft. Official government involvement in ufology in the United States ended in the late 1960s after the Condon Committee report and the termination of Project Blue Book. Other countries, such as the United Kingdom, Canada, Denmark, Italy, and Sweden, also ended government-sponsored UFO activities. France is an exception, maintaining the GEIPAN program. In September 2023, NASA appointed Mark McInerney as the Director of U.A.P. to study such occurrences scientifically and transparently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;as-a-field&#34;&gt;As a Field &lt;a href=&#34;#as-a-field&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;status-as-a-pseudoscience&#34;&gt;Status as a Pseudoscience &lt;a href=&#34;#status-as-a-pseudoscience&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology is not recognized as a scientific field by academia and is generally considered a pseudoscience. Pseudoscience lacks adherence to the scientific method, supporting evidence, plausibility, or falsifiability. Social factors contribute to this status, including mistrust between ufology, the sciences, and government investigative bodies. Poor science communication regarding the extraterrestrial intelligence (ETI) hypothesis also hinders public understanding and academic inquiry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-interest&#34;&gt;Current Interest &lt;a href=&#34;#current-interest&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interest in ufology persists. In 2021, Avi Loeb launched The Galileo Project to collect scientific evidence of extraterrestrial technology. The University of Würzburg in Germany is developing sensors to detect and analyze aerial objects. A 2021 Gallup poll indicated increased belief among Americans that some UFOs are extraterrestrial spacecraft. In 2022, NASA announced a study to investigate UAP. In 2023, the RAND Corporation published a study reviewing 101,151 public reports of UAP sightings in the United States from 1998 to 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;methodological-issues&#34;&gt;Methodological Issues &lt;a href=&#34;#methodological-issues&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific UFO research faces challenges due to the unpredictable nature of the phenomena, lack of reproducibility, and absence of tangible physicality. Most UFO sightings have mundane explanations, limiting the interpretive power of extraordinary events. Carl Sagan noted that reliable cases are uninteresting, and interesting cases are unreliable. J. Allen Hynek and Jacques Vallée developed descriptive systems for characterizing UFO sightings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;phenomena-linked-to-ufology&#34;&gt;Phenomena Linked to Ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#phenomena-linked-to-ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain phenomena are of interest to some ufologists:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crop circles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cattle mutilations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anomalous materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alien abductions and implants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ufologists promote UFO conspiracy theories, such as the Roswell Incident and Majestic 12 documents. Robert Sheaffer has accused ufology of a &amp;ldquo;credulity explosion,&amp;rdquo; while James E. McDonald identified &amp;ldquo;cultism&amp;rdquo; as negatively impacting ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-posadism&#34;&gt;In Posadism &lt;a href=&#34;#in-posadism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the Cold War, ufology was synthesized with the ideas of Posadism, a Trotskyist movement in South America. Juan Posadas, the main theorist, believed humanity should appeal to extraterrestrials to intervene and collaborate in suppressing poverty and creating a socialist system on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;governmental-and-private-ufology-studies&#34;&gt;Governmental and Private Ufology Studies &lt;a href=&#34;#governmental-and-private-ufology-studies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting in the 1940s, governmental agencies and private groups sponsored investigations, studies, and conferences related to ufology. These studies include Project Sign, Project Magnet, Project Blue Book, the Robertson Panel, and the Condon Committee in the United States; the Flying Saucer Working Party and Project Condign in Britain; GEIPAN in France; and Project Hessdalen in Norway. Private studies include those by the RAND Corporation, Harvey Rutledge of the University of Missouri, and the National Press Club&amp;rsquo;s Disclosure Project. The United Nations sponsored meetings and hearings concerning UFO sightings from 1977 to 1979. In August 2020, the United States Department of Defense established the Unidentified Aerial Phenomena Task Force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufo-organizations-and-events&#34;&gt;UFO Organizations and Events &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-organizations-and-events&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerous private organizations worldwide are dedicated to the study and discussion of ufology. Skeptic organizations also exist, emphasizing the pseudoscientific nature of ufology. During World UFO Day (July 2), ufologists raise public awareness of ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ufology&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ufology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mutual UFO Network</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_0b91b1d30426/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 20:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_0b91b1d30426/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;mutual-ufo-network&#34;&gt;Mutual UFO Network &lt;a href=&#34;#mutual-ufo-network&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mutual UFO Network (MUFON) is a US-based non-profit organization dedicated to the scientific study of UFOs. Founded in 1969, it has grown to include over 4,000 members worldwide, with chapters in over 43 countries and all 50 US states. MUFON aims to investigate UFO sightings and provide information to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MUFON was originally established as the Midwest UFO Network on May 31, 1969, in Quincy, Illinois, by Allen R. Utke, Walter H. Andrus, Jr., John F. Schuessler, and others. It was renamed the Mutual UFO Network in 1973 due to its expansion. In July 2020, Executive Director Jan Harzan was arrested on charges of soliciting sex from a minor and was subsequently removed from his position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;operation&#34;&gt;Operation &lt;a href=&#34;#operation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headquartered in Cincinnati, Ohio, MUFON has chapters throughout the U.S. and internationally. It hosts an annual international symposium and publishes the monthly &lt;em&gt;MUFON UFO Journal&lt;/em&gt;. In 2015, MUFON founded Mutual UFO Network University, an unaccredited online institution for training UFO investigators. The organization has over 500 field investigators who investigate potential physical evidence of extraterrestrial craft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;criticism&#34;&gt;Criticism &lt;a href=&#34;#criticism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pseudoscience&#34;&gt;Pseudoscience &lt;a href=&#34;#pseudoscience&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MUFON has faced criticism for its focus on pseudoscience, including topics like alien abduction, conspiracy theories, and human-ET hybrids. Critics argue that MUFON&amp;rsquo;s investigations lack scientific rigor and that its researchers are often not scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;officers-and-donors-with-far-right-viewpoints&#34;&gt;Officers and donors with far-right viewpoints &lt;a href=&#34;#officers-and-donors-with-far-right-viewpoints&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; reported on anti-immigrant, anti-trans, and anti-Muslim sentiments among MUFON officials and donors, including J. Z. Knight and John Ventre. This led to resignations from members like Chris Cogswell and James Clarkson. In 2020, &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt; reported that Ken Pfeifer, head of MUFON&amp;rsquo;s Rhode Island chapter, posted racist content on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;popular-culture&#34;&gt;Popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MUFON has been mentioned in various television shows and news articles, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;television&#34;&gt;Television &lt;a href=&#34;#television&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;UFOs Over Earth&lt;/em&gt; (2008)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;UFO Hunters&lt;/em&gt; (2008)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hangar 1: The UFO Files&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;9-1-1: Lone Star&lt;/em&gt; (Season 3, Episode 6 &amp;ldquo;The ATX-Files&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;news&#34;&gt;News &lt;a href=&#34;#news&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; article &amp;ldquo;People Are Seeing U.F.O.s Everywhere, and This Book Proves It&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forbes&lt;/em&gt; article &amp;ldquo;MUFON, America&amp;rsquo;s UFO Experts, Discuss Roswell And Possible Cover-Ups&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MUFON&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MUFON&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
