<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Media on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Media on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 05:39:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Nation (novel series)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_33e1f69f7f3e/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 05:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_33e1f69f7f3e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-nation-novel-series&#34;&gt;Alien Nation (novel series) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-nation-novel-series&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt; novel series, which is based on the movie and television series of the same name. The series began in March 1993, published by Pocket Books. The novels follow the adventures of human Detective Matthew Sikes and his Tenctonese partner George Francisco. The books often mirror the TV series&amp;rsquo; structure, using parallel storylines that converge at the end, and frequently comment on real-life social issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alien-nation-a-novelization&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation: A Novelization&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-nation-a-novelization&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the novelization of the original &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt; movie. It was written by Alan Dean Foster and released in 1989. It&amp;rsquo;s an adaptation of the movie, not the TV series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alien-nation-1-day-of-descent&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation #1: Day of Descent&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-nation-1-day-of-descent&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the first book in the series, &lt;em&gt;Day of Descent&lt;/em&gt;, written by Judith and Garfield Reeves-Stevens and released in 1993. It serves as a prequel to both the movie and TV series, depicting the events leading up to the Tenctonese arrival on Earth. Matthew Sikes, a rookie detective, investigates a murder and uncovers a conspiracy. Simultaneously, on a distant planet, a Tenctonese slave named Stangya Soren&amp;rsquo;tzahh (later George Francisco) becomes involved in his people&amp;rsquo;s fight for freedom against the Overseers. The slave ship crashes on Earth, and Matt and George unknowingly collaborate to avert a disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alien-nation-2-dark-horizon&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation #2: Dark Horizon&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-nation-2-dark-horizon&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the second book, &lt;em&gt;Dark Horizon&lt;/em&gt;, written by K. W. Jeter and released in 1993. It was published before the television movie of the same name. The book aims to resolve some of the unresolved plot points from the &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt; TV series, especially since it was uncertain if the show would return to television. It recaps the events of &amp;ldquo;Green Eyes,&amp;rdquo; the series&amp;rsquo; final episode, and incorporates the unproduced script from &amp;ldquo;Dark Horizon,&amp;rdquo; which was intended to be the second season&amp;rsquo;s first episode. The plot involves a deadly bacteria created by a Purist group targeting Newcomers. George Francisco&amp;rsquo;s wife and daughter are infected. A threat from space emerges, aiming to enslave the Tenctonese and humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alien-nation-3-body-and-soul&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation #3: Body and Soul&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-nation-3-body-and-soul&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the third book, &lt;em&gt;Body and Soul&lt;/em&gt;, written by Peter David and released in 1993. It&amp;rsquo;s a novelization of the unproduced script for the second two-hour television movie of the same name. The film adaptation differed somewhat from the novel. The plot involves Matt and George investigating rumors of a half-human, half-Tenctonese child. Sikes&amp;rsquo; relationship with Cathy Frankel becomes more serious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alien-nation-4-the-change&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation #4: The Change&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-nation-4-the-change&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the fourth book, &lt;em&gt;The Change&lt;/em&gt;, written by Barry B. Longyear and released in 1994. It&amp;rsquo;s based on an unproduced script for the second television season. George Francisco undergoes a metamorphosis that could lead to a new life or his death. He also faces a killer seeking revenge on him and his family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alien-nation-5-slag-like-me&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation #5: Slag Like Me&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-nation-5-slag-like-me&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the fifth book, &lt;em&gt;Slag Like Me&lt;/em&gt;, written by Barry B. Longyear and released in 1994. The plot centers on a journalist named Micky Cass who goes undercover as a Newcomer to expose racism against the Tenctonese. When Cass goes missing, Matthew Sikes disguises himself as a Newcomer to find him. This puts Matt in a dangerous situation and forces him to confront a hidden truth within himself. The title is an allusion to the book &lt;em&gt;Black Like Me&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alien-nation-6-passing-fancy&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation #6: Passing Fancy&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-nation-6-passing-fancy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the sixth book, &lt;em&gt;Passing Fancy&lt;/em&gt;, written by David Spencer and released in 1994. Matt encounters a woman from his past and becomes involved in an investigation of a deadly Newcomer drug. He asks the woman he loves to risk her life. The case creates tension between Matt and George as they discover that some Newcomers will do anything to assimilate into human society. &lt;em&gt;Black Like Me&lt;/em&gt; is mentioned again, and Sikes reads it to gain understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alien-nation-7-extreme-prejudice&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation #7: Extreme Prejudice&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-nation-7-extreme-prejudice&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the seventh book, &lt;em&gt;Extreme Prejudice&lt;/em&gt;, written by L.A. Graf and released in 1995. Matt, the Franciscos, and Cathy attend a conference in Pittsburgh when a series of murders leads them to suspect a Tenctonese creature is responsible. The author includes a joke where a Tenctonese writing team uses the pen name &amp;ldquo;L.A. Graf.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alien-nation-8-cross-of-blood&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation #8: Cross of Blood&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-nation-8-cross-of-blood&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the eighth book, &lt;em&gt;Cross of Blood&lt;/em&gt;, written by K.W. Jeter and released in 1995. The plot explores the possibility of Cathy Frankel becoming pregnant with Matt Sikes&amp;rsquo; child. The resulting political tension and racial riots threaten to tear Los Angeles apart. The book references characters and events from &lt;em&gt;Dark Horizon&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Nation_(novel_series)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Nation_(novel_series)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
