<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ufology on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/ufology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ufology on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/ufology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>List of reported UFO sightings</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_583476a95eee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_583476a95eee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-reported-ufo-sightings&#34;&gt;List of Reported UFO Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-reported-ufo-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Wikipedia article provides a compilation of notable reported sightings of Unidentified Flying Objects (UFOs), including claims of close encounters and alien abduction. It clarifies that UFOs encompass any aerial phenomenon that cannot be immediately identified, noting that most are eventually explained as known objects or atmospheric phenomena. The article also mentions the use of the term &amp;ldquo;Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena&amp;rdquo; (UAP) to avoid associations with UFO conspiracy theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;antiquity&#34;&gt;Antiquity &lt;a href=&#34;#antiquity&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details alleged UFO sightings from ancient times, drawing from historical texts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c. 1450 BC:&lt;/strong&gt; The Tulli Papyrus describes an event during Thutmose III&amp;rsquo;s reign in Ancient Egypt, where a &amp;ldquo;star came down&amp;rdquo; and set fire to his adversaries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;218 BC:&lt;/strong&gt; Reports from the Roman Republic in Italia mention &amp;ldquo;phantom navy&amp;rdquo; seen shining in the sky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;76 BC:&lt;/strong&gt; An account from Asia (Roman Republic) describes a &amp;ldquo;spark&amp;rdquo; falling from a star, growing to the size of the Moon, and then transforming into a torch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;73 BC:&lt;/strong&gt; Plutarch recounts a &amp;ldquo;flame-like body&amp;rdquo; resembling a wine-jar (pithos) falling between Roman and Pontic armies in Phrygia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AD 65:&lt;/strong&gt; Flavius Josephus reports chariots &amp;ldquo;hurtling through the clouds&amp;rdquo; in Judaea before the First Jewish–Roman War.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AD 196:&lt;/strong&gt; Cassius Dio describes a &amp;ldquo;fine rain resembling silver&amp;rdquo; falling from a clear sky in Rome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;8th-century&#34;&gt;8th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#8th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a single entry:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c. AD 740:&lt;/strong&gt; The &amp;ldquo;Air ship of Clonmacnoise&amp;rdquo; is recorded in Irish annals, describing &amp;ldquo;ships with their crews were seen in the air&amp;rdquo; over Teltown and Clonmacnoise in Ireland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;16th17th-centuries&#34;&gt;16th–17th Centuries &lt;a href=&#34;#16th17th-centuries&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists reports from the Renaissance and early modern periods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1561:&lt;/strong&gt; A celestial phenomenon over Nuremberg, Bavaria, is described as an aerial battle with spheres, cylinders, and other odd-shaped objects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1566:&lt;/strong&gt; A broadsheet depicts spherical objects appearing out of the sun over Basel, Switzerland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1609:&lt;/strong&gt; Multiple witnesses in Joseon (Korea) describe a Halo or washbowl that was divided in two in the sky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;19th-century&#34;&gt;19th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#19th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers sightings from the 1800s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1883:&lt;/strong&gt; Astronomer José Bonilla photographed hundreds of dark objects crossing the sun at the Zacatecas Observatory in Mexico.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1896-1897:&lt;/strong&gt; Reports of &amp;ldquo;mystery airships&amp;rdquo; with bright lights and cigar-shaped bodies appear in newspapers across California and the Midwest United States.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1897:&lt;/strong&gt; S.E. Hayden reports the crash of an airship piloted by an alien in Aurora, Texas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;20th-century&#34;&gt;20th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#20th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is divided into two sub-sections: 1900-1949 and 1950-1974.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;19001949&#34;&gt;1900–1949 &lt;a href=&#34;#19001949&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the early to mid-20th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1904:&lt;/strong&gt; Crew members aboard the USS &lt;em&gt;Supply&lt;/em&gt; report seeing three &amp;ldquo;bright red&amp;rdquo; objects in geometrical formation flight pattern in the North Pacific.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1907:&lt;/strong&gt; Fighters of Çerçiz Topulli in Albania report seeing a shiny object suspended in the air.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1909:&lt;/strong&gt; Moving lights are reported in the sky around Otago, New Zealand, followed by more sightings across the country.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1917:&lt;/strong&gt; Thousands gather in Fátima, Portugal, and claim to see bizarre solar activity, later interpreted as a mass UFO sighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1926:&lt;/strong&gt; Nicholas Roerich reports an oval object in the sky above his caravan in Tibet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1933:&lt;/strong&gt; Frank Smythe witnesses two spots hovering and pulsating in the sky near Mount Everest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1940s:&lt;/strong&gt; Allied fighter pilots report colorful balls of light following their aircraft during World War II (Foo fighters).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1941:&lt;/strong&gt; A local legend emerges in Cape Girardeau, Missouri, about a crashed flying saucer and its dying crew.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1942:&lt;/strong&gt; Anti-aircraft artillery fires thousands of rounds at an unidentified aerial object over Los Angeles, California (Battle of Los Angeles).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1942:&lt;/strong&gt; Control tower operator near Flying School, Columbus, Missouri observes two reddish colored round objects descend-hover-accelerate away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1944:&lt;/strong&gt; 468th Bomb Group reports an intense red or orange object that throbbed or vibrated constantly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1945:&lt;/strong&gt; Conflicting accounts emerge regarding an avocado-shaped craft piloted by insectoid aliens crashing at the Trinity nuclear test site in New Mexico.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1946:&lt;/strong&gt; Thousands of UFO sightings are reported over Europe (Ghost Rockets), prompting investigations by the Swedish and Greek governments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1946:&lt;/strong&gt; Swedish entrepreneur Gösta Carlsson commemorates a 1946 UFO encounter with a concrete monument in Ängelholm, Sweden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; Private pilot Kenneth Arnold reports seeing a group of reflective craft moving at high speeds near Mount Rainier, Washington, coining the term &amp;ldquo;flying saucers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; Over 800 similar sightings are reported throughout 1947 after the Kenneth Arnold sighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; A United Airlines crew witnesses nine unidentified objects en route from Boise, Idaho, to Pendleton, Oregon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; William Albert Rhodes takes photographs of a silent grey object in Phoenix, Arizona.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; Walter Haut issues a press release announcing the &amp;ldquo;capture&amp;rdquo; of a &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; near Roswell, New Mexico, later retracted as a weather balloon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; Fred Crisman mails an account of flying doughnut-shaped objects and threats from Men in Black to Raymond A. Palmer (Maury Island hoax).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; Reports of green flares streaking across the sky are investigated by the US Air Force (The Green Fireballs).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; Captain Thomas F. Mantell dies in the crash of his P-51 Mustang fighter plane near Franklin, Kentucky, after pursuing an unidentified flying object.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; Conmen Silas Newton and Leo Gebauer sell &amp;ldquo;magnetic oil-detecting machines&amp;rdquo; based on a story about replicated technology from a crashed spaceship (Aztec, New Mexico UFO hoax).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; Clarence Chiles and John Whitted report that their airplane nearly collided with a UFO near Montgomery, Alabama.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; A US Air Force pilot sights and pursues a UFO for 27 minutes over Fargo, North Dakota (Gorman dogfight).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;19501974&#34;&gt;1950–1974 &lt;a href=&#34;#19501974&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the mid to late 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1950:&lt;/strong&gt; A farmer takes pictures of a purported &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; near McMinnville, Oregon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1950:&lt;/strong&gt; The manager of Great Falls&amp;rsquo; pro baseball team took color film of two UFOs flying over Great Falls, Montana.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1951:&lt;/strong&gt; Two pilots and a military officer passenger aboard a commercial DC-3 reported being buzzed by an unidentified straight-winged plane over Sioux City, Iowa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1951:&lt;/strong&gt; Several lights in V-shaped formations were repeatedly spotted flying over the city of Lubbock, Texas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952:&lt;/strong&gt; Four American military personnel aboard two different B-29 bombers reported seeing an orange globe-shaped light over two different cities in northern Korea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952:&lt;/strong&gt; A series of sightings accompanied radar contacts in the Washington, D.C. area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952:&lt;/strong&gt; William B. Nash and William H. Fortenberry, pilots of a DC-4 airliner of Pan American Airways, radioed the Norfolk civil aviation authority to report eight large, round, glowing red objects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952:&lt;/strong&gt; Three local boys followed a bright object into the forest to what they believed was a UFO landing in Flatwoods, West Virginia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1954:&lt;/strong&gt; French metalworker Marius Dewilde claimed to have become a contactee in Quarouble, France.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1954:&lt;/strong&gt; A football game between Fiorentina and Pistoiese was under way at the Stadio Artemio Franchi in Florence when a group of UFOs traveling at high speed abruptly stopped over the stadium.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1955:&lt;/strong&gt; Eleven people witnessed creatures in the night at a rural farmhouse near Hopkinsville, Kentucky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1956:&lt;/strong&gt; United States Air Force (USAF) and Royal Air Force (RAF) radar operators detected up to 15 objects over Suffolk, England.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1956:&lt;/strong&gt; Elizabeth Klarer claimed detailed adventures with an alien race including having had an alien lover, Akon, who would have fathered her son Ayling in Drakens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO_sightings&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO_sightings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien abduction</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_85a477e6d898/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_85a477e6d898/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-abduction&#34;&gt;Alien Abduction &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-abduction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alien abduction, also known as abduction phenomenon, alien abduction syndrome, or UFO abduction, is the subjective experience of individuals reporting being kidnapped by extraterrestrial beings and subjected to physical and psychological experimentation. These individuals are often referred to as &amp;ldquo;abductees&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;experiencers.&amp;rdquo; While most scientists and mental health professionals attribute these experiences to factors like suggestibility, sleep paralysis, deception, and psychopathology, some researchers give credence to the claims. Typical claims involve forced medical examinations, often focusing on reproductive systems, warnings about environmental abuses and nuclear weapons, or interspecies breeding. The content of these narratives often varies with the abductee&amp;rsquo;s cultural background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainstream scientists generally reject the literal interpretation of alien abduction claims. However, some, like psychiatrist John E. Mack, argue that many abductees are sane individuals, with psychopathology only present in some cases. Detailed abduction reports have led to the development of a subculture with support groups and a complex mythos explaining the roles, origins, and motivations of various alien types, such as Greys, Reptilians, and Nordics. Some abductees engage in independent research and attribute the lack of wider awareness to extraterrestrial or governmental cover-ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;paleo-abductions&#34;&gt;Paleo-abductions &lt;a href=&#34;#paleo-abductions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the widespread attention to alien abduction in the 1960s, some older stories have been reinterpreted as possible early cases, termed &amp;ldquo;paleo-abductions&amp;rdquo; by UFO researcher Jerome Clark. One example is Colonel H. G. Shaw&amp;rsquo;s 1896 claim of being harassed by tall, slender humanoids. An article from 1953 asked if flying saucers were kidnapping humans for zoological specimens or vivisection. The 1955 publication of Harold T. Wilkins&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Flying Saucers Uncensored&lt;/em&gt; reported speculation that Karl Hunrath and Wilbur Wilkinson, who claimed alien contact, disappeared due to abduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;two-landmark-cases&#34;&gt;Two landmark cases &lt;a href=&#34;#two-landmark-cases&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Antônio Vilas-Boas case in Brazil during the mid-1950s was an early claim but received limited attention initially. The Betty and Barney Hill abduction in 1961 gained widespread publicity, including a 1975 television film. The Hill incident is considered a prototypical abduction case, possibly the first to describe beings later known as the Greys and explicitly identify an extraterrestrial origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;later-developments&#34;&gt;Later developments &lt;a href=&#34;#later-developments&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R. Leo Sprinkle, a psychologist at the University of Wyoming, became interested in the phenomenon in the 1960s and linked abductions to cattle mutilation. Budd Hopkins became a key figure in the abductee subculture in the 1970s, using hypnosis to uncover details of remembered events. The 1980s saw increased mainstream attention, with works by Hopkins, Whitley Strieber, David M. Jacobs, and John E. Mack presenting alien abduction as a plausible experience. Thomas E. Bullard&amp;rsquo;s comparative analysis of nearly 300 alleged abductees was also published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jacobs and Hopkins argued that alien abduction was more common than previously thought, estimating tens of thousands of North Americans had been abducted. They also proposed an alien effort to create human-alien hybrids. While anecdotal reports of phantom pregnancies related to UFO encounters existed earlier, Hopkins and Jacobs popularized the idea of widespread interbreeding efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Boston Globe&lt;/em&gt; writer Linda Rodriguez McRobbie, alien abduction stories have declined in mainstream media. Michael Shermer suggests that the ubiquity of camera phones has increased the burden of evidence, contributing to the decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;john-e-mack&#34;&gt;John E. Mack &lt;a href=&#34;#john-e-mack&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harvard psychiatry professor John E. Mack believed in the credibility of alien abduction claims. Niall Boyce, writing in &lt;em&gt;The Lancet&lt;/em&gt;, suggested that Mack&amp;rsquo;s work in hypnotic regression helped spread the Grey aliens meme. Mack interviewed over 800 people and wrote two books on the subject. His professional reputation suffered due to his belief and promotion of abduction claims, leading to a Harvard review in 1994.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abductees&#34;&gt;Abductees &lt;a href=&#34;#abductees&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The precise number of alleged abductees is uncertain. Early studies found 1,700 claimants, while contested surveys suggested 5–6 percent of the general population claim to have been abducted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;demographics&#34;&gt;Demographics &lt;a href=&#34;#demographics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While abduction reports are usually made by adults, children sometimes report similar experiences. These reports often share specific details with adult reports, including circumstances, narrative, entities, and aftermaths. Young abductees often have family members who have reported abduction experiences, and family involvement in the military or residence near a military base is also common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mental-health&#34;&gt;Mental health &lt;a href=&#34;#mental-health&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some studies suggest that abductees have psychological characteristics that render their testimony suspect, while others show that abductees are not different from the general population in terms of psychopathology prevalence. Elizabeth Slater&amp;rsquo;s blind study found abductees prone to &amp;ldquo;mildly paranoid thinking,&amp;rdquo; nightmares, and weak sexual identity, while Richard McNally&amp;rsquo;s study concluded that none of the abductees suffered from psychiatric illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;political-conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;Political conspiracy theories &lt;a href=&#34;#political-conspiracy-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Political scientist Michael Barkun highlights links between radical politics and conspiracy theories involving UFOs, alien visitation, environmental pollution, hidden groups, and government takeover. He observed the rise of &amp;ldquo;improvisional millenarism.&amp;rdquo; UFO and abduction stories can be part of stigmatized knowledge narratives. UFO and alien-related conspiracy theories emerged in far-right politics from the 1980s onwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Barkun, TV shows like &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt; included aliens as part of coverup conspiracies, with militias and black helicopters, and demonized FEMA. Political scientist Jodi Dean noted that the stigma of alien abduction stories is seductive to dismiss &amp;ldquo;consensus reality&amp;rdquo; in favor of deviant alternative realities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-described abduction victims often join self-help communities and may resort to questionable regression therapy. Some espouse conspiracy theories of technological mind control, including implants, to force them to serve a New World Order or for the purposes of the antichrist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abduction-narrative&#34;&gt;Abduction narrative &lt;a href=&#34;#abduction-narrative&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various researchers have noted common points in report narratives. CUFOS defines an abductee as someone taken against their will by non-human beings to an extraterrestrial place or spaceship, subjected to examination or communication, with memories that may be conscious or recovered through hypnosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although cases vary, some UFO researchers argue that there is a fairly consistent sequence and description of events that make up the typical &amp;ldquo;close encounter of the fourth kind.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bullard argues most abduction accounts feature the following events:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capture&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductee is rendered incapable of resisting and taken to an alien spacecraft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Examination and Procedures&lt;/strong&gt;: Invasive physiological and psychological procedures, and on occasion simulated behavioral situations, training &amp;amp; testing, or sexual liaisons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conference&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductors communicate with the abductee or direct them to interact with specific individuals for some purpose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tour&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductees are given a tour of their captors&amp;rsquo; vessel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loss of Time&lt;/strong&gt;: Abductees often rapidly forget the majority of their experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Return&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductees are returned to earth, occasionally in a different location or with new injuries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theophany&lt;/strong&gt;: Abductees may have a profound sense of love, a &amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo; similar to those induced by certain drugs, or a &amp;ldquo;mystical experience&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aftermath&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductee must cope with the psychological, physical, and social effects of the experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David M. Jacobs says that the entire abduction event is precisely orchestrated, with predetermined procedures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;capture&#34;&gt;Capture &lt;a href=&#34;#capture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abduction claimants report unusual feelings preceding the onset of an abduction experience, such as a compulsive desire to be at a certain place or expectations that something &amp;ldquo;familiar yet unknown&amp;rdquo; will occur. They also report feeling severe anxiety. Eventually, the experiencer will undergo an apparent &amp;ldquo;shift&amp;rdquo; into an altered state of consciousness. External sounds cease to have any significance, and they report feeling introspective and unusually calm. As consciousness shifts, lights are alleged to appear, occasionally accompanied by a strange mist. As the alleged abduction proceeds, claimants say they will walk or be levitated into an alien craft, often through solid objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;examination&#34;&gt;Examination &lt;a href=&#34;#examination&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The examination phase is characterized by medical procedures and examinations by alien beings against the will of the experiencer. Such procedures often focus on sex and reproductive biology. The entity in charge of the operation is often taller than the others and may appear to be of a different species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miller notes different areas of emphasis between human medicine and what is reported as being practiced by the abductors. The abductors&amp;rsquo; areas of interest appear to be the cranium, nervous system, skin, reproductive system, and joints. Systems given less attention include the cardiovascular system, the respiratory system below the pharynx, and the lymphatic system. The abductors also appear to ignore the upper region of the abdomen in favor of the lower one. The abductors do not appear to wear gloves during the &amp;ldquo;examination.&amp;rdquo; Other constants of terrestrial medicine like pills and tablets are missing from abduction narratives, although sometimes abductees are asked to drink liquids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;subsequent-procedures&#34;&gt;Subsequent procedures &lt;a href=&#34;#subsequent-procedures&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the medical exam, the alleged abductees often report other procedures being performed with the entities. Common among these post-examination procedures are imaging, envisioning, staging, and testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Imaging&amp;rdquo; procedures consist of an abductee being made to view screens displaying images and scenes that appear to be specially chosen with the intent to provoke certain emotional responses in the abductee. &amp;ldquo;Envisioning&amp;rdquo; is a similar procedure, with the primary difference being that the images being viewed, rather than being on a screen, actually seem to be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_abduction&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_abduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in Poland</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6e43e9f78bd4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 18:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6e43e9f78bd4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-sightings-in-poland&#34;&gt;UFO Sightings in Poland &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-sightings-in-poland&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article documents alleged UFO sightings in Poland. It includes specific incidents with dates, locations, and brief descriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-may-1978-emilcin&#34;&gt;10 May 1978, Emilcin &lt;a href=&#34;#10-may-1978-emilcin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the Emilcin Abduction, where a farmer in Emilcin claimed to have been abducted and examined by short, green-faced humanoid beings. The encounter allegedly took place inside a white, hovering craft. A memorial now stands at the site of the alleged abduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;19-january-2009-jarnołtówek&#34;&gt;19 January 2009, Jarnołtówek &lt;a href=&#34;#19-january-2009-jarno%c5%82t%c3%b3wek&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details a sighting in Jarnołtówek near Prudnik. Adam Maksymów reported seeing a large saucer with a triangular blue beam rising into the sky. The object was accompanied by loud noises and a buzzing sound. Other residents of Jarnołtówek also reported witnessing the same object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the main &amp;ldquo;List of reported UFO sightings&amp;rdquo; article on Wikipedia, allowing readers to explore a broader range of UFO incidents worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources used to support the claims made in the article. These include news articles from &lt;em&gt;Kraków Post&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Nowa Trybuna Opolska&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Gazeta Krakowska&lt;/em&gt;. The references provide external verification and further reading on the reported sightings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Poland&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Poland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in Belgium</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_4dc18de43b38/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 17:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_4dc18de43b38/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-sightings-in-belgium&#34;&gt;UFO Sightings in Belgium &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-sightings-in-belgium&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article documents alleged UFO sightings in Belgium, focusing primarily on the significant wave of sightings between 1989 and 1990.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1989-1990&#34;&gt;1989-1990 &lt;a href=&#34;#1989-1990&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights the Belgian UFO wave, a period of intense UFO activity. The main feature of this wave was the frequent reports of triangular UFOs observed across the country. These objects were even pursued by Belgian Air Force F-16 fighter jets, and some photographs were taken. One speculative explanation suggested these sightings might have been misidentified stealth aircraft, specifically the F-117 Nighthawk, using Belgian highways for navigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1990-03-30&#34;&gt;1990-03-30 &lt;a href=&#34;#1990-03-30&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details a specific mass sighting event that occurred on March 30, 1990, in Ans, Wallonia. Numerous witnesses reported seeing large, silent, low-flying black triangles. These objects were tracked by multiple NATO radar systems and intercepted by jet fighters. The Belgian military investigated the incident, and photographic evidence is said to exist. A close encounter was also reported during this event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the general &amp;ldquo;List of reported UFO sightings&amp;rdquo; Wikipedia article, allowing readers to explore UFO sightings in other locations and time periods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section includes an external link to the MUFON (Mutual UFO Network) website, specifically to a page displaying the latest 20 UFO sighting reports and pictures. This provides a resource for readers interested in contemporary UFO sighting information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufos-template&#34;&gt;UFOs Template &lt;a href=&#34;#ufos-template&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a template linking to various UFO-related topics on Wikipedia. It includes links to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ufology:&lt;/strong&gt; The study of UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Claimed Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A general list of reported UFO sightings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sightings in outer space and near atomic sites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sightings from pre-20th century to the 21st century, including notable events like the Roswell incident, the Phoenix Lights, and the USS Nimitz UFO incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confirmed hoaxes like the Maury Island hoax and the Alien Autopsy film.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sightings by country, including Africa, Australia, Belgium, Brazil, Canada, China, France, Mexico, Russia, Spain, the United Kingdom, and the United States.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Types of UFOs:&lt;/strong&gt; Black triangles, flying saucers, foo fighters, ghost rockets, green fireballs, mystery airships, and space jellyfish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Types of Alleged Extraterrestrial Beings:&lt;/strong&gt; Energy beings, grey aliens, insectoids, little green men, Nordic aliens, and reptilian humanoids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Studies and Timeline:&lt;/strong&gt; Projects and reports like Project Sign, Project Blue Book, the Condon Report, and the Advanced Aerospace Threat Identification Program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hypotheses:&lt;/strong&gt; Ancient astronauts, extraterrestrial, interdimensional, psychological, and psychosocial hypotheses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conspiracy Theories:&lt;/strong&gt; Area 51, Bob Lazar, Dulce Base, and Men in Black.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Involvement:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abduction claims, including history, entities, narrative, and perspectives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other aspects like implants, cattle mutilation, close encounters, contactees, crop circles, government responses, and ufologists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Culture:&lt;/strong&gt; UFOs in fiction and religions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skepticism:&lt;/strong&gt; Links to scientific skeptics and the Committee for Skeptical Inquiry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Government &amp;amp; Law:&lt;/strong&gt; Mentions United States Congress hearings on UFOs and the Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena Disclosure Act (UADPA).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Belgium&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Belgium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Roswell Incident (1980 book)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_35f31e4c5c9f/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 19:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_35f31e4c5c9f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-roswell-incident-1980-book&#34;&gt;The Roswell Incident (1980 book) &lt;a href=&#34;#the-roswell-incident-1980-book&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry details the 1980 book &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt; by Charles Berlitz and William Moore, which significantly contributed to popularizing the Roswell incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for the Roswell incident, focusing on the events of 1947 and the renewed interest in the story in the late 1970s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;events-of-1947&#34;&gt;Events of 1947 &lt;a href=&#34;#events-of-1947&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection outlines the initial reports of the Roswell incident during the &amp;ldquo;flying disc craze&amp;rdquo; of 1947, Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting, the Roswell Army Air Field&amp;rsquo;s initial press release about recovering a crashed disc, and the subsequent retraction stating it was a weather balloon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;roswell-revisited&#34;&gt;Roswell revisited &lt;a href=&#34;#roswell-revisited&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explains how the Roswell story gained traction again in 1978 when retired lieutenant colonel Jesse Marcel claimed in an interview with ufologist Stanton Friedman that the debris he recovered was extraterrestrial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;authors&#34;&gt;Authors &lt;a href=&#34;#authors&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides background information on the authors of the book, Charles Berlitz and William Moore. It mentions Berlitz&amp;rsquo;s previous success with &lt;em&gt;The Bermuda Triangle&lt;/em&gt; and their collaboration on &lt;em&gt;The Philadelphia Experiment: Project Invisibility&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents &lt;a href=&#34;#contents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the book&amp;rsquo;s central argument: that an extraterrestrial craft crashed in New Mexico while observing nuclear weapons activity, and the US government engaged in a cover-up. It highlights accounts of debris described as &amp;ldquo;nothing made on this earth&amp;rdquo; and mentions witnesses like Bill Brazel, Floyd Proctor, and Walt Whitman Jr. The section also notes the book&amp;rsquo;s introduction of the idea that the debris shown in photos with Marcel was substituted as part of the cover-up. It also mentions the claim that the military sought to discredit the growing interest in flying saucers. The section also notes that the authors claimed to have interviewed over 90 witnesses, but only a fraction of those accounts appear in the book. The section also notes that the book elevated Marcel&amp;rsquo;s narrative above that of Cavitt, whose description of the debris contradicted Marcel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-bodies&#34;&gt;Alien bodies &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-bodies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the book&amp;rsquo;s introduction of the story about Barney Barnett and archaeology students encountering wreckage and &amp;ldquo;alien bodies&amp;rdquo; on the Plains of San Agustin. It also mentions the conflation of the Roswell incident with the Aztec, New Mexico, UFO incident, a hoaxed flying saucer crash promoted by Frank Scully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the reception of the book, noting that critics deemed it &amp;ldquo;a collection of wild hearsay&amp;rdquo; and that it &amp;ldquo;did not make the commercial impact its authors hoped.&amp;rdquo; It also mentions accusations against Moore regarding the Majestic 12 documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aftermath&#34;&gt;Aftermath &lt;a href=&#34;#aftermath&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions Moore&amp;rsquo;s admission at a 1989 MUFON conference that he had engaged in &amp;ldquo;disinformation&amp;rdquo; activities against Paul Bennewitz on behalf of the Air Force Office of Special Investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modern-views&#34;&gt;Modern views &lt;a href=&#34;#modern-views&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section references the 1993 inquiry by the General Accounting Office in response to US congressman Steven Schiff, which led to a 1994 Air Force report concluding that the recovered material was likely debris from Project Mogul, a military surveillance program using high-altitude balloons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Roswell_Incident_(1980_book)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Roswell_Incident_(1980_book)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finnish Air Force UFO sighting</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_46310b08f1d3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 12:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_46310b08f1d3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;finnish-air-force-ufo-sighting&#34;&gt;Finnish Air Force UFO Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#finnish-air-force-ufo-sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Finnish Air Force UFO sighting, also known as &amp;ldquo;The seven balloons of Pori,&amp;rdquo; refers to a UFO observation that occurred on April 12, 1969, in Pori, Finland, during military training exercises. This event is notable as the only UFO observation acknowledged by the Finnish Air Force. The Air Force suggested the objects may have been foreign reconnaissance aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sighting&#34;&gt;Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a Fouga Magister jet training mission at Pori Airport on April 12, 1969, a Finnish Defence Forces flight controller instructed pilot-in-training Tarmo Tukeva to investigate seven airborne objects. These objects were floating at an altitude of approximately 1500-3000 meters above the airport. Tukeva described the objects as ball or disc-shaped but could not accurately determine his distance from them. He reported that the objects accelerated away from him &amp;ldquo;at great speed.&amp;rdquo; Radar images, the nature of which remains undetermined, were also reported 200 kilometers away in Vaasa. Jouko Kuronen, another pilot-in-training, stated that he overheard the radio communications between the flight controller and Tukeva and also observed the objects. According to the Finnish Armed Forces magazine &lt;em&gt;Ruotuväki&lt;/em&gt;, the reports from April 12 were similar to other cases occurring over bodies of water during ongoing military exercises, suggesting the possibility of &amp;ldquo;transnational spy planes or aircraft.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The references section lists the sources used to support the information presented in the article. These include articles from &lt;em&gt;Ilta-Sanomat&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Yle Uutiset&lt;/em&gt;, both Finnish news outlets. These articles provide further details and context regarding the UFO sighting and the Finnish Air Force&amp;rsquo;s acknowledgment of the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufos&#34;&gt;UFOs &lt;a href=&#34;#ufos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a comprehensive template of UFO-related topics, including ufology, claimed sightings, types of UFOs, alleged extraterrestrial beings, studies, hypotheses, conspiracy theories, alien involvement, culture, skepticism, government involvement, and related categories. It serves as a navigation tool to explore various aspects of the UFO phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Finnish_Air_Force_UFO_sighting&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Finnish_Air_Force_UFO_sighting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Harder</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ed1204981fce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 16:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ed1204981fce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;james-a-harder&#34;&gt;James A. Harder &lt;a href=&#34;#james-a-harder&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James Albert Harder was a professor of civil and hydraulic engineering at the University of California, Berkeley, and later a professor emeritus. He also had a notable interest in ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;engineering&#34;&gt;Engineering &lt;a href=&#34;#engineering&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harder taught civil engineering at various levels, emphasizing practical aspects like lab experiments and model testing. While he didn&amp;rsquo;t publish extensively, his work was recognized for its quality. He made significant contributions to flow simulations before computers were widely used. A paper he co-authored, &lt;em&gt;Sea Water Intrusion in California&lt;/em&gt;, received an award in 1957. His work was applied in Suisun Bay and the Mekong Delta, and he also studied fish protection facilities. Later in his career, he studied fluid mechanics in a medical context, working on artificial hearts, endoscopes, and colostomy equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufology&#34;&gt;Ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harder believed that unidentified flying objects were extraterrestrial beings. He testified before the House of Representatives Committee on Science and Astronautics and was involved with the Aerial Phenomena Research Organization (APRO).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education &lt;a href=&#34;#education&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harder&amp;rsquo;s education included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;B.S. from the California Institute of Technology in 1948.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M.S. in Civil Engineering from UC Berkeley in 1952.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ph.D. in Fluid Mechanics from UC Berkeley in 1957.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;career&#34;&gt;Career &lt;a href=&#34;#career&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harder&amp;rsquo;s career included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;U.S. Navy as an electronics technician (1944-45).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design Engineer for the soil conservation service, U.S. Department of Agriculture (1948–50).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resident engineer at UC Berkeley (1952–57).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assistant professor of hydraulic engineering at UC Berkeley (1957–62).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Associate professor of civil engineering at UC Berkeley (1962–70).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professor of civil engineering at UC Berkeley (1970–91).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professor emeritus at UC Berkeley (1991).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;organizations&#34;&gt;Organizations &lt;a href=&#34;#organizations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harder was a Fellow of the American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS) and the American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE). He was also a founding member of the Society for Scientific Exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Harder_(ufologist)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Harder_(ufologist)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
