<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ufology on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/ufology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ufology on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 22:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/ufology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nordic aliens</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7c6654f96aa5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 22:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7c6654f96aa5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;nordic-aliens&#34;&gt;Nordic Aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#nordic-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In ufology, &amp;ldquo;Nordics,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Nordic aliens,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Tall Whites&amp;rdquo; are terms used to describe alleged humanoid extraterrestrial races from the Pleiades star cluster. These beings are said to resemble Nordic, Germanic, or Scandinavian humans, with features like tall stature (6-7 ft), blond hair, blue eyes, and fair skin. Some reports describe their skin tone as pale blue/grey or pastel purple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cultural historian David J. Skal suggests that early stories of Nordic aliens may have been inspired by the 1951 film &lt;em&gt;The Day the Earth Stood Still&lt;/em&gt;. Stephanie Kelley-Romano describes alien abduction beliefs as a &amp;ldquo;living myth,&amp;rdquo; noting that believers often associate Nordic aliens with spiritual growth and protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In ufology, Nordic aliens are often portrayed as benevolent beings concerned about Earth&amp;rsquo;s ecology and world peace, possessing telepathic powers and described as paternal, watchful, smiling, affectionate, and youthful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the 1950s, many people, especially in Europe, claimed encounters with these beings. However, such claims became less common in later decades as the grey alien became more prevalent in extraterrestrial encounter accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publications-by-those-claiming-to-have-been-contacted&#34;&gt;Publications by Those Claiming to Have Been Contacted &lt;a href=&#34;#publications-by-those-claiming-to-have-been-contacted&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several books detail alleged personal contact with Nordic aliens, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flying Saucers Have Landed&lt;/em&gt; by Desmond Leslie and George Adamski&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inside the Space Ships&lt;/em&gt; by George Adamski&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Outer Space to You&lt;/em&gt; by Howard Menger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Walton Experience&lt;/em&gt; by Travis Walton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Millennial Hospitality&lt;/em&gt; by Charles James Hall (adapted into the film &lt;em&gt;Walking with the Tall Whites&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UFO religion Universe People also publishes interactions with &amp;ldquo;Cosmic Friends.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See Also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists related topics, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Space Brothers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Truman Bethurum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elizabeth Klarer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Billy Meier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linda Moulton Howe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of alleged extraterrestrial beings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star people (New Age)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arcturians (New Age)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFOs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFO religion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of cited sources used in the article, including books, articles, and websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_aliens&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_aliens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crop circle</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_990cc3fef0ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 09:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_990cc3fef0ed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;crop-circle&#34;&gt;Crop Circle &lt;a href=&#34;#crop-circle&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;A crop circle, also known as a crop formation or corn circle, is a pattern created by flattening a crop, usually a cereal. The term was coined in the early 1980s. While fringe theorists suggest obscure natural causes or alien origins, there is no scientific evidence for such explanations, and all crop circles are consistent with human causation. In 1991, Doug Bower and Dave Chorley, two hoaxers, claimed responsibility for creating over 200 crop circles throughout England. Reported circles in the United Kingdom appear near roads, areas of medium to dense population, and cultural heritage monuments, such as Stonehenge or Avebury, and usually appear overnight. Archaeological remains can cause cropmarks in the fields in the shapes of circles and squares, but these do not appear overnight, and are always in the same places every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;before-the-20th-century&#34;&gt;Before the 20th century &lt;a href=&#34;#before-the-20th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A 1678 news pamphlet &lt;em&gt;The Mowing-Devil: or, Strange News Out of Hartfordshire&lt;/em&gt; describes a crop whose stalks were cut rather than bent. In 1686, English naturalist Robert Plot reported on rings or arcs of mushrooms in &lt;em&gt;The Natural History of Stafford-Shire&lt;/em&gt;, proposing air flows from the sky as a cause. In 1991, meteorologist Terence Meaden linked this report with modern crop circles. An 1880 letter to the editor of &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt; by amateur scientist John Rand Capron describes how several circles of flattened crops in a field were formed under suspicious circumstances and possibly caused by &amp;ldquo;cyclonic wind action&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;20th-century&#34;&gt;20th century &lt;a href=&#34;#20th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1932, archaeologist E. C. Curwen observed four dark rings in a field at Stoughton Down near Chichester. In &lt;em&gt;Fortean Times,&lt;/em&gt; David Wood reported that in 1940 he made crop circles near Gloucestershire using ropes. In 1963, Patrick Moore described a crater in a potato field in Wiltshire and several circular and elliptical areas in nearby wheat fields. Astronomer Hugh Ernest Butler observed similar craters and said they were likely caused by lightning strikes. During the 1960s, there were many reports of UFO sightings and circular formations in swamp reeds and sugarcane fields in Tully, Queensland, Australia, and in Canada. On 8 August 1967, three circles were found in a field in Duhamel, Alberta, Canada; Department of National Defence investigators concluded that it was artificial. The most famous case is the 1966 Tully &amp;ldquo;saucer nest&amp;rdquo;. British pranksters Doug Bower and Dave Chorley reported they started creating crop circles in British cornfields in 1978, inspired by the Tully &amp;ldquo;saucer nest&amp;rdquo; case. The first film to depict a geometric crop circle, in this case created by super-intelligent ants, was the 1974 science-fiction film &lt;em&gt;Phase IV&lt;/em&gt;. The majority of reports of crop circles have appeared and spread since the late 1970s. By 2001, approximately 10,000 crop circles have been reported internationally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;21st-century&#34;&gt;21st century &lt;a href=&#34;#21st-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the start of the 21st century, crop formations have increased in size and complexity. The researcher Jeremy Northcote found that crop circles in the UK in 2002 were not spread randomly across the landscape. They tended to appear near roads, areas of medium-to-dense population, and cultural heritage monuments such as Stonehenge or Avebury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bower-and-chorley&#34;&gt;Bower and Chorley &lt;a href=&#34;#bower-and-chorley&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1991, Doug Bower and Dave Chorley, made headlines by saying they had started the crop circle phenomenon in 1978, using simple tools. To prove their case they made a circle in front of journalists; a &amp;ldquo;cereologist&amp;rdquo;, Pat Delgado, examined the circle and declared it authentic before it was revealed that it was a hoax. Inspired by Australian crop circle accounts from 1966, Bower and Chorley claimed to be responsible for all circles made prior to 1987, and for more than 200 crop circles in 1978–1991.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;art-and-business&#34;&gt;Art and business &lt;a href=&#34;#art-and-business&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After reports of simple circles in the 1970s, increasingly complex geometric designs have been created by anonymous artists, in some cases to attract tourists to an area. Since the early 1990s, the UK arts collective Circlemakers, founded by Rod Dickinson and John Lundberg, has been creating crop circles in the UK and around the world as part of its art practice and also for commercial clients. The Led Zeppelin Boxed Set that was released on 7 September 1990, features an image of a crop circle that appeared in East Field in Alton Barnes, Wiltshire. On the night of 11–12 July 1992, a crop-circle-making competition with a prize of £3,000 was held in Berkshire. In 2002, Discovery Channel commissioned five aeronautics and astronautics graduate students from MIT to create crop circles of their own. In 2009, &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; reported that crop circle activity had been waning around Wiltshire, in part because makers preferred creating promotional crop circles for companies that paid well for their efforts. A video sequence used in connection with the opening of the 2012 Summer Olympics in London showed two crop circles in the shape of the Olympic rings. A 3 ha (7 acres) crop circle depicting the emblem of the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; Rebel Alliance was created in California in December 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;legal-implications&#34;&gt;Legal implications &lt;a href=&#34;#legal-implications&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1992, Gábor Takács and Róbert Dallos, both then aged 17, were the first people to face legal action after creating a crop circle in Hungary. In 2000, Matthew Williams became the first man in the UK to be arrested for causing criminal damage after making a crop circle near Devizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;creation&#34;&gt;Creation &lt;a href=&#34;#creation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;human-origin&#34;&gt;Human origin &lt;a href=&#34;#human-origin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The scientific consensus on crop circles is that they are constructed by human beings as hoaxes, advertising, or art. The most widely known method for a person or group to construct a crop formation is to tie one end of a rope to an anchor point and the other end to a board which is used to crush the plants. Bower and Chorley confessed in 1991 to making the first crop circles in southern England. In a copycat effect, increasingly complex circles started appearing in many countries around the world, including fractal figures. Some crop formations are paid for by companies who use them as advertising. Hoaxers have been caught in the process of making new circles, such as in 2004 in the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;natural-origins&#34;&gt;Natural origins &lt;a href=&#34;#natural-origins&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;weather&#34;&gt;Weather &lt;a href=&#34;#weather&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has been suggested that crop circles may be the result of extraordinary meteorological phenomena ranging from freak tornadoes to ball lightning, but there is no evidence of any crop circle being created by any of these causes. In 1880, an amateur scientist, John Rand Capron, wrote a letter to the editor of journal &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt; about some circles in crops and blamed them on a recent storm. In 1980, Terence Meaden, a meteorologist and physicist, proposed that the circles were caused by whirlwinds whose course was affected by southern England hills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;animal-activity&#34;&gt;Animal activity &lt;a href=&#34;#animal-activity&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2009, the attorney general for the island state of Tasmania stated that Australian wallabies had been found creating crop circles in fields of opium poppies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alternative-explanations&#34;&gt;Alternative explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#alternative-explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In science magazines from the 1980s and 1990s, one could read reports suggesting that the plants were bent by something that could be microwave radiation, rather than broken by physical impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;paranormal&#34;&gt;Paranormal &lt;a href=&#34;#paranormal&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since becoming the focus of widespread media attention in the 1980s, crop circles have been the subject of speculation by various paranormal, ufological, and anomalistic investigators, ranging from proposals that they were created by bizarre meteorological phenomena to messages from extraterrestrial beings. There has also been speculation that crop circles have a relation to ley lines. Some paranormal advocates think that crop circles are caused by ball lightning and that the patterns are so complex that they have to be controlled by some entity. Responding to local beliefs that &amp;ldquo;extraterrestrial beings&amp;rdquo; in UFOs were responsible for crop circles appearing, the Indonesian National Institute of Aeronautics and Space (LAPAN) described crop circles as &amp;ldquo;man-made&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;changes-to-crops&#34;&gt;Changes to crops &lt;a href=&#34;#changes-to-crops&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A small number of scientists (physicist Eltjo Haselhoff, the late biophysicist William Levengood) have claimed to observe differences between the crops inside the circles and outside them, citing this as evidence they were not man made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;related-art&#34;&gt;Related art &lt;a href=&#34;#related-art&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patterns similar to crop circles can also be made in snow, by using skis, snow shoes or just walking with ordinary shoes. Patterns similar to crop circles can also be made in sand. Images can be made in forests by cutting trees, especially in areas with snow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;folklore&#34;&gt;Folklore &lt;a href=&#34;#folklore&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Researchers of crop circles have linked modern crop circles to old folkloric tales to support the claim that they are not artificially produced. Crop circles are culture dependent: they appear mostly in developed and secularised Western countries where people are receptive to New Age beliefs, including Japan, but they do not appear at all in other zones, such as Muslim countries. Fungi can cause circular areas of crop to die, probably the origin of tales of &amp;ldquo;fairie rings&amp;rdquo;. A 17th-century English woodcut called the &lt;em&gt;Mowing-Devil&lt;/em&gt; depicts the devil with a scythe mowing (cutting) a circular design in a field of oats. In the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crop_circle&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crop_circle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unidentified flying object</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a18aebf49ab5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 02:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a18aebf49ab5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;unidentified-flying-object-ufo&#34;&gt;Unidentified Flying Object (UFO) &lt;a href=&#34;#unidentified-flying-object-ufo&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;An unidentified flying object (UFO), also known as unidentified aerial phenomena (UAP) or unidentified anomalous phenomena, is defined as an object or phenomenon observed in the sky that cannot be immediately identified or explained. While reports of unusual aerial sightings date back to at least the 3rd century BC, the term &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; gained prominence after World War II and escalated during the Space Age. Most UFOs are later identified as known objects or atmospheric phenomena, but a small percentage remain unexplained. Government investigations and studies by various organizations have occurred over the years, but without confirmation of claims that UFOs are evidence of extraterrestrial intelligence or other unconventional hypotheses. Skeptics often attribute UFO sightings to natural phenomena, human technology, delusions, or hoaxes. The philosophical implications of UFOs relate to epistemology, dealing with temporarily or permanently unknowable anomalous phenomena. The U.S. government has two entities dedicated to UFO data collection and analysis: NASA&amp;rsquo;s UAP independent study team and the Department of Defense&amp;rsquo;s All-domain Anomaly Resolution Office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;terminology&#34;&gt;Terminology &lt;a href=&#34;#terminology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the late 1940s and 1950s, UFOs were commonly referred to as &amp;ldquo;flying saucers&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;flying discs,&amp;rdquo; originating from the Kenneth Arnold incident. Captain Edward J. Ruppelt of the USAF coined the acronym &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; to replace the misleading term &amp;ldquo;flying saucer.&amp;rdquo; The term &amp;ldquo;unidentified aerial phenomena&amp;rdquo; (UAP) emerged in the late 1960s and has gained usage in the 21st century due to negative connotations associated with &amp;ldquo;UFO.&amp;rdquo; UAP is sometimes expanded to &amp;ldquo;unidentified anomalous phenomenon.&amp;rdquo; In popular culture, UFO has become synonymous with alien spacecraft, sometimes referred to as &amp;ldquo;extra-terrestrial vehicle&amp;rdquo; (ETV).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;identification&#34;&gt;Identification &lt;a href=&#34;#identification&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most UFOs can be identified as ordinary objects or phenomena after careful investigation. Common identified sources include aircraft, astronomical objects, balloons, hoaxes, light phenomena, other atmospheric objects and phenomena, and psychological effects. The USAF&amp;rsquo;s 1952–1955 study categorized UFOs as balloons, astronomical objects, aircraft, light phenomena, birds, clouds, dust, insufficient information, psychological manifestations, unknown, and other. Allan Hendry, a CUFOS researcher, found that fewer than one percent of cases were hoaxes, with most sightings being misidentifications of prosaic phenomena due to inexperience or misperception. Astronomer Andrew Fraknoi encourages critical thinking when evaluating UFO claims, suggesting that thorough investigation often reveals less to the stories than initially perceived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-history-before-the-20th-century&#34;&gt;Early history before the 20th century &lt;a href=&#34;#early-history-before-the-20th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Throughout history, people have observed unusual sights in the sky, including comets, meteors, planets, planetary conjunctions, and optical phenomena. Halley&amp;rsquo;s Comet, first recorded by Chinese astronomers, was often seen as a supernatural portent or omen. Some UFO enthusiasts have drawn parallels between religious symbols in medieval paintings and UFO reports, but art historians offer conventional religious interpretations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of pre-contemporary reports include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Julius Obsequens, a Roman writer, documented wonders and portents in Rome between 249 and 12 BCE, with descriptions resembling meteor showers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shen Kuo, a Song Chinese scholar-official, described a flying object with opening doors and blinding light in his &lt;em&gt;Dream Pool Essays&lt;/em&gt; (1088).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A woodcut by Hans Glaser from 1561, known as the &amp;ldquo;celestial phenomenon over Nuremberg,&amp;rdquo; has been linked to ancient astronaut claims, though skeptics argue it depicts a sundog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A similar report from 1566 over Basel, along with other leaflets from the 15th and 16th centuries, described &amp;ldquo;miracles&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sky spectacles&amp;rdquo; resembling natural phenomena.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 1878, farmer John Martin reported seeing a large, dark, circular object resembling a saucer, marking one of the first uses of the word &amp;ldquo;saucer&amp;rdquo; in association with a UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From November 1896 to April 1897, newspapers reported numerous sightings of &amp;ldquo;mystery airships,&amp;rdquo; with some people claiming to have spoken to the pilots. Thomas Edison dismissed these reports as fake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;20th-century-and-after&#34;&gt;20th century and after &lt;a href=&#34;#20th-century-and-after&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;During World War II, Allied and Axis pilots reported round, glowing fireballs known as &amp;ldquo;foo fighters.&amp;rdquo; Explanations for these sightings included St. Elmo&amp;rsquo;s fire, the planet Venus, hallucinations, and German secret weapons. In 1946, over 2,000 reports of unidentified aerial objects, referred to as &amp;ldquo;Russian hail&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;ghost rockets,&amp;rdquo; were collected, primarily by the Swedish military.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Science fiction depictions of spacecraft similar to flying saucers predated the first widely reported UFO sighting in 1947.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modern UFO craze began with the Kenneth Arnold sighting on June 24, 1947, when he described seeing &amp;ldquo;flying saucers&amp;rdquo; near Mount Rainier. Within weeks, reports of flying saucer sightings became common, including the Roswell incident in 1947. In 1950, influential books by Donald Keyhoe, Frank Scully, and Gerald Heard proposed the extraterrestrial UFO hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Media speculation ran rampant, especially during the 1952 UFO scare in Washington, D.C. By 1953, intelligence officials worried that genuine incursions by enemy aircraft could be lost in a flood of UFO reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 1947, the U.S. Air Force began investigating UFO reports through Project Sign, followed by Project Grudge and Project Blue Book. In the late 1950s, public pressure mounted for declassification of UFO records, but the CIA resisted. Official U.S. Air Force interest in UFO reports ended in 1969 after the Condon Report concluded that further investigation was not justified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the 1960s to 1990s, UFOs became part of American popular culture&amp;rsquo;s obsession with the supernatural and paranormal. In 1961, the Barney and Betty Hill alien abduction account gained notoriety. In 1966, 5% of Americans reported seeing something they thought was a &amp;ldquo;flying saucer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December 2017, media attention increased with the revelation of the secret Advanced Aviation Threat Identification Program, funded from 2007 to 2012. Leaked Pentagon UFO videos led to increased mainstream attention to UFO stories. In July 2021, Harvard astronomer Avi Loeb announced the Galileo Project to seek evidence of extraterrestrial artifacts. Government programs, such as NASA&amp;rsquo;s UAP independent study team and the All-domain Anomaly Resolution Office, were established to investigate UFO claims more fully. In May 2022, the United States House Intelligence Subcommittee held congressional hearings on UAPs, the first public hearing on UFO sightings in the US in over 50 years. Another Congressional hearing took place on July 26, 2023, featuring the whistleblower claims of former U.S. Air Force officer David Grusch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polls have shown varying levels of belief in UFOs among Americans, with some indicating that a significant percentage believe UFOs are evidence of alien life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFOs have been taken up by religious studies scholars, and popular culture has played a significant role in shaping public perception of extraterrestrials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notable-cases-and-incidents&#34;&gt;Notable cases and incidents &lt;a href=&#34;#notable-cases-and-incidents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Notable cases and incidents include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;britain&#34;&gt;Britain &lt;a href=&#34;#britain&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Rendlesham Forest incident (1980)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;france&#34;&gt;France &lt;a href=&#34;#france&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Valensole UFO incident (1965)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Trans-en-Provence Case (1981)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;united-states&#34;&gt;United States &lt;a href=&#34;#united-states&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Kecksburg UFO incident (1965)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Travis Walton abduction claim (1975)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Phoenix Lights (1997)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;famous-hoaxes&#34;&gt;Famous hoaxes &lt;a href=&#34;#famous-hoaxes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Maury Island incident&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;George Adamski&amp;rsquo;s claims of meetings with telepathic aliens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ed Walters&amp;rsquo; Gulf Breeze UFO incident (1987)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investigations-of-reports&#34;&gt;Investigations of reports &lt;a href=&#34;#investigations-of-reports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;UFOs have been investigated by governments and academics in various countries. No official government investigation has ever publicly concluded that UFOs are indisputably real, physical objects, extraterrestrial in origin, or of concern to national defense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Known government studies include the Swedish military&amp;rsquo;s ghost rockets investigation (1946–1947), Project Blue Book by the USAF (1947–1969), Project Twinkle investigation into green fireballs (1948–1951), Project Blue Book Special Report No. 14 by the Battelle Memorial Institute, and the Brazilian Air Force&amp;rsquo;s Operação Prato (1977). France has had an ongoing investigation (GEPAN/SEPRA/GEIPAN) since 1977, and Uruguay has had a similar investigation since 1989.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;americas&#34;&gt;Americas &lt;a href=&#34;#americas&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;brazil-19522016&#34;&gt;Brazil (1952–2016) &lt;a href=&#34;#brazil-19522016&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The National Archives of Brazil has documentation from the Brazilian Air Force regarding UFO investigations between 1952 and 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;chile-c-1968&#34;&gt;Chile (c. 1968) &lt;a href=&#34;#chile-c-1968&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The SEFAA (previously CEFAA) began receiving case reports of UFO sightings in Chile in 1968.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;canada-c-1950&#34;&gt;Canada (c. 1950) &lt;a href=&#34;#canada-c-1950&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Department of National Defence has dealt with UFO reports and investigations across&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unidentified_flying_object&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unidentified_flying_object&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial UFO hypothesis</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_244257a9a6ef/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 23:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_244257a9a6ef/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-ufo-hypothesis&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial UFO Hypothesis &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-ufo-hypothesis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the extraterrestrial hypothesis (ETH), which suggests that some unidentified flying objects (UFOs) are best explained as physical spacecraft occupied by intelligent extraterrestrial organisms or probes designed by them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;usage-of-the-term&#34;&gt;Usage of the Term &lt;a href=&#34;#usage-of-the-term&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section traces the use of the term &amp;ldquo;extraterrestrial hypothesis&amp;rdquo; in UFO literature back to the 1960s. Key figures mentioned include French ufologist Jacques Vallée, who used the term in his 1966 book, and French engineer Aimé Michel. James E. McDonald and James Harder also used the term in 1968, including during testimony before Congress. Skeptic Philip J. Klass used it in his 1968 book. Physicist Edward Condon is credited with popularizing the term and its abbreviation &amp;ldquo;ETH&amp;rdquo; in 1969 when presenting the findings of the Condon Report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chronology&#34;&gt;Chronology &lt;a href=&#34;#chronology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section explores the historical roots of the ETH, tracing it back to earlier concepts such as Percival Lowell&amp;rsquo;s ideas about Martian canals and civilizations, the science fiction writings of H. G. Wells and Edgar Rice Burroughs, and the works of Emanuel Swedenborg, who linked other worlds to the afterlife. It also mentions Charles Fort, who collected accounts of anomalous aerial phenomena in the early 20th century and theorized about visitors from other worlds. The modern ETH took root in the late 1940s and 1950s, influenced by pseudoscience and popular culture, and bolstered by unexplained sightings investigated by governments and civilian groups like NICAP and APRO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-reports-of-extraterrestrial-visits&#34;&gt;Historical Reports of Extraterrestrial Visits &lt;a href=&#34;#historical-reports-of-extraterrestrial-visits&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides examples of early speculation about extraterrestrial visitors. It mentions a story from 1864 about American geologists discovering an alien-like creature inside an egg-shaped structure. It also discusses H. G. Wells&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;The War of the Worlds&lt;/em&gt; and the &amp;ldquo;mystery airships&amp;rdquo; reported in the late 19th century, with some speculating they were from Mars. The section also notes the influence of comic strips, radio, and movie serials like Buck Rogers and Flash Gordon on popularizing the idea of alien visitation in spaceships. The 1938 radio broadcast of &lt;em&gt;The War of the Worlds&lt;/em&gt; by Orson Welles is mentioned as creating public panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-1947-flying-saucer-wave-in-america&#34;&gt;The 1947 Flying Saucer Wave in America &lt;a href=&#34;#the-1947-flying-saucer-wave-in-america&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the events following Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting of unidentified disk-shaped aircraft near Mount Rainier in June 1947. It notes that Arnold quickly considered the possibility of the objects being extraterrestrial. The section mentions the speculation in newspapers about the nature of the objects, including comments from U.S. Senator Glen Taylor and R. DeWitt Miller. It also references Charles Fort&amp;rsquo;s earlier documentation of unidentified flying objects. The section highlights that most people were initially unwilling to conclude the objects were extraterrestrial, with theories such as secret military projects, Russian spy devices, hoaxes, optical illusions, and mass hysteria being more popular. It cites a Gallup poll from August 1947 showing that most people either had no opinion or believed in a mundane explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;evolution-of-public-opinion&#34;&gt;Evolution of Public Opinion &lt;a href=&#34;#evolution-of-public-opinion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section examines how public opinion on UFOs and the ETH evolved. It mentions the release of several movies in the early 1950s depicting flying saucers and aliens. It cites a &lt;em&gt;Popular Science&lt;/em&gt; poll from 1951 indicating that most UFO witnesses believed they had seen man-made aircraft, while only a small percentage believed they had seen an alien craft. By 1957, a quarter of Americans were willing to believe in the ETH. A Roper poll in 2002 reported that a majority of respondents thought UFOs were real, with nearly half believing they had visited Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;religion&#34;&gt;Religion &lt;a href=&#34;#religion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section briefly mentions the connection between UFOs and religion, citing the Aetherius Society founded by George King in 1955 as one of the first and most enduring UFO cults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nasa&#34;&gt;NASA &lt;a href=&#34;#nasa&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section discusses NASA&amp;rsquo;s evolving stance on UAPs. It mentions that in June 2021, NASA Administrator Bill Nelson directed NASA scientists to investigate Unidentified Aerial Phenomenon and explored the possibility that UAP could represent extraterrestrial technology. NASA scientist Ravi Kopparapu advocates studying UAP using scientific methods. Kopparapu presented a paper in August 2021 that supported ETH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;private-or-government-studies&#34;&gt;Private or Government Studies &lt;a href=&#34;#private-or-government-studies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section details private and governmental studies that have supported the ETH or had members who dissented from official conclusions. It mentions a 1948 USAF Europe document citing Swedish air intelligence&amp;rsquo;s conclusion that some UFOs had extraterrestrial origins. It also discusses the USAF Project Sign&amp;rsquo;s Top Secret Estimate of the Situation in 1948, which concluded that the ETH was the most likely explanation for unexplained cases, but was ordered destroyed. A secret West German study from 1951 to 1954, headed by Hermann Oberth, also concluded that UFOs were extraterrestrial. The CIA&amp;rsquo;s internal review of UFOs is mentioned, with some scientists considering the ETH. The section also notes individuals within Project Blue Book, such as Major Dewey Fournet and consultant J. Allen Hynek, who supported the ETH. Statements from former CIA Director Roscoe H. Hillenkoetter and Greek physicist Paul Santorini are included. The section also mentions the COMETA report, and Jean-Jacques Velasco&amp;rsquo;s book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;critical-responses-and-positions-of-the-eth&#34;&gt;Critical Responses and Positions of the ETH &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-responses-and-positions-of-the-eth&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section presents critical responses to the ETH. It states that there is no scientific proof to back up assertions of alien presence on Earth. It notes that no rigorous analysis has ever concluded that UFO sightings are verifiable evidence for the ETH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;us-military-investigation-and-debunkery&#34;&gt;U.S. Military Investigation and Debunkery &lt;a href=&#34;#us-military-investigation-and-debunkery&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the U.S. military&amp;rsquo;s involvement in investigating and debunking UFOs. It mentions the Army Air Forces Intelligence&amp;rsquo;s secret study of saucer reports in 1947 and the formation of Project Sign. It notes that Project Sign concluded without endorsing any unified explanation, and the ETH was rejected by USAF Chief of Staff General Hoyt Vandenberg. The CIA&amp;rsquo;s Office of Scientific Investigation took interest in UFOs following the 1952 UFO flap. The Robertson Panel, organized by the CIA in 1953, reviewed Blue Book&amp;rsquo;s evidence and recommended a policy of public debunkery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;involvement-of-scientists&#34;&gt;Involvement of Scientists &lt;a href=&#34;#involvement-of-scientists&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section highlights the scientific community&amp;rsquo;s lack of support for the ETH. It mentions Stephen Hawking&amp;rsquo;s skepticism and quotes Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s warning against self-deception in accepting or rejecting the idea of extraterrestrial visitation. It also quotes Peter A. Sturrock&amp;rsquo;s call for examining other possible theories beyond the ETH. The section presents the results of Sturrock&amp;rsquo;s polls of American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics and American Astronomical Society members, showing limited support for the ETH. It summarizes J. Allen Hynek&amp;rsquo;s seven key reasons for not accepting the ETH, including the failure of surveillance systems to detect UFOs, gravitational and atmospheric considerations, statistical considerations, the behavior of UFOs and their occupants, the isolation of the UFO phenomenon, the space unworthiness of UFOs, and the problem of astronomical distances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fewer-sightings-despite-camera-phone-technology&#34;&gt;Fewer Sightings Despite Camera Phone Technology &lt;a href=&#34;#fewer-sightings-despite-camera-phone-technology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section notes that the proliferation of smartphone camera technology has not led to a significant increase in recorded UFO sightings, which has called into question the claimed phenomenology of UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nasa-1&#34;&gt;NASA &lt;a href=&#34;#nasa-1&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section states NASA&amp;rsquo;s official position as of 2006, which is that the ETH lacks empirical evidence. It quotes David Morrison&amp;rsquo;s statements that no one has ever found a single artifact or convincing evidence for alien visits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cia&#34;&gt;CIA &lt;a href=&#34;#cia&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section mentions the CIA&amp;rsquo;s organization of the Robertson Panel in 1953 to debunk the data collected by Project Blue Book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;official-white-house-position&#34;&gt;Official White House Position &lt;a href=&#34;#official-white-house-position&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section presents the White House&amp;rsquo;s official response in November 2011 to petitions asking the U.S. government to acknowledge alien visits and disclose any withholding of government interactions with extraterrestrial beings. The response states that the U.S. government has no evidence of life outside our planet or that an extraterrestrial presence has contacted or engaged any member of the human race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;counter-critique-of-the-official-position-conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;Counter Critique of the Official Position: Conspiracy Theories &lt;a href=&#34;#counter-critique-of-the-official-position-conspiracy-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the concept of a conspiracy of silence or official cover-up to conceal information about UFOs. It mentions James Harder&amp;rsquo;s argument in 1968 that significant evidence existed to prove UFOs but had been suppressed. It cites a 1971 survey showing that more Americans believed the government was concealing information about UFOs than believed in the existence of UFOs or the ETH itself. It also mentions comments from former NASA astronauts Gordon Cooper and Brian O&amp;rsquo;Leary about NASA and the government suppressing UFO sightings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_UFO_hypothesis&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_UFO_hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Roswell Incident (1980 book)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_35f31e4c5c9f/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 19:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_35f31e4c5c9f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-roswell-incident-1980-book&#34;&gt;The Roswell Incident (1980 book) &lt;a href=&#34;#the-roswell-incident-1980-book&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This entry focuses on the 1980 book &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt; by Charles Berlitz and William Moore, which significantly contributed to popularizing the Roswell incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for the Roswell incident, starting with the events of 1947.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;events-of-1947&#34;&gt;Events of 1947 &lt;a href=&#34;#events-of-1947&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This subsection details the initial reports surrounding the Roswell incident. It mentions the flying disc craze of 1947, Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting, and the Roswell Army Air Field&amp;rsquo;s initial press release about recovering a &amp;ldquo;flying disc,&amp;rdquo; which was quickly retracted and replaced with the explanation of a weather balloon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;roswell-revisited&#34;&gt;Roswell revisited &lt;a href=&#34;#roswell-revisited&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This part highlights the renewed interest in the Roswell story in 1978, sparked by an interview with retired lieutenant colonel Jesse Marcel, who claimed the debris he retrieved was of extraterrestrial origin. Stanton Friedman, a ufologist, conducted the interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;authors&#34;&gt;Authors &lt;a href=&#34;#authors&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides background information on the authors of the book. Charles Berlitz is noted for authoring &lt;em&gt;The Bermuda Triangle&lt;/em&gt;, a bestseller that popularized the mysteries surrounding that area. William L. Moore is identified as a UFO researcher. Their previous collaboration, &lt;em&gt;The Philadelphia Experiment: Project Invisibility&lt;/em&gt;, is also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents &lt;a href=&#34;#contents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the book&amp;rsquo;s central argument: that an extraterrestrial craft crashed in New Mexico while observing nuclear weapons activity, and the US government engaged in a cover-up. It mentions accounts of debris described as &amp;ldquo;nothing made on this earth&amp;rdquo; by Jesse Marcel. Other individuals mentioned include Bill Brazel, Floyd Proctor, and Walt Whitman Jr. The book is described as &amp;ldquo;version 1&amp;rdquo; of the Roswell myth. It also introduces the idea that the debris shown in photos with Marcel was substituted as part of the cover-up and that the press was not allowed to closely inspect the recovered material. The authors claimed to have interviewed over 90 witnesses, but only a fraction of their testimonies appear in the book. The incarceration of Mac Brazel is also mentioned. The section notes that Marcel&amp;rsquo;s narrative was elevated above that of Cavitt, whose description of the debris contradicted Marcel&amp;rsquo;s account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-bodies&#34;&gt;Alien bodies &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-bodies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the book&amp;rsquo;s introduction of the &amp;ldquo;alien bodies&amp;rdquo; narrative. It mentions the second-hand stories of Grady &amp;ldquo;Barney&amp;rdquo; Barnett and archaeology students encountering wreckage and &amp;ldquo;alien bodies&amp;rdquo; on the Plains of San Agustin, far from the initial Roswell crash site. It also points out that some accounts of the Roswell incident contain information from the Aztec, New Mexico, UFO incident, a hoax promoted by Frank Scully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section notes that critics have deemed &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt; as &amp;ldquo;a collection of wild hearsay&amp;rdquo; and that the book &amp;ldquo;did not make the commercial impact its authors hoped.&amp;rdquo; It also mentions that fingers were pointed at Moore when critics and skeptics characterized the Majestic 12 documents as fraudulent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aftermath&#34;&gt;Aftermath &lt;a href=&#34;#aftermath&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section mentions that William Moore claimed to have engaged in &amp;ldquo;disinformation&amp;rdquo; activities against Paul Bennewitz on behalf of the Air Force Office of Special Investigations at a 1989 MUFON conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modern-views&#34;&gt;Modern views &lt;a href=&#34;#modern-views&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section references the 1993 inquiry from US congressman Steven Schiff, which led to a General Accounting Office investigation and an Air Force report. The 1994 Air Force report concluded that the material recovered was likely debris from Project Mogul, a military surveillance program using high-altitude balloons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Roswell_Incident_(1980_book)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Roswell_Incident_(1980_book)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in the United States</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8d3b71993ef9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 17:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8d3b71993ef9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-the-united-states&#34;&gt;List of Alleged UFO Sightings in the United States &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-the-united-states&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a comprehensive list of alleged UFO sightings in the United States, presented in a tabular format. Each entry includes the date, city, state, a link to a main article if available, and a brief description of the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;table-of-sightings&#34;&gt;Table of Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#table-of-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The table is the core of the article, detailing numerous alleged UFO sightings across the United States from 1865 to 2023. Key information includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 1865, Cadotte Pass, Montana:&lt;/strong&gt; Trapper James Lumley reported a craft crash with sulfur smells and hieroglyphics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1896-1897, Multiple Locations:&lt;/strong&gt; Sightings of &amp;ldquo;mystery airships&amp;rdquo; across the US.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 17, 1897, Aurora, Texas:&lt;/strong&gt; Residents claimed an airship crashed, and the alien pilot was buried in the local cemetery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 24, 1942, Los Angeles, California:&lt;/strong&gt; The &amp;ldquo;Battle of Los Angeles,&amp;rdquo; initially thought to be an enemy attack, later attributed to &amp;ldquo;war nerves&amp;rdquo; and a weather balloon. Secretary of the Navy Frank Knox called it a &amp;ldquo;false alarm.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 1945, Jornada del Muerto, New Mexico:&lt;/strong&gt; Two boys reported an &amp;ldquo;avocado-shaped&amp;rdquo; object crashing with insect-like alien creatures. This is known as the Trinity UFO Case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June 21, 1947, Maury Island, Washington:&lt;/strong&gt; An incident reported before the Kenneth Arnold sighting, involving alleged encounters with &amp;ldquo;men in black.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June 24, 1947, Mount Rainier, Washington:&lt;/strong&gt; Kenneth Arnold reported seeing nine unusual objects flying in formation, describing them as &amp;ldquo;erratic&amp;rdquo; and moving at &amp;ldquo;tremendous speed.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 1947, Roswell, New Mexico:&lt;/strong&gt; The Roswell UFO Incident, involving the recovery of materials that became the subject of intense speculation. The US military claims it was a research balloon, while ufologists believe it was an alien craft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 7, 1948, Maysville, Kentucky:&lt;/strong&gt; The Mantell Incident, where Captain Thomas F. Mantell, a Kentucky Air National Guard pilot, crashed and died while pursuing a UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 24, 1948, Montgomery, Alabama:&lt;/strong&gt; The Chiles-Whitted UFO Encounter, where two commercial pilots reported their Douglas DC-3 nearly collided with a strange torpedo-shaped object.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 1, 1948, Fargo, North Dakota:&lt;/strong&gt; The Gorman Dogfight, where a US Air Force pilot sighted and pursued a UFO for 27 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 11, 1950, McMinnville, Oregon:&lt;/strong&gt; The McMinnville UFO photographs, taken by Paul and Evelyn Trent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 29, 1950, Mount Vernon, Maryland:&lt;/strong&gt; Captain Willis Sperry and crew reported a &amp;ldquo;brilliant, diffused, bluish light.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 15, 1950, Great Falls, Montana:&lt;/strong&gt; The Mariana UFO incident, which garnered national media attention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 25, 1951, Lubbock, Texas:&lt;/strong&gt; The Lubbock Lights, a V-shaped formation of lights seen over the town.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 24, 1952, Burbank, California:&lt;/strong&gt; Orfeo Angelucci claimed to encounter flying saucers and friendly pilots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 13, 1952, Washington, D.C.:&lt;/strong&gt; The 1952 Washington D.C. UFO incident, a series of unidentified flying object reports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 12, 1952, Flatwoods, West Virginia:&lt;/strong&gt; Six boys and a woman reported a UFO landing and a bizarre-looking creature, known as the Flatwoods monster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 23, 1953, Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan:&lt;/strong&gt; Felix Moncla, Jr., a US Air Force pilot, disappeared with 2nd Lt. Robert Wilson while pursuing a UFO over Lake Superior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 2, 1957, Levelland, Texas:&lt;/strong&gt; The Levelland UFO case, where multiple residents reported seeing a UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 19, 1961, Lancaster, New Hampshire:&lt;/strong&gt; Betty and Barney Hill claimed to have been abducted by extraterrestrials, known as the Hill Abduction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 24, 1964, Socorro, New Mexico:&lt;/strong&gt; Lonnie Zamora, a New Mexico police officer, reported a UFO close encounter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 3, 1965, Exeter, New Hampshire:&lt;/strong&gt; The Exeter incident, where a large UFO was seen by a teenager and two police officers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 9, 1965, Kecksburg, Pennsylvania:&lt;/strong&gt; The Kecksburg UFO incident, where a large fireball was seen, and metal debris was reported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1969, Leary, Georgia:&lt;/strong&gt; Jimmy Carter claimed to have seen a UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 11, 1973, Pascagoula, Mississippi:&lt;/strong&gt; The Pascagoula Abduction, where Charles Hickson and Calvin Parker claimed to have been abducted by aliens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 12, 1975, North Bergen, New Jersey:&lt;/strong&gt; The Stonehenge incident, reported near the Stonehenge apartment building.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 5, 1975, Snowflake, Arizona:&lt;/strong&gt; Travis Walton claimed to have been abducted by a UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 17, 1977, Council Bluffs, Iowa:&lt;/strong&gt; Residents reported a reddish fireball and a grass fire with molten metal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 27, 1979, Stephen, Minnesota:&lt;/strong&gt; The Val Johnson incident, where Deputy Sheriff Val Johnson&amp;rsquo;s patrol car was struck by a ball of light.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 29, 1980, Dayton, Texas:&lt;/strong&gt; The Cash-Landrum Incident, where witnesses claimed health damage after a UFO sighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 11, 1987, Gulf Breeze, Florida:&lt;/strong&gt; The Gulf Breeze UFO incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March 8, 1994, Multiple Locations, Michigan:&lt;/strong&gt; Over 100 witnesses reported multiple objects across West Michigan, known as the 1994 Lake Michigan UFO event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March 13, 1997, Phoenix, Arizona:&lt;/strong&gt; The Phoenix Lights, a series of optical phenomena seen by thousands. Former Arizona governor Fife Symington admitted to seeing a delta-shaped craft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 5, 2000, Highland, Illinois:&lt;/strong&gt; The &amp;ldquo;St. Clair Triangle&amp;rdquo; sighting, where police officers and other witnesses reported a massive, silent, triangular aircraft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 21, 2004, Chicago, Illinois:&lt;/strong&gt; A triangular formation of reddish lights was seen by hundreds of witnesses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 7, 2006, Chicago, Illinois:&lt;/strong&gt; The Chicago O&amp;rsquo;Hare UFO sighting, where airport employees witnessed a metallic, saucer-shaped craft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 5, 2009, Morristown, New Jersey:&lt;/strong&gt; Five unidentified red objects were seen, later revealed to be a hoax by Joe Rudy and Chris Russo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 19, 2018, Desert, Arizona:&lt;/strong&gt; Commercial pilots saw an unidentified object, likely a &amp;ldquo;high-altitude research balloon.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 21, 2021, Clayton, New Mexico:&lt;/strong&gt; A pilot reported seeing a long cylindrical object.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 10, 2023, Deadhorse, Alaska:&lt;/strong&gt; A high-altitude object was shot down by the U.S. Air Force.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 12, 2023, Lake Huron, Michigan:&lt;/strong&gt; An octagonal object was shot down by the US Air Force.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to related Wikipedia articles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of reported UFO sightings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psychological perspectives on UFO belief&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, providing links to external websites, news articles, and books that support the information presented in the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section is currently empty, but it is intended to provide links to external resources related to UFO sightings in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_the_United_States&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_the_United_States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien visitation</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_9a9f42ca947b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 12:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_9a9f42ca947b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;alien-visitation&#34;&gt;Alien Visitation &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-visitation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This entry directs readers to the Wiktionary definition of &amp;ldquo;visitation.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alien visitation&lt;/strong&gt; refers to the concept that intelligent extraterrestrial beings have visited Earth. Several claimed forms of these visitations are listed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alien abduction:&lt;/strong&gt; The act of being kidnapped by aliens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ancient astronaut:&lt;/strong&gt; The theory that aliens influenced major historical events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Close encounter:&lt;/strong&gt; The observation of alien vessels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contactee:&lt;/strong&gt; A person who claims to have been contacted by aliens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to a disambiguation page for the term &amp;ldquo;Visitation,&amp;rdquo; indicating that the term has multiple meanings beyond the context of alien encounters. It also includes a disambiguation note that directs users to the correct article if they arrived at this page via an internal link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_visitation&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_visitation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
