<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abduction on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/abduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Abduction on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 19:23:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/abduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pascagoula Abduction</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_9dcf98b2107a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 19:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_9dcf98b2107a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;pascagoula-abduction&#34;&gt;Pascagoula Abduction &lt;a href=&#34;#pascagoula-abduction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pascagoula Abduction refers to an alleged UFO sighting and alien abduction that occurred in 1973. Charles Hickson and Calvin Parker claimed to have been abducted and examined by extraterrestrial beings while fishing near the Pascagoula River in Mississippi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alleged-abduction&#34;&gt;Alleged abduction &lt;a href=&#34;#alleged-abduction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the evening of October 11, 1973, Charles Hickson and Calvin Parker reported to the Jackson County, Mississippi, sheriff&amp;rsquo;s office that they experienced an unusual event while fishing on a pier along the Pascagoula River. They described hearing a strange whirring sound and seeing flashing blue lights, followed by the appearance of an oval-shaped object. Hickson and Parker claimed they were paralyzed and then taken aboard the object by three creatures with robotic features and crab-like pincers, where they underwent an examination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publicity-and-later-activities&#34;&gt;Publicity and later activities &lt;a href=&#34;#publicity-and-later-activities&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the incident, Charles Hickson engaged in interviews, lectures, and television appearances, including an episode of &lt;em&gt;To Tell The Truth&lt;/em&gt;. He also claimed additional encounters with aliens and authored a book titled &lt;em&gt;UFO Contact at Pascagoula&lt;/em&gt;. Calvin Parker attended UFO conventions and started a company called &amp;ldquo;UFO Investigations.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles Hickson died in September 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, Calvin Parker released his own book, &lt;em&gt;Pascagoula: The Closest Encounter, My Story&lt;/em&gt;, providing his full account of the event and its impact on his life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June 2019, a historical marker was unveiled at the site of the alleged abduction. Calvin Parker, along with Hickson&amp;rsquo;s son and family, attended the unveiling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calvin Parker died in August 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;skepticism&#34;&gt;Skepticism &lt;a href=&#34;#skepticism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aviation journalist and UFO skeptic Philip J. Klass found discrepancies in Hickson&amp;rsquo;s story and noted his refusal to take a polygraph exam. Klass concluded that the case was a hoax. Skeptical investigator Joe Nickell questioned Hickson&amp;rsquo;s behavior and suggested that the alien encounter may have been a hypnagogic &amp;ldquo;waking dream state.&amp;rdquo; Nickell also suggested that Parker&amp;rsquo;s corroboration was due to suggestibility, as he initially claimed to have passed out during the incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the &amp;ldquo;List of UFO sightings&amp;rdquo; for further reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited within the article, including news articles, books, and websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external websites related to the Pascagoula Abduction, including information about Calvin Parker&amp;rsquo;s book, a transcript of an interview with Hickson and Parker, and an article by Joe Nickell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pascagoula_Abduction&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pascagoula_Abduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
