<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ancient Astronaut Theory on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ancient-astronaut-theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ancient Astronaut Theory on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 08:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ancient-astronaut-theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ancient astronauts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_96b21753a786/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 08:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_96b21753a786/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ancient-astronauts&#34;&gt;Ancient Astronauts &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-astronauts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ancient astronauts, also known as ancient aliens, is a pseudoscientific belief that intelligent extraterrestrial beings visited Earth in ancient times and influenced the development of human civilization. Proponents suggest that these aliens affected modern cultures, technologies, religions, and human biology. A common idea is that deities from religions are extraterrestrial in origin, with advanced technologies interpreted as divine status by early humans. Academics and archaeologists dismiss these claims as pseudoarchaeological and unscientific, lacking credible peer-reviewed studies. Evidence presented is often distorted or fabricated. Some argue that ancient astronaut theories have racist undertones, diminishing the accomplishments of indigenous cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Various terms reference claims about ancient astronauts, including ancient aliens, ancient ufonauts, ancient space pilots, paleocontact, astronaut- or alien gods, and paleo- or biblical-SETI. Believers maintain that humans are descendants or creations of extraterrestrial intelligence that landed on Earth in the past. Human knowledge, religion, and culture came from extraterrestrial visitors, acting as a &amp;ldquo;mother culture.&amp;rdquo; Proponents claim that structures like Egyptian pyramids and the Moai stone heads of Easter Island were built by space travelers or with their aid. Evidence comes from documentary gaps in historical and archaeological records, citing anachronistic artifacts beyond the technical capabilities of ancient people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The History Channel series &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt; promotes these ideas, mixing fact with fiction to spread theories of an alternate past with white supremacist, nativist, imperialist, settler-colonial, and Christian Identity beliefs. Proponents focus on monumental archaeological structures, implying that non-white indigenous people could not have built them on their own. However, some indigenous peoples believe the denial of extraterrestrial encounters is part of &amp;ldquo;Indigenous erasure,&amp;rdquo; as many trace their ancestry to &amp;ldquo;star-people.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common feature in the stories portrays the aliens as light-skinned or Aryan in complexion, as Erich von Däniken claims in &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; Some ancient astronaut proponents are associated with white supremacism. Mainstream archaeologists largely ignored these claims until recently, with dedicated popular science explainers and skeptics universally panning them. Carl Sagan noted that cases of interest have reasonable alternative explanations or are misreported, hoaxes, and distortions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34;&gt;History of Ancient Aliens Beliefs and Their Proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paleocontact or &amp;ldquo;ancient astronaut&amp;rdquo; narratives first appeared in early science fiction, including &lt;em&gt;Edison&amp;rsquo;s Conquest of Mars&lt;/em&gt; (1898) and the works of H.P. Lovecraft. Harold T. Wilkins proposed the idea in earnest in 1954. It grew in popularity in the 1960s due to the Space Race and Erich von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s works, though it received limited consideration as a serious hypothesis. Critics emerged throughout the 1970s, discrediting Von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s claims. Ufologists separated the idea from the UFO controversy. By the early 1980s, little support remained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;shklovskii-and-sagan&#34;&gt;Shklovskii and Sagan &lt;a href=&#34;#shklovskii-and-sagan&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Carl Sagan co-authored &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Life in the Universe&lt;/em&gt; with Soviet astrophysicist Iosif Shklovsky in 1966. In &lt;em&gt;Broca&amp;rsquo;s Brain&lt;/em&gt; (1979), Sagan suggested that he and Shklovsky might have inspired the wave of 1970s ancient astronaut books, disapproving of &amp;ldquo;von Däniken and other uncritical writers&amp;rdquo; who built on these ideas as &amp;ldquo;valid evidence of extraterrestrial contact.&amp;rdquo; Sagan pointed out that while many legends, artifacts, and purported out-of-place artifacts were cited, they could be easily explained with more conventional hypotheses. He reiterated that extraterrestrial visits to Earth were possible but unproven and improbable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;erich-von-däniken&#34;&gt;Erich von Däniken &lt;a href=&#34;#erich-von-d%c3%a4niken&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Erich von Däniken was a leading proponent in the late 1960s and early 1970s, gaining a large audience through &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; (1968) and its sequels. According to von Däniken, certain artifacts require more sophisticated technology than was available to ancient cultures. These artifacts were constructed either directly by extraterrestrial visitors or by humans who learned from them. Examples include Stonehenge, Pumapunku, the Moai of Easter Island, the Great Pyramid of Giza, and the ancient Baghdad electric batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Von Däniken writes that ancient art and iconography illustrate air and space vehicles, non-human but intelligent creatures, ancient astronauts, and artifacts of advanced technology. He states that geographically separated cultures share artistic themes, implying a common origin. One example is his interpretation of the sarcophagus lid from the tomb of Pacal the Great in Palenque, which he sees as a seated astronaut, while Maya text identifies it as a portrait of the ruler with the World Tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Von Däniken interprets the origins of many religions as reactions to encounters with an alien race, considering their technology supernatural and the aliens themselves as gods. He states that religious traditions contain references to alien visitors, such as Ezekiel&amp;rsquo;s revelation, which he interprets as a landing spacecraft (&lt;em&gt;The Spaceships of Ezekiel&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His hypotheses became popularized in the U.S. after the NBC-TV documentary &lt;em&gt;In Search of Ancient Astronauts&lt;/em&gt; and the film &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods&lt;/em&gt;. Critics argue that von Däniken misrepresented data, that many of his claims were unfounded, and that none of his core claims have been validated. The Christian creationist community is highly critical, with Clifford A. Wilson publishing &lt;em&gt;Crash Go the Chariots&lt;/em&gt; (1972) to discredit his claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the Nazca Lines, von Däniken states that &amp;ldquo;Seen from the air, the clear-cut impression that the 60 km [37-mile] long plain of Nazca made on me was that of an airfield.&amp;rdquo; He exhibits confirmation bias, not considering the Nazca Lines to be man-made until after the publication of &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; Kenneth L. Feder argues that readers seeing the Nazca Lines in a book about aliens would be more likely to associate them with extraterrestrial origins. In 1970, von Däniken admitted that the Nazca markings &amp;ldquo;could have been laid out on their gigantic scale by working from a model using a system of coordinates.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;zecharia-sitchin&#34;&gt;Zecharia Sitchin &lt;a href=&#34;#zecharia-sitchin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zecharia Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s series &lt;em&gt;The Earth Chronicles&lt;/em&gt;, beginning with &lt;em&gt;The 12th Planet&lt;/em&gt;, revolves around his interpretation of ancient Sumerian and Middle Eastern texts, megalithic sites, and artifacts. He hypothesizes that the gods of old Mesopotamia were astronauts from the planet &amp;ldquo;Nibiru,&amp;rdquo; which Sitchin states the Sumerians believed to be a remote &amp;ldquo;12th planet&amp;rdquo; associated with the god Marduk. According to Sitchin, Nibiru continues to orbit the Sun on a 3,600-year elongated orbit. Modern astronomy has found no evidence to support Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitchin argues that Sumerian texts tell the story that 50 Anunnaki, inhabitants of Nibiru, came to Earth approximately 400,000 years ago to mine raw materials, especially gold. They genetically engineered laborers to work the mines, creating &lt;em&gt;Homo sapiens sapiens&lt;/em&gt;: the &amp;ldquo;Adapa&amp;rdquo; (model man) or Adam of later mythology. Sitchin contended the Anunnaki were active in human affairs until their culture was destroyed by global catastrophes caused by the abrupt end of the last ice age some 12,000 years ago. The Anunnaki left Earth after giving humans the opportunity and means to govern themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s work has not received mainstream scholarly support and has been criticized by professionals. Semitic languages scholar Michael S. Heiser says that many of Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s translations of Sumerian and Mesopotamian words are not consistent with Mesopotamian cuneiform bilingual dictionaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alan F. Alford, author of &lt;em&gt;Gods of the New Millennium&lt;/em&gt; (1996), was an adherent of the ancient astronaut hypothesis, drawing on Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s hypotheses. However, he now finds fault with Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s hypothesis, stating that: &amp;ldquo;I am now firmly of the opinion that these gods personified the falling sky; in other words, the descent of the gods was a poetic rendition of the cataclysm myth which stood at the heart of ancient Near Eastern religions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;robert-temple&#34;&gt;Robert Temple &lt;a href=&#34;#robert-temple&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Robert K. G. Temple&amp;rsquo;s 1976 book, &lt;em&gt;The Sirius Mystery,&lt;/em&gt; argues that the Dogon people of northwestern Mali preserved an account of extraterrestrial visitation from around 5,000 years ago. He quotes various lines of evidence, including advanced astronomical knowledge inherited by the tribe, descriptions, and comparative belief systems with ancient civilizations such as ancient Egypt and Sumer. His work draws heavily on the studies of cultural anthropologists Marcel Griaule and Germaine Dieterlen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His conclusions have been criticized by scientists, who point out discrepancies within Temple&amp;rsquo;s account and suggested that the Dogon may have received some of their astronomical information recently, probably from European sources, and may have misrepresented Dogon ethnography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ufo-religions&#34;&gt;UFO Religions &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-religions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Various new religious movements including some branches of Theosophy, Scientology, Raëlism, Aetherius Society, and Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate believe in ancient and present-day contact with extraterrestrial intelligence. Many of these faiths see both ancient scriptures and recent revelations as connected with the action of aliens from other planetary systems. Psychologists have found that UFO religions have similarities which suggest that members of these groups consciously or subliminally associate enchantment with the memes of science fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;claims-of-proponents&#34;&gt;Claims of Proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#claims-of-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among scientists, the consensus is that the ancient astronaut&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
