<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visual Artifacts on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/visual-artifacts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visual Artifacts on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 15:55:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/visual-artifacts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>List of alleged extraterrestrial beings</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a196d122f6c1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 15:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a196d122f6c1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-extraterrestrial-beings&#34;&gt;List of Alleged Extraterrestrial Beings &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-extraterrestrial-beings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Wikipedia entry provides a compilation of extraterrestrial beings that have been reported in alleged close encounters, claimed sightings, or speculated to be associated with unidentified flying objects (UFOs). It clarifies that the term &amp;ldquo;extraterrestrial being&amp;rdquo; in this context differs from the biological definition of &amp;ldquo;alien species&amp;rdquo; in ecology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;list&#34;&gt;List &lt;a href=&#34;#list&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents a table listing various alleged extraterrestrial beings along with brief descriptions. Key entities include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flatwoods monster:&lt;/strong&gt; A tall humanoid with a spade-shaped head.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Greys:&lt;/strong&gt; Grey-skinned humanoids, typically around 1 meter tall, hairless, with large heads, black almond-shaped eyes, and minimal facial features. The Roswell incident is associated with this type.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hopkinsville goblin:&lt;/strong&gt; Small, greenish-silver humanoids, linked to the Kelly–Hopkinsville encounter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Little green men:&lt;/strong&gt; Diminutive green humanoids, included for cultural reference despite a lack of consistent reports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nordic aliens:&lt;/strong&gt; Humanoids with stereotypical &amp;ldquo;Nordic&amp;rdquo; features (tall, blonde hair, blue eyes), sometimes called Space Brothers. Subgroups include Plejaren (previously Pleiadeans), Venusians, Tall Whites, and Agarthans from Agartha.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cryptozoological animals and cryptobotanical plants:&lt;/strong&gt; Creatures from folklore, religion, and mythology, such as Mothman, Jersey Devil, Loch Ness Monster, Nommo, Mokele-mbembe, Yokai, Quinametzin, Rephaite, and Loveland Frogman. These are sometimes linked to extraterrestrial or mixed origins through hypotheses like the extraterrestrial, interdimensional, or cryptoterrestrial hypotheses. Charles Fort, Fortean Times, and William R. Corliss are mentioned in relation to anomalous phenomena.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reptilians and reptiloids:&lt;/strong&gt; Tall, scaly humanoids, sometimes associated with ancient astronauts. Draconians and Orion reptilian-humanoids are mentioned. David Icke is noted for advocating the reptilian conspiracy theory. Fictional portrayals are referenced, including &lt;em&gt;They Live&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;V&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Stargate&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Worldwar&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Gamehendge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rods or skyfish:&lt;/strong&gt; Elongated visual artifacts appearing in photos and videos, often claimed to be extraterrestrial beings but generally attributed to motion blur from flying insects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics and concepts, categorized as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General concepts:&lt;/strong&gt; Alien abduction, Alien abduction entities, Alleged extraterrestrial beings, Ancient astronauts, Chimera, Conspiracy theory, Contactees, Cryptoterrestrial hypothesis, Evolutionary biology, Extraterrestrial hypothesis, Genetic mutation, Horizontal evolution, Interdimensional hypothesis, List of conspiracy theories, List of cryptids, List of humanoid aliens, List of occult terms, MUFON (United States), Kosmopoisk (Russia), New World Order.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In fiction:&lt;/strong&gt; Fictional biology, Lists of fictional alien species, List of fictional extraterrestrials, Lists of fictional species, Science fiction, &lt;em&gt;Babylon 5&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Battlestar Galactica&lt;/em&gt;, List of alien races in DC Comics, List of alien races in Marvel Comics, &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Stargate&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Twilight Zone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited within the article, providing links to the original materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a link to &lt;em&gt;Abducted: How People Come to Believe They Were Kidnapped by Aliens&lt;/em&gt; (2005) by Susan A. Clancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_alleged_extraterrestrial_beings&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_alleged_extraterrestrial_beings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
