<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mantell on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/mantell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mantell on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 10:25:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/mantell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mantell UFO incident</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a1f1da726206/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 10:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a1f1da726206/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;mantell-ufo-incident&#34;&gt;Mantell UFO Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#mantell-ufo-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mantell UFO incident occurred on January 7, 1948, when Kentucky Air National Guard pilot Captain Thomas F. Mantell died in a crash near Franklin, Kentucky, while pursuing an unidentified flying object (UFO). The incident gained significant publicity and became one of the most well-known early UFO reports. Later investigations suggested Mantell was likely chasing a Skyhook balloon, a top-secret project at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;incident&#34;&gt;Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 7, 1948, Godman Army Airfield at Fort Knox, Kentucky, received reports of an unusual aerial object. Captain Thomas F. Mantell and three other pilots were instructed to investigate. Mantell climbed to 22,000 feet in pursuit of the object, but his wingmen couldn&amp;rsquo;t follow due to a lack of oxygen equipment. Mantell&amp;rsquo;s aircraft also lacked the necessary oxygen equipment, and it&amp;rsquo;s believed he lost consciousness due to hypoxia at high altitude, causing his plane to crash south of Franklin, Kentucky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;press-coverage-and-rumors&#34;&gt;Press Coverage and Rumors &lt;a href=&#34;#press-coverage-and-rumors&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mantell incident received widespread press coverage and generated numerous sensational rumors. These rumors included claims of a Soviet missile, an alien spacecraft shooting down Mantell&amp;rsquo;s plane, Mantell&amp;rsquo;s body being riddled with bullets or missing, the plane disintegrating in the air, and radioactive wreckage. However, no evidence ever substantiated these claims, and the Air Force rejected some of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;explanations&#34;&gt;Explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initial explanations suggested Mantell mistook Venus for a UFO, but this was later retracted. Project Blue Book eventually concluded that Mantell was pursuing a Skyhook balloon, a top-secret project at the time. These balloons could reach altitudes of 100,000 feet. It&amp;rsquo;s believed Mantell lost consciousness due to lack of oxygen while pursuing the balloon. An astronomer at Vanderbilt University also reported seeing a pear-shaped balloon with cables and a basket attached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thomas-mantell-biography&#34;&gt;Thomas Mantell Biography &lt;a href=&#34;#thomas-mantell-biography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain Thomas Francis Mantell Jr. (1922-1948) was a United States Air Force officer and World War II veteran. He received the Distinguished Flying Cross for his actions during D-Day and an Air Medal with three oak leaf clusters. He joined the Kentucky Air National Guard after the war. A historical marker honoring Mantell was unveiled in Franklin, Kentucky, in 2001.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;career&#34;&gt;Career &lt;a href=&#34;#career&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mantell graduated from Male High School in Louisville and joined the United States Army Air Corps in 1942. During World War II, he was a C-47 Skytrain pilot assigned to the 440th Troop Carrier Group and participated in the Normandy airdrop. He was awarded the Distinguished Flying Cross for his heroism. After the war, he joined the Kentucky Air National Guard as an F-51D Mustang pilot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;awards&#34;&gt;Awards &lt;a href=&#34;#awards&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mantell&amp;rsquo;s awards include the Pilot Badge, Distinguished Flying Cross, Air Medal with three oak leaf clusters, Distinguished Unit Citation, American Campaign Medal, European–African–Middle Eastern Campaign Medal with two campaign stars, and World War II Victory Medal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;See also&amp;rdquo; section provides links to related articles, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of reported UFO sightings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of unusual deaths in the 20th century&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project Mogul&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mantell_UFO_incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mantell_UFO_incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
