<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Extraterrestrial Folklore and Mythology on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/extraterrestrial-folklore-and-mythology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Extraterrestrial Folklore and Mythology on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 15:55:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/extraterrestrial-folklore-and-mythology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>List of alleged extraterrestrial beings</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a196d122f6c1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 15:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a196d122f6c1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-extraterrestrial-beings&#34;&gt;List of Alleged Extraterrestrial Beings &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-extraterrestrial-beings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Wikipedia entry catalogues various extraterrestrial beings reported in close encounters, claimed sightings, or speculated to be associated with unidentified flying objects (UFOs). It clarifies that the term &amp;ldquo;extraterrestrial being&amp;rdquo; in this context differs from the biological definition of &amp;ldquo;alien species&amp;rdquo; in ecology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;list&#34;&gt;List &lt;a href=&#34;#list&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section presents a table outlining alleged extraterrestrial beings, providing their names, descriptions, and associated events or concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flatwoods Monster:&lt;/strong&gt; A tall humanoid with a spade-shaped head, linked to the Flatwoods Monster incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Greys:&lt;/strong&gt; Grey-skinned humanoids, typically around 1 meter tall, hairless, with large heads and black almond-shaped eyes. They are associated with the Roswell incident and are the most common type of extraterrestrial being reported since the 1960s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hopkinsville Goblin:&lt;/strong&gt; Small, greenish-silver humanoids, connected to the Kelly–Hopkinsville encounter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Little Green Men:&lt;/strong&gt; Diminutive green humanoids, a classic cultural stereotype, though actual abduction reports rarely match this description.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nordic Aliens:&lt;/strong&gt; Humanoids with stereotypical &amp;ldquo;Nordic&amp;rdquo; features (tall, blonde hair, blue eyes). They are sometimes called Space Brothers and include groups like the Plejaren (previously known as Pleiadeans), Venusians, Tall Whites, and Agarthans from Agartha.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cryptozoological Animals and Cryptobotanical Plants:&lt;/strong&gt; Creatures from folklore, religion, and mythology (e.g., golems, dwarves, giants from Atlantis), as well as reports of ghosts, poltergeists, and time travelers. Examples include the Mothman, Jersey Devil, Loch Ness Monster, Nommo, Mokele-mbembe, Yokai, Quinametzin, Rephaite, and Loveland Frogman. Some believe these creatures are of extraterrestrial or mixed origin, as suggested by the extraterrestrial, interdimensional, or cryptoterrestrial hypotheses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reptilians and Reptiloids:&lt;/strong&gt; Tall, scaly humanoids, sometimes linked to ancient astronauts. They include Draconians and Orion reptilian-humanoid matriarchies. David Icke is a prominent advocate of the reptilian conspiracy theory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rods or Skyfish:&lt;/strong&gt; Elongated visual artifacts in photos and videos, sometimes claimed to be extraterrestrial beings, but generally believed to be motion blur from flying insects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics and concepts, categorized as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt; Alien abduction, alien abduction entities, alleged extraterrestrial beings, ancient astronauts, chimera, conspiracy theory, contactees, cryptoterrestrial hypothesis, evolutionary biology, extraterrestrial hypothesis, genetic mutation, horizontal evolution, interdimensional hypothesis, list of conspiracy theories, list of cryptids, list of humanoid aliens, list of occult terms, MUFON (United States), Kosmopoisk (Russia), and New World Order.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Fiction:&lt;/strong&gt; Fictional biology, lists of fictional alien species, list of fictional extraterrestrials, lists of fictional species, &lt;em&gt;Babylon 5&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Battlestar Galactica&lt;/em&gt;, List of alien races in DC Comics, List of alien races in Marvel Comics, &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Stargate&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Twilight Zone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, providing links to the original materials. These references support the information presented about each alleged extraterrestrial being and related concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section contains links to external resources, such as Susan A. Clancy&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;em&gt;Abducted: How People Come to Believe They Were Kidnapped by Aliens&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_alleged_extraterrestrial_beings&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_alleged_extraterrestrial_beings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
