<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>United Kingdom on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/united-kingdom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in United Kingdom on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 18:28:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/united-kingdom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in the United Kingdom</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_46b42ba56548/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 18:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_46b42ba56548/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-the-united-kingdom&#34;&gt;List of Alleged UFO Sightings in the United Kingdom &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-the-united-kingdom&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article documents notable alleged sightings of unidentified flying objects (UFOs) in the United Kingdom. It notes the increased awareness of such sightings due to the release of the Ministry of Defence&amp;rsquo;s UFO sighting reports by the National Archives between 2008 and 2013. It also mentions that many recent sightings of slow-moving lights are often explained as Chinese lanterns. Project Condign, undertaken between 1997 and 2000, concluded that all investigated UK sightings of unidentified aerial phenomena could be attributed to misidentified objects or poorly understood natural phenomena. London is noted as the city with the most UFO sightings in the UK, followed by Manchester and Birmingham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;12th-century&#34;&gt;12th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#12th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a single entry:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1113:&lt;/strong&gt; Religious pilgrims in South West England reported seeing a glowing, fire-belching &amp;ldquo;dragon&amp;rdquo; emerge from the sea, fly into the air, and disappear into the sky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;13th-century&#34;&gt;13th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#13th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists two alleged sightings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 1254:&lt;/strong&gt; In St. Albans, a scribe recorded a sighting of a large, elegantly shaped ship of marvelous color in the sky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1290:&lt;/strong&gt; Friars of Byland Abbey described a &amp;ldquo;flat, round shining silvery object&amp;rdquo; flying overhead. However, it&amp;rsquo;s noted that this report is considered a hoax perpetrated by teenagers in the 1950s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;20th-century&#34;&gt;20th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#20th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers alleged UFO sightings throughout the 20th century, broken down by decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1900s&#34;&gt;1900s &lt;a href=&#34;#1900s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1909:&lt;/strong&gt; Sightings of a &amp;ldquo;mystery airship&amp;rdquo; over Ipswich, Cardiff, and Dublin. Referred to as a &amp;ldquo;scareship&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;phantom airship,&amp;rdquo; it had two visible lights and moved at a rapid rate. Mr. Chatten, a grocer&amp;rsquo;s assistant, saw a similar craft over Tharston in Norfolk. The Willows airships are mentioned as the first British airships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1910s&#34;&gt;1910s &lt;a href=&#34;#1910s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Late 1912:&lt;/strong&gt; The &amp;ldquo;scareships&amp;rdquo; returned. A sighting occurred over Kent on 14 October 1912. Conservative MP William Joynson-Hicks questioned Winston Churchill in parliament about Britain&amp;rsquo;s airship capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1940s&#34;&gt;1940s &lt;a href=&#34;#1940s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 1942:&lt;/strong&gt; Eileen Arnold in Cheltenham experienced an altered state and saw a large oval shape radiating light.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 1942:&lt;/strong&gt; Albert Lancaster, a guard at a radar site near Newbiggin-by-the-Sea, Northumberland, claimed to have been abducted by aliens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5 August 1944:&lt;/strong&gt; Winston Churchill allegedly banned the reporting of a UFO incident involving a Royal Air Force reconnaissance plane intercepted by a metallic object. The plane&amp;rsquo;s crew supposedly photographed the object.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1950s&#34;&gt;1950s &lt;a href=&#34;#1950s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 June 1950:&lt;/strong&gt; A Gloster Meteor at RAF Tangmere encountered a &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; lit up with lights over Portsmouth. This led to the establishment of the Flying Saucer Working Party.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14 August 1950:&lt;/strong&gt; F/Lt Hubbard, an experienced pilot, saw a 50 ft-diameter disc UFO over the Royal Aircraft Establishment (RAE).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26 August 1950:&lt;/strong&gt; A woman in Stanton Drew, Somerset, reported seeing a bright saucer-shaped object hovering over a field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14–25 September 1952:&lt;/strong&gt; Operation Mainbrace. A silver disc-shaped object followed a Gloster Meteor returning to RAF Topcliffe on 19 September. On 21 September, six RAF planes followed a spherical object over the North Sea. Flt Lt John Kilburn of 269 Squadron reported the incident. Roy Mason, later the Secretary of State for Defence, discussed it in parliament in 1959.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21 October 1952:&lt;/strong&gt; Two RAF pilots in a Gloster Meteor saw three disc-shaped objects at 35,000 ft in the Little Rissington UFO incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9 October 1953:&lt;/strong&gt; Two BEA pilots flying from London to Paris saw a saucer object over the English Channel. Captain Peter Fletcher and First Officer R L. Lemon were the pilots involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 November 1953:&lt;/strong&gt; Terry Johnson and Geoffrey Smythe in an RAF de Havilland Vampire saw a UFO over RAF West Malling. The sighting was discussed in parliament, with the Secretary of State for Air, Nigel Birch, attributing it to a weather balloon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;29 June 1954:&lt;/strong&gt; A BOAC pilot in a Boeing 377 Stratocruiser saw seven UFOs over the North Atlantic. Captain James Howard, air hostess Daphne Webster, and First Officer Lee Boyd were involved. The incident was later discussed on BBC programs and in the House of Lords.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14 October 1954:&lt;/strong&gt; F/Lt James Salandin of the Royal Auxiliary Air Force narrowly missed two UFOs over Southend-on-Sea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17 July 1955:&lt;/strong&gt; A 30-foot-wide saucer-shaped object was seen hovering over a street in Bexleyheath by Margaret Fry and her doctor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13 August 1956:&lt;/strong&gt; Lakenheath-Bentwaters incident – 12 to 15 objects were picked up by USAF radar over East Anglia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22 September 1956:&lt;/strong&gt; A large, spherical glass-like object was seen over the Cleethorpes coast and on radar from RAF Manby.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4 April 1957:&lt;/strong&gt; West Freugh incident – a large object was seen on radar at RAF West Freugh near Stranraer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;29 April 1957:&lt;/strong&gt; An unknown object was tracked by radar over the English Channel near Dover. Conservative MP Patrick Wall and Labour MP Frank Beswick discussed it in parliament.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20 May 1957:&lt;/strong&gt; Milton Torres 1957 UFO Encounter – a USAF F-86D Sabre based at RAF Manston intercepted an object over East Anglia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21 November 1957:&lt;/strong&gt; Silpho Moor UFO – a small saucer-shaped container was discovered containing copper pages with messages in glyphs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1960s&#34;&gt;1960s &lt;a href=&#34;#1960s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday 9 February 1962:&lt;/strong&gt; A Luton motor mechanic, Ron Wildman, saw an oval-shaped, glowing white object near Aston Clinton that disabled his car engine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday 21 May 1962:&lt;/strong&gt; Aer Lingus pilot Gordon Pendleton saw a moving object with no wings over Taunton in Somerset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From late spring to early summer 1965:&lt;/strong&gt; Many UFO sightings occurred in the Warminster area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;28 April 1967:&lt;/strong&gt; A dome-shaped object was sighted over Brixham in Devon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1967:&lt;/strong&gt; Clapham Wood in West Sussex experienced a rash of UFO sightings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 August 1967:&lt;/strong&gt; Policemen Lionel Haw and Steve Parsonage saw a large white object in Hindley.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 September 1967:&lt;/strong&gt; An object was seen over Stoke-on-Trent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24 October 1967:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;Devon Flying Cross UFO&amp;rdquo; – PCs Roger Willey and Clifford Waycott saw a bright cross-shaped object near Holsworthy. Christopher Garner also witnessed the object. The sighting was discussed in parliament by MPs Peter Mills and John Langford-Holt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25 October 1967:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;Sussex Flying Cross&amp;rdquo; – Policemen in East Sussex reported a bright flying cross. Wing Commander Eric Cox also saw a &amp;ldquo;fiery cross&amp;rdquo; in Hampshire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26 October 1967:&lt;/strong&gt; Angus Brooks saw a circular translucent craft near Holworth in Dorset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1970s&#34;&gt;1970s &lt;a href=&#34;#1970s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25 January 1971:&lt;/strong&gt; Pat Otter of the &lt;em&gt;Grimsby Evening Telegraph&lt;/em&gt; claimed that RAF aircraft were sent to investigate mysterious objects over the North Sea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1971:&lt;/strong&gt; Unidentified silent craft were allegedly seen by schoolchildren near Muchalls, Scotland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25 May 1971:&lt;/strong&gt; Eunice Rose saw a glowing object near Hinckley in Leicestershire that affected her car.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12 August 1971:&lt;/strong&gt; Olwyn Grainger and others saw a silent cylindrical object over a field near Wombourne. The British music group Henry Cow wrote a suite inspired by this event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16 October 1973:&lt;/strong&gt; Gabriella Versacci claimed to have been taken aboard an alien spaceship near Langford Budville in Somerset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23 January 1974:&lt;/strong&gt; A UFO allegedly crashed on the Berwyn Mountains in Wales.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4 February 1977:&lt;/strong&gt; A cigar-shaped craft allegedly landed next to Broad Haven Primary School, and children saw a silver creature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday 16 February 1977:&lt;/strong&gt; Nine girls and a teacher saw a mysterious object at Rhosybol in Anglesey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_the_United_Kingdom&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_the_United_Kingdom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
