<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ETH on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/eth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ETH on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 23:16:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/eth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial UFO hypothesis</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_526895167195/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 23:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_526895167195/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-ufo-hypothesis&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial UFO Hypothesis &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-ufo-hypothesis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the extraterrestrial hypothesis (ETH), which suggests that some unidentified flying objects (UFOs) are best explained as spacecraft or probes from intelligent extraterrestrial civilizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;usage-of-the-term&#34;&gt;Usage of the Term &lt;a href=&#34;#usage-of-the-term&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section traces the use of the term &amp;ldquo;extraterrestrial hypothesis&amp;rdquo; in UFO literature. It notes that the term gained traction in the latter half of the 1960s, with early usage attributed to French ufologist Jacques Vallée in his 1966 book. Other figures who used the term in the late 1960s include Aimé Michel, James E. McDonald, and James Harder. Physicist Edward Condon is credited with popularizing the term and its abbreviation &amp;ldquo;ETH&amp;rdquo; in 1969 when presenting the findings of the Condon Report. Skeptic Philip J. Klass also used the term in his 1968 book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chronology&#34;&gt;Chronology &lt;a href=&#34;#chronology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the historical context leading up to the modern ETH. It traces the origins of the idea of extraterrestrial life and visitation to earlier concepts, including Percival Lowell&amp;rsquo;s theories about Martian canals and ancient Martian civilizations, the science fiction writings of H. G. Wells and Edgar Rice Burroughs, and the works of Emanuel Swedenborg, who linked other worlds to the afterlife. It also mentions Charles Fort, who collected accounts of anomalous aerial phenomena in the early 20th century and theorized about visitors from other worlds. The modern ETH, linking unidentified aircraft to alien life, took root in the late 1940s and 1950s, influenced by pseudoscience and popular culture, and bolstered by unexplained sightings investigated by governments and civilian groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-reports-of-extraterrestrial-visits&#34;&gt;Historical Reports of Extraterrestrial Visits &lt;a href=&#34;#historical-reports-of-extraterrestrial-visits&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents examples of early speculation about extraterrestrial visitors. It mentions a French newspaper story from 1864 about the discovery of an alien-like creature inside an egg-shaped structure. It also discusses H. G. Wells&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;The War of the Worlds&amp;rdquo; (1898), which popularized the idea of Martian visitation and invasion. The section notes a surge in &amp;ldquo;mystery airship&amp;rdquo; reports in the late 19th century, with some speculating about Martian origins. It also mentions the influence of comic strips, radio shows, and movies like Buck Rogers and Flash Gordon in popularizing the idea of alien visitation in spaceships. Orson Welles&amp;rsquo; 1938 radio broadcast of &amp;ldquo;The War of the Worlds&amp;rdquo; caused some public panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-1947-flying-saucer-wave-in-america&#34;&gt;The 1947 Flying Saucer Wave in America &lt;a href=&#34;#the-1947-flying-saucer-wave-in-america&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the events surrounding the Kenneth Arnold sighting in 1947 and the subsequent &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; craze. It details Arnold&amp;rsquo;s initial report of seeing unidentified disk-shaped aircraft near Mount Rainier and his consideration of the possibility of extraterrestrial origins. The section notes the widespread speculation in newspapers about the nature of the &amp;ldquo;saucers,&amp;rdquo; including theories about secret military projects, Russian spy devices, hoaxes, optical illusions, and mass hysteria. It mentions Senator Glen Taylor&amp;rsquo;s comment about wishing the saucers were spaceships from another planet and R. DeWitt Miller&amp;rsquo;s suggestion that they could be vehicles from Mars or other dimensions. The section also cites journalist Edward R. Murrow&amp;rsquo;s observation that the ETH did not gain widespread attention until about 18 months after Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;evolution-of-public-opinion&#34;&gt;Evolution of Public Opinion &lt;a href=&#34;#evolution-of-public-opinion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines how public opinion regarding UFOs and the ETH evolved. It mentions the release of the first U.S. poll of public UFO perceptions by Gallup in August 1947, which showed that most people either had no opinion or believed there was a mundane explanation for the sightings. The section also discusses the influence of movies depicting flying saucers and aliens in the early 1950s. It cites a poll published in Popular Science magazine in 1951, which reported that most UFO witnesses believed they had seen a man-made aircraft. By 1957, 25% of Americans were willing to believe in the ETH. A Roper poll in 2002 reported that 56% of respondents thought UFOs were real, with 48% believing that UFOs had visited Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;religion&#34;&gt;Religion &lt;a href=&#34;#religion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section briefly mentions the connection between UFOs and religion, citing the Aetherius Society, founded by George King in 1955, as one of the first and most enduring UFO cults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nasa&#34;&gt;NASA &lt;a href=&#34;#nasa&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses NASA&amp;rsquo;s evolving stance on UAPs. In June 2021, NASA Administrator Bill Nelson directed NASA scientists to investigate Unidentified Aerial Phenomenon, exploring the possibility that UAP could represent extraterrestrial technology. NASA scientist Ravi Kopparapu advocates studying UAP with an agnostic approach, involving experts from various fields to collect data and deduce the identity of such UAP. In August 2021, Kopparapu presented a paper supporting ETH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;private-or-government-studies&#34;&gt;Private or Government Studies &lt;a href=&#34;#private-or-government-studies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents examples of private or government studies that have concluded in favor of the ETH or have had members who disagreed with official conclusions. It mentions a 1948 Top Secret USAF Europe document citing Swedish air intelligence&amp;rsquo;s conclusion that some UFOs had extraterrestrial origins. It also discusses the USAF Project Sign&amp;rsquo;s 1948 Top Secret Estimate of the Situation, which concluded that the ETH was the most likely explanation for the most perplexing unexplained cases. The section mentions a secret West German study from 1951 to 1954, headed by Hermann Oberth, which also concluded that UFOs were extraterrestrial. It also discusses the CIA&amp;rsquo;s internal scientific review of UFOs in the early 1950s, noting that some CIA scientists were seriously considering the ETH. The section mentions extraterrestrial &amp;ldquo;believers&amp;rdquo; within Project Blue Book, including Major Dewey Fournet and consultant J. Allen Hynek, who later became a staunch supporter of the ETH. It also cites statements from former CIA Director Roscoe H. Hillenkoetter, who urged Congressional action to reduce the dangers from secrecy about unidentified flying objects. The section mentions Greek physicist Paul Santorini&amp;rsquo;s claim that a 1947 Greek government investigation into the European Ghost rockets concluded that they were extraterrestrial. It also discusses the 1968 Condon Report, noting that many members of the study disagreed with Condon&amp;rsquo;s methods and biases. The section mentions the 1999 private French COMETA report, which concluded that the hypothesis of extraterrestrial visitors best accounted for the facts. It also discusses Jean-Jacques Velasco, the head of the official French UFO investigation SEPRA, who stated that 14% of the cases studied by SEPRA were &amp;lsquo;utterly inexplicable and extraterrestrial&amp;rsquo; in origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;critical-responses-and-positions-of-the-eth&#34;&gt;Critical Responses and Positions of the ETH &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-responses-and-positions-of-the-eth&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents critical responses to the ETH. It notes that there is no scientific proof to back up assertions of alien encounters. It states that despite ardent believers, no rigorous analysis has ever concluded that various UFO sightings are verifiable evidence for the ETH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;us-military-investigation-and-debunkery&#34;&gt;U.S. Military Investigation and Debunkery &lt;a href=&#34;#us-military-investigation-and-debunkery&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the U.S. military&amp;rsquo;s investigation of UFOs and its efforts to debunk the ETH. It mentions the formation of Project Sign in 1947, the first official U.S. military UFO study. It notes that Project Sign concluded without endorsing any unified explanation for all UFO reports, and the ETH was rejected by USAF Chief of Staff General Hoyt Vandenberg. The section also discusses the CIA&amp;rsquo;s Robertson Panel, which was organized in 1953 to review the Blue Book&amp;rsquo;s best evidence and recommend an official policy of public debunkery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;involvement-of-scientists&#34;&gt;Involvement of Scientists &lt;a href=&#34;#involvement-of-scientists&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines the scientific community&amp;rsquo;s response to the ETH. It notes that the scientific community has shown very little support for the ETH, largely accepting the explanation that UFO reports are the result of misinterpretations or hoaxes. It mentions Stephen Hawking&amp;rsquo;s skepticism about the ETH. The section cites Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s observation about the emotional nature of the idea of extraterrestrial visitation and the potential for self-deception. It also quotes Peter A. Sturrock&amp;rsquo;s statement about the narrow polarization of the UFO debate around the ETH. The section presents the results of a 1973 poll of American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics members, which found that about 10% believed that UFOs were vehicles from outer space. It also presents the results of a 1977 poll of American Astronomical Society members, which asked them to assign probabilities to eight possible explanations for UFOs. The section summarizes the primary scientific arguments against ETH, as outlined by J. Allen Hynek, including the failure of surveillance systems to detect UFOs, gravitational and atmospheric considerations, statistical considerations, the behavior of UFOs and their occupants, the isolation of the UFO phenomenon in time and space, the space unworthiness of UFOs, and the problem of astronomical distances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fewer-sightings-despite-camera-phone-technology&#34;&gt;Fewer Sightings Despite Camera Phone Technology &lt;a href=&#34;#fewer-sightings-despite-camera-phone-technology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the argument that the proliferation of smartphone camera technology has not led to a significant increase in recorded UFO sightings, calling into question the claimed phenomenology of UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nasa-1&#34;&gt;NASA &lt;a href=&#34;#nasa-1&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents NASA&amp;rsquo;s official standpoint on the ETH, which is that it lacks empirical evidence. It quotes David Morrison&amp;rsquo;s statements that no one has ever found a single artifact or any other convincing evidence for alien visits and that no claims of UFOs as being alien craft have any validity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cia&#34;&gt;CIA &lt;a href=&#34;#cia&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions the CIA&amp;rsquo;s organization of the January 1953 Robertson Panel of scientists to debunk the data collected by the Air Force&amp;rsquo;s Project Blue Book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;official-white&#34;&gt;Official White &lt;a href=&#34;#official-white&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_hypothesis&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
