<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spacecraft on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/spacecraft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spacecraft on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 21:51:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/spacecraft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spacecraft</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_c3ed943147b3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 21:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_c3ed943147b3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;spacecraft&#34;&gt;Spacecraft &lt;a href=&#34;#spacecraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spacecraft is a vehicle or machine designed to fly and operate in outer space. It serves various purposes, including communications, Earth observation, meteorology, navigation, space colonization, planetary exploration, and transporting humans and cargo. Spacecraft typically require a launch vehicle to reach space, except for single-stage-to-orbit vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The history of spacecraft begins with the German V-2 rocket, which reached an altitude of 189 km in June 1944 in Peenemünde, Germany. Sputnik 1, launched by the Soviet Union on October 4, 1957, was the first artificial satellite, marking the start of the Space Age. Sputnik 1&amp;rsquo;s launch initiated new political, military, technological, and scientific developments. It also helped identify the density of the upper atmospheric layer and provided data on radio-signal distribution in the ionosphere. While Sputnik 1 was the first spacecraft to orbit the Earth, other human-made objects had previously reached an altitude of 100 km, the Kármán line, which is the height required by the international organization Fédération Aéronautique Internationale to count as a spaceflight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crewed-and-uncrewed-spacecraft&#34;&gt;Crewed and Uncrewed Spacecraft &lt;a href=&#34;#crewed-and-uncrewed-spacecraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spacecraft are categorized into crewed and uncrewed vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;crewed-spacecraft&#34;&gt;Crewed Spacecraft &lt;a href=&#34;#crewed-spacecraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of 2016, only Russia, the United States, and China have flown crewed spacecraft. Vostok 1, carrying Soviet cosmonaut Yuri Gagarin in 1961, was the first crewed spacecraft to complete a full Earth orbit. The second crewed spacecraft was &lt;em&gt;Freedom 7&lt;/em&gt;, which performed a sub-orbital spaceflight in 1961 carrying American astronaut Alan Shepard. Other crewed spacecraft include the Soviet Voskhod and Soyuz, the American Gemini and Apollo spacecraft, the Skylab space station, the Space Shuttle, and the Chinese Shenzhou. The International Space Station (ISS), crewed since November 2000, is a joint venture between Russia, the United States, Canada, and other countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;uncrewed-spacecraft&#34;&gt;Uncrewed Spacecraft &lt;a href=&#34;#uncrewed-spacecraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncrewed spacecraft operate autonomously or telerobotically, often preferred for cost-effectiveness and lower risk. They are used for missions unsuitable for humans, such as exploring Venus or the outer planets. Robotic spacecraft used for scientific research are space probes, while those orbiting a planetary body are artificial satellites. Examples include the Hubble Space Telescope and cargo spacecraft like the Jules Verne Automated Transfer Vehicle (ATV).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other&#34;&gt;Other &lt;a href=&#34;#other&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some spacecraft, like the Buran spaceplane and SpaceX Dragon 2, can operate as both crewed and uncrewed vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;types-of-spacecraft&#34;&gt;Types of Spacecraft &lt;a href=&#34;#types-of-spacecraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spacecraft are designed for various specific purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;communications-satellite&#34;&gt;Communications Satellite &lt;a href=&#34;#communications-satellite&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communications satellites relay and amplify radio telecommunication signals between a source transmitter and a receiver on Earth. They are used for television, telephone, radio, internet, and military applications. Many are in geostationary orbit, while others form satellite constellations in low Earth orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cargo-spacecraft&#34;&gt;Cargo Spacecraft &lt;a href=&#34;#cargo-spacecraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cargo spacecraft are robotic vehicles designed to carry cargo, such as food, propellant, and other supplies, to support space station operations. Automated cargo spacecraft have serviced Salyut 6, Salyut 7, Mir, the International Space Station, and Tiangong space station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;space-probes&#34;&gt;Space Probes &lt;a href=&#34;#space-probes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space probes are robotic spacecraft sent to explore deep space or astronomical bodies other than Earth. They have visited every planet in the Solar System and Pluto. The Voyager probes, launched in 1977, took advantage of a rare alignment of Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, and Neptune to visit all four planets in one mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;voyager-program&#34;&gt;Voyager Program &lt;a href=&#34;#voyager-program&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Voyager probes, launched in 1977, took advantage of a rare planetary alignment to visit Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, and Neptune. Voyager 1 and Voyager 2 are now escaping the Solar System, providing valuable data from interstellar space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;space-telescopes&#34;&gt;Space Telescopes &lt;a href=&#34;#space-telescopes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space telescopes are telescopes in outer space used to observe astronomical objects, avoiding the filtering and distortion of electromagnetic radiation and light pollution. Examples include the Hubble Space Telescope and the James Webb Space Telescope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;landers&#34;&gt;Landers &lt;a href=&#34;#landers&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Landers are spacecraft that make a soft landing on the surface of an astronomical body other than Earth. They use various techniques, including fuel supply and aerobraking, to achieve a safe landing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;space-capsules&#34;&gt;Space Capsules &lt;a href=&#34;#space-capsules&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space capsules are spacecraft that can return from space at least once. They have a blunt shape and do not possess wings. The Vostok capsule, built by the Soviet Union, carried the first person in space, Yuri Gagarin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;spaceplanes&#34;&gt;Spaceplanes &lt;a href=&#34;#spaceplanes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spaceplanes are spacecraft built in the shape of airplanes. The North American X-15 was an early example, while the Space Shuttle orbiter was the first reusable orbital spaceplane. The Buran-class shuttle, launched by the USSR, was the first autonomous reusable spaceplane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;space-shuttle&#34;&gt;Space Shuttle &lt;a href=&#34;#space-shuttle&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Space Shuttle was a reusable Low Earth Orbital launch system consisting of two reusable Solid Rocket Boosters, a Space Shuttle Orbiter, and a throwaway Space Shuttle external tank. It flew 135 times from 1981 to 2011, supporting Mir, the Hubble Space Telescope, and the International Space Station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-1&#34;&gt;Other &lt;a href=&#34;#other-1&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some spacecraft do not fit neatly into the general categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;spacex-starship&#34;&gt;SpaceX Starship &lt;a href=&#34;#spacex-starship&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starship is a spacecraft and second stage under development by SpaceX, designed to transport crew and cargo to Earth orbit, the Moon, Mars, and beyond. It will also be capable of point-to-point transport on Earth and refueling other Starship vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;mission-extension-vehicle&#34;&gt;Mission Extension Vehicle &lt;a href=&#34;#mission-extension-vehicle&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mission Extension Vehicle is a robotic spacecraft designed to prolong the life of another spacecraft by docking to it and correcting its orientation or orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;subsystems&#34;&gt;Subsystems &lt;a href=&#34;#subsystems&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spacecraft&amp;rsquo;s astrionics system comprises various subsystems, including attitude determination and control, guidance, navigation and control, communications, command and data handling, power, thermal control, propulsion, and structures. Spacecraft intended for human spaceflight must also include a life support system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;spacecraft-records&#34;&gt;Spacecraft Records &lt;a href=&#34;#spacecraft-records&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spacecraft records include achievements such as speed and distance from the Sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fastest-spacecraft&#34;&gt;Fastest Spacecraft &lt;a href=&#34;#fastest-spacecraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parker Solar Probe (estimated 700,000 km/h at final perihelion)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helios I and II Solar Probes (252,792 km/h)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;furthest-spacecraft-from-the-sun&#34;&gt;Furthest Spacecraft from the Sun &lt;a href=&#34;#furthest-spacecraft-from-the-sun&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voyager 1 (156.13 AU as of April 2022)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pioneer 10 (122.48 AU as of December 2018)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voyager 2 (122.82 AU as of January 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pioneer 11 (101.17 AU as of December 2018)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spacecraft&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spacecraft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
