<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alien Empires on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/alien-empires/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alien Empires on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 09:47:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/alien-empires/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>List of alien races in Marvel Comics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_d6e5f3331d85/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 09:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_d6e5f3331d85/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alien-races-in-marvel-comics&#34;&gt;List of Alien Races in Marvel Comics &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alien-races-in-marvel-comics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document provides a comprehensive list of alien races that appear in Marvel Comics. It is organized alphabetically and includes both major and secondary races, along with their key characteristics and appearances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents &lt;a href=&#34;#contents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section simply lists the letters of the alphabet, serving as a quick index to find alien races by their starting letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section establishes that the Marvel Comics universe contains a vast number of extraterrestrial races, most of which are humanoid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;galactic-council&#34;&gt;Galactic Council &lt;a href=&#34;#galactic-council&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces the Galactic Council, an assembly of leaders from various alien empires. It was created to address universal matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;current-members&#34;&gt;Current members &lt;a href=&#34;#current-members&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lists the current members of the Galactic Council, including representatives from the Kree/Skrull Alliance (Kl&amp;rsquo;rt/Paibok), Shi&amp;rsquo;ar Empire (Oracle-2/Izzy Kane), Utopian Kree (Noh-Varr), Earth/Nova Corps (Richard Rider), Spartax (Empress Victoria/Peter Quill), Rigellians (Mentacle), Kymellians (Nymbis Sternhoof), Wakanda (Riitho), Galactic Rim Collective (Zoralis Gupa/Orbis Stellaris), Badoon Sisterhood (Lani Ko Ako), Chitauri Empire (Peacebringer), and Zn&amp;rsquo;rx Empire (Empress Kuga).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;former-members&#34;&gt;Former members &lt;a href=&#34;#former-members&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lists former members of the Galactic Council, including representatives from Asgard (Freyja), Brotherhood of the Badoon (Y-Gaaar), Kree Empire (Supreme Intelligence/Ronan the Accuser), Negative Zone (Annihilus), Axi-Tun (Alberik), Shi&amp;rsquo;ar Empire (Majestor/Lilandra), Badoon (Manat), Brood (Brood Queen), Inhuman Royal Family (Gorgon/Medusa/Crystal/Karnak), Ruul/Kree Empire (Kronaster Sintariis), Kree/Skrull Alliance (Captain Val-Lorr), Krylorians (Bartos), Kymellians (Fayrelyte Strongheart), Negative Zone (Blastaar), Planet X (Groot), Rigellians (Nelet Pa), Skrull Empire (Kreddik), Sneepers (Dibdeb), Stonians (Basaltar), Wobbow (Wibbow), Spartax (J&amp;rsquo;son), Zn&amp;rsquo;rx (Emperor Stote), and Chitauri (Peacemaker).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;in-other-media&#34;&gt;In other media &lt;a href=&#34;#in-other-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section notes the Galactic Council&amp;rsquo;s appearance in the &lt;em&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/em&gt; animated series, with members including J&amp;rsquo;son, Thor, Irani Rael, the Rigellian Grand Commissioner, and the Supreme Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;major-races&#34;&gt;Major races &lt;a href=&#34;#major-races&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces alien races that have had significant presence in Marvel Comics publications, including major crossovers and storylines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;badoon&#34;&gt;Badoon &lt;a href=&#34;#badoon&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Badoon are reptilian aliens known for strict gender segregation, resulting in the Brotherhood of Badoon (ruled by a &amp;ldquo;Brother Royal&amp;rdquo;) and the Sisterhood of Badoon (ruled by a Queen). They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;Silver Surfer&lt;/em&gt; #2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;beyonders&#34;&gt;Beyonders &lt;a href=&#34;#beyonders&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Beyonders are enigmatic, virtually omnipotent entities powerful enough to collect planets. They cannot leave their dimension and operate through agents. The Beyonder is the most notable member. They were first mentioned in &lt;em&gt;Marvel Two-in-One&lt;/em&gt; #63.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;brood&#34;&gt;Brood &lt;a href=&#34;#brood&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Brood are a race of insectoid, parasitic, extraterrestrial beings. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;The Uncanny X-Men&lt;/em&gt; #155.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;celestials&#34;&gt;Celestials &lt;a href=&#34;#celestials&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Celestials have existed since near the birth of the universe. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;The Eternals&lt;/em&gt; #1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chitauri&#34;&gt;Chitauri &lt;a href=&#34;#chitauri&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chitauri are aliens similar to the Skrulls in the Ultimate Marvel universe. They have since been established in the main Marvel Universe. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;The Ultimates&lt;/em&gt; #8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cotati&#34;&gt;Cotati &lt;a href=&#34;#cotati&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cotati are a race of highly intelligent, telepathic plants originating on Hala, the same planet as the Kree. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;The Avengers&lt;/em&gt; #133.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dire-wraiths&#34;&gt;Dire Wraiths &lt;a href=&#34;#dire-wraiths&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dire Wraiths are an evolutionary offshoot of the Skrulls from the Andromeda Galaxy. Like the Skrulls, they are shapeshifters. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;Rom the Spaceknight&lt;/em&gt; #1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kree&#34;&gt;Kree &lt;a href=&#34;#kree&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kree are a scientifically and technologically advanced militaristic alien race native to the planet Hala. They were the rivals of the Skrulls. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;Fantastic Four&lt;/em&gt; #65.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;phalanx&#34;&gt;Phalanx &lt;a href=&#34;#phalanx&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Phalanx are a cybernetic species that form a hive-mind. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;The Uncanny X-Men&lt;/em&gt; #305.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;shiar&#34;&gt;Shi&amp;rsquo;ar &lt;a href=&#34;#shiar&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shi&amp;rsquo;ar are alien humanoids of avian descent residing in the Shi&amp;rsquo;ar Empire. Their empire is a vast collection of alien species, cultures, and worlds. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;X-Men&lt;/em&gt; #97.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;skrulls&#34;&gt;Skrulls &lt;a href=&#34;#skrulls&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Skrulls are a race of shapeshifting aliens originating from the planet Skrullos. They were the rivals of the Kree. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;Fantastic Four&lt;/em&gt; #2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;symbiotes&#34;&gt;Symbiotes &lt;a href=&#34;#symbiotes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Symbiotes are amorphous extraterrestrial parasites that envelop their hosts like costumes, creating a symbiotic bond. They are also known as the Klyntar. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;Secret Wars&lt;/em&gt; #8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;watchers&#34;&gt;Watchers &lt;a href=&#34;#watchers&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Watchers are the first humanoid race created in the Marvel Universe. They observe and compile knowledge on all aspects of the universe but have vowed not to interfere. Uatu is the most known Watcher. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;Fantastic Four&lt;/em&gt; #13.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;secondary-races&#34;&gt;Secondary races &lt;a href=&#34;#secondary-races&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists a multitude of other extraterrestrial races that have appeared in Marvel Comics, though not as prominently as the major races.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a&#34;&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;#a&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists alien races starting with the letter &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;aaskvarii&#34;&gt;A&amp;rsquo;askvarii &lt;a href=&#34;#aaskvarii&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The A&amp;rsquo;askvarii are a green-skinned humanoid race with octopus traits from the oceanic planet O&amp;rsquo;erlanii. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;Black Goliath&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-chiltarians&#34;&gt;A-Chiltarians &lt;a href=&#34;#a-chiltarians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The A-Chiltarians are a purple-grey furred humanoid race with many eyes from the marshy planet A-Chiltar III. Kraglin is an A-Chiltarian. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;Tales to Astonish&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;aakon&#34;&gt;Aakon &lt;a href=&#34;#aakon&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Aakon are a yellow-skinned, dark-haired humanoid race and enemies of the Kree. They are allied with the Shadow Consortium. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;Captain Marvel&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;acanti&#34;&gt;Acanti &lt;a href=&#34;#acanti&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Acanti are a race of space creatures that resemble whales. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;The Uncanny X-Men&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;achernonians&#34;&gt;Achernonians &lt;a href=&#34;#achernonians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Achernonians are a purple-skinned humanoid race from the rocky planet Achernon. They are depicted as superstitious and have a dictatorial government. Some can become immaterial. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;Thor&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;aedians&#34;&gt;Aedians &lt;a href=&#34;#aedians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Aedians are thin humanoid bipeds with elongated craniums and no noses. They possess telepathic and empathic powers and can project their astral selves. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;Silver Surfer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;agullo&#34;&gt;Agullo &lt;a href=&#34;#agullo&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Agullo are an alien race that was diminished from over 60,000,000 to a few thousands after Thanos came to their planet Ahl-Agullo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;alpha-centaurians&#34;&gt;Alpha Centaurians &lt;a href=&#34;#alpha-centaurians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Alpha Centaurians are a humanoid race with grey scales adapted for underwater living from the planet Arima. They have a feudal government and are capable of near-lightspeed travel. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;Sub-Mariner&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;amebids&#34;&gt;Amebids &lt;a href=&#34;#amebids&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Amebids are a race of jellyfish-like aliens that come from the planet Sakaar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;annunaki&#34;&gt;Annunaki &lt;a href=&#34;#annunaki&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Annunaki are an alien race that helped Silver Surfer gather and protect some of Earth&amp;rsquo;s most extraordinary gifted children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;archeopians&#34;&gt;Archeopians &lt;a href=&#34;#archeopians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Archeopians are from the planet Archeopia. Most of the race was killed when the incubator cube of Galactus was opened and he consumed Archeopia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;arcturans&#34;&gt;Arcturans &lt;a href=&#34;#arcturans&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Arcturans are a pink-white skinned humanoid race from Arcturus IV. A significant portion of their population are mutants. Starhawk and Aleta are Arcturans. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;Fear&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;aris&#34;&gt;Aris &lt;a href=&#34;#aris&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Aris are an alien race that comes from the planet Ariston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;arthrosians&#34;&gt;Arthrosians &lt;a href=&#34;#arthrosians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Arthrosians are a race of insectoids that come from the planet Anthros in the Negative Zone. Annihilus is an Arthrosian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;aspirants&#34;&gt;Aspirants &lt;a href=&#34;#aspirants&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Aspirants are a race of celestial beings that were the result of the First Firmament&amp;rsquo;s loneliness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;astrans&#34;&gt;Astrans &lt;a href=&#34;#astrans&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Astrans are a yellow-skinned humanoid race with flat feet from the planet Astra. They can control metal and are mostly priests or artists. They first appeared in &lt;em&gt;The Incredible Hulk&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;astrans-in-other-media&#34;&gt;Astrans in other media &lt;a href=&#34;#astrans-in-other-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Astrans appear in &lt;em&gt;Agents of S.H.I.E.L.D.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;ataraxians&#34;&gt;Ataraxians &lt;a href=&#34;#ataraxians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ataraxians are a race of aliens from the planet Ataraxia in the Negative Zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;autocrons&#34;&gt;Autocrons &lt;a href=&#34;#autocrons&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Autocrons are a blue-black skinned humanoid race with iron-based bodies from the planet Cron. They possess superhuman strength and durability and have an imperialistic, militaristic culture ruled by a world-computer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_alien_races_in_Marvel_Comics&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_alien_races_in_Marvel_Comics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
