<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UAPs on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/uaps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UAPs on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 13:04:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/uaps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_9c34e91b7ea9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 13:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_9c34e91b7ea9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;national-defense-authorization-act-for-fiscal-year-2024&#34;&gt;National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024 &lt;a href=&#34;#national-defense-authorization-act-for-fiscal-year-2024&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024 (NDAA 2024) is a United States federal law that outlines the budget, expenditures, and policies of the U.S. Department of Defense (DOD) for fiscal year 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Defense Authorization Act is an annual bill proposed in the United States Congress that redefines the United States military budget for the following fiscal year. Each chamber of Congress introduced a version of the NDAA: H.R. 2670 in the House and S. 2226 in the Senate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The House passed their version on July 14, 2023 by a vote of 219–210. Led by Chuck Schumer and Mike Rounds, the Senate passed theirs on July 27, 2023 by a vote of 86–11. The Senate then replaced H.R. 2670 with the text of S. 2226 and passed it by unanimous consent, and indefinitely postponed S. 2226. The House disagreed to the Senate amendment and asked to hold conference on September 19, with the Senate insisting on its amendment and agreeing to conference on November 15. The subsequent conference report was filed on December 6 (H. Rept. 118-301). The bill was approved by the Senate and House and sent to President Joe Biden on December 14. Biden signed it into law on December 22. In his signing statement, Biden expressed reservations about provisions that restrict the executive branch&amp;rsquo;s discretion in Guantanamo detainee transfers and raised constitutional concerns regarding congressional oversight and foreign policy authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;provisions&#34;&gt;Provisions &lt;a href=&#34;#provisions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section requires updating to reflect recent events or newly available information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;unidentified-flying-objects-ufos&#34;&gt;Unidentified flying objects (UFOs) &lt;a href=&#34;#unidentified-flying-objects-ufos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sections 1841 et seq. outline the creation and management of a comprehensive collection of government records on UFOs or unidentified anomalous phenomena (UAP) at the National Archives (NARA), detailing the processes for assembling, preserving, and providing public access to these records, along with specific protocols for their review, disclosure, and secure handling. NARA subsequently provided guidance to federal agencies to identify, organize, and disclose UAP records for the new collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sections 1687 and 7343 disallow use of funds or independent research and development (IRAD) indirect expenses for UFOs or UAP unless such material and information is made available the appropriate congressional committees and congressional leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Language on the topic of UFO/UAP was also included in the previous 2023 NDAA, the 2022 NDAA, the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022, as well as an accompanying Senate Select Committee on Intelligence report for the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;foreign-extortion-prevention-act&#34;&gt;Foreign Extortion Prevention Act &lt;a href=&#34;#foreign-extortion-prevention-act&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Foreign Extortion Prevention Act (FEPA) enables US authorities to prosecute foreign officials who demand or accept bribes from a US citizen, US company, or within a US jurisdiction. FEPA addresses a longstanding gap in US anti-bribery legislation by tackling the &amp;ldquo;demand&amp;rdquo; side of bribery. At the same time, the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act (FCPA) focuses on the &amp;ldquo;supply&amp;rdquo; side of bribery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;counter-extremist-working-group-defunded&#34;&gt;Counter-extremist working group defunded &lt;a href=&#34;#counter-extremist-working-group-defunded&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Republicans opposed the anti-extremism working group created by Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin. That working group had been created by Austin after it became apparent that some service members and veterans had participated in the attack on the US Capitol January 6, 2021. That working group released recommendations at the end of 2021. Implementation, however, appeared to stall as Republicans increasingly opposed diversity, equity, and inclusion efforts in the military, which Republicans derided as &amp;ldquo;wokeness&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, a recent inspector general report found dozens of troops, who appeared to be advocating violent overthrow of the US government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The seriousness of this issue seems apparent from the fact that military and veterans have participated in other violent extremist events. For example, the Oklahoma City bomber, Timothy McVeigh, had served with distinction in Operation Desert Storm but had earned a reputation as a sergeant for assigning undesirable work to black servicemen and using derogatory language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nato-withdrawal&#34;&gt;NATO withdrawal &lt;a href=&#34;#nato-withdrawal&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Section 1250A prevents the President from withdrawing the United States from NATO without the approval of a two-thirds Senate supermajority or an act of Congress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;original-proposals&#34;&gt;Original proposals &lt;a href=&#34;#original-proposals&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original House bill contained provisions to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Space Force Personnel Management Act: Disestablish the regular Space Force in order to integrate both active duty and reserve personnel into one Space Force entity. This is to allow for better flexibility for the Space Force by replacing &amp;ldquo;active duty&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;sustained duty&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;full-time&amp;rdquo; status, and replacing &amp;ldquo;reserve&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;part-time&amp;rdquo; status. This change would only pertain to the Space Force and not to the other armed services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elevate the position of vice chief of the National Guard Bureau to hold a statutory rank of general.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Permanently establish the titles of commissioned officer ranks of the Space Force to be the same as the Army, Marine Corps, and Air Force.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authorize a $886 billion spending budget for national defense programs including:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A 5.2% pay increase for service members of the armed forces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Procurement of up to 13 &lt;em&gt;Virginia&lt;/em&gt;-class submarines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authorize the sale and transfer of defense articles and services relating to the implementation of the AUKUS partnership, including:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Up to three &lt;em&gt;Virginia&lt;/em&gt;-class submarines, one year after this act is passed, however the Navy doesn&amp;rsquo;t intend implement this until 2032.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Senate amendment contained:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UAP Disclosure Act: The Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena Disclosure Act of 2023 would direct the National Archives and Records Administration to collect and disclose records on unidentified flying objects (UFOs) or unidentified anomalous phenomena (UAP) no later than 25 years after enactment with a presumption of immediate disclosure. The U.S. president can certify that continued postponement can be made necessary by an identifiable harm to military defense, intelligence operations, law enforcement or conduct of foreign relations. The federal government would have eminent domain over recovered technologies of unknown origin (TUO) and biological evidence of non-human intelligence (NHI) that may be controlled by private persons or entities, such as aerospace companies. Legislation was necessary in part because UAP records had not been subject to mandatory declassification review due to exemptions under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 as well as an over-broad interpretation of &amp;ldquo;transclassified foreign nuclear information&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Intelligence Authorization Act (IAA) requires people currently or formerly under contract with the federal government to make all UFO/UAP material and information and a comprehensive list of all extraterrestrial or exotic UAP material available to the All-domain Anomaly Resolution Office (AARO).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A provision that prevents the President of the United States from withdrawing the U.S. from NATO without approval of a two-thirds Senate supermajority or an act of Congress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unidentified_Anomalous_Phenomena_Disclosure_Act&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unidentified_Anomalous_Phenomena_Disclosure_Act&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Grusch UFO whistleblower claims</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_daddd7e70514/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 17:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_daddd7e70514/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;david-grusch-former-us-military-intelligence-officers-claims-about-non-human-spacecraft-recovery&#34;&gt;David Grusch: Former U.S. Military Intelligence Officer&amp;rsquo;s Claims About &amp;ldquo;Non-Human&amp;rdquo; Spacecraft Recovery &lt;a href=&#34;#david-grusch-former-us-military-intelligence-officers-claims-about-non-human-spacecraft-recovery&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article focuses on the claims made by David Grusch, a former U.S. Air Force officer and intelligence official, regarding the U.S. government&amp;rsquo;s alleged involvement in recovering and reverse-engineering &amp;ldquo;non-human&amp;rdquo; spacecraft. It also covers the responses to these claims from various experts and government entities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Charles Grusch is introduced as an Afghanistan combat veteran and former intelligence officer who worked at the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA) and the National Reconnaissance Office (NRO). From 2019 to 2021, he served as the NRO representative to the Unidentified Aerial Phenomena Task Force. He assisted in drafting the National Defense Authorization Act of 2023, which included whistleblower protections for UFO reporting. The section notes that Congressional interest in UFOs increased prior to Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims due to the downing of four objects by the Air Force in February 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gruschs-claims&#34;&gt;Grusch&amp;rsquo;s Claims &lt;a href=&#34;#gruschs-claims&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details Grusch&amp;rsquo;s allegations, which were initially reported by Leslie Kean and Ralph Blumenthal in &lt;em&gt;The Debrief&lt;/em&gt;. Grusch claims the U.S. government possesses multiple spacecraft of &amp;ldquo;non-human&amp;rdquo; origin and the corpses of their pilots. He alleges a secret UFO retrieval program, &amp;ldquo;substantive evidence&amp;rdquo; of white-collar crime to conceal UFO programs, and that officials have stated people have been killed to conceal these programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an interview with &lt;em&gt;Le Parisien&lt;/em&gt;, Grusch elaborated, suggesting UFOs could be from extra dimensions, mentioning &amp;ldquo;football-field&amp;rdquo; sized crafts, the transfer of crashed UFOs to defense contractors, and &amp;ldquo;malevolent activity&amp;rdquo; by UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a Congressional hearing in July 2023, Grusch testified about being informed of a multi-decade UAP crash retrieval and reverse-engineering program to which he was denied access. He stated his belief that the U.S. government possesses UAP based on interviews with 40 witnesses. He also claimed the U.S. has retrieved &amp;ldquo;non-human &amp;lsquo;biologics&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; from the crafts. When asked about harm or injury related to cover-ups, Grusch said yes, but could only provide details in a SCIF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;responses-from-relevant-experts&#34;&gt;Responses from Relevant Experts &lt;a href=&#34;#responses-from-relevant-experts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents the views of various experts on Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims. It highlights that his assertions are based on alleged documents and conversations, rather than testable evidence. The scientific community generally considers claims of government conspiracy to conceal extraterrestrial visitation untrue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joshua Semeter of NASA&amp;rsquo;s UAP independent study team states that without data or material evidence, evaluating the claims is impossible. Adam Frank, an astrophysics professor, criticizes the claims as hearsay and lacking extraordinary evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stuart Clark&amp;rsquo;s opinion piece in &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; includes questions from scientists like Avi Loeb, Michael Garrett, and Sara Russell, who point out the lack of observed extraterrestrial activity and the ease of identifying extraterrestrial materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg Eghigian, a history professor and UFO expert, notes the historical pattern of individuals making &amp;ldquo;bombshell allegations&amp;rdquo; about UFOs and the lack of corroboration. Seth Shostak, senior astronomer at the SETI Institute, questions the absence of physical evidence and dismisses the claims as an &amp;ldquo;argument from authority.&amp;rdquo; Michael Shermer, publisher of &lt;em&gt;Skeptic&lt;/em&gt; magazine, notes the lack of physical evidence and scientific community involvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Physicist Sean M. Carroll calls Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims &amp;ldquo;laughable&amp;rdquo; and describes him as a &amp;ldquo;complete crackpot.&amp;rdquo; NASA&amp;rsquo;s JPL director, Laurie Leshin, denies having seen spacecraft from outside this world. Michio Kaku suggests the burden of proof has shifted to the Pentagon, a statement criticized by Ross Pomeroy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;responses-from-the-united-states-government&#34;&gt;Responses from the United States Government &lt;a href=&#34;#responses-from-the-united-states-government&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the responses from various U.S. government entities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;department-of-defense-and-nasa&#34;&gt;Department of Defense and NASA &lt;a href=&#34;#department-of-defense-and-nasa&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;White House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre referred questions to the Department of Defense (DoD). A Pentagon spokesperson stated that AARO has not discovered verifiable information to substantiate claims of programs regarding the possession or reverse-engineering of extraterrestrial materials. General Mark Milley stated he had never encountered evidence verifying Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims. NASA stated it has not found credible evidence of extraterrestrial life and that there is no evidence that UAPs are extraterrestrial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;congress&#34;&gt;Congress &lt;a href=&#34;#congress&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representative Mike Turner stated there is no evidence of the U.S. possessing UFOs from outer space. Senator Lindsey Graham found the claims unreasonable. Senator Josh Hawley said the allegations sounded close to what they were &amp;ldquo;grudgingly admitted to us in the briefing&amp;rdquo;. Senator Kirsten Gillibrand intends to hold a hearing to assess whether &amp;ldquo;rogue SAP programs&amp;rdquo; existed. Senator Marco Rubio said people with &amp;ldquo;first-hand knowledge&amp;rdquo; have shared information with his committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In July 2023, Senators Chuck Schumer and Mike Rounds proposed the UAP Disclosure Act 2023, an amendment to the 2024 National Defence Authorization Act, to provide wider access to UAP records. The enrolled bill directs the National Archives to collect government documents about UAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January 2024, members of the House Oversight Committee received a classified briefing from the Intelligence Community Inspector General (IC IG) Thomas A. Monheim regarding UAP reporting transparency. Some members were frustrated by the lack of new information regarding Grusch&amp;rsquo;s allegations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2023-house-committee-oversight-and-accountability-hearing&#34;&gt;2023 House Committee Oversight and Accountability Hearing &lt;a href=&#34;#2023-house-committee-oversight-and-accountability-hearing&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representatives Anna Paulina Luna and Tim Burchett organized a hearing on July 26, 2023, in response to Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims. Grusch testified, repeating his earlier UFO claims. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez asked where to look for evidence, and Grusch offered to provide specifics in a closed environment. Officials later informed lawmakers that Grusch lacked security clearance to discuss the issues in a SCIF. Following the hearing, a bipartisan group of U.S. representatives called for the formation of a select committee on UAPs with subpoena power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AARO&amp;rsquo;s director Sean Kirkpatrick wrote that Grusch &amp;ldquo;has refused to speak with AARO&amp;rdquo; and that the hearing was &amp;ldquo;insulting&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sean-kirkpatrick&#34;&gt;Sean Kirkpatrick &lt;a href=&#34;#sean-kirkpatrick&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After retiring from AARO, Kirkpatrick wrote an opinion piece for &lt;em&gt;Scientific American&lt;/em&gt; stating that the US Government UFO coverup allegations &amp;ldquo;derive from inadvertent or unauthorized disclosures of legitimate U.S. programs or related R&amp;amp;D that have nothing to do with extraterrestrial issues or technology.&amp;rdquo; He described the allegations&amp;rsquo; supporters as &amp;ldquo;a small group of interconnected believers and others with possibly less than honest intentions,&amp;rdquo; who promote a &amp;ldquo;whirlwind of tall tales, fabrication and secondhand or thirdhand retellings&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an interview with Peter Bergen, Kirkpatrick said that Grusch may have misinterpreted things or fallen under the influence of a core group of people. He characterized the situation as a &amp;ldquo;self licking ice cream cone,&amp;rdquo; where UFO true believers are carrying out a conspiracy to get the government involved in investigating aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;media-reporting-on-gruschs-claims&#34;&gt;Media Reporting on Grusch&amp;rsquo;s Claims &lt;a href=&#34;#media-reporting-on-gruschs-claims&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines how the media has covered Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;connections-to-studies-funded-by-robert-bigelow&#34;&gt;Connections to Studies Funded by Robert Bigelow &lt;a href=&#34;#connections-to-studies-funded-by-robert-bigelow&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keith Kloor draws a connection between Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims and studies funded by Robert Bigelow, noting specific references to &amp;ldquo;a football field–sized UFO&amp;rdquo; in both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reporting-on-psychiatric-treatment-received-by-grusch&#34;&gt;Reporting on Psychiatric Treatment Received by Grusch &lt;a href=&#34;#reporting-on-psychiatric-treatment-received-by-grusch&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ken Klippenstein reported in &lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt; that Grusch was twice committed after incidents involving drunkenness and suicidal comments. Police records mentioned PTSD. Grusch was placed under an emergency custody order and transported to an emergency room. Grusch sued Loudoun County Sheriff Mike Chapman for releasing the information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;news-stories-and-commentary&#34;&gt;News Stories and Commentary &lt;a href=&#34;#news-stories-and-commentary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick Pope, who previously ran the British Ministry of Defense &amp;ldquo;UFO Desk&amp;rdquo;, expressed doubt about confirming Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims. Marina Koren wrote that the case fits a pattern of unprovable claims. Matt Laslo described the sympathetic hearing of Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims by some members of Congress as an indication that &amp;ldquo;once-fringe notions have built-in fan bases in today&amp;rsquo;s Capitol&amp;rdquo;. Tucker Carlson publicized the claims. Tom Rogan was skeptical but opined that they should be further investigated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Prokop wrote that skeptics question whether Grusch is repeating tall tales. Sean Thomas expressed confusion that others have tried to convince officials and the public that UFOs are worthy of serious considerations. Ross Douthat noted that one interpretation is that parts of the U.S. government see benefit in promoting belief in UFOs. Matt Stieb described Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims as &amp;ldquo;crazy&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ezra Klein interviewed Leslie Kean, noting that reactions to her story about Grusch have been either to embrace it as definitive truth or dismiss it out of hand. Steven Greenstreet criticized Grusch for previously attending UFO conventions and associating with Jeremy Corbell and George Knapp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story received attention from multiple foreign mainstream news outlets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disinformation-campaign-allegations&#34;&gt;Disinformation Campaign Allegations &lt;a href=&#34;#disinformation-campaign-allegations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grusch claimed that intentional disinformation was being promoted by the US government to cast doubt on the veracity of &amp;ldquo;non-human&amp;rdquo; UFO claims. Adam Gabbatt described Grusch&amp;rsquo;s position as &amp;ldquo;a common conspiracy trope in the UFO community&amp;rdquo;. Others have suggested that Grusch was given disinformation about aliens. Gareth Nicholson wrote that &amp;ldquo;the current UAP flap could be an attempt by the US military to engage in a disinformation campaign to disguise real aerospace breakthroughs or an attempt to flush out advanced technologies held by rivals such as Russia and China&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Grusch_UFO_whistleblower_claims&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Grusch_UFO_whistleblower_claims&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 United States Congress hearings on UFOs</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cacc9618f5eb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 13:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cacc9618f5eb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;2022-united-states-congressional-hearings-on-unexplained-aerial-phenomena&#34;&gt;2022 United States Congressional Hearings on Unexplained Aerial Phenomena &lt;a href=&#34;#2022-united-states-congressional-hearings-on-unexplained-aerial-phenomena&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the United States congressional hearings held on May 17, 2022, by the House Intelligence Subcommittee on Counterterrorism, Counterintelligence, and Counterproliferation to discuss military reports of Unexplained Aerial Phenomena (UAPs). It was the first public congressional hearing on UFO sightings in the US in over 50 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides the historical context leading up to the 2022 hearings. It mentions the last public congressional hearing on UAPs in 1969, initiated by then-congressman Gerald Ford in 1966. Project Blue Book, a U.S. Air Force program investigating UFOs, was disbanded in 1969. The section also notes the 2017 reports of Pentagon investigations into UAPs and the 2020 COVID-19 relief bill that mandated a report on UAPs from US intelligence agencies. The unclassified report released in June 2021 is highlighted, noting its conclusion that 144 incidents defied explanation and called for further investigation. Finally, the establishment of the Airborne Object Identification and Management Synchronization Group (AOIMSG) in November 2021 and the provisions in the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022 and the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2022, for a permanent agency to investigate UAPs are mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hearings&#34;&gt;Hearings &lt;a href=&#34;#hearings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the events of the May 17, 2022, congressional hearings. Rep. André Carson, chairman of the subcommittee, opened the hearing, expressing concerns about national security threats posed by UAPs and criticizing the Pentagon&amp;rsquo;s lack of updates and leadership for the AOIMSG. Testimony was given by Under Secretary of Defense for Intelligence and Security Ronald S. Moultrie and Deputy Director of Naval Intelligence Scott Bray. Bray stated that reported sightings had grown to about 400 since the previous year&amp;rsquo;s report and dismissed extraterrestrial origins. He also noted no collisions had been reported. The section mentions that other countries have similar reports and communicate with U.S. intelligence agencies. Moultrie emphasized the need for cooperation with the Federal Aviation Administration and other government agencies. Declassified images and footage of UFOs were shown, including a video of a &amp;ldquo;spherical object&amp;rdquo; and triangular objects seen through night-vision goggles. Concerns about potential Russian or Chinese hypersonic weapons programs were raised by lawmakers like Rick Crawford. The standardization of civilian reporting was discussed. The public portion of the hearing was followed by a private classified session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reactions&#34;&gt;Reactions &lt;a href=&#34;#reactions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the reactions to the congressional hearings. Rep. Tim Burchett criticized the Pentagon&amp;rsquo;s transparency and dismissiveness of extraterrestrial explanations. UFO skeptic Robert Sheaffer derided the footage shown at the hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external resources related to the hearings, including the event page on Congress.gov, the hearing on C-SPAN, and a YouTube video of the hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2022_United_States_Congress_hearings_on_UFOs&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2022_United_States_Congress_hearings_on_UFOs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
