<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fiction on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fiction on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 13:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO conspiracy theories</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_58890638264e/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 13:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_58890638264e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;UFO Conspiracy Theories &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-conspiracy-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Wikipedia article discusses various conspiracy theories surrounding Unidentified Flying Objects (UFOs), particularly the idea that governments, especially the United States government, are suppressing evidence of extraterrestrial life or technology. It also explores the evolution of these theories, their proponents, and their presence in popular culture and religion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces the core concept of UFO conspiracy theories: governments concealing evidence of extraterrestrial involvement. It traces the origins of these theories back to pulp science fiction and the &amp;ldquo;lost continent&amp;rdquo; myths. The section highlights Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s 1947 sighting as a catalyst for widespread UFO reports and the subsequent speculation about secret technologies. Donald Keyhoe is identified as a key figure in popularizing the idea of a government cover-up. The emergence of the &amp;ldquo;Men in Black&amp;rdquo; concept is also mentioned. The section further explains how UFO conspiracy theories became more prevalent after the Kennedy assassination, linking his death to aliens. The term &amp;ldquo;Cosmic Watergate&amp;rdquo; is introduced to describe the alleged cover-up. The section also mentions the influence of films like &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt; and the introduction of the Roswell incident to a mass audience. The shift from benevolent &amp;ldquo;space brothers&amp;rdquo; to malevolent aliens in the 1980s is discussed, along with the connection of UFO cover-ups to alien abductions, cattle mutilations, and the JFK assassination. The section concludes by noting the resurgence of interest in UFO conspiracy theories in the 1990s and 2017 with Leslie Kean&amp;rsquo;s stories of a Pentagon UFO program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mainstream-views&#34;&gt;Mainstream Views &lt;a href=&#34;#mainstream-views&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents the mainstream scientific perspective on UFOs. It acknowledges the historical and cultural prominence of UFO sightings, particularly after World War II and during the Space Age. It mentions government investigations like Project Blue Book and Project Condign, as well as studies by organizations and individuals. The section emphasizes that these investigations have not confirmed claims of extraterrestrial intelligence or other unconventional explanations for UFOs. It highlights that scientists and skeptical organizations offer prosaic explanations, such as natural phenomena, human technology, delusions, and hoaxes. The section also notes that beliefs surrounding UFOs have inspired new religions and that social scientists view the ongoing interest in UFOs as a form of modern folklore and mythology. Benjamin Radford&amp;rsquo;s argument against the feasibility of a long-term, international UFO cover-up is also presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notable-proponents&#34;&gt;Notable Proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#notable-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section identifies key individuals who have promoted UFO conspiracy theories. Donald Keyhoe, Jacque Vallee, J. Allen Hynek, and Stanton Friedman are mentioned as prominent figures from the 1950s to the 1970s. The section also notes that some proponents, like Richard Shaver and Paul Bennewitz, had mental health issues, while others, like Gray Barker, Carl Allen, Richard Doty, Bill Moore, and Ray Santelli, confessed to hoaxes or lies. The violent ends of Morris Jessup, James E. McDonald, and Bill Cooper are also mentioned. The section lists individuals who have suggested that UFO evidence is being suppressed, including Barry Goldwater, Lord Hill-Norton, Roscoe H. Hillenkoetter, Gordon Cooper, and Edgar Mitchell. 21st-century proponents such as Paul Hellyer, Garry Nolan, Haim Eshed, Jim Semivan, Harold E. Puthoff, Tom DeLonge, Luis Elizondo, and David Grusch are also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-fiction&#34;&gt;In Popular Fiction &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-fiction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the presence of UFO conspiracy theories in popular culture. It mentions films like &lt;em&gt;2001: A Space Odyssey&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Easy Rider&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Flight of the Navigator&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Total Recall&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Independence Day&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Men in Black&lt;/em&gt;. Television series such as &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Dark Skies&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Stargate&lt;/em&gt; are also mentioned as featuring government efforts to conceal information about extraterrestrial beings. John Glenn&amp;rsquo;s appearance on &lt;em&gt;Frasier&lt;/em&gt;, where he confesses to a UFO cover-up, is also noted. The Sidney Sheldon novel &lt;em&gt;The Doomsday Conspiracy&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;American Horror Story: Double Feature&lt;/em&gt; series are also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-religion&#34;&gt;In Religion &lt;a href=&#34;#in-religion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines the connection between UFO conspiracy theories and new religious movements. It identifies the Nation of Islam, Scientology, and Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate as examples of religious groups that have incorporated UFO-related beliefs. Mormon cosmology&amp;rsquo;s view of inhabited planets is also mentioned. Theosophists and occultists, such as Meade Layne, George Adamski, George Hunt Williamson, and Guy Warren Ballard, are discussed as early proponents of extraterrestrial contact. The Nation of Islam&amp;rsquo;s concept of The Mother Plane is also explored. The section also mentions UFO religions such as Unarius, the Aetherius Society, Raëlism, and the Order of the Solar Temple. The Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate mass suicide, linked to the Hale-Bopp comet, is also discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chronology-of-ufo-conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;Chronology of UFO Conspiracy Theories &lt;a href=&#34;#chronology-of-ufo-conspiracy-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a detailed timeline of the development of UFO conspiracy theories, starting with Raymond Palmer&amp;rsquo;s pulp magazine in the 1940s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1940s-origin-in-raymond-palmers-pulp-magazine&#34;&gt;1940s Origin in Raymond Palmer&amp;rsquo;s Pulp Magazine &lt;a href=&#34;#1940s-origin-in-raymond-palmers-pulp-magazine&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection focuses on Raymond Palmer, the editor of &lt;em&gt;Amazing Stories&lt;/em&gt;, and his role in popularizing UFO conspiracy theories. It mentions his hiring of Kenneth Arnold to investigate the Maury Island incident and the magazine&amp;rsquo;s claims of a cover-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;spaceships-of-the-shaver-mystery&#34;&gt;Spaceships of &amp;ldquo;The Shaver Mystery&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#spaceships-of-the-shaver-mystery&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses Richard Shaver&amp;rsquo;s stories of a secret underground race and their spaceships, published in &lt;em&gt;Amazing Stories&lt;/em&gt;. It mentions Palmer&amp;rsquo;s argument that governments were aware of spaceships visiting Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kenneth-arnold-ignites-flying-disc-craze&#34;&gt;Kenneth Arnold Ignites Flying Disc Craze &lt;a href=&#34;#kenneth-arnold-ignites-flying-disc-craze&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s 1947 sighting and the subsequent &amp;ldquo;flying disc craze.&amp;rdquo; It mentions the Roswell incident and Palmer&amp;rsquo;s investigation of the Maury Island report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aftermath&#34;&gt;Aftermath &lt;a href=&#34;#aftermath&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the aftermath of the 1947 flying disc craze, including Palmer&amp;rsquo;s linking of the sightings to Shaver&amp;rsquo;s claims and Shaver&amp;rsquo;s prediction that the truth about the discs would remain secret. It also mentions Palmer&amp;rsquo;s later linking of UFOs to the JFK assassination and Watergate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;national-coverage-in-the-1950s&#34;&gt;National Coverage in the 1950s &lt;a href=&#34;#national-coverage-in-the-1950s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the increase in governmental and civilian investigative efforts and reports of public disinformation and suppression of evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aztec-alien-bodies-hoax&#34;&gt;Aztec &amp;ldquo;Alien Bodies&amp;rdquo; Hoax &lt;a href=&#34;#aztec-alien-bodies-hoax&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection details the Frank Scully&amp;rsquo;s claims of recovered alien bodies from crashed flying saucers and the subsequent exposure of the hoax by &lt;em&gt;True&lt;/em&gt; magazine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;air-force-accounts&#34;&gt;Air Force Accounts &lt;a href=&#34;#air-force-accounts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers the Air Force&amp;rsquo;s response to UFO sightings, including General John Samford&amp;rsquo;s press conference and the Robertson Panel&amp;rsquo;s recommendation for public education. It also mentions Al Chop&amp;rsquo;s role as a press officer for Project Bluebook and the film &lt;em&gt;Unidentified Flying Objects: The True Story of Flying Saucers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;philadelphia-experiment-hoax&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Philadelphia Experiment&amp;rdquo; Hoax &lt;a href=&#34;#philadelphia-experiment-hoax&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the Morris K. Jessup&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;em&gt;The Case for the UFO&lt;/em&gt; and the &amp;ldquo;Philadelphia Experiment&amp;rdquo; hoax, involving Carl Meredith Allen&amp;rsquo;s letters and annotations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;men-in-black-legends&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Men in Black&amp;rsquo; Legends &lt;a href=&#34;#men-in-black-legends&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explores the origin of the &amp;ldquo;Men in Black&amp;rdquo; concept in Gray Barker&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;em&gt;They Knew Too Much About Flying Saucers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1960-70s-growing-distrust-in-government&#34;&gt;1960-70s: Growing Distrust in Government &lt;a href=&#34;#1960-70s-growing-distrust-in-government&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the increasing government skepticism during the 1960s and 1970s, fueled by events like the Kennedy assassination, the Pentagon Papers, and the Watergate scandal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fred-crisman-and-jfk-conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;Fred Crisman and JFK Conspiracy Theories &lt;a href=&#34;#fred-crisman-and-jfk-conspiracy-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers Jim Garrison&amp;rsquo;s prosecution of Clay Shaw and the involvement of Fred Crisman, linking UFO conspiracy theories to the Kennedy assassination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cosmic-watergate&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cosmic Watergate&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#cosmic-watergate&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the concept of a &amp;ldquo;Cosmic Watergate,&amp;rdquo; with J. Allen Hynek&amp;rsquo;s accusations of a government cover-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-bodies-at-hangar-18&#34;&gt;Alien Bodies at &amp;ldquo;Hangar 18&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-bodies-at-hangar-18&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explores the legends of alien bodies stored at &amp;ldquo;Hangar 18&amp;rdquo; at Wright-Patterson Air Force Base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-abductions&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Alien Abductions&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-abductions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the emergence of alien abduction reports, starting with the Betty and Barney Hill case and the Travis Walton incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;close-encounters-of-the-third-kind&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#close-encounters-of-the-third-kind&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection examines the influence of the film &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt; on UFO conspiracy theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;jesse-marcel-and-roswell&#34;&gt;Jesse Marcel and Roswell &lt;a href=&#34;#jesse-marcel-and-roswell&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers Jesse Marcel&amp;rsquo;s changing statements about the Roswell incident and the increasing attention given to the story by the &lt;em&gt;National Enquirer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;doty-and-lear-promote-the-dark-side&#34;&gt;Doty and Lear Promote the &amp;ldquo;Dark Side&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#doty-and-lear-promote-the-dark-side&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the shift towards &amp;ldquo;ufology&amp;rsquo;s dark side&amp;rdquo; in the 1980s, with Richard Doty and John Lear promoting theories of government collusion with evil aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cattle-mutilations-and-quiet-helicopters&#34;&gt;Cattle Mutilations and Quiet Helicopters &lt;a href=&#34;#cattle-mutilations-and-quiet-helicopters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explores the connection between cattle mutilations, UFO sightings, and &amp;ldquo;quiet helicopters&amp;rdquo; in the Colorado-New Mexico border region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;doty-deceives-mutiliation-researchers&#34;&gt;Doty Deceives Mutiliation Researchers &lt;a href=&#34;#doty-deceives-mutiliation-researchers&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers Richard Doty&amp;rsquo;s deception of Paul Bennewitz and Linda Moulton Howe, feeding them false stories of a UFO conspiracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;doty-and-bill-moore-spread-bogus-mj-12-docs&#34;&gt;Doty and Bill Moore Spread Bogus MJ-12 Docs &lt;a href=&#34;#doty-and-bill-moore-spread-bogus-mj-12-docs&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses the spread of fabricated Majestic 12 documents by Richard Doty and Bill Moore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lear-promotes-bill-cooper-and-bob-lazar&#34;&gt;Lear Promotes Bill Cooper and Bob Lazar &lt;a href=&#34;#lear-promotes-bill-cooper-and-bob-lazar&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explores John Lear&amp;rsquo;s promotion of Bill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_conspiracy_theory&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_conspiracy_theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Guardian Alien</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_8d4c72af093b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 09:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_8d4c72af093b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-guardian-alien&#34;&gt;My Guardian Alien &lt;a href=&#34;#my-guardian-alien&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2024 Philippine television drama series broadcast by GMA Network. It is a science fiction drama directed by Zig Madamba Dulay, starring Marian Rivera. The series premiered on April 1, 2024, and concluded on June 28, 2024, with 65 episodes. Originally titled &lt;em&gt;Against All Odds&lt;/em&gt;, it was later renamed. The series is also available for streaming on YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;premise&#34;&gt;Premise &lt;a href=&#34;#premise&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot centers around Katherine, who dies in a shooting accident. During her funeral, an alien &amp;ldquo;pod&amp;rdquo; lands on Earth, and the alien takes Katherine&amp;rsquo;s form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast-and-characters&#34;&gt;Cast and Characters &lt;a href=&#34;#cast-and-characters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the actors and the characters they portray in the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lead Cast:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marian Rivera plays Katherine Villegas-Soriano / 11-1-20-8-5-22-9-12-5 / Grace B. Formin / Mommy Two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supporting Cast:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gabby Concepcion plays Carlos Soriano.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Max Collins plays Venus del Rosario.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raphael Landicho plays Adrian &amp;ldquo;Doy&amp;rdquo; Soriano.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gabby Eigenmann plays Cepheus &amp;ldquo;Ceph&amp;rdquo; Corona.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caitlyn Stave plays Halley del Rosario.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Josh Ford plays Aries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kiray Celis plays Marites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arnold Reyes plays Minggoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tanya Gomez plays Isay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sean Lucas plays Kevin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marissa Delgado plays Nova Soriano.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guest Cast:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maricar de Mesa as younger Nova&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ana Marin as Aurora &amp;ldquo;Auring&amp;rdquo; Vega-Corona&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tart Carlos as Karen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christian Antolin as Sputnik&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kirst Viray as Delfin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyn Barro as Aera Simmons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shanelle Agustin as Emily&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jericho Arceo as Ikong&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Richard Arellano as Generoso&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luke Conde as Vega / Arnold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anne Garcia as Ofel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kitsi Pagaspas as Belen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ira Ruzz as Jenny&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ryan Sandoval as Chito&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orlando Sol as Isko&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Richard Arellano as Generoso&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rodjun Cruz as a dancer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Juan Rodrigo as Tiago&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rochelle Barrameda as Juliet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anjay Anson as Sandro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stanley Abuloc as Tonyo / 11-15-2-12-78-15-22-31-12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists all 65 episodes of &lt;em&gt;My Guardian Alien&lt;/em&gt; with their titles and original release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1: &amp;ldquo;World Premiere&amp;rdquo; (April 1, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 2: &amp;ldquo;Paano Makaka-move On?&amp;rdquo; (April 2, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 3: &amp;ldquo;Ang Pagdating&amp;rdquo; (April 3, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 4: &amp;ldquo;Tao Nga Ba?&amp;rdquo; (April 4, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 5: &amp;ldquo;Memories&amp;rdquo; (April 5, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 6: &amp;ldquo;First Encounter&amp;rdquo; (April 8, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 7: &amp;ldquo;Super Hero&amp;rdquo; (April 9, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 8: &amp;ldquo;Mommy Two&amp;rdquo; (April 10, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 9: &amp;ldquo;How to Hide an Alien?&amp;rdquo; (April 11, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 10: &amp;ldquo;Boses ni Katherine&amp;rdquo; (April 12, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 11: &amp;ldquo;Protect Doy&amp;rdquo; (April 15, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 12: &amp;ldquo;Fight, Fight, Fight&amp;rdquo; (April 16, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 13: &amp;ldquo;Cheers&amp;rdquo; (April 17, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 14: &amp;ldquo;Carlos Meets Alien&amp;rdquo; (April 18, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 15: &amp;ldquo;Alien Encounter&amp;rdquo; (April 19, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 16: &amp;ldquo;Peace Offering&amp;rdquo; (April 22, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 17: &amp;ldquo;Ghost Hunting&amp;rdquo; (April 23, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 18: &amp;ldquo;Babang Luksa&amp;rdquo; (April 24, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 19: &amp;ldquo;The Search&amp;rdquo; (April 25, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 20: &amp;ldquo;Together Again&amp;rdquo; (April 26, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 21: &amp;ldquo;Hello, Grace&amp;rdquo; (April 29, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 22: &amp;ldquo;Time to Recharge&amp;rdquo; (April 30, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 23: &amp;ldquo;Invasion of Privacy&amp;rdquo; (May 1, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 24: &amp;ldquo;Surprise&amp;rdquo; (May 2, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 25: &amp;ldquo;Confrontation&amp;rdquo; (May 3, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 26: &amp;ldquo;Alien Dance&amp;rdquo; (May 6, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 27: &amp;ldquo;Riot sa Bar&amp;rdquo; (May 7, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 28: &amp;ldquo;Lesson in Fear&amp;rdquo; (May 8, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 29: &amp;ldquo;Rejection&amp;rdquo; (May 9, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 30: &amp;ldquo;Crush Landing&amp;rdquo; (May 10, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 31: &amp;ldquo;Confession&amp;rdquo; (May 13, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 32: &amp;ldquo;First LQ&amp;rdquo; (May 14, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 33: &amp;ldquo;Connection&amp;rdquo; (May 15, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 34: &amp;ldquo;Truth Serum&amp;rdquo; (May 16, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 35: &amp;ldquo;Best Day Ever&amp;rdquo; (May 17, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 36: &amp;ldquo;Parental Guidance&amp;rdquo; (May 20, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 37: &amp;ldquo;Bitter Ampalaya&amp;rdquo; (May 21, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 38: &amp;ldquo;Snaky Moves&amp;rdquo; (May 22, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 39: &amp;ldquo;Rage&amp;rdquo; (May 23, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 40: &amp;ldquo;Resbak&amp;rdquo; (May 24, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 41: &amp;ldquo;Scheme&amp;rdquo; (May 27, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 42: &amp;ldquo;Traydor&amp;rdquo; (May 28, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 43: &amp;ldquo;Matinding Duda&amp;rdquo; (May 29, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 44: &amp;ldquo;Rebelasyon&amp;rdquo; (May 30, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 45: &amp;ldquo;Backfire&amp;rdquo; (May 31, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 46: &amp;ldquo;Guilty as Hell&amp;rdquo; (June 3, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 47: &amp;ldquo;Truth and Lies&amp;rdquo; (June 4, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 48: &amp;ldquo;The Confession&amp;rdquo; (June 5, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 49: &amp;ldquo;Dark Secrets&amp;rdquo; (June 6, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 50: &amp;ldquo;Taken&amp;rdquo; (June 7, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 51: &amp;ldquo;Tuso&amp;rdquo; (June 10, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 52: &amp;ldquo;Special Glue&amp;rdquo; (June 11, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 53: &amp;ldquo;FH Virus&amp;rdquo; (June 12, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 54: &amp;ldquo;The Proposal&amp;rdquo; (June 13, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 55: &amp;ldquo;Friend or Spy?&amp;rdquo; (June 14, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 56: &amp;ldquo;Sukdulan&amp;rdquo; (June 17, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 57: &amp;ldquo;In Danger&amp;rdquo; (June 18, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 58: &amp;ldquo;Missing&amp;rdquo; (June 19, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 59&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Guardian_Alien&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Guardian_Alien&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Max Evans (Roswell)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_a9fd8cc44766/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 23:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_a9fd8cc44766/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;max-evans-roswell&#34;&gt;Max Evans (Roswell) &lt;a href=&#34;#max-evans-roswell&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maxwell &amp;ldquo;Max&amp;rdquo; Evans is a fictional character created by Melinda Metz for the &lt;em&gt;Roswell High&lt;/em&gt; book series and adapted for the &lt;em&gt;Roswell&lt;/em&gt; television series (1999-2002). He is portrayed by Jason Behr in the original series and by Nathan Parsons in the CW reboot. Max is a central character throughout the series, first appearing in the pilot episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fictional-character-summary&#34;&gt;Fictional character summary &lt;a href=&#34;#fictional-character-summary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the TV character, distinguishing it from the &lt;em&gt;Roswell High&lt;/em&gt; book version. Max&amp;rsquo;s backstory reveals that in a previous life, he was Zan, the king of Antar. After Zan&amp;rsquo;s death, his DNA and human DNA were used to create alien/human hybrids or clones, including Isabel Evans (Vilandra, Zan&amp;rsquo;s sister), Michael Guerin (Rath, Vilandra&amp;rsquo;s betrothed), and Tess Harding (Ava, Zan&amp;rsquo;s bride). These clones were sent to Earth to escape their enemies, particularly Kivar. The craft carrying Max, Isabel, Michael, and Tess crashed in Roswell, New Mexico, in 1947. The U.S. Army initially took the alien pods, but they were rescued and hidden. The clones emerged in 1989, appearing as children. Max and Isabel were adopted by the Evans, while Michael ended up in foster care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;characteristics&#34;&gt;Characteristics &lt;a href=&#34;#characteristics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max is presented as shy and introverted, a facade necessitated by his hybrid nature. He is a complex character, displaying both timidity and passion. Despite his initial shyness, he emerges as the leader among his friends. He is portrayed as a deep thinker, often spurred to action by his protective instincts. He takes responsibility for his actions and is known for his unique healing powers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;powers-and-abilities&#34;&gt;Powers and abilities &lt;a href=&#34;#powers-and-abilities&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max possesses molecular manipulation and telekinesis, abilities shared by the other hybrids. His unique power is healing through physical contact, famously used to save Liz Parker in the pilot episode. He also develops the ability to generate a force field. It is suggested that his healing ability can trigger the development of alien powers in those he heals, such as Liz Parker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;relationship-with-liz-parker&#34;&gt;Relationship with Liz Parker &lt;a href=&#34;#relationship-with-liz-parker&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max&amp;rsquo;s love for Liz Parker is a central theme. He has been in love with her since childhood but keeps his distance due to his alien identity. He reveals his secret to save her life after she is shot, initiating the main plot of the show. Their connection is portrayed as deep and mysterious, with Liz able to sense when Max is in danger. Their relationship is considered a core aspect of the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recurring-themes&#34;&gt;Recurring themes &lt;a href=&#34;#recurring-themes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relationship between Max and Liz is presented as a modern example of forbidden love, with references to &lt;em&gt;Romeo and Juliet&lt;/em&gt;. Maria De Luca refers to them as &amp;ldquo;modern Romeo and Juliet against the world.&amp;rdquo; The concept of soulmates is also a recurring theme, emphasizing their deep connection and compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fictional-biography&#34;&gt;Fictional biography &lt;a href=&#34;#fictional-biography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-one&#34;&gt;Season one &lt;a href=&#34;#season-one&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max is first seen watching Liz at the Crashdown Café. After Liz is accidentally shot, Max heals her, revealing his alien nature. Liz discovers his secret and becomes his confidante. Max and Liz&amp;rsquo;s relationship develops, complicated by his secret. Liz breaks up with Kyle Valenti to be with Max. The hybrids search for answers about their origins. Max discovers a fourth alien. Tess Harding arrives, revealed to be another hybrid. Nasedo kidnaps Liz, prompting Max to save her. Max is abducted by the FBI but rescued by Nasedo and Michael. Sheriff Valenti pledges to protect Max, Isabel, and Michael. The ship reveals their past as the Royal Four of Antar, with Tess and Max being married.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-two&#34;&gt;Season two &lt;a href=&#34;#season-two&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max struggles with his role as &amp;ldquo;reluctant king.&amp;rdquo; His relationship with Liz is strained. He learns about new powers and responsibilities. The &amp;ldquo;skins&amp;rdquo; arrive in Roswell. Max tries to rekindle his relationship with Liz, but she rejects him. A future version of Max warns that their love will cause the end of the world. Max and Tess become friends. Alex dies. Max has a personal crisis and loses his balance. Tess helps him remember his past. Max sleeps with Tess, who becomes pregnant. Max takes responsibility and stays with Tess. Tess mindwarps him into believing the baby is sick. Max and his friends plan to return to Antar. Liz, Maria, and Kyle discover that Tess killed Alex. Max confronts Tess and lets her go to Antar to save the baby. He reunites with Liz and declares his love for her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-three&#34;&gt;Season three &lt;a href=&#34;#season-three&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max searches for his son. He and Liz rob a convenience store to find the ship. Liz&amp;rsquo;s parents forbid her from seeing Max. Max discovers Cal Langley, an alien protector. Langley tries to interfere with Max&amp;rsquo;s search. Max forces Langley to help him find the ship. The ship doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. Max realizes he almost lost everything, especially Liz. Max encounters Samuel, an autistic child. Max realizes that Liz is his family. Liz develops alien powers. Liz decides to take a break from Roswell. Someone kills Michael&amp;rsquo;s friend, Monk. Michael discovers that Meta-Chem is tracking him. Max, Michael, and Isabel rescue Valenti. Max sacrifices his life to heal Meris&amp;rsquo; husband. Max&amp;rsquo;s soul is inside Clayton. Clayton assumes Max&amp;rsquo;s body. Clayton tries to kill Liz. Max takes control and tells Liz to kill him. Liz kills Clayton, and Max is resurrected. Michael becomes the king. Max returns to be the king. Tess returns with Max&amp;rsquo;s son, Zan. Tess sacrifices herself. Max gives Zan up for adoption. Liz receives visions of the future. The group agrees to flee Roswell. Max proposes to Liz. Max and Liz get married. The group leaves Roswell together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;jason-behr-about-his-character&#34;&gt;Jason Behr about his character &lt;a href=&#34;#jason-behr-about-his-character&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason Behr discusses his initial understanding of Max, relating to his search for truth and his place in the world. He highlights the richness of the script and its honest portrayal of relationships and emotions. Behr notes Max&amp;rsquo;s evolution throughout the show, from being the conscience of the group to learning to allow others to make their own mistakes. He also expresses his open-mindedness about extraterrestrial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason Behr was cast as Max Evans, despite the character&amp;rsquo;s original description as blond with blue eyes. David Nutter explains that Behr was chosen for his natural talent, humility, calmness, maturity, and wisdom. Melinda Metz, the original books&amp;rsquo; writer, approved of the casting choice. Jason Behr won a Young Hollywood Award for his portrayal of Max Evans and received nominations at the Teen Choice Awards and Saturn Awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Max_Evans_(Roswell)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Max_Evans_(Roswell)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
