<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cover-Up on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/cover-up/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cover-Up on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 10:20:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/cover-up/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Roswell (film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_9ba574eb9443/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 10:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_9ba574eb9443/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;roswell-film&#34;&gt;Roswell (film) &lt;a href=&#34;#roswell-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry details the 1994 American science fiction television film &lt;em&gt;Roswell&lt;/em&gt;, also known as &lt;em&gt;Roswell: The U.F.O. Cover-Up&lt;/em&gt;. The film is based on the alleged Roswell UFO incident, which involves the U.S. military&amp;rsquo;s supposed capture of a flying saucer and its alien crew after a crash near Roswell, New Mexico, in July 1947. The film also references other UFOlogy events, including Area 51, alien autopsies, the death of James Forrestal, and Majestic-12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot unfolds through flashbacks at a 30-year reunion of the 509th Operations Group. It centers on Major Jesse Marcel&amp;rsquo;s investigation into strange debris found on a rancher&amp;rsquo;s field in July 1947. Despite being told by his superiors that it was merely a downed weather balloon, Marcel persists in his search for the truth, ultimately uncovering the reality of what occurred. Key figures include Major Jesse Marcel and the setting is Roswell, New Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received reviews from &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Los Angeles Times&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; praised the film&amp;rsquo;s tense drama but questioned the plausibility of a long-term cover-up. &lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt; called it a gripping fictional account and highlighted the convincing pacing and unflinching portrayal of military mendacity. &lt;em&gt;The Los Angeles Times&lt;/em&gt; viewed the film as more than just a sci-fi story, focusing on the protagonist&amp;rsquo;s search for truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cast includes Kyle MacLachlan as Jesse A. Marcel, Martin Sheen as Townsend, and Dwight Yoakam as Mac Brazel. Other notable cast members include Xander Berkeley, Bob Gunton, Kim Greist, Peter MacNicol, John M. Jackson, and Nick Searcy. The cast also features appearances by Charles Hallahan, Ray McKinnon, Eugene Roche, and Charles Martin Smith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the citations used in the article, including reviews from &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Los Angeles Times&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the film&amp;rsquo;s entry on the IMDb (Internet Movie Database) website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell_(film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell_(film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Age of Disclosure</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_bede4bc9e3eb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_bede4bc9e3eb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-age-of-disclosure&#34;&gt;The Age of Disclosure &lt;a href=&#34;#the-age-of-disclosure&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2025 American documentary film directed and produced by Dan Farah, exploring the alleged existence and cover-up of extraterrestrial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film premiered at SXSW (South by Southwest Film &amp;amp; TV Festival) on March 9, 2025. This section highlights the film&amp;rsquo;s debut at a major film festival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received &amp;ldquo;mixed or average&amp;rdquo; reviews, earning a score of 52 out of 100 on Metacritic based on four critics. Owen Gleiberman of &lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt; questioned the film&amp;rsquo;s evidence, expressing skepticism about the quality and authenticity of the presented footage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including articles from &lt;em&gt;Hollywood Reporter&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;People&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;, the SXSW 2025 schedule, and Metacritic. These references provide verification for the information presented about the film&amp;rsquo;s production, release, and reception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to the film&amp;rsquo;s official website and its IMDb page. These links offer additional resources for those interested in learning more about the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Age_of_Disclosure&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Age_of_Disclosure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Grusch UFO whistleblower claims</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_20bdbf3bb53b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 17:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_20bdbf3bb53b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;david-grusch-former-us-military-intelligence-officers-claims-about-non-human-spacecraft-recovery&#34;&gt;David Grusch: Former U.S. Military Intelligence Officer&amp;rsquo;s Claims About &amp;ldquo;Non-Human&amp;rdquo; Spacecraft Recovery &lt;a href=&#34;#david-grusch-former-us-military-intelligence-officers-claims-about-non-human-spacecraft-recovery&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article focuses on the claims made by David Grusch, a former U.S. Air Force officer and intelligence official, regarding the U.S. government&amp;rsquo;s alleged involvement in recovering and reverse-engineering &amp;ldquo;non-human&amp;rdquo; spacecraft. It also covers the responses to these claims from various experts and government entities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Charles Grusch is introduced as an Afghanistan combat veteran and former intelligence officer who worked at the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA) and the National Reconnaissance Office (NRO). From 2019 to 2021, he served as the NRO representative to the Unidentified Aerial Phenomena Task Force. He assisted in drafting the National Defense Authorization Act of 2023, which included whistleblower protections for UFO reporting. The section notes that Congressional interest in UFOs increased prior to Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims due to the downing of four objects by the Air Force in February 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gruschs-claims&#34;&gt;Grusch&amp;rsquo;s Claims &lt;a href=&#34;#gruschs-claims&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the specific claims made by David Grusch. He alleges that the U.S. federal government maintains a highly secretive UFO retrieval program, possessing multiple spacecraft of &amp;ldquo;non-human&amp;rdquo; origin and the deceased pilots. He also claims there is evidence of white-collar crime to conceal these programs and that officials have stated people were killed to maintain secrecy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grusch further elaborated on his claims in an interview with &lt;em&gt;Le Parisien&lt;/em&gt;, suggesting UFOs could be from extra dimensions and that the U.S. government transferred crashed UFOs to a defense contractor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a Congressional hearing in July 2023, Grusch testified that he was informed of a multi-decade UAP crash retrieval and reverse-engineering program, but was denied access. He stated that the U.S. government possesses UAP based on interviews with 40 witnesses. He also claimed the U.S. has retrieved &amp;ldquo;non-human &amp;lsquo;biologics&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; from the crafts. When asked about harm or injury related to cover-ups, Grusch said yes, but could only provide details in a SCIF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;responses-from-relevant-experts&#34;&gt;Responses from Relevant Experts &lt;a href=&#34;#responses-from-relevant-experts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents the perspectives of various experts on Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims. It highlights that his assertions are primarily based on alleged documents and conversations, rather than testable evidence. The scientific community generally views claims of government concealment of extraterrestrial visitation as untrue due to a lack of supporting evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joshua Semeter of NASA&amp;rsquo;s UAP independent study team emphasizes the lack of data or material evidence. Adam Frank, an astrophysics professor, criticizes the claims as hearsay. Stuart Clark&amp;rsquo;s opinion piece in &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; includes questions from scientists like Avi Loeb, Michael Garrett, and Sara Russell, who point out the lack of observed extraterrestrial activity and the ease of identifying extraterrestrial materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg Eghigian, a history professor, notes the historical pattern of individuals making &amp;ldquo;bombshell allegations&amp;rdquo; about UFOs without corroboration. Seth Shostak of the SETI Institute questions the lack of physical evidence and dismisses the claims as an &amp;ldquo;argument from authority.&amp;rdquo; Michael Shermer of &lt;em&gt;Skeptic&lt;/em&gt; magazine notes the absence of physical evidence and scientific community involvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Physicist Sean M. Carroll calls the evidence &amp;ldquo;laughable&amp;rdquo; and describes Grusch as a &amp;ldquo;complete crackpot.&amp;rdquo; NASA&amp;rsquo;s JPL director Laurie Leshin denies seeing spacecraft from outside Earth. Michio Kaku suggests the burden of proof has shifted to the Pentagon, a statement Ross Pomeroy criticizes as unscientific.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;responses-from-the-united-states-government&#34;&gt;Responses from the United States Government &lt;a href=&#34;#responses-from-the-united-states-government&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the responses from various U.S. government entities to Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;White House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre referred questions to the Department of Defense (DoD). The Pentagon stated that AARO has not discovered any verifiable information to substantiate claims of programs regarding the possession or reverse-engineering of extraterrestrial materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General Mark Milley, Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, stated he had never encountered evidence to verify Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims. NASA stated it has not found any credible evidence of extraterrestrial life and no evidence that UAPs are extraterrestrial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representative Mike Turner, chairman of the House Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, stated there is no evidence to support claims of the U.S. possessing UFOs from outer space. Senator Lindsey Graham found the claims unreasonable. Senator Josh Hawley expressed less surprise, while other senators, like Kirsten Gillibrand and Marco Rubio, expressed concern about potential unbriefed special access programs and firsthand knowledge from individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senators Chuck Schumer and Mike Rounds proposed the UAP Disclosure Act 2023, an amendment to the 2024 National Defence Authorization Act, to increase access to UAP records. The enrolled bill directs the National Archives to collect government documents about UAPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members of the House Oversight Committee&amp;rsquo;s national security subcommittee received a classified briefing from the Intelligence Community Inspector General (IC IG) Thomas A. Monheim regarding UAP reporting transparency. Some members expressed frustration with the lack of new information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2023-house-committee-oversight-and-accountability-hearing&#34;&gt;2023 House Committee Oversight and Accountability Hearing &lt;a href=&#34;#2023-house-committee-oversight-and-accountability-hearing&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representatives Anna Paulina Luna and Tim Burchett organized a hearing on July 26, 2023, in response to Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims. Grusch testified, repeating his earlier UFO claims. Representative Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez asked where to look for evidence, to which Grusch offered to provide specific information in a closed environment. Officials later informed lawmakers that Grusch lacked the security clearance to discuss the issues in a SCIF. A bipartisan group of U.S. representatives called for the formation of a select committee on UAPs with subpoena power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AARO&amp;rsquo;s director Sean Kirkpatrick criticized Grusch for refusing to speak with AARO and described the hearing as &amp;ldquo;insulting&amp;rdquo; to DoD and Intelligence Community officers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sean-kirkpatrick&#34;&gt;Sean Kirkpatrick &lt;a href=&#34;#sean-kirkpatrick&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After retiring from AARO, Kirkpatrick wrote an opinion piece for &lt;em&gt;Scientific American&lt;/em&gt; stating that the US Government UFO coverup allegations &amp;ldquo;derive from inadvertent or unauthorized disclosures of legitimate U.S. programs or related R&amp;amp;D that have nothing to do with extraterrestrial issues or technology.&amp;rdquo; He described the allegations&amp;rsquo; supporters as &amp;ldquo;a small group of interconnected believers and others with possibly less than honest intentions,&amp;rdquo; who promote a &amp;ldquo;whirlwind of tall tales, fabrication and secondhand or thirdhand retellings&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an interview with Peter Bergen, Kirkpatrick said that Grusch may have misinterpreted things or fallen under the influence of a core group of people. He characterized the situation as a conspiracy by UFO true believers to get the government involved in investigating aliens, a &amp;ldquo;self licking ice cream cone&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;media-reporting-on-gruschs-claims&#34;&gt;Media Reporting on Grusch&amp;rsquo;s Claims &lt;a href=&#34;#media-reporting-on-gruschs-claims&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines how the media has covered Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;connections-to-studies-funded-by-robert-bigelow&#34;&gt;Connections to Studies Funded by Robert Bigelow &lt;a href=&#34;#connections-to-studies-funded-by-robert-bigelow&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keith Kloor writing for &lt;em&gt;Scientific American&lt;/em&gt; draws a connection between Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims and studies funded by Robert Bigelow, noting the specific reference to &amp;ldquo;a football field–sized UFO&amp;rdquo; in both Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims and past claims by Bigelow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reporting-on-psychiatric-treatment-received-by-grusch&#34;&gt;Reporting on Psychiatric Treatment Received by Grusch &lt;a href=&#34;#reporting-on-psychiatric-treatment-received-by-grusch&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ken Klippenstein reported in &lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt; that Grusch was twice committed after incidents involving drunkenness and suicidal comments. Police records mentioned PTSD. Grusch was placed under an emergency custody order and transported to an emergency room, then transferred to an inpatient psychiatric program. The article noted that Grusch&amp;rsquo;s ability to keep his security clearance despite this history &amp;ldquo;appears to contrast with the government&amp;rsquo;s treatment of other employees&amp;rdquo;. Grusch later sued Loudoun County Sheriff for releasing the information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;news-stories-and-commentary&#34;&gt;News Stories and Commentary &lt;a href=&#34;#news-stories-and-commentary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick Pope, who previously ran the British Ministry of Defense &amp;ldquo;UFO Desk,&amp;rdquo; expressed hope for confirmation but notes the difficulty given Grusch&amp;rsquo;s lost security clearance and lack of a &amp;ldquo;smoking gun.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marina Koren wrote in &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt; that the case fits a pattern of unprovable claims. Matt Laslo, writing for &lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt;, described the sympathetic hearing of Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims by some members of Congress as an indication that once-fringe notions have built-in fan bases. Tucker Carlson publicized the claims in a video posted to Twitter and in an interview with Grusch. Tom Rogan, writing in the &lt;em&gt;Washington Examiner&lt;/em&gt;, was skeptical but opined that the claims should be investigated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Prokop, writing for &lt;em&gt;Vox&lt;/em&gt;, noted that skeptics question whether Grusch is repeating tall tales and that mainstream media sources have remained wary. Sean Thomas expressed confusion that others have tried to convince officials and the public that UFOs are worthy of serious consideration. &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; columnist Ross Douthat noted that one interpretation is that parts of the U.S. government see benefit in promoting belief in UFOs. Matt Stieb, writing for &lt;em&gt;New York&lt;/em&gt;, described Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims as &amp;ldquo;crazy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ezra Klein, a columnist with &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, interviewed Leslie Kean, noting the polarized reactions to the story. Steven Greenstreet, a documentary filmmaker, criticized Grusch for associating with ufologists Jeremy Corbell and George Knapp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story received attention from multiple foreign mainstream news outlets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disinformation-campaign-allegations&#34;&gt;Disinformation Campaign Allegations &lt;a href=&#34;#disinformation-campaign-allegations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grusch claimed that intentional disinformation was being promoted by the US government to cast doubt on the veracity of &amp;ldquo;non-human&amp;rdquo; UFO claims. Adam Gabbatt of &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; described Grusch&amp;rsquo;s position as &amp;ldquo;a common conspiracy trope in the UFO community&amp;rdquo;. Others have suggested that Grusch was given disinformation about aliens to encourage belief in the extraordinary claim of aliens. Gareth Nicholson, editor for the *South&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Grusch&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Grusch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Grusch UFO whistleblower claims</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_daddd7e70514/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 17:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_daddd7e70514/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;david-grusch-former-us-military-intelligence-officers-claims-about-non-human-spacecraft-recovery&#34;&gt;David Grusch: Former U.S. Military Intelligence Officer&amp;rsquo;s Claims About &amp;ldquo;Non-Human&amp;rdquo; Spacecraft Recovery &lt;a href=&#34;#david-grusch-former-us-military-intelligence-officers-claims-about-non-human-spacecraft-recovery&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article focuses on the claims made by David Grusch, a former U.S. Air Force officer and intelligence official, regarding the U.S. government&amp;rsquo;s alleged involvement in recovering and reverse-engineering &amp;ldquo;non-human&amp;rdquo; spacecraft. It also covers the responses to these claims from various experts and government entities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Charles Grusch is introduced as an Afghanistan combat veteran and former intelligence officer who worked at the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA) and the National Reconnaissance Office (NRO). From 2019 to 2021, he served as the NRO representative to the Unidentified Aerial Phenomena Task Force. He assisted in drafting the National Defense Authorization Act of 2023, which included whistleblower protections for UFO reporting. The section notes that Congressional interest in UFOs increased prior to Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims due to the downing of four objects by the Air Force in February 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gruschs-claims&#34;&gt;Grusch&amp;rsquo;s Claims &lt;a href=&#34;#gruschs-claims&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details Grusch&amp;rsquo;s allegations, which were initially reported by Leslie Kean and Ralph Blumenthal in &lt;em&gt;The Debrief&lt;/em&gt;. Grusch claims the U.S. government possesses multiple spacecraft of &amp;ldquo;non-human&amp;rdquo; origin and the corpses of their pilots. He alleges a secret UFO retrieval program, &amp;ldquo;substantive evidence&amp;rdquo; of white-collar crime to conceal UFO programs, and that officials have stated people have been killed to conceal these programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an interview with &lt;em&gt;Le Parisien&lt;/em&gt;, Grusch elaborated, suggesting UFOs could be from extra dimensions, mentioning &amp;ldquo;football-field&amp;rdquo; sized crafts, the transfer of crashed UFOs to defense contractors, and &amp;ldquo;malevolent activity&amp;rdquo; by UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a Congressional hearing in July 2023, Grusch testified about being informed of a multi-decade UAP crash retrieval and reverse-engineering program to which he was denied access. He stated his belief that the U.S. government possesses UAP based on interviews with 40 witnesses. He also claimed the U.S. has retrieved &amp;ldquo;non-human &amp;lsquo;biologics&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; from the crafts. When asked about harm or injury related to cover-ups, Grusch said yes, but could only provide details in a SCIF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;responses-from-relevant-experts&#34;&gt;Responses from Relevant Experts &lt;a href=&#34;#responses-from-relevant-experts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents the views of various experts on Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims. It highlights that his assertions are based on alleged documents and conversations, rather than testable evidence. The scientific community generally considers claims of government conspiracy to conceal extraterrestrial visitation untrue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joshua Semeter of NASA&amp;rsquo;s UAP independent study team states that without data or material evidence, evaluating the claims is impossible. Adam Frank, an astrophysics professor, criticizes the claims as hearsay and lacking extraordinary evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stuart Clark&amp;rsquo;s opinion piece in &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; includes questions from scientists like Avi Loeb, Michael Garrett, and Sara Russell, who point out the lack of observed extraterrestrial activity and the ease of identifying extraterrestrial materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg Eghigian, a history professor and UFO expert, notes the historical pattern of individuals making &amp;ldquo;bombshell allegations&amp;rdquo; about UFOs and the lack of corroboration. Seth Shostak, senior astronomer at the SETI Institute, questions the absence of physical evidence and dismisses the claims as an &amp;ldquo;argument from authority.&amp;rdquo; Michael Shermer, publisher of &lt;em&gt;Skeptic&lt;/em&gt; magazine, notes the lack of physical evidence and scientific community involvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Physicist Sean M. Carroll calls Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims &amp;ldquo;laughable&amp;rdquo; and describes him as a &amp;ldquo;complete crackpot.&amp;rdquo; NASA&amp;rsquo;s JPL director, Laurie Leshin, denies having seen spacecraft from outside this world. Michio Kaku suggests the burden of proof has shifted to the Pentagon, a statement criticized by Ross Pomeroy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;responses-from-the-united-states-government&#34;&gt;Responses from the United States Government &lt;a href=&#34;#responses-from-the-united-states-government&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the responses from various U.S. government entities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;department-of-defense-and-nasa&#34;&gt;Department of Defense and NASA &lt;a href=&#34;#department-of-defense-and-nasa&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;White House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre referred questions to the Department of Defense (DoD). A Pentagon spokesperson stated that AARO has not discovered verifiable information to substantiate claims of programs regarding the possession or reverse-engineering of extraterrestrial materials. General Mark Milley stated he had never encountered evidence verifying Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims. NASA stated it has not found credible evidence of extraterrestrial life and that there is no evidence that UAPs are extraterrestrial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;congress&#34;&gt;Congress &lt;a href=&#34;#congress&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representative Mike Turner stated there is no evidence of the U.S. possessing UFOs from outer space. Senator Lindsey Graham found the claims unreasonable. Senator Josh Hawley said the allegations sounded close to what they were &amp;ldquo;grudgingly admitted to us in the briefing&amp;rdquo;. Senator Kirsten Gillibrand intends to hold a hearing to assess whether &amp;ldquo;rogue SAP programs&amp;rdquo; existed. Senator Marco Rubio said people with &amp;ldquo;first-hand knowledge&amp;rdquo; have shared information with his committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In July 2023, Senators Chuck Schumer and Mike Rounds proposed the UAP Disclosure Act 2023, an amendment to the 2024 National Defence Authorization Act, to provide wider access to UAP records. The enrolled bill directs the National Archives to collect government documents about UAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January 2024, members of the House Oversight Committee received a classified briefing from the Intelligence Community Inspector General (IC IG) Thomas A. Monheim regarding UAP reporting transparency. Some members were frustrated by the lack of new information regarding Grusch&amp;rsquo;s allegations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2023-house-committee-oversight-and-accountability-hearing&#34;&gt;2023 House Committee Oversight and Accountability Hearing &lt;a href=&#34;#2023-house-committee-oversight-and-accountability-hearing&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representatives Anna Paulina Luna and Tim Burchett organized a hearing on July 26, 2023, in response to Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims. Grusch testified, repeating his earlier UFO claims. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez asked where to look for evidence, and Grusch offered to provide specifics in a closed environment. Officials later informed lawmakers that Grusch lacked security clearance to discuss the issues in a SCIF. Following the hearing, a bipartisan group of U.S. representatives called for the formation of a select committee on UAPs with subpoena power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AARO&amp;rsquo;s director Sean Kirkpatrick wrote that Grusch &amp;ldquo;has refused to speak with AARO&amp;rdquo; and that the hearing was &amp;ldquo;insulting&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sean-kirkpatrick&#34;&gt;Sean Kirkpatrick &lt;a href=&#34;#sean-kirkpatrick&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After retiring from AARO, Kirkpatrick wrote an opinion piece for &lt;em&gt;Scientific American&lt;/em&gt; stating that the US Government UFO coverup allegations &amp;ldquo;derive from inadvertent or unauthorized disclosures of legitimate U.S. programs or related R&amp;amp;D that have nothing to do with extraterrestrial issues or technology.&amp;rdquo; He described the allegations&amp;rsquo; supporters as &amp;ldquo;a small group of interconnected believers and others with possibly less than honest intentions,&amp;rdquo; who promote a &amp;ldquo;whirlwind of tall tales, fabrication and secondhand or thirdhand retellings&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an interview with Peter Bergen, Kirkpatrick said that Grusch may have misinterpreted things or fallen under the influence of a core group of people. He characterized the situation as a &amp;ldquo;self licking ice cream cone,&amp;rdquo; where UFO true believers are carrying out a conspiracy to get the government involved in investigating aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;media-reporting-on-gruschs-claims&#34;&gt;Media Reporting on Grusch&amp;rsquo;s Claims &lt;a href=&#34;#media-reporting-on-gruschs-claims&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines how the media has covered Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;connections-to-studies-funded-by-robert-bigelow&#34;&gt;Connections to Studies Funded by Robert Bigelow &lt;a href=&#34;#connections-to-studies-funded-by-robert-bigelow&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keith Kloor draws a connection between Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims and studies funded by Robert Bigelow, noting specific references to &amp;ldquo;a football field–sized UFO&amp;rdquo; in both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reporting-on-psychiatric-treatment-received-by-grusch&#34;&gt;Reporting on Psychiatric Treatment Received by Grusch &lt;a href=&#34;#reporting-on-psychiatric-treatment-received-by-grusch&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ken Klippenstein reported in &lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt; that Grusch was twice committed after incidents involving drunkenness and suicidal comments. Police records mentioned PTSD. Grusch was placed under an emergency custody order and transported to an emergency room. Grusch sued Loudoun County Sheriff Mike Chapman for releasing the information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;news-stories-and-commentary&#34;&gt;News Stories and Commentary &lt;a href=&#34;#news-stories-and-commentary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick Pope, who previously ran the British Ministry of Defense &amp;ldquo;UFO Desk&amp;rdquo;, expressed doubt about confirming Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims. Marina Koren wrote that the case fits a pattern of unprovable claims. Matt Laslo described the sympathetic hearing of Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims by some members of Congress as an indication that &amp;ldquo;once-fringe notions have built-in fan bases in today&amp;rsquo;s Capitol&amp;rdquo;. Tucker Carlson publicized the claims. Tom Rogan was skeptical but opined that they should be further investigated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Prokop wrote that skeptics question whether Grusch is repeating tall tales. Sean Thomas expressed confusion that others have tried to convince officials and the public that UFOs are worthy of serious considerations. Ross Douthat noted that one interpretation is that parts of the U.S. government see benefit in promoting belief in UFOs. Matt Stieb described Grusch&amp;rsquo;s claims as &amp;ldquo;crazy&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ezra Klein interviewed Leslie Kean, noting that reactions to her story about Grusch have been either to embrace it as definitive truth or dismiss it out of hand. Steven Greenstreet criticized Grusch for previously attending UFO conventions and associating with Jeremy Corbell and George Knapp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story received attention from multiple foreign mainstream news outlets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disinformation-campaign-allegations&#34;&gt;Disinformation Campaign Allegations &lt;a href=&#34;#disinformation-campaign-allegations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grusch claimed that intentional disinformation was being promoted by the US government to cast doubt on the veracity of &amp;ldquo;non-human&amp;rdquo; UFO claims. Adam Gabbatt described Grusch&amp;rsquo;s position as &amp;ldquo;a common conspiracy trope in the UFO community&amp;rdquo;. Others have suggested that Grusch was given disinformation about aliens. Gareth Nicholson wrote that &amp;ldquo;the current UAP flap could be an attempt by the US military to engage in a disinformation campaign to disguise real aerospace breakthroughs or an attempt to flush out advanced technologies held by rivals such as Russia and China&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Grusch_UFO_whistleblower_claims&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Grusch_UFO_whistleblower_claims&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roswell incident</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e0eebde49501/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e0eebde49501/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-legend-caused-by-1947-balloon-crash-roswell-incident&#34;&gt;UFO Legend Caused by 1947 Balloon Crash: Roswell Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-legend-caused-by-1947-balloon-crash-roswell-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Roswell incident is a cornerstone of UFO lore, stemming from the recovery of debris near Roswell, New Mexico, in 1947. Initially reported as a &amp;ldquo;flying disc&amp;rdquo; capture, the U.S. Army quickly retracted the statement, claiming it was a weather balloon. This event, coupled with subsequent government explanations and retractions, fueled decades of conspiracy theories alleging a cover-up of extraterrestrial contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1947-military-balloon-crash&#34;&gt;1947 Military Balloon Crash &lt;a href=&#34;#1947-military-balloon-crash&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the initial event and its immediate aftermath. In 1947, rancher W.W. &amp;ldquo;Mac&amp;rdquo; Brazel discovered debris on his property near Corona, New Mexico. The debris consisted of tinfoil, rubber, tape, and wooden beams. Unaware of the ongoing &amp;ldquo;flying disc craze,&amp;rdquo; Brazel initially didn&amp;rsquo;t connect the debris to UFOs. However, after visiting Corona, his uncle suggested it could be from a &amp;ldquo;flying disk.&amp;rdquo; Brazel reported the findings to Sheriff George Wilcox, who contacted Roswell Army Air Field (RAAF).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RAAF sent Major Jesse Marcel and Captain Sheridan Cavitt to investigate. A press release issued by public information officer Walter Haut announced the military&amp;rsquo;s recovery of a &amp;ldquo;flying disc.&amp;rdquo; This announcement made international headlines but was quickly retracted. General Roger Ramey and weather officer Irving Newton identified the material as a weather balloon at a press conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufo-conspiracy-theories-19471978&#34;&gt;UFO Conspiracy Theories (1947–1978) &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-conspiracy-theories-19471978&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the period between the initial incident and the rise of modern Roswell conspiracy theories. The Roswell debris retrieval faded from public attention for three decades. However, belief in government UFO cover-ups grew, fueled by hoaxes and legends of crashed spaceships and alien bodies in New Mexico. The Aztec, New Mexico crashed saucer hoax introduced the idea of recovered alien bodies, which later became associated with Roswell. The concept of &amp;ldquo;Hangar 18,&amp;rdquo; a fictional location at Wright-Patterson Air Force Base, emerged as a storage site for alien craft and bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;roswell-conspiracy-theories-19781994&#34;&gt;Roswell Conspiracy Theories (1978–1994) &lt;a href=&#34;#roswell-conspiracy-theories-19781994&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the resurgence of interest in Roswell and the development of modern conspiracy theories. In 1978, ufologist Stanton Friedman interviewed Jesse Marcel, who stated that the &amp;ldquo;weather balloon&amp;rdquo; explanation was a cover story and that he believed the debris was extraterrestrial. This interview, along with subsequent media attention, reignited interest in the Roswell incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1980 book &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt; by Charles Berlitz and Bill Moore popularized Marcel&amp;rsquo;s account and added the claim of alien bodies found on the Plains of San Agustin. The book also connected Marcel&amp;rsquo;s account to Lydia Sleppy, a former teletype operator who claimed she was ordered to stop transmitting a story about crashed saucer wreckage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Majestic 12 hoax, involving faked government documents, emerged in the 1980s, further fueling conspiracy theories. Glenn Dennis, a former mortician, provided an account of extraterrestrial corpses, which was endorsed by prominent Roswell ufologists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competing accounts of the Roswell incident led to a schism among ufologists in the early 1990s. &lt;em&gt;UFO Crash at Roswell&lt;/em&gt; by Kevin Randle and Donald Schmitt added testimony from new witnesses. &lt;em&gt;Crash at Corona&lt;/em&gt; by Stanton Friedman and Don Berliner introduced the idea of two crashed saucers and eight aliens. &lt;em&gt;The Truth About the UFO Crash at Roswell&lt;/em&gt; by Randle and Schmitt proposed a new crash site and a different group of archaeologists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;air-force-response&#34;&gt;Air Force Response &lt;a href=&#34;#air-force-response&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the official government response to the growing Roswell conspiracy theories. Under pressure from New Mexico congressman Steven Schiff and the General Accounting Office (GAO), the Air Force published reports in the mid-1990s. The initial 1994 report admitted that the weather balloon explanation was a cover story for Project Mogul, a military surveillance program. The 1995 report, &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Report: Fact vs. Fiction in the New Mexico Desert&lt;/em&gt;, supported this with documentation that narrowed the cause of the debris to a specific Mogul balloon train. The 1997 report, &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Report: Case Closed&lt;/em&gt;, detailed how eyewitness accounts of military personnel loading aliens into &amp;ldquo;body bags&amp;rdquo; matched the Air Force&amp;rsquo;s procedures for retrieving parachute test dummies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;later-theories-and-hoaxes-1994present&#34;&gt;Later Theories and Hoaxes (1994–Present) &lt;a href=&#34;#later-theories-and-hoaxes-1994present&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the continued development of Roswell theories and hoaxes in recent decades. &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy: Fact or Fiction&lt;/em&gt;, a pseudo-documentary, played a major role in shaping popular opinion of Roswell. The film centered around Ray Santilli&amp;rsquo;s hoaxed footage of an alien autopsy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1997, retired army intelligence officer Philip J. Corso released &lt;em&gt;The Day After Roswell&lt;/em&gt;, alleging that he was shown a nonhuman body and helped oversee a project to reverse engineer recovered crash debris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other theories include Annie Jacobsen&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Area 51: An Uncensored History of America&amp;rsquo;s Top Secret Military Base&lt;/em&gt;, which featured a claim that Nazi doctor Josef Mengele was recruited by Soviet leader Joseph Stalin to produce &amp;ldquo;grotesque, child-size aviators.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;explanations&#34;&gt;Explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents the explanations for the Roswell incident, focusing on Project Mogul and anthropomorphic dummies. The Air Force reports identified Project Mogul as the source of the 1947 debris and concluded that other alien crash accounts were likely misidentified military programs or accidents. The 1997 Air Force report concluded that the alleged &amp;ldquo;bodies&amp;rdquo; reported by later eyewitnesses came from memories of accidents involving military casualties and memories of the recovery of anthropomorphic dummies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultural-impact&#34;&gt;Cultural Impact &lt;a href=&#34;#cultural-impact&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the impact of the Roswell incident on tourism, commercialization, and popular fiction. Roswell&amp;rsquo;s tourism industry is based on ufology museums and businesses, as well as alien-themed iconography. A yearly UFO festival has been held since 1995.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incident has been depicted in numerous films and television shows, including &lt;em&gt;Hangar 18&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Independence Day&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Roswell&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Widespread speculation of a cover-up led to United States presidents being questioned about the Roswell incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell_UFO_incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell_UFO_incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien Hunter (2003 Film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ef89d1d65030/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 11:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ef89d1d65030/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-hunter-2003-film&#34;&gt;Alien Hunter (2003 Film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-hunter-2003-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry provides information about the 2003 American-Bulgarian science fiction thriller film &lt;em&gt;Alien Hunter&lt;/em&gt;. It includes details about the film&amp;rsquo;s production, plot, cast, and links to external resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot summary details a series of events triggered by a mysterious signal. In 1947, a radio operator disappears while investigating a signal from Roswell, New Mexico. In the present day, the same signal reappears, originating from the South Pole. Cryptologist Julian Rome (played by James Spader) is recruited to investigate an alien object discovered in Antarctica. The object, emitting the signal, contains a deadly virus and an alien. The virus kills members of the research team and threatens a global pandemic. A nuclear strike is ordered to contain the threat. Julian communicates with the alien before it is killed, discovering the virus&amp;rsquo;s potential to destroy all life on Earth. Julian and three others are rescued by an alien spacecraft moments before the nuclear strike. The government covers up the incident, claiming a nuclear reactor meltdown. The film concludes with the alien spacecraft carrying the survivors leaving the solar system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the actors and the characters they portray in the film. Key actors include James Spader as Julian Rome, John Lynch as Dr. Michael Straub, Leslie Stefanson as Nyla Olson, and Carl Lewis as Grisham. Other notable cast members include Roy Dotrice and Keir Dullea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a reference to &lt;em&gt;The Thing&lt;/em&gt; (1982 film), suggesting a thematic similarity or influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is empty, indicating a lack of citations within the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to the film&amp;rsquo;s entry on IMDb, the TCM Movie Database, and a full film on YouTube via Crackle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Hunter&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Hunter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Sur UFO</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_76b62dd0f587/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 12:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_76b62dd0f587/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-big-sur-ufo&#34;&gt;The Big Sur UFO &lt;a href=&#34;#the-big-sur-ufo&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details a reported UFO incident that allegedly occurred during a 1964 Air Force mission near Big Sur, California. The Air Force team was stationed on a mountaintop to film Atlas missile tests from Vandenberg Air Force Base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;air-force-deployment-to-anderson-peak&#34;&gt;Air Force deployment to Anderson Peak &lt;a href=&#34;#air-force-deployment-to-anderson-peak&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From August to November 1964, the U.S. Air Force deployed personnel to the Los Padres National Forest in California. They used a special telescope borrowed from Boston University to photograph missile launches from Vandenberg Air Force Base. Lt. Robert Jacobs was the commander for the Big Sur location, managed by the 1369th Photo Squadron. The team successfully filmed nine launches, including one of an Atlas missile called &amp;ldquo;Buzzing Bee,&amp;rdquo; capturing footage of a re-entry vehicle deploying decoy warheads. This technology was highly classified and designed to protect American nuclear weapons from Soviet interception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fringe-claims-of-extra-terrestrials&#34;&gt;Fringe claims of extra-terrestrials &lt;a href=&#34;#fringe-claims-of-extra-terrestrials&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1982, Robert Jacobs wrote about the incident in the tabloid &lt;em&gt;National Enquirer&lt;/em&gt;, claiming he had been part of a cover-up and was now breaking his silence. He described film footage of an unidentified object next to a warhead and a senior official&amp;rsquo;s reaction. Jacobs claimed he was instructed to never discuss the film. Major Florenz Mansmann reportedly confirmed Jacobs&amp;rsquo; account in a 1987 letter. Robert Hastings, a UFO author, further popularized the story in 2007. In 2021, Jacobs participated in a press conference to discuss his interpretation of the incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;decoy-warheads-explanation&#34;&gt;Decoy warheads explanation &lt;a href=&#34;#decoy-warheads-explanation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kingston A. George, the project engineer during the incident, disputed Jacob&amp;rsquo;s claims of extraterrestrial interference in the &lt;em&gt;Skeptical Inquirer&lt;/em&gt;. George stated that he, too, had seen footage he wasn&amp;rsquo;t cleared to see and was instructed not to speak of it. However, George claims he knew the true purpose of the test: filming the deployment of decoy warheads and chaff to confuse enemy air defenses. He attributed the lights Jacobs reported to the explosive deployment of decoys and chaff, not a UFO energy beam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including articles from Military.com, Skeptical Inquirer, National Enquirer, and MUFON UFO Journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the &amp;ldquo;Malmstrom UFO incident&amp;rdquo; Wikipedia page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Sur_UFO&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Sur_UFO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Roswell Incident (1980 book)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_35f31e4c5c9f/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 19:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_35f31e4c5c9f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-roswell-incident-1980-book&#34;&gt;The Roswell Incident (1980 book) &lt;a href=&#34;#the-roswell-incident-1980-book&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry details the 1980 book &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt; by Charles Berlitz and William Moore, which significantly contributed to popularizing the Roswell incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for the Roswell incident, focusing on the events of 1947 and the renewed interest in the story in the late 1970s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;events-of-1947&#34;&gt;Events of 1947 &lt;a href=&#34;#events-of-1947&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection outlines the initial reports of the Roswell incident during the &amp;ldquo;flying disc craze&amp;rdquo; of 1947, Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting, the Roswell Army Air Field&amp;rsquo;s initial press release about recovering a crashed disc, and the subsequent retraction stating it was a weather balloon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;roswell-revisited&#34;&gt;Roswell revisited &lt;a href=&#34;#roswell-revisited&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explains how the Roswell story gained traction again in 1978 when retired lieutenant colonel Jesse Marcel claimed in an interview with ufologist Stanton Friedman that the debris he recovered was extraterrestrial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;authors&#34;&gt;Authors &lt;a href=&#34;#authors&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides background information on the authors of the book, Charles Berlitz and William Moore. It mentions Berlitz&amp;rsquo;s previous success with &lt;em&gt;The Bermuda Triangle&lt;/em&gt; and their collaboration on &lt;em&gt;The Philadelphia Experiment: Project Invisibility&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents &lt;a href=&#34;#contents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the book&amp;rsquo;s central argument: that an extraterrestrial craft crashed in New Mexico while observing nuclear weapons activity, and the US government engaged in a cover-up. It highlights accounts of debris described as &amp;ldquo;nothing made on this earth&amp;rdquo; and mentions witnesses like Bill Brazel, Floyd Proctor, and Walt Whitman Jr. The section also notes the book&amp;rsquo;s introduction of the idea that the debris shown in photos with Marcel was substituted as part of the cover-up. It also mentions the claim that the military sought to discredit the growing interest in flying saucers. The section also notes that the authors claimed to have interviewed over 90 witnesses, but only a fraction of those accounts appear in the book. The section also notes that the book elevated Marcel&amp;rsquo;s narrative above that of Cavitt, whose description of the debris contradicted Marcel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-bodies&#34;&gt;Alien bodies &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-bodies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the book&amp;rsquo;s introduction of the story about Barney Barnett and archaeology students encountering wreckage and &amp;ldquo;alien bodies&amp;rdquo; on the Plains of San Agustin. It also mentions the conflation of the Roswell incident with the Aztec, New Mexico, UFO incident, a hoaxed flying saucer crash promoted by Frank Scully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the reception of the book, noting that critics deemed it &amp;ldquo;a collection of wild hearsay&amp;rdquo; and that it &amp;ldquo;did not make the commercial impact its authors hoped.&amp;rdquo; It also mentions accusations against Moore regarding the Majestic 12 documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aftermath&#34;&gt;Aftermath &lt;a href=&#34;#aftermath&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions Moore&amp;rsquo;s admission at a 1989 MUFON conference that he had engaged in &amp;ldquo;disinformation&amp;rdquo; activities against Paul Bennewitz on behalf of the Air Force Office of Special Investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modern-views&#34;&gt;Modern views &lt;a href=&#34;#modern-views&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section references the 1993 inquiry by the General Accounting Office in response to US congressman Steven Schiff, which led to a 1994 Air Force report concluding that the recovered material was likely debris from Project Mogul, a military surveillance program using high-altitude balloons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Roswell_Incident_(1980_book)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Roswell_Incident_(1980_book)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO Coverup? Live</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_de7d5a729491/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 04:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_de7d5a729491/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-coverup-live&#34;&gt;UFO Coverup? Live &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-coverup-live&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UFO Coverup? Live&lt;/em&gt; (also known as &lt;em&gt;UFO&amp;hellip; The Unsolved Mystery&lt;/em&gt; on VHS) was a US television broadcast that aired in syndication on October 14, 1988. It is notable for introducing the Majestic 12 hoax to a wide audience and for being the first public mention of Area 51 as a site associated with aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;synopsis&#34;&gt;Synopsis &lt;a href=&#34;#synopsis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program, hosted by Mike Farrell, imitated a live broadcast format despite being pre-recorded. It featured interviews with various figures involved in UFO research and skepticism. Key topics discussed included the 1952 Washington, D.C., UFO incident, the Mantell UFO incident, and the Tehran UFO incident. The program also touched on notable hoaxers like George Adamski and Billy Meier. Soviet UFOlogists were interviewed about Soviet events, including the Tunguska blast. The show included segments on alien abduction experiences, featuring interviews with Budd Hopkins and psychiatrist Rima E. Laibow. The Roswell incident was discussed with Bill Moore, Stanton Friedman, and Jesse Marcel Jr. Robert Emenegger and Paul Shartle were interviewed about the Holloman UFO incident. Skeptics David Williamson, James Oberg, and Herbert Spiegel provided counterpoints. The program incorporated clips from various science fiction films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A significant portion of the program focused on the Majestic 12 documents, drawing on the work of Bill Moore and Jaime Shandera. Shadow-clad informants Falcon (Richard Doty) and Condor were interviewed, claiming that the US government had agreements with aliens from Zeta Reticuli, who operated a base in Nevada called Area 51. Falcon claimed the aliens were called EBEs and one of them liked strawberry ice cream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reactions&#34;&gt;Reactions &lt;a href=&#34;#reactions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program received mixed reactions. Philip J. Imbrogno criticized the show for making the study of UFOs look silly, particularly due to the mention of an alien liking strawberry ice cream. Bill Moore admitted that the program contained disinformation. Stanton Friedman expressed regret for his participation, citing issues with the teleprompter and the untrustworthiness of &amp;ldquo;Falcon&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Condor.&amp;rdquo; Bill Knell argued that the program brought the UFO phenomenon to a wider audience. &lt;em&gt;UFO Coverup? Live&lt;/em&gt; influenced Chris Carter&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article lists similar films:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unidentified Flying Objects: The True Story of Flying Saucers&lt;/em&gt;, a similar film from 1956&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;UFOs: Past, Present, and Future&lt;/em&gt;, a similar film from 1974&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_Cover_Up%3F_Live&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_Cover_Up%3F_Live&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
