<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Literature on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/literature/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Literature on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 14:49:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/literature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>List of humanoid aliens</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_889911f31664/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_889911f31664/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-humanoid-aliens&#34;&gt;List of Humanoid Aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-humanoid-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Wikipedia entry is a compilation of fictional extraterrestrial humanoid characters from various media. It emphasizes that these aliens possess human-like traits such as upright posture, bipedalism, opposable thumbs, and facial features. The list is organized by medium: Animation, Comics, Film, Literature, Television, and Video Games. Each entry includes the character&amp;rsquo;s name, origin (the work in which they appear), and brief notes about their role or characteristics. The article is flagged as needing additional citations for verification and may not be complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;animation&#34;&gt;Animation &lt;a href=&#34;#animation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists humanoid aliens featured in animated works. Key characters include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Great Gazoo&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Flintstones&lt;/em&gt;): A tiny alien exiled to Earth who can only be seen by Fred, Barney, children, and animals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cure Princess/Hime Shirayuki&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;HappinessCharge PreCure!&lt;/em&gt;): A princess from the Blue Sky Kingdom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mikitaka Hazekura&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;JoJo&amp;rsquo;s Bizarre Adventure&lt;/em&gt;): An alien who appears as a teenage boy with pointed ears.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interplanet Janet&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Schoolhouse Rock&lt;/em&gt;): A cyborg girl from another galaxy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jet Propulsion&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Ready Jet Go!&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from Bortron 7 studying Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cure Milky/Lala Hagoromo&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Star Twinkle PreCure&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from the planet Samaan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Little Twelvetoes&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Schoolhouse Rock&lt;/em&gt;): A jovial alien with green skin and six fingers and toes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marvin the Martian&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Looney Tunes&lt;/em&gt;): A Martian often accompanied by his dog K-9.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ozmodiar&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Simpsons&lt;/em&gt;): A parody of The Great Gazoo, only visible to Homer Simpson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roger&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;American Dad!&lt;/em&gt;): An alien living in Stan&amp;rsquo;s attic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sailor Starlights&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Sailor Moon&lt;/em&gt;): Sailor Guardians from Planet Kinmoku.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shadow Galactica&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Sailor Moon&lt;/em&gt;): Antagonists from various planets in the Milky Way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Son Goku&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Dragon Ball&lt;/em&gt;): A Saiyan from Planet Vegeta.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cure Cosmo/Yuni&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Star Twinkle PreCure&lt;/em&gt;): A shapeshifting catgirl from Planet Rainbow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zim&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Invader Zim&lt;/em&gt;): An Irken invader sent to conquer Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upgrade&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Ben 10&lt;/em&gt;): A Galvanic Mechamorph from Galvan B.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atomix&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Ben 10&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from an unknown planet who can create nuclear energy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comics&#34;&gt;Comics &lt;a href=&#34;#comics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details humanoid aliens from comic books. Notable entries include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Annihilus&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Fantastic Four&lt;/em&gt;): A villain from the Marvel Universe. Created by Stan Lee and Jack Kirby.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cosmo&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Cosmo the Merry Martian&lt;/em&gt;): A Martian who visits Earth. Created by Bob White.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Darna&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Darna&lt;/em&gt;): An extraterrestrial warrior who manifests in a human girl. Created by Mars Ravelo and Nestor Redondo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Khâny&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Yoko Tsuno&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from the planet Vinea. Created by Roger Leloup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plunk&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Plunk&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from the planet Smurk. Created by Luc Cromheecke and Laurent Letzer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Scrameustache&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Scrameustache&lt;/em&gt;): An alien with a cat-like face. Created by Roland Goossens (Gos).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr. Skygack&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Mr. Skygack, from Mars&lt;/em&gt;): A Martian studying human behavior. Created by A.D. Condo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Superman/Clark Kent&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Action Comics #1&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from Krypton with superhuman powers. Created by Jerry Siegel and Joe Shuster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xal-Kor&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Xal-Kor the Human Cat&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from Felis who can transform between cat, hybrid, and human forms. Created by Grass Green.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zook&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Zook&lt;/em&gt;): A Martian who visits Earth. Created by Jack Miller and Joe Certa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;film&#34;&gt;Film &lt;a href=&#34;#film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists humanoid aliens appearing in movies. Key examples include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E.T.&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial&lt;/em&gt;): An alien who befriends a human boy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Various&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/em&gt;): Includes Asgardians, members of the Guardians of the Galaxy, and Eternals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Klaatu&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Day the Earth Stood Still&lt;/em&gt;): An alien who delivers a peaceful message to Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Various&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;): Includes Chewbacca, Yoda, Darth Maul, and Ahsoka Tano.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zaphod Beeblebrox&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from near Betelgeuse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mork&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Mork and Mindy&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from Ork who studies humanity on Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Alien Girl&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Super Deluxe&lt;/em&gt;): An alien living on Earth, mingling with humans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;literature&#34;&gt;Literature &lt;a href=&#34;#literature&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section compiles humanoid aliens from literary works. Notable characters include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Little Prince&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Little Prince&lt;/em&gt;): A prince from an asteroid who visits Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Curtis&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;One Door Away from Heaven&lt;/em&gt;): A shape-shifting alien on the run.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ras Thavas&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Master Mind of Mars&lt;/em&gt;): A Martian mad scientist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Thing&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Who Goes There?&lt;/em&gt;): A shapeshifting alien that takes a human form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;television&#34;&gt;Television &lt;a href=&#34;#television&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists humanoid aliens featured in television shows. Key characters include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adric&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Doctor Who&lt;/em&gt;): A young native of Alzarius in E-Space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ALF/Gordon Shumway&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;ALF&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from Melmac who crash lands on Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beldar, Prymaat, and Connie&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Coneheads&lt;/em&gt;): An alien family from Remulak with conical heads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big Giant Head&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;3rd Rock from the Sun&lt;/em&gt;): The alien leader of the Solomons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Doctor&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Doctor Who&lt;/em&gt;): An adventurer and scientist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fofão&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Balão Mágico&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;TV Fofão&lt;/em&gt;): An extraterrestrial child character.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gonzo&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Muppet Show&lt;/em&gt;): A puppet revealed to be of extraterrestrial origin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mork&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Mork &amp;amp; Mindy&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from Ork who befriends a human woman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martin O&amp;rsquo;Hara&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;My Favorite Martian&lt;/em&gt;): A Martian anthropologist stranded on Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dick Solomon&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;3rd Rock from the Sun&lt;/em&gt;): An alien in human guise on Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry Solomon&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;3rd Rock from the Sun&lt;/em&gt;): An alien in human guise on Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sally Solomon&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;3rd Rock from the Sun&lt;/em&gt;): An alien in human guise on Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tommy Solomon&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;3rd Rock from the Sun&lt;/em&gt;): An alien in human guise on Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spock&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;): A Vulcan science officer on the Enterprise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ultraman&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Ultraman&lt;/em&gt;): A race of aliens who protect the universe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ultronians&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;My Hero&lt;/em&gt;): A species from the planet Ultron with superpowers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-games&#34;&gt;Video Games &lt;a href=&#34;#video-games&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists humanoid aliens appearing in video games. Key examples include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abe&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Oddworld&lt;/em&gt;): The central character of the &lt;em&gt;Oddworld&lt;/em&gt; series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artanis&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt;): A Protoss commander and protagonist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forerunner&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;): Ancient Humanoid Aliens that created the Halo rings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_humanoid_aliens&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_humanoid_aliens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrials in fiction</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_86feb41cd744/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 03:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_86feb41cd744/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;fictional-depictions-of-extraterrestrial-life&#34;&gt;Fictional Depictions of Extraterrestrial Life &lt;a href=&#34;#fictional-depictions-of-extraterrestrial-life&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses extraterrestrials as they are portrayed in works of fiction, distinguishing them from alleged real-life encounters. It includes a link to a separate article listing alleged extraterrestrial beings. A banner at the top indicates that the article relies heavily on a limited number of sources and needs more citations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the historical evolution of extraterrestrial depictions in fiction, starting from antiquity and progressing through modern times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;antiquity&#34;&gt;Antiquity &lt;a href=&#34;#antiquity&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers early depictions of extraterrestrials, beginning with Lucian&amp;rsquo;s 2nd-century satire &lt;em&gt;True History&lt;/em&gt;, where the protagonist visits the Moon and finds it inhabited by warring factions. It emphasizes how early concepts of extraterrestrials were tied to the development of astronomy and the understanding of celestial objects as physical entities. Early depictions often portrayed aliens as human-like, as exemplified by Voltaire&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Micromégas&lt;/em&gt; and works by Johannes Kepler, Francis Godwin, and Cyrano de Bergerac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-20th-century&#34;&gt;Early 20th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#early-20th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the impact of Charles Darwin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;On the Origin of Species&lt;/em&gt; on alien depictions, leading to the creation of non-humanoid aliens in fiction. Camille Flammarion&amp;rsquo;s works are mentioned as early examples of genuinely alien lifeforms. The section also highlights H.G. Wells&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;The War of the Worlds&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The First Men in the Moon&lt;/em&gt; as influential works that explored the implications of evolution and alien civilizations. The rise of pulp magazines and their role in popularizing science fiction with various alien tropes are also discussed, including the common use of Martians, Venusians, and other Solar System inhabitants. Stanley G. Weinbaum&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;A Martian Odyssey&lt;/em&gt; is noted for its unique Martian ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;modern-times&#34;&gt;Modern Times &lt;a href=&#34;#modern-times&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the evolution of alien depictions in more recent times. It mentions &lt;em&gt;The Eternaut&lt;/em&gt; by Héctor Germán Oesterheld, an Argentine work that critiques imperialism and colonialism through an alien invasion of Buenos Aires. The Barney and Betty Hill incident is discussed as a pivotal event that popularized the &amp;ldquo;grey alien&amp;rdquo; archetype. The influence of TV and films, particularly &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt;, is highlighted, noting the trend towards human-like aliens due to budgetary constraints. The section concludes by mentioning the impact of computer-generated imagery (CGI) on creating more diverse and bizarre alien lifeforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;types&#34;&gt;Types &lt;a href=&#34;#types&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section categorizes the various ways extraterrestrials are portrayed in fiction. It discusses differences in intelligence levels, biological forms (humanoid, Earth-species-like, or bizarre), and attitudes towards humanity (hostile, friendly, or indifferent). It also mentions that some extraterrestrials in fiction originate from unexplored areas of Earth, such as the sea, sky, underground, or other dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See Also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related Wikipedia articles, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parasites in fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of fictional extraterrestrials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of films featuring extraterrestrials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of humanoid aliens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mars in fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First contact (science fiction)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including books, journal articles, and online resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bibliography&#34;&gt;Bibliography &lt;a href=&#34;#bibliography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists additional books related to the topic of extraterrestrials in fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further Reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of additional resources for readers interested in learning more about the topic, including books and articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External Links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a link to an external website with additional information on the use of aliens as metaphors in fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_life_in_popular_culture&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_life_in_popular_culture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lists of fictional extraterrestrials</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_9db7ce81fb33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 11:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_9db7ce81fb33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lists-of-fictional-extraterrestrial-species&#34;&gt;Lists of Fictional Extraterrestrial Species &lt;a href=&#34;#lists-of-fictional-extraterrestrial-species&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page serves as a central index for various lists cataloging fictional extraterrestrial species found across different media. It also provides links to related topics like fictional species in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alphabetical&#34;&gt;Alphabetical &lt;a href=&#34;#alphabetical&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a comprehensive alphabetical listing of links to individual pages, each dedicated to fictional alien species whose names begin with a specific letter of the alphabet. This allows users to quickly navigate to species based on their name. For example, there are links for A, B, C, and so on, up to Z.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;by-medium--franchise&#34;&gt;By Medium &amp;amp; Franchise &lt;a href=&#34;#by-medium--franchise&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section organizes lists of fictional extraterrestrial species based on the specific medium or franchise in which they appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;literature&#34;&gt;Literature &lt;a href=&#34;#literature&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List of &lt;em&gt;Noon Universe&lt;/em&gt; alien races:&lt;/strong&gt; Links to the section on alien races within the &lt;em&gt;Noon Universe&lt;/em&gt;, a science fiction setting created by Arkady and Boris Strugatsky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comics&#34;&gt;Comics &lt;a href=&#34;#comics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List of alien races in DC Comics:&lt;/strong&gt; Directs to a list of alien species featured in publications by DC Comics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List of alien races in Marvel Comics:&lt;/strong&gt; Directs to a list of alien species featured in publications by Marvel Comics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;film-and-television&#34;&gt;Film and Television &lt;a href=&#34;#film-and-television&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List of Doctor Who universe creatures and aliens:&lt;/strong&gt; Links to a comprehensive list of creatures and aliens appearing in the &lt;em&gt;Doctor Who&lt;/em&gt; franchise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List of Star Trek aliens:&lt;/strong&gt; Links to a list of alien species from the &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt; universe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List of Star Wars creatures:&lt;/strong&gt; Links to a list of creatures from the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; universe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lists of Star Wars species:&lt;/strong&gt; Provides a breakdown of &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; species lists, divided alphabetically:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A–E&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;F–J&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;K–O&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;P–T&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;U–Z&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Species of the Marvel Cinematic Universe:&lt;/strong&gt; Links to a list of species appearing in the Marvel Cinematic Universe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;games&#34;&gt;Games &lt;a href=&#34;#games&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battlelords of the 23rd Century#Races:&lt;/strong&gt; Links to the section detailing alien races in the &lt;em&gt;Battlelords of the 23rd Century&lt;/em&gt; role-playing game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Races of Mass Effect:&lt;/strong&gt; Links to a list of the various alien races featured in the &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect&lt;/em&gt; video game series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Races of StarCraft:&lt;/strong&gt; Links to a list of the various alien races featured in the &lt;em&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt; video game series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;by-appearance&#34;&gt;By Appearance &lt;a href=&#34;#by-appearance&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section categorizes alien species based on their physical characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List of humanoid aliens:&lt;/strong&gt; Links to a list of alien species that resemble humans in their basic body plan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List of reptilian humanoids:&lt;/strong&gt; Links to a list of humanoid aliens that possess reptilian features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to other relevant lists and templates related to fictional life forms and science fiction in general. It includes a comprehensive table linking to lists of fictional plants, animals (categorized by type), humanoids, and other creatures, as well as templates for fictional biology and science fiction topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_fictional_extraterrestrials&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_fictional_extraterrestrials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
