<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flying Saucer on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/flying-saucer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Flying Saucer on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 23:06:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/flying-saucer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kenneth Arnold UFO sighting</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cf6ec7935450/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 23:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cf6ec7935450/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alleged-1947-sighting-in-washington-us-kenneth-arnold-ufo-sighting&#34;&gt;Alleged 1947 Sighting in Washington, US: Kenneth Arnold UFO Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#alleged-1947-sighting-in-washington-us-kenneth-arnold-ufo-sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the alleged UFO sighting by private pilot Kenneth Arnold on June 24, 1947, near Mount Rainier, Washington. This sighting is considered a seminal event in the modern history of UFOs, as it garnered nationwide news coverage and popularized the terms &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;flying disc.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sighting&#34;&gt;Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 24, 1947, Kenneth Arnold, while flying from Chehalis to Yakima, Washington, detoured to search for a crashed U.S. Marine Corps C-46 transport plane near Mount Rainier. Near Mineral, Washington, at approximately 9,200 feet, Arnold observed nine shiny objects flying in formation past Mount Rainier. He estimated their speed to be over 1,200 miles per hour. Arnold described the objects as thin, flat, and convex, with one being crescent-shaped. He likened their movement to saucers skipping on water. The objects traveled from Mount Rainier to Mount Adams in 1 minute and 42 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;arnold-shares-the-story&#34;&gt;Arnold Shares the Story &lt;a href=&#34;#arnold-shares-the-story&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After landing in Yakima, Arnold shared his experience with fellow pilots. He was interviewed by reporters from the &lt;em&gt;East Oregonian&lt;/em&gt; in Pendleton, Oregon, the next day. The reporters found Arnold to be a credible witness. Arnold expressed his desire to speak with the FBI due to the widespread attention and skepticism surrounding his account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;corroboration&#34;&gt;Corroboration &lt;a href=&#34;#corroboration&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several other individuals reported similar sightings around the same time as Arnold. L.G. Bernier of Richland, Washington, saw three objects flying towards Mount Rainier about half an hour before Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting. Ethel Wheelhouse in Yakima, Washington, also reported seeing flying discs moving at high speeds. A member of the Washington State forest service reported seeing flashes over Mount Rainier at the same time as Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting. Ten days later, a United Airlines crew over Idaho also spotted similar objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;arnold-talks-of-possible-non-earthly-origins&#34;&gt;Arnold Talks of Possible Non-Earthly Origins &lt;a href=&#34;#arnold-talks-of-possible-non-earthly-origins&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In early July 1947, Arnold discussed the possibility of extraterrestrial origins for the objects. He mentioned receiving fan mail with various interpretations, including visitations from another planet. Arnold expressed his hope that the devices were U.S. Army creations but also stated that if the government knew anything, the public should be informed. He also noted the objects&amp;rsquo; abrupt turns, suggesting they might be controlled from elsewhere, possibly another planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publicity-and-origins-of-term-flying-saucer&#34;&gt;Publicity and Origins of Term &amp;ldquo;Flying Saucer&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#publicity-and-origins-of-term-flying-saucer&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arnold&amp;rsquo;s account received widespread media coverage, appearing in numerous U.S. and Canadian newspapers. The terms &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;flying disc&amp;rdquo; became popular descriptors for UFOs following the sighting. While the exact origin of the terms is debated, it&amp;rsquo;s believed they emerged from early news stories about Arnold&amp;rsquo;s experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-term-appears&#34;&gt;The Term Appears &lt;a href=&#34;#the-term-appears&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newspapers began using the terms &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;flying disc&amp;rdquo; to describe the objects starting on June 26 and 27. The Arnold sighting is credited with popularizing these terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bequette-interview&#34;&gt;Bequette Interview &lt;a href=&#34;#bequette-interview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years later, Arnold claimed he told Bill Bequette that the objects &amp;ldquo;flew erratic, like a saucer if you skip it across the water,&amp;rdquo; emphasizing the motion rather than the shape. Bequette&amp;rsquo;s initial articles described the objects as &amp;ldquo;saucer-like&amp;rdquo; and their motion as &amp;ldquo;like fish flipping in the sun.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;military-investigation-of-arnold-story&#34;&gt;Military Investigation of Arnold Story &lt;a href=&#34;#military-investigation-of-arnold-story&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first investigation of Arnold&amp;rsquo;s claims was conducted by Lt. Frank Brown and Capt. William Davidson of Hamilton Field, California, on July 12. They concluded that Arnold likely saw what he reported. However, First Lt. Hal L. Eustace of the Army Air Corps described Arnold as &amp;ldquo;excitable&amp;rdquo; and his report as a &amp;ldquo;silly season episode.&amp;rdquo; The Army Air Force&amp;rsquo;s official conclusion was that the objects were due to a mirage. AAF intelligence, with FBI assistance, initiated a secret investigation of the best sightings, including Arnold&amp;rsquo;s. This led to the formation of Project Sign at the end of 1947, the first publicly acknowledged USAF UFO investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;widespread-ufo-reports-after-arnold-sighting&#34;&gt;Widespread UFO Reports After Arnold Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#widespread-ufo-reports-after-arnold-sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the weeks following Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting, numerous reports of similar objects flooded in from the U.S. and around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;skeptical-explanations&#34;&gt;Skeptical Explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#skeptical-explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officials at McChord Army Air Field suggested the objects could have been fast P-80 jets. Lieutenant Colonel Harry R. Turner of the White Sands Proving Ground also stated that Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting was consistent with jet airplanes. Steuart Campbell proposed that the objects were mirages of snow-capped peaks in the Cascade Range. Philip J. Klass argued that Arnold might have misidentified meteors. James Easton suggested that Arnold may have misidentified pelicans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;donald-menzels-explanations&#34;&gt;Donald Menzel&amp;rsquo;s Explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#donald-menzels-explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donald Menzel, a Harvard astronomer and UFO debunker, offered several explanations for Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting, including clouds of snow, orographic clouds, wave clouds, and spots of water on his airplane&amp;rsquo;s windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kenneth_Arnold_UFO_sighting&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kenneth_Arnold_UFO_sighting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flying saucer</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_3239f175f6ea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_3239f175f6ea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;flying-saucer&#34;&gt;Flying Saucer &lt;a href=&#34;#flying-saucer&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A flying saucer, or flying disc, is a purported type of disc-shaped unidentified flying object (UFO). The term originated in 1947 when US news media reported pilot Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s claim of seeing objects flying near his airplane over Washington State. The news reports included implausible speed estimates and preceded a wave of sightings across the US, including the Roswell incident and the Flight 105 UFO sighting. A National Guard pilot died in 1948 while pursuing a flying saucer. Civilian research groups and conspiracy theories developed around the topic, and the concept spread to other countries. Early reports speculated about secret military technology, but flying saucers became associated with aliens by 1950. The terms unidentified flying object (UFO) and unidentified anomalous phenomena (UAP) have gradually replaced the term over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An aerial photo taken over Lake Cote, Costa Rica, by Sergio Loaiza in 1971 is included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In science fiction, UFO sightings, UFO conspiracy theories, and popular culture, saucers are typically piloted by nonhuman beings. Most reported sightings describe saucers in the distance and do not mention a crew. Descriptions of the craft vary considerably. Early reports emphasized speed, but the descriptions shifted over the decades to the objects mostly hovering. They are generally said to be round, sometimes with a protrusion on top, but details of the shape vary between reports. Witnesses describe flying saucers as silent or deafening, with lights of every color, and flying alone or in formation. Size estimates range from small enough to fit in a living room to over 2,000 feet (610 m) in diameter. Sightings are most frequent at night. Astronomer Donald Howard Menzel concluded that the reports were too varied to all be describing the same type of objects. Experts have identified most reported saucers as known phenomena, including astronomical objects such as Venus, airborne objects such as balloons, and optical phenomena such as sun dogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1950s pop culture embraced flying saucers. The discs appeared in film, television, literature, music, toys, and advertising. Their reports influenced religious movements and were the subject of military investigations. The shape became visual shorthand for alien invaders. During the 1960s, saucers waned in popularity as UFOs were reported and depicted in other shapes. Discs ceased to be viewed as the standard shape for alien spacecraft but are still often depicted, sometimes for their retro value to evoke the early Cold War era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports of fantastical aircraft predate the first flying saucers. In antiquity, mysterious lights in the sky were interpreted as spiritual phenomena. In the 1800s, many newspapers reported massive airships with glowing lights and humming engines. These are often seen as precursors to flying saucer and UFO sightings. On January 25, 1878, the &lt;em&gt;Denison Daily News&lt;/em&gt; printed an article in which John Martin, a local farmer, reported an object resembling a balloon flying &amp;ldquo;at wonderful speed&amp;rdquo;. The newspaper said it appeared to be about the size of a saucer from his perspective, one of the first uses of the word &amp;ldquo;saucer&amp;rdquo; in association with a UFO. An outbreak of a number of sightings of mystery airships occurred in America in 1896 and 1897. During World War II, Allied pilots reported balls of light following their planes. They named the lights foo fighters and believed they were advanced Axis aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many aspects of the typical flying saucer first appeared in science fiction. French sociologist Bertrand Méheust noted Jean de La Hire&amp;rsquo;s 1908 novel &lt;em&gt;La Roue fulgurante&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Lightning Wheel&lt;/em&gt;). In the novel, a flying disc-shaped machine abducts the protagonists via a beam of light. Science fiction magazine &lt;em&gt;Amazing Stories&lt;/em&gt; began publishing &amp;ldquo;The Shaver Mystery&amp;rdquo; in 1945. Written by Richard Sharpe Shaver and edited by Raymond A. Palmer, they were science fiction tales about technologically advanced &amp;ldquo;detrimental robots&amp;rdquo; that abducted humans, but the stories were presented as a true account of Shaver&amp;rsquo;s life. Until the magazine ceased printing The Shaver Mystery, &lt;em&gt;Amazing Stories&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt; letter column was regularly full of readers sharing their own purportedly true sightings of the robots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the flying saucer was coined as a term, fantasy artwork in pulp magazines depicted flying discs. Skeptical physicist Milton Rothman noted the appearance of so-called flying saucers in the fantasy artwork of 1930s pulp science fiction magazines, by artists such as Frank R. Paul. One of Paul&amp;rsquo;s earliest depictions of a flying saucer appeared on the cover of the November 1929 issue of Hugo Gernsback&amp;rsquo;s pulp science fiction magazine &lt;em&gt;Science Wonder Stories&lt;/em&gt;. Science fiction illustrator Frank Wu wrote that the idea of space vehicles shaped like flying saucers was imprinted in the national psyche for many years prior to 1947, when the Roswell incident took place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;origins&#34;&gt;Origins &lt;a href=&#34;#origins&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modern flying saucer concept, including the association with aliens, can be traced to the 1947 Kenneth Arnold UFO sighting. On June 24, 1947, businessman and amateur pilot Kenneth Arnold landed at the Yakima, Washington airstrip. He told staff and friends that he&amp;rsquo;d seen nine unusual airborne objects. Arnold estimated their speed at 1,700 miles per hour, beyond the capabilities of known aircraft. Newspapers soon contacted Arnold for interviews. The &lt;em&gt;East Oregonian&lt;/em&gt; reported his supposed aircraft as &amp;ldquo;saucer-like&amp;rdquo;. In a June 26 radio interview, Arnold described them as &amp;ldquo;something like a pie plate that was cut in half with a sort of a convex triangle in the rear&amp;rdquo;. Headline writers coined the terms &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;flying disk&amp;rdquo; (or &amp;ldquo;disc&amp;rdquo;) for the story. Arnold later told CBS News that the early coverage &amp;ldquo;did not quote me properly [&amp;hellip;] when I described how they flew, I said that they flew like they take a saucer and throw it across the water. Most of the newspapers misunderstood and misquoted that, too. They said that I said that they were saucer-like; I said that they flew in a saucer-like fashion.&amp;rdquo; The circular shape of typical flying saucers may be due to reporters mistaking Arnold&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;saucer-like&amp;rdquo; description of motion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arnold&amp;rsquo;s story preceded a wave of hundreds of flying saucer reports. Lieutenant Governor of Idaho Donald S. Whitehead claimed he saw a fast-moving object resembling a meteor around the time of Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting. In early July, head of Air Materiel Command Nathan F. Twining told reporters that &amp;ldquo;anyone seeing the objects&amp;rdquo; should contact Wright Field. The next widely publicized report was the sighting by a United Airlines crew on July 4 of nine more disc-like objects pacing their plane over Idaho.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The public was divided on the potential origin of the saucers. Arnold told military intelligence officers he suspected the discs were experimental aircraft, and early newspapers reported Arnold saying, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know what they were—unless they were guided missiles.&amp;rdquo; News media speculated on a Soviet origin, and many war veterans connected them to the foo fighters seen during World War II. A Gallup Poll found that 90% of Americans were aware of the saucer stories, and 16 percent believed they were secret military weapons, most likely American. The most common explanation given was some type of illusion or mirage. Less than one percent believed they were alien craft. One report from Seattle, Washington, described a hammer and sickle painted onto a flying disc. The stories spread to other countries, where they were influenced by local political and social concerns. In Europe, which was still recovering from the Second World War, saucers were often reported with rocket-like features. German newspapers reported flying saucers that exploded or had tails of fire. The names for the discs were largely derived from the English &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; including the French &lt;em&gt;soucoupe volante&lt;/em&gt;, Spanish &lt;em&gt;platillo volante&lt;/em&gt;, Portuguese &lt;em&gt;disco voador&lt;/em&gt;, Swedish &lt;em&gt;flygande tefat&lt;/em&gt;, German &lt;em&gt;fliegende Untertasse&lt;/em&gt;, and Italian &lt;em&gt;disco volante&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1947 sightings peaked in the days after the Fourth of July and declined rapidly through mid-July. Multiple organizations offered $1,000 rewards for hard proof. In the widely reported July 7, 1947, Twin Falls saucer hoax, four teenagers in Idaho fabricated a crashed disc from jukebox parts. On July 8, the Army Air Force base at Roswell, New Mexico, issued a press release saying that they had recovered a &amp;ldquo;flying disc&amp;rdquo; from a nearby ranch; the so-called Roswell UFO incident made front-page news. International media covered the military&amp;rsquo;s announcement of a crashed disc, but within 24 hours were reporting the military&amp;rsquo;s retraction and explanation that the material was balloon debris. By July 11, the most widely reported story was a North Hollywood resident&amp;rsquo;s claim that a 30-inch galvanized iron disc containing glass radio tubes had crashed in his garden. Newspapers quoted Fire Battalion Chief Wallace Newcombe&amp;rsquo;s assessment, &amp;ldquo;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t look to me like it could fly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Air Force collected over a hundred reports at Wright Field, now Wright-Patterson Air Force Base, Ohio. Air Force General Nathan Twining established Project SAUCER, later renamed Project Sign, the first in a series of UFO investigations by the US Government. Other national governments followed suit. Canada began Project Magnet and the United Kingdom launched the Flying Saucer Working Party in 1950, which attributed saucer reports to meteorological phenomena, astronomical phenomena, misidentification, optical illusions, misconceptions, or hoaxes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flying_Saucers&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flying_Saucers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO (video game)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_68eb5a240ad0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 17:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_68eb5a240ad0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-video-game&#34;&gt;UFO (video game) &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-video-game&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry details the 1989 video game &lt;em&gt;UFO&lt;/em&gt;, published by Sublogic for MS-DOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gameplay&#34;&gt;Gameplay &lt;a href=&#34;#gameplay&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explains the core gameplay of &lt;em&gt;UFO&lt;/em&gt;. The player controls an alien flying saucer with the objective of harvesting energy from humans by inducing fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the critical reception of the game. Daniel Hockman of &lt;em&gt;Computer Gaming World&lt;/em&gt; reviewed the game, noting its uniqueness and challenging flight demands. He suggested that players looking for something different and willing to overlook the polygon graphics might enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reviews&#34;&gt;Reviews &lt;a href=&#34;#reviews&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists reviews of the game that appeared in various publications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;ASM (Aktueller Software Markt)&lt;/em&gt; - Nov, 1989&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Games Machine&lt;/em&gt; - Jan, 1990&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Computer Gaming World&lt;/em&gt; - Nov, 1992&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of references used in the article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Hague&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Giant List of Classic Game Programmers&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daniel Hockman&amp;rsquo;s review in &lt;em&gt;Computer Gaming World&lt;/em&gt; (December 1989)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review in &lt;em&gt;The Games Machine&lt;/em&gt; Issue 26&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_(video_game)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_(video_game)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
