<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gaming on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/gaming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gaming on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 16:25:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/gaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Hominid</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b24fba8b4b8d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 16:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b24fba8b4b8d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-hominid&#34;&gt;Alien Hominid &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-hominid&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Hominid&lt;/em&gt; is a run and gun video game developed by The Behemoth. It initially launched as a Flash game on Newgrounds in 2002, created by Tom Fulp and Dan Paladin. The game was later re-released in expanded versions for various consoles and computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The initial release was an Adobe Flash game on August 7, 2002. Expanded console versions were released on PlayStation 2, GameCube, and Xbox in 2004 and 2005. A Game Boy Advance port arrived in 2006. &lt;em&gt;Alien Hominid HD&lt;/em&gt; was released for Xbox 360 via Xbox Live Arcade in 2007. A remaster, &lt;em&gt;Alien Hominid HD&lt;/em&gt;, was released for Windows, Nintendo Switch, Xbox One, and Xbox Series X/S on November 1, 2023, alongside a sequel, &lt;em&gt;Alien Hominid Invasion&lt;/em&gt;. A PlayStation 4 and PlayStation 5 release is planned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gameplay&#34;&gt;Gameplay &lt;a href=&#34;#gameplay&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Hominid&lt;/em&gt; is a side-scrolling run and gun shooter, similar to &lt;em&gt;Metal Slug&lt;/em&gt;. Gameplay involves instant kills with a two-player simultaneous mode. Players control the titular hominid, fighting off waves of secret agents using a blaster, melee attacks, and grenades. Advanced moves include rolling, biting off heads, digging underground, and scaring enemies. Power-ups provide extra grenades, shields, and unique ammo. Players can also drive vehicles, ride a Yeti, and pilot a UFO. Completing tasks unlocks hats for the Hominid. The main game features sixteen stages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside the main game, there are multiplayer modes (Challenge, Neutron Ball, and Pinata Boss), a PDA game (featuring around 200 levels and a level editor), an extra mode called &lt;em&gt;All You Can Eat&lt;/em&gt;, and a retro minigame, &lt;em&gt;Super Soviet Missile Mastar&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Alien Hominid is flying over Earth when the FBI intercepts its spacecraft, causing it to crash. The FBI steals the ship, prompting the alien to retrieve it with the help of &amp;ldquo;fat kids.&amp;rdquo; After retrieving the ship, the alien crashes into Russia due to a Soviet missile. The alien retrieves the ship again, but is captured by an Area 51 spaceship. The alien escapes, befriends a sentient eyeball, and defeats a buff alien. The &amp;ldquo;fat kids&amp;rdquo; help the alien and eyeball escape in the alien&amp;rsquo;s ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game received generally favorable reviews on most platforms, praised for its old-school gameplay, difficulty, and humor. It won awards at the Independent Games Festival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legacy&#34;&gt;Legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hominid appears in The Behemoth&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Castle Crashers&lt;/em&gt; and is playable to those who downloaded &lt;em&gt;Alien Hominid 360&lt;/em&gt; on Xbox 360. The green eyeball appears as an Animal Orb. Hominid is a playable character in &lt;em&gt;Super Meat Boy&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;Super Soviet Missile Mastar&lt;/em&gt; minigame was released as a free iOS app. An improved version of the &lt;em&gt;PDA Games&lt;/em&gt; minigame was released for iOS. Tom Fulp cited the &lt;em&gt;PDA Games&lt;/em&gt; as inspiration for &lt;em&gt;BattleBlock Theater&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 30, 2020, Behemoth announced &lt;em&gt;Alien Hominid Invasion&lt;/em&gt;, described as a &amp;ldquo;re-imagination&amp;rdquo; of the original game. It was released on November 1, 2023, alongside a remaster of the original game, &lt;em&gt;Alien Hominid HD&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Hominid&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Hominid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
