<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gaming on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/gaming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gaming on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 14:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/gaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Hive</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_4d3214fd7917/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_4d3214fd7917/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-hive&#34;&gt;Alien Hive &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-hive&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Hive&lt;/em&gt; is a puzzle video game developed and published by Malaysia-based studio Appxplore. It was released in March 2013 for iOS, Android, and Windows Phone platforms. The game combines match-three and sliding puzzle mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gameplay&#34;&gt;Gameplay &lt;a href=&#34;#gameplay&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The core gameplay involves swiping tiles to match eggs and aliens, with the goal of hatching, breeding, and evolving them into the Supreme Alien. Players aim to build the ultimate alien hive by matching resource tiles. Players must avoid Naughty Bots and use power-ups to eliminate them, while also trying to minimize the number of moves used. As players progress, they encounter more aliens and uncover their mysteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magic Fruit, collected by merging seeds into saplings, is essential for evolving Supreme Aliens. These fruits allow players to merge similar-level items using only two of a kind instead of three. Evolved Supreme Aliens can be activated using gold to provide special bonuses in future games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-app-purchase&#34;&gt;In App Purchase &lt;a href=&#34;#in-app-purchase&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Hive&lt;/em&gt; incorporates microtransactions, where players can exchange real money for in-game gold to purchase consumable items. This aspect of the game has faced criticism, with some reviewers suggesting that microtransactions are almost necessary to progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Hive&lt;/em&gt; received an average score of 70 out of 100 based on reviews aggregated by Metacritic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 2015, the game had achieved over 3 million downloads across all platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including links to the game&amp;rsquo;s page on Appxplore&amp;rsquo;s website, the Google Play Store, and reviews from sites like Gamezebo and Vulcan Post. These references provide verification for the information presented in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the official website of &lt;em&gt;Alien Hive&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Hive&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Hive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien Hominid</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b24fba8b4b8d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 16:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b24fba8b4b8d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-hominid&#34;&gt;Alien Hominid &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-hominid&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Hominid&lt;/em&gt; is a run and gun video game developed by The Behemoth. It initially launched as a Flash game on Newgrounds in 2002, created by Tom Fulp and Dan Paladin. It was later re-released in expanded versions for various consoles and computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;developer-and-publisher-information&#34;&gt;Developer and Publisher Information &lt;a href=&#34;#developer-and-publisher-information&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game was developed by The Behemoth, with Dan Paladin as the designer and Tom Fulp as the programmer. Matthew E. Harwood composed the music. The original Flash version was released in 2002. Console versions were released in 2004 and 2005 for PlayStation 2, GameCube, and Xbox. A Game Boy Advance port, developed by Tuna Technologies, came out in 2006. A high-definition version, &lt;em&gt;Alien Hominid HD&lt;/em&gt;, was released for Xbox 360 in 2007. A remaster, also titled &lt;em&gt;Alien Hominid HD&lt;/em&gt;, was released in 2023 for Windows, Nintendo Switch, Xbox One, and Xbox Series X/S, alongside a sequel, &lt;em&gt;Alien Hominid Invasion&lt;/em&gt;. A PlayStation 4 and PlayStation 5 version is planned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gameplay&#34;&gt;Gameplay &lt;a href=&#34;#gameplay&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Hominid&lt;/em&gt; is a side-scrolling run and gun shooter, similar to &lt;em&gt;Metal Slug&lt;/em&gt;. Gameplay involves instant death upon being hit and supports two-player simultaneous play. Players control the Alien Hominid, who defends against waves of secret agents using a blaster, melee attacks, and grenades. Advanced moves include rolling, biting off heads, digging underground, and collecting power-ups for extra grenades, shields, and unique ammo. Players can also drive vehicles, ride a Yeti, and pilot a UFO. Completing tasks unlocks hats for the Hominid. The main game has sixteen stages. Additional modes include Challenge, Neutron Ball, Pinata Boss, a PDA game with 200 levels and a level editor, &lt;em&gt;All You Can Eat&lt;/em&gt;, and the &lt;em&gt;Super Soviet Missile Mastar&lt;/em&gt; minigame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Alien Hominid is flying over Earth when the FBI intercepts its spacecraft, causing it to crash. The FBI steals the ship, leading the alien to pursue them with the help of &amp;ldquo;fat kids.&amp;rdquo; After retrieving the ship, the alien crashes into Russia due to a Soviet missile. The alien recovers the ship again but is captured by an Area 51 spaceship. The alien escapes, befriends a sentient eyeball, and defeats a buff alien. The &amp;ldquo;fat kids&amp;rdquo; help the alien and eyeball escape in the ship, using a tractor beam to lift the kids out of an Area 51 truck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game received generally favorable reviews on most platforms, with the Game Boy Advance version receiving universal acclaim. Reviewers praised its old-school gameplay, difficulty, and humor. &lt;em&gt;GameSpot&lt;/em&gt; nominated it for &amp;ldquo;Funniest Game&amp;rdquo; in 2004.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legacy&#34;&gt;Legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hominid appears in The Behemoth&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Castle Crashers&lt;/em&gt; and is a playable character in &lt;em&gt;Super Meat Boy&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;Super Soviet Missile Mastar&lt;/em&gt; minigame was released as a free iOS app in 2011, and an improved version of the &lt;em&gt;PDA Games&lt;/em&gt; minigame was released for iOS in 2011. Tom Fulp cited the &lt;em&gt;PDA Games&lt;/em&gt; as inspiration for &lt;em&gt;BattleBlock Theater&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes &lt;a href=&#34;#notes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tuna Technologies ported the game to Game Boy Advance and J2ME. Zoo Digital Publishing and O3 Entertainment published the PlayStation 2, GameCube, Xbox, and Game Boy Advance versions in Europe and North America, respectively. Allister Brimble and Anthony N. Putson composed the Game Boy Advance music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Hominid&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Hominid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
