<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sci-Fi Horror on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/sci-fi-horror/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sci-Fi Horror on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 19:38:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/sci-fi-horror/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial (2014 film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_da6823111923/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 19:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_da6823111923/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-2014-film&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial (2014 film) &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-2014-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2014 Canadian science fiction horror film directed by Colin Minihan, one half of The Vicious Brothers, who also co-produced, wrote, and edited the film. The film stars Brittany Allen, Freddie Stroma, and Melanie Papalia as a group of friends who must defend themselves against an alien onslaught.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;April and her boyfriend Kyle, along with friends Seth, Melanie, and Lex, head to April&amp;rsquo;s parents&amp;rsquo; cabin for the weekend. After a series of events including a traffic stop and some recreational drug use, they witness a UFO crash in the woods. Investigating, they discover an alien spacecraft and footprints. The group encounters an alien, which they shoot. After this, the group is hunted by aliens, and they seek help from Travis, a family friend of April&amp;rsquo;s, who explains the government&amp;rsquo;s alleged treaty with the aliens. The friends try to survive the night as they are picked off one by one. The survivors are eventually abducted and experimented on. Kyle and April are returned to Earth, only to be killed by U.S. Army soldiers who are cleaning up the crash site, covering up the existence of extraterrestrials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film stars Brittany Allen as April, Freddie Stroma as Kyle, and Melanie Papalia as Melanie. Other notable cast members include Jesse Moss as Seth, Anja Savcic as Lex, Gil Bellows as Sheriff Murphy, and Michael Ironside as Travis. Sean Rogerson plays Deputy Mitchell, Emily Perkins plays Nancy McPherson, and Jacob Tremblay has an uncredited role as Matty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Extraterrestrial&lt;/em&gt; premiered at the Tribeca Film Festival on April 18, 2014, under the IFC Midnight banner. The Scream Factory later released the film on Blu-ray and DVD on May 12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critical reception for &lt;em&gt;Extraterrestrial&lt;/em&gt; has been predominantly negative. Reviewers criticized the film for relying too heavily on familiar tropes and clichés of sci-fi horror movies. Some reviewers praised the film&amp;rsquo;s visuals, but overall, the film received poor reviews. Rotten Tomatoes reports an aggregate score of 28%, with the consensus being that the film delivers some gory thrills but is weighed down by clichés.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_(2014_film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_(2014_film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
