<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Signal Analysis on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/signal-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Signal Analysis on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 04:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/signal-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Search for extraterrestrial intelligence</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_66a1335bfda8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_66a1335bfda8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence-seti&#34;&gt;Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence (SETI) &lt;a href=&#34;#search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence-seti&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The search for extraterrestrial intelligence (SETI) encompasses various scientific projects aimed at detecting signals or evidence of intelligent life beyond Earth. These efforts involve monitoring electromagnetic radiation, searching for optical signals, and investigating potential extraterrestrial artifacts. While some initiatives focus on detection, others, like NASA&amp;rsquo;s Golden Record, attempt to send messages to hypothetical alien civilizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-work&#34;&gt;Early Work &lt;a href=&#34;#early-work&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early searches for extraterrestrial intelligence within the Solar System include Nikola Tesla&amp;rsquo;s suggestion in 1896 to use his wireless electrical transmission system to contact beings on Mars. In 1899, Tesla thought he detected a signal from Mars at his Colorado Springs experimental station. Guglielmo Marconi, Lord Kelvin, and David Peck Todd also believed radio could be used to contact Martians. In 1924, during a close opposition of Mars, a &amp;ldquo;National Radio Silence Day&amp;rdquo; was promoted in the United States, with a radio receiver lifted 3 kilometers above ground to listen for Martian messages, with William F. Friedman assigned to translate any potential Martian messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-ozma-and-early-radio-searches&#34;&gt;Project Ozma and Early Radio Searches &lt;a href=&#34;#project-ozma-and-early-radio-searches&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1959, Philip Morrison and Giuseppe Cocconi proposed searching the microwave spectrum for interstellar communications. In 1960, Frank Drake conducted the first modern SETI experiment, Project Ozma, at Green Bank, West Virginia, examining Tau Ceti and Epsilon Eridani near the 1.420 gigahertz marker frequency. Soviet scientists also showed strong interest in SETI during the 1960s, with Iosif Shklovsky co-authoring &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Life in the Universe&lt;/em&gt; with Carl Sagan. John D. Kraus began the Ohio State University SETI program, using the &amp;ldquo;Big Ear&amp;rdquo; radio telescope in Delaware, Ohio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-cyclops-and-the-wow-signal&#34;&gt;Project Cyclops and the Wow! Signal &lt;a href=&#34;#project-cyclops-and-the-wow-signal&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1971, NASA funded a SETI study that proposed Project Cyclops, an Earth-based radio telescope array with 1,500 dishes, but it was not built. The Ohio State SETI program gained fame on August 15, 1977, when Jerry Ehman witnessed the Wow! signal, a strong signal considered a candidate for an extraterrestrial source. In May 2023, a test extraterrestrial signal was transmitted to radio telescopes on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sentinel-meta-and-beta&#34;&gt;Sentinel, META, and BETA &lt;a href=&#34;#sentinel-meta-and-beta&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1980, Carl Sagan, Bruce Murray, and Louis Friedman founded the Planetary Society to support SETI studies. In the early 1980s, Harvard University physicist Paul Horowitz designed spectrum analyzers specifically for SETI, leading to &amp;ldquo;Suitcase SETI&amp;rdquo; in 1981 and Project META (Megachannel Extra-Terrestrial Assay) in 1985. META II was begun in Argentina in 1990. The follow-on project, BETA (Billion-channel Extraterrestrial Assay), commenced observation in 1995. In 1999, the 26-meter radio telescope used by these projects was damaged by strong winds, forcing BETA to cease operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mop-and-project-phoenix&#34;&gt;MOP and Project Phoenix &lt;a href=&#34;#mop-and-project-phoenix&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1978, the NASA SETI program faced criticism, but funding was restored in 1982 after Carl Sagan convinced Senator William Proxmire of its value. In 1992, the U.S. government funded the NASA Microwave Observing Program (MOP), but it was canceled one year after its start. In 1995, the SETI Institute resurrected the MOP program as Project Phoenix, directed by Jill Tarter, studying roughly 1,000 nearby Sun-like stars until approximately 2015, using radio telescopes in Australia, West Virginia, and Puerto Rico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ongoing-radio-searches&#34;&gt;Ongoing Radio Searches &lt;a href=&#34;#ongoing-radio-searches&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many radio frequencies penetrate Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere, leading to the use of radio telescopes for investigating the cosmos. Human communications emit electromagnetic radiation that could be recognized as artificial signals. Earth has been sending radio waves into space for over 100 years, reaching over 1,000 stars. Many international radio telescopes, including LOFAR in Europe, MWA in Australia, and the Lovell Telescope in the United Kingdom, are used for radio SETI searches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;allen-telescope-array&#34;&gt;Allen Telescope Array &lt;a href=&#34;#allen-telescope-array&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SETI Institute collaborated with the Radio Astronomy Laboratory at the Berkeley SETI Research Center to develop the Allen Telescope Array (ATA). The array currently has 42 operational dishes at the Hat Creek Radio Observatory in northern California. The full array is planned to consist of 350 or more radio dishes. The first portion of the array (ATA-42) became operational in October 2007. The SETI Institute&amp;rsquo;s Center for SETI Research (CSR) uses ATA in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence, observing 12 hours a day, 7 days a week. Berkeley astronomers used the ATA to pursue several science topics until 2011, when the collaboration between the University of California, Berkeley and the SETI Institute was terminated. In 2012, the ATA was revitalized with a donation by Franklin Antonio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;serendip&#34;&gt;SERENDIP &lt;a href=&#34;#serendip&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SERENDIP (Search for Extraterrestrial Radio Emissions from Nearby Developed Intelligent Populations) is a SETI program launched in 1979 by the Berkeley SETI Research Center. SERENDIP analyzes deep space radio telescope data obtained while other astronomers are using the telescopes. The most recently deployed SERENDIP spectrometer, SERENDIP VI, was installed at both the Arecibo Telescope and the Green Bank Telescope in 2014–2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;breakthrough-listen&#34;&gt;Breakthrough Listen &lt;a href=&#34;#breakthrough-listen&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Breakthrough Listen&lt;/em&gt; is a ten-year initiative with $100 million funding begun in July 2015 to actively search for intelligent extraterrestrial communications in the universe. The science program is based at Berkeley SETI Research Center. The project observes for thousands of hours every year on the Green Bank Observatory in West Virginia, and the Parkes Observatory in Australia. The Automated Planet Finder at Lick Observatory is searching for optical signals coming from laser transmissions. Some of the data are also analyzed by volunteers in the SETI@home volunteer computing network. Frank Drake was one of the scientists on the project&amp;rsquo;s advisory committee. In October 2019, Breakthrough Listen started a collaboration with scientists from the TESS team to look for signs of advanced extraterrestrial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fast&#34;&gt;FAST &lt;a href=&#34;#fast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China&amp;rsquo;s 500 meter Aperture Spherical Telescope (FAST) lists detecting interstellar communication signals as part of its science mission. FAST is the first radio observatory built with SETI as a core scientific goal. FAST consists of a fixed 500 m diameter spherical dish constructed in a natural depression sinkhole. In June 2022, astronomers working with FAST reported the possibility of having detected artificial signals, but cautioned that further studies were required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ucla&#34;&gt;UCLA &lt;a href=&#34;#ucla&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2016, University of California Los Angeles (UCLA) students have been participating in radio searches for technosignatures with the Green Bank Telescope. Targets include the Kepler field, TRAPPIST-1, and solar-type stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;community-seti-projects&#34;&gt;Community SETI Projects &lt;a href=&#34;#community-seti-projects&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;setihome&#34;&gt;SETI@home &lt;a href=&#34;#setihome&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SETI@home project used volunteer computing to analyze signals acquired by the SERENDIP project. It was launched by the Berkeley SETI Research Center at the University of California, Berkeley, in May 1999. Any individual could become involved with SETI research by downloading the BOINC software program and allowing the program to run as a background process. On March 31, 2020, the project stopped sending out new work to SETI@home users, bringing this particular SETI effort to an indefinite hiatus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;seti-net&#34;&gt;SETI Net &lt;a href=&#34;#seti-net&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SETI Network was the only fully operational private search system. The SETI Net station consisted of off-the-shelf, consumer-grade electronics. It had a 3-meter parabolic antenna that could be directed in azimuth and elevation. SETI Net started operation in the early 1980s and was decommissioned on 2021-12-04.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-seti-league-and-project-argus&#34;&gt;The SETI League and Project Argus &lt;a href=&#34;#the-seti-league-and-project-argus&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1994 in response to the United States Congress cancellation of the NASA SETI program, The SETI League, Incorporated is a membership-supported nonprofit organization. The SETI League pioneered the conversion of backyard satellite TV dishes into research-grade radio telescopes. The organization concentrates on coordinating a global network of small, amateur-built radio telescopes under Project Argus, an all-sky survey seeking to achieve real-time coverage of the entire sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;optical-experiments&#34;&gt;Optical Experiments &lt;a href=&#34;#optical-experiments&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some SETI researchers have considered the possibility that alien civilizations might be using powerful lasers for interstellar communications at optical wavelengths. There are two problems with optical SETI: lasers are highly &amp;ldquo;monochromatic&amp;rdquo; and lasers are highly directional. Several optical SETI experiments are now in progress. A Harvard-Smithsonian group designed a laser detector and mounted it on Harvard&amp;rsquo;s 155-centimeter optical telescope. The Harvard-Smithsonian group is now working with Princeton University to mount a similar detector system on Princeton&amp;rsquo;s 91-centimeter telescope. The Harvard-Smithsonian SETI group led by Professor Paul Horowitz built a dedicated all-sky optical survey system featuring a 1.8-meter telescope. The University of California, Berkeley, is also conducting optical SETI searches and collaborates with the NIROSETI program. The SETI Institute also runs a program called &amp;lsquo;Laser SETI&amp;rsquo; with an instrument composed of several&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Optical_SETI&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Optical_SETI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
