<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1967 on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/1967/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1967 on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:07:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/1967/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1967 British flying saucer hoax</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_ca77cd9256e0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_ca77cd9256e0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;1967-british-flying-saucer-hoax&#34;&gt;1967 British Flying Saucer Hoax &lt;a href=&#34;#1967-british-flying-saucer-hoax&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1967 British flying saucer hoax involved the supposed landing of six &amp;lsquo;spaceships&amp;rsquo; across Southern England on September 4, 1967. These &amp;lsquo;spacecraft&amp;rsquo; prompted a significant response from the police and army. The objects were described as being 54 inches long, 30 inches wide, and 20 inches deep, weighing 100 pounds, and emitting an electronic noise. The six craft were located along the 51st line of latitude, stretching from the Thames Estuary to the Bristol Channel. Specific locations included Queenborough on the Isle of Sheppey, Bromley golf course in south London, Winkfield village near Ascot, Welford near Newbury, Chippenham in Wiltshire, and Dial Hill in Clevedon, Somerset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;planning-and-building-the-spacecraft&#34;&gt;Planning and Building the &amp;lsquo;Spacecraft&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#planning-and-building-the-spacecraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hoax was conceived in January 1967 by aircraft engineering apprentices from the Royal Aircraft Establishment (RAE) at Farnborough as part of Rag Week. The apprentices constructed the flying saucers from fiberglass halves, covered them in metal, and equipped them with electronic devices to produce eerie sounds when flipped. Each saucer also contained a mixture of flour and water. Teams of two or three transported the saucers to the chosen locations at night, flipped them over to activate the sound, and then left the scene undetected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;response-from-the-authorities&#34;&gt;Response from the Authorities &lt;a href=&#34;#response-from-the-authorities&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discovery of the saucers triggered a large-scale response from authorities. Police cordoned off each site, and the British army&amp;rsquo;s southern command, multiple police forces, army bomb disposal units, and RAF helicopters were mobilized. The Ministry of Defence was notified. The army detonated the saucer found in Chippenham, while the one on the Isle of Sheppey was removed by helicopter. Other saucers were sent to the Atomic Weapons Establishment at Aldermaston and the British Aircraft Corporation&amp;rsquo;s guided weapons division. When one of the saucers was drilled into, the mixture inside exploded, covering police officers in foul-smelling slime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;revealing-the-hoax&#34;&gt;Revealing the Hoax &lt;a href=&#34;#revealing-the-hoax&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christopher Southall and Roger Palmer, both 21 years old, were identified as the pranksters behind the hoax. Their motive was to raise funds during Rag Week. The hoax generated extensive media coverage both in Britain and internationally. The apprentices revealed the hoax on the same day the saucers were found. No legal action was taken against them, and they successfully raised £2,000 for charity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources used in the article, including BBC and The Guardian articles, and a GetSurrey news report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to pictures of the hoax flying saucers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1967_British_flying_saucer_hoax&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1967_British_flying_saucer_hoax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Close encounter of Cussac</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_014e76193abe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 01:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_014e76193abe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;close-encounter-incident-in-cussac-cantal-france&#34;&gt;Close encounter incident in Cussac, Cantal, France &lt;a href=&#34;#close-encounter-incident-in-cussac-cantal-france&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the alleged close encounter that occurred in Cussac, Cantal, France in 1967.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary &lt;a href=&#34;#summary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces the topic as a claimed close encounter with alien beings by a young brother and sister in Cussac, Cantal, France. It cites a source that refers to the incident as a &amp;ldquo;close encounter of the third kind,&amp;rdquo; comparing its fame in France to the Kelly-Hopkinsville encounter in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;details-of-the-incident&#34;&gt;Details of the Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#details-of-the-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the events of August 29, 1967, when a 13-year-old boy and his 9-year-old sister reported seeing four small, black beings about 47 inches tall while watching cows in a field. The children claimed the beings rose into the air and entered a round spaceship, about 15 feet in diameter, that was hovering over the field. Police noted a sulfur odor and dried grass at the alleged takeoff site. The incident is mentioned as one of the UFO sightings investigated by the French government and made public in a mass release of documents in March 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a link to the &amp;ldquo;UFO sightings in France&amp;rdquo; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources used in the article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rossini, David; Maillot, Eric; Déguillaume, Eric (February 2009). &amp;ldquo;UFOs: an Assessment of Thirty Years of Official Studies in France&amp;rdquo;. &lt;em&gt;Skeptical Inquirer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moore, Molly (March 23, 2007). &amp;ldquo;French Get a Look at Nation&amp;rsquo;s UFO Files&amp;rdquo;. &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of additional resources for readers interested in learning more about the Cussac incident:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report on the Scientific Council - GEPAN, t. 4, National Centre for Space Studies, 140, June 1978 No. 68.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thierry Pinvidic, &amp;ldquo;Witnesses to a&amp;rdquo; legend &amp;ldquo;: a case of UFO sighting &amp;lsquo;in&amp;rsquo; Communications&amp;rsquo;, No. 52, October 1990, p. 311-335.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thierry Pinvidic, &amp;ldquo;A classic that has a hard time&amp;rdquo; in Pinvindic Thiery (ed). &amp;lsquo;UFO: towards an anthropology of contemporary myth&amp;rsquo;, Editions Heimdal, Paris, 1993, p. 199-209.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Close_encounter_of_Cussac&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Close_encounter_of_Cussac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
