<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sighting on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/sighting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sighting on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 06:53:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/sighting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chiles-Whitted UFO encounter</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_d56305523c82/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 06:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_d56305523c82/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chiles-whitted-ufo-encounter&#34;&gt;Chiles-Whitted UFO encounter &lt;a href=&#34;#chiles-whitted-ufo-encounter&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chiles-Whitted UFO encounter occurred on July 24, 1948, at approximately 2:45 AM near Montgomery, Alabama. Two commercial pilots, Clarence S. Chiles and John B. Whitted, reported seeing a &amp;ldquo;glowing object&amp;rdquo; fly past their plane. The object appeared to ascend into a cloud and disappear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-incident&#34;&gt;The incident &lt;a href=&#34;#the-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the morning of July 24, 1948, Clarence Chiles and John Whitted were flying a Douglas DC-3 passenger plane for Eastern Air Lines near Montgomery, Alabama, at an altitude of about 5,000 feet. Chiles noticed a red glow above and ahead of the aircraft. The object quickly approached their plane, and both pilots observed it passing by the right side at high speed. They said it then ascended into the clouds with a burst of flame. The pilots estimated they observed the object for ten to fifteen seconds. They described it as a wingless aircraft, approximately 100 feet long and 25–30 feet in diameter, with two rows of bright windows and flames coming from its tail. One passenger, C.L. McKelvie, reported seeing a bright streak of light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;investigation-and-explanation&#34;&gt;Investigation and explanation &lt;a href=&#34;#investigation-and-explanation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After landing in Atlanta, Georgia, Chiles and Whitted reported their sighting to the United States Air Force (USAF). They were interviewed by Project Sign personnel, the Air Force&amp;rsquo;s initial UFO investigation group. The pilots disagreed on some details; Chiles described a lighted cockpit, a long boom on the object&amp;rsquo;s nose, and a transparent center section, while Whitted did not see a cockpit or boom and described rectangular windows instead of a transparent section. Neither pilot heard any sound, and the plane was not affected by turbulence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USAF Captain Edward Ruppelt noted the report significantly impacted the Air Technical Intelligence Center (ATIC). Project Sign created a trajectory map indicating the object would have passed over Macon, Georgia. An Air Force crew chief at Robins Air Force Base near Macon reported seeing a bright light moving at high speed on the same night, seemingly corroborating the Chiles-Whitted sighting. Project Sign personnel drafted an &amp;ldquo;Estimate of the Situation,&amp;rdquo; concluding that UFOs were interplanetary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Air Force Chief of Staff Hoyt S. Vandenberg rejected the Estimate of the Situation in October 1948, citing insufficient evidence. J. Allen Hynek, an astronomer and consultant to Project Sign, suggested the pilots had seen a bright meteor. He noted that the flaming tail and sudden disappearance aligned with meteor behavior and that many bright meteors were observed that night. He speculated that the pilots&amp;rsquo; perception of windows and a cockpit could be a subjective impression caused by the meteor&amp;rsquo;s trail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astronomer Donald Menzel pointed out that the sighting occurred during a period of increased meteor activity, specifically the Aquarid streams. He noted reports of numerous meteors in the Southeast on July 24. Menzel argued that the pilots misinterpreted an unusually bright meteor, its body glowing intensely and emitting flaming gases. He cited a similar experience of another pilot in 1959 who recognized a fiery object as a meteor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFO skeptic Philip Klass supported the meteor explanation, criticizing Project Sign&amp;rsquo;s initial conclusion. While ufologist James E. McDonald interviewed Chiles and Whitted in the 1960s and disagreed with the meteor explanation, the USAF, based on the analysis of Hynek, Menzel, and others, officially attributed the Chiles-Whitted incident to a fireball-type meteor in 1959.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chiles-Whitted_UFO_encounter&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chiles-Whitted_UFO_encounter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nash-Fortenberry UFO sighting</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f9288f9c7c4f/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 01:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f9288f9c7c4f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;nash-fortenberry-ufo-sighting&#34;&gt;Nash-Fortenberry UFO Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#nash-fortenberry-ufo-sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Nash-Fortenberry UFO sighting occurred on July 14, 1952, when two commercial pilots, William B. Nash and William H. Fortenberry, reported seeing eight UFOs in a tight echelon formation over Chesapeake Bay in Virginia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description &lt;a href=&#34;#description&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two commercial pilots, William B. Nash and William H. Fortenberry, reported observing eight UFOs flying in formation over Chesapeake Bay, Virginia. Ufologists highlight the pilots&amp;rsquo; observation allowed for measurements of the objects&amp;rsquo; motion and size relative to known landmarks. The sighting was reportedly corroborated by independent ground witnesses. Project Blue Book listed the case as an &amp;ldquo;unknown.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;explanations&#34;&gt;Explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donald Howard Menzel suggested the pilots might have seen distorted ground lights due to haze or fireflies trapped in the cockpit window. Steuart Campbell proposed the sighting was a mirage of Venus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A NICAP report by Thomas Thulien revisiting the Nash/Fortenberry sighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donald Howard Menzel&amp;rsquo;s book, &lt;em&gt;The World of Flying Saucers&lt;/em&gt;, where he offers naturalistic explanations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steuart Campbell&amp;rsquo;s book, &lt;em&gt;The UFO Mystery Solved&lt;/em&gt;, where he suggests the sighting was a mirage of Venus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further Reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists additional resources for further information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steuart Campbell&amp;rsquo;s book, &lt;em&gt;The UFO Mystery Solved&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James W. Moseley and Karl T. Pflock&amp;rsquo;s book, &lt;em&gt;Shockingly Close to the Truth: Confessions of a Grave-Robbing Ufologist&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External Links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Pilots&amp;rsquo; Tale&amp;rdquo; at Saturday Night Uforia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;We Flew Above Flying Saucers&amp;rdquo; by William B. Nash and William H. Fortenberry, published in &lt;em&gt;True&lt;/em&gt; magazine in 1967.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nash-Fortenberry_UFO_sighting&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nash-Fortenberry_UFO_sighting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
