<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mexico on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/mexico/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mexico on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 18:06:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/mexico/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in Mexico</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ec4ffc292768/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 18:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ec4ffc292768/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-sightings-in-mexico&#34;&gt;UFO Sightings in Mexico &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-sightings-in-mexico&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article documents alleged UFO sightings in Mexico, spanning from the late 19th century to the early 21st century. It presents specific incidents, including details, locations, and explanations where available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1883&#34;&gt;1883 &lt;a href=&#34;#1883&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the observations made by astronomer José Bonilla on August 12, 1883, at the Zacatecas Observatory. Bonilla reported seeing and photographing numerous dark objects crossing the sun. Initially considered a potential early UFO photograph, the objects were later identified as high-flying geese. Despite the explanation, the event is still sometimes cited in ufological contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1974&#34;&gt;1974 &lt;a href=&#34;#1974&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the alleged mid-air collision between a UFO and a small airplane near Coyame on August 25, 1974. It mentions reports from local residents and claims of a subsequent military investigation and cover-up. However, it also presents an alternative explanation suggesting the reports were related to the crash and military recovery of a Cessna aircraft involved in drug trafficking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2004&#34;&gt;2004 &lt;a href=&#34;#2004&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes an incident on March 5, 2004, where Mexican Air Force pilots, using infrared equipment, recorded 11 unidentified objects over southern Campeche. The Mexican Defense Department released a press release and videotape of the event. Ufologist Jaime Maussan interpreted the footage as evidence of alien visitation. Skeptic Michael Shermer criticized the varying witness accounts, and other experts suggested the lights were likely burn-off flares from offshore oil platforms in the Gulf of Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of links to related topics, including a general list of reported UFO sightings and a specific link to an article about a UFO sighting over pyramids in Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including books and articles that provide further information and context for the described UFO sightings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the MUFON (Mutual UFO Network) website, specifically to a page displaying the latest UFO sightings and pictures reported to the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Mexico&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Mexico&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
