<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nazi UFOs on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/nazi-ufos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nazi UFOs on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 01:04:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/nazi-ufos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nazi UFOs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_2a3ccadade41/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 01:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_2a3ccadade41/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;conspiracy-theories-alleging-connections-between-ufos-and-nazi-germany&#34;&gt;Conspiracy theories alleging connections between UFOs and Nazi Germany &lt;a href=&#34;#conspiracy-theories-alleging-connections-between-ufos-and-nazi-germany&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article explores the conspiracy theories linking UFOs to Nazi Germany, asserting that the Nazis attempted to develop advanced aircraft and spacecraft before and during World War II. It further claims that these craft survived in secret underground bases in Antarctica, South America, or the United States, along with their creators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-ufos-as-possible-nazi-technology&#34;&gt;Early UFOs as possible Nazi technology &lt;a href=&#34;#early-ufos-as-possible-nazi-technology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses how unusual aerial sightings during and after World War II were initially attributed to novel Nazi technology. During the Cold War, speculation arose that the Soviets might be deploying captured or reverse-engineered Nazi technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;foo-fighters&#34;&gt;Foo fighters &lt;a href=&#34;#foo-fighters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During World War II, Allied and Axis personnel witnessed unusual aerial phenomena called &amp;ldquo;foo fighters.&amp;rdquo; While some reports were dismissed as misperceptions, others were taken seriously, leading scientists like Luis Alvarez to investigate. Allied intelligence suspected some foo fighters were advanced German aircraft or weapons, given Germany&amp;rsquo;s technological innovations like V-1 and V-2 missiles and the Me 262 jet fighter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ghost-rockets&#34;&gt;Ghost rockets &lt;a href=&#34;#ghost-rockets&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1946, rocket- or missile-shaped UFOs, known as &amp;ldquo;ghost rockets,&amp;rdquo; were sighted primarily in Sweden and nearby countries. Finnish observers made the first reports in February 1946. Investigations suggested some sightings were meteors, but others displayed characteristics inconsistent with meteors, such as maneuverability. It was initially believed that the ghost rockets originated from the former German rocket facility at Peenemünde and were Soviet tests of captured German missiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;flying-discs&#34;&gt;Flying discs &lt;a href=&#34;#flying-discs&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s 1947 sighting of crescent-shaped objects, speculation about German technology resurfaced. Project Sign personnel noted similarities between the Horten brothers&amp;rsquo; flying wing designs and some UFO reports. Edward J. Ruppelt, the first head of Project Blue Book, noted that the Germans had several radical aircraft and guided missiles under development at the end of WWII.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The earliest media assertion of German flying saucers appeared in the Italian newspaper &lt;em&gt;Il Giornale d&amp;rsquo;Italia&lt;/em&gt; in 1950. Professor Giuseppe Belluzzo claimed that flying discs were designed and studied in Germany and Italy as early as 1942.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the same month, German technician Rudolf Schriever claimed to &lt;em&gt;Der Spiegel&lt;/em&gt; that he designed a craft powered by rotating turbine blades while working at BMW&amp;rsquo;s Prague works until April 1945. He said his designs were stolen, and he believed Czech agents built his craft for a foreign power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1953, German engineer Georg Klein claimed that designs similar to Avro Canada&amp;rsquo;s Avrocar had been developed during the Nazi era. Klein identified two types of supposed German flying disks: one developed by Richard Miethe in Breslau and another developed by Rudolf Schriever and Klaus Habermohl in Prague.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aeronautical engineer Roy Fedden stated in 1945 that the only craft that could approach the capabilities attributed to flying saucers were those being designed by the Germans towards the end of the war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nazi-ufo-conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;Nazi UFO conspiracy theories &lt;a href=&#34;#nazi-ufo-conspiracy-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the 1960s, fringe authors began circulating tales of Nazi UFOs tied to the occult or aliens. These theories reference various potential code-names or sub-classifications of Nazi UFO craft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;German UFO literature often aligns with documented history regarding Nazi Germany&amp;rsquo;s claim to New Swabia in Antarctica and its research into advanced propulsion technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-morning-of-the-magicians&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Morning of the Magicians&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#the-morning-of-the-magicians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Le Matin des Magiciens&lt;/em&gt;, a 1960 book by Louis Pauwels and Jacques Bergier, made claims about the Vril Society of Berlin. Later writers, including Jan van Helsing, Norbert-Jürgen Ratthofer, and Vladimir Terziski, connected the Vril Society with UFOs, claiming the society contacted an alien race and developed spacecraft to reach them. They allege that the Vril Society, in partnership with the Thule Society and the Nazi Party, developed flying disc prototypes and retreated to a base in Antarctica after the Nazi defeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-works-of-ernst-zündel&#34;&gt;The works of Ernst Zündel &lt;a href=&#34;#the-works-of-ernst-z%c3%bcndel&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ernst Zündel&amp;rsquo;s Samisdat Publishers claimed that flying saucers were Nazi secret weapons launched from an underground base in Antarctica, aiming to conquer Earth and other planets. Zündel also sold seats on an exploration team to locate the polar entrance to the hollow earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;miguel-serranos-book&#34;&gt;Miguel Serrano&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;a href=&#34;#miguel-serranos-book&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1978, Miguel Serrano published &lt;em&gt;El Cordón Dorado: Hitlerismo Esotérico&lt;/em&gt;, claiming that Adolf Hitler was an Avatar of Vishnu communing with Hyperborean gods in an underground Antarctic base in New Swabia. Serrano predicted that Hitler would lead a fleet of UFOs from the base to establish the Fourth Reich.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;die-glocke&#34;&gt;Die Glocke &lt;a href=&#34;#die-glocke&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Die Glocke&lt;/em&gt; (&amp;ldquo;The Bell&amp;rdquo;) was a purported top-secret Nazi scientific technological device or &lt;em&gt;Wunderwaffe&lt;/em&gt;. First described by Igor Witkowski in &lt;em&gt;Prawda o Wunderwaffe&lt;/em&gt; (2000) and popularized by Nick Cook, it was associated with Nazi occultism, antigravity, and free energy suppression research. Claims about Die Glocke have been criticized as fictional and a hoax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists examples of Nazi UFOs appearing in popular culture, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert A. Heinlein&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Rocket Ship Galileo&lt;/em&gt; (1947) featuring a Nazi Moon base.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The video game &lt;em&gt;Medal of Honor: Frontline&lt;/em&gt; (2002) featuring a Nazi UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The movie &lt;em&gt;Iron Sky&lt;/em&gt; (2012) featuring a Nazi base on the moon launching an assault on Earth with flying saucers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revell releasing a scale model kit of a Nazi flying saucer called &amp;ldquo;Haunebu II&amp;rdquo; (2018), which was later removed from production due to historical inaccuracies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The video game &lt;em&gt;Wolfenstein II: The New Colossus&lt;/em&gt; (2017) featuring &amp;ldquo;Haunebu-V&amp;rdquo; craft manufactured in Nazi-controlled Roswell, New Mexico.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Commando Comic Flight of Fancy (2017) featuring the Schriever Flugkreisel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The second season finale of &lt;em&gt;30 Coins&lt;/em&gt; (2023) mentioning Haunebu UFOs as copies of Nazca UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nazi_UFOs&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nazi_UFOs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
