<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roswell on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/roswell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Roswell on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/roswell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Autopsy (1995 television film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f41f4fadf611/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f41f4fadf611/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-autopsy-1995-television-film&#34;&gt;Alien Autopsy (1995 television film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-autopsy-1995-television-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the 1995 pseudo-documentary &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy: Fact or Fiction&lt;/em&gt;, which featured footage purporting to show an alien autopsy conducted after the Roswell incident. The article distinguishes the original footage from the 2006 feature film &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt;, which is based on the events surrounding the creation of the hoax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section details the production of the &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; footage. It highlights Ray Santilli and Gary Shoefield&amp;rsquo;s admission in the 2006 documentary &lt;em&gt;Eamonn Investigates: Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; that they created the 1995 footage. The section describes how they filmed a simulated autopsy on a fabricated alien in a set constructed in a London living room. Artist and sculptor John Humphreys constructed two dummy alien bodies filled with raspberry jam, sheep brains, chicken entrails, and knuckle joints. Humphreys also played the role of the chief examiner. The section also mentions the creation of alien artifacts and the recruitment of a homeless man to play the role of the cameraman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section explores how &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; was received and satirized in the media. It mentions &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt; referencing the footage and later satirizing it in the episode &amp;ldquo;Jose Chung&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;From Outer Space&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. It also notes Fox airing a special debunking the footage and the release of the comedy film &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; (2006), which fictionalized the creation of the footage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including books, news articles, and documentaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of additional resources for readers interested in learning more about the &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; film and the surrounding controversy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external resources, including Ray Santilli&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;My Story&amp;rdquo; on VJ Enterprises, his IMDb page, and a YouTube link to &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy: Fact or Fiction?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Autopsy_(1995_film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Autopsy_(1995_film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Roswell Incident (1980 book)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_35f31e4c5c9f/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 19:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_35f31e4c5c9f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-roswell-incident-1980-book&#34;&gt;The Roswell Incident (1980 book) &lt;a href=&#34;#the-roswell-incident-1980-book&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This entry details the 1980 book &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt; by Charles Berlitz and William Moore, which popularized stories about the Roswell incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for the Roswell incident, focusing on the events of 1947 and the renewed interest in the story in the late 1970s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;events-of-1947&#34;&gt;Events of 1947 &lt;a href=&#34;#events-of-1947&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This subsection outlines the initial reports of unusual debris recovered near Roswell Army Air Field in July 1947, amidst a broader wave of &amp;ldquo;flying disc&amp;rdquo; sightings. It mentions Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting, the initial press release by Roswell Army Air Field, and the Army&amp;rsquo;s subsequent retraction, claiming the object was a weather balloon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;roswell-revisited&#34;&gt;Roswell revisited &lt;a href=&#34;#roswell-revisited&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This subsection highlights the resurgence of interest in the Roswell story in 1978, sparked by an interview with retired lieutenant colonel Jesse Marcel, who claimed the debris he retrieved was of extraterrestrial origin. Stanton Friedman, a ufologist, is also mentioned in this context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;authors&#34;&gt;Authors &lt;a href=&#34;#authors&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides background information on the authors of the book, Charles Berlitz and William Moore. It notes Berlitz&amp;rsquo;s previous success with &lt;em&gt;The Bermuda Triangle&lt;/em&gt;, a book that popularized the Bermuda Triangle mystery. It also mentions their collaboration on &lt;em&gt;The Philadelphia Experiment: Project Invisibility&lt;/em&gt;, which promoted the Philadelphia Experiment conspiracy theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents &lt;a href=&#34;#contents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the book&amp;rsquo;s central argument: that an extraterrestrial craft crashed near Roswell while observing nuclear weapons activity, and that the US government engaged in a cover-up. It mentions accounts of debris described as &amp;ldquo;nothing made on this earth&amp;rdquo; and includes testimonies from Bill Brazel, Floyd Proctor, and Walt Whitman Jr. It also introduces the idea that the debris shown in photos with Marcel was substituted as part of a cover-up. The section also notes that the authors claimed to have interviewed over 90 witnesses, but only a fraction of their testimonies appear in the book. The incarceration of Mac Brazel is also mentioned. The section also notes that the book elevated Marcel&amp;rsquo;s narrative above that of Cavitt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-bodies&#34;&gt;Alien bodies &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-bodies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the book&amp;rsquo;s introduction of the &amp;ldquo;Barnett Legend,&amp;rdquo; involving Grady &amp;ldquo;Barney&amp;rdquo; Barnett and archaeology students encountering wreckage and &amp;ldquo;alien bodies&amp;rdquo; on the Plains of San Agustin, far from the initial Roswell crash site. It also mentions the conflation of the Roswell incident with the Aztec, New Mexico, UFO incident, a hoax promoted by Frank Scully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the critical reception of &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt;, noting that some critics deemed it &amp;ldquo;a collection of wild hearsay&amp;rdquo; and questioned the authenticity of the Majestic 12 documents, pointing fingers at Moore. It also notes that the book did not achieve the commercial success its authors anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aftermath&#34;&gt;Aftermath &lt;a href=&#34;#aftermath&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section mentions Moore&amp;rsquo;s later admission at a MUFON conference in 1989 that he had engaged in &amp;ldquo;disinformation&amp;rdquo; activities against Paul Bennewitz on behalf of the Air Force Office of Special Investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modern-views&#34;&gt;Modern views &lt;a href=&#34;#modern-views&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section briefly mentions the 1993 inquiry by the General Accounting Office in response to US congressman Steven Schiff, and the subsequent 1994 Air Force report concluding that the recovered material was likely debris from Project Mogul, a military surveillance program using high-altitude balloons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Roswell_Incident_(1980_book)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Roswell_Incident_(1980_book)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
