<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roswell on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/roswell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Roswell on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/roswell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>List of reported UFO sightings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_583476a95eee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_583476a95eee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-reported-ufo-sightings&#34;&gt;List of Reported UFO Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-reported-ufo-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Wikipedia article provides a compilation of notable reported sightings of Unidentified Flying Objects (UFOs), including claims of close encounters and alien abduction. It clarifies that UFOs encompass any aerial phenomenon that cannot be immediately identified, noting that most are eventually explained as known objects or atmospheric phenomena. The article also mentions the use of the term &amp;ldquo;Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena&amp;rdquo; (UAP) to avoid associations with UFO conspiracy theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;antiquity&#34;&gt;Antiquity &lt;a href=&#34;#antiquity&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details alleged UFO sightings from ancient times, drawing from historical texts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c. 1450 BC:&lt;/strong&gt; The Tulli Papyrus describes an event during Thutmose III&amp;rsquo;s reign in Ancient Egypt, where a &amp;ldquo;star came down&amp;rdquo; and set fire to his adversaries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;218 BC:&lt;/strong&gt; Reports from the Roman Republic in Italia mention &amp;ldquo;phantom navy&amp;rdquo; seen shining in the sky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;76 BC:&lt;/strong&gt; An account from Asia (Roman Republic) describes a &amp;ldquo;spark&amp;rdquo; falling from a star, growing to the size of the Moon, and then transforming into a torch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;73 BC:&lt;/strong&gt; Plutarch recounts a &amp;ldquo;flame-like body&amp;rdquo; resembling a wine-jar (pithos) falling between Roman and Pontic armies in Phrygia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AD 65:&lt;/strong&gt; Flavius Josephus reports chariots &amp;ldquo;hurtling through the clouds&amp;rdquo; in Judaea before the First Jewish–Roman War.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AD 196:&lt;/strong&gt; Cassius Dio describes a &amp;ldquo;fine rain resembling silver&amp;rdquo; falling from a clear sky in Rome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;8th-century&#34;&gt;8th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#8th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a single entry:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c. AD 740:&lt;/strong&gt; The &amp;ldquo;Air ship of Clonmacnoise&amp;rdquo; is recorded in Irish annals, describing &amp;ldquo;ships with their crews were seen in the air&amp;rdquo; over Teltown and Clonmacnoise in Ireland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;16th17th-centuries&#34;&gt;16th–17th Centuries &lt;a href=&#34;#16th17th-centuries&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists reports from the Renaissance and early modern periods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1561:&lt;/strong&gt; A celestial phenomenon over Nuremberg, Bavaria, is described as an aerial battle with spheres, cylinders, and other odd-shaped objects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1566:&lt;/strong&gt; A broadsheet depicts spherical objects appearing out of the sun over Basel, Switzerland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1609:&lt;/strong&gt; Multiple witnesses in Joseon (Korea) describe a Halo or washbowl that was divided in two in the sky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;19th-century&#34;&gt;19th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#19th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers sightings from the 1800s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1883:&lt;/strong&gt; Astronomer José Bonilla photographed hundreds of dark objects crossing the sun at the Zacatecas Observatory in Mexico.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1896-1897:&lt;/strong&gt; Reports of &amp;ldquo;mystery airships&amp;rdquo; with bright lights and cigar-shaped bodies appear in newspapers across California and the Midwest United States.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1897:&lt;/strong&gt; S.E. Hayden reports the crash of an airship piloted by an alien in Aurora, Texas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;20th-century&#34;&gt;20th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#20th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is divided into two sub-sections: 1900-1949 and 1950-1974.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;19001949&#34;&gt;1900–1949 &lt;a href=&#34;#19001949&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the early to mid-20th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1904:&lt;/strong&gt; Crew members aboard the USS &lt;em&gt;Supply&lt;/em&gt; report seeing three &amp;ldquo;bright red&amp;rdquo; objects in geometrical formation flight pattern in the North Pacific.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1907:&lt;/strong&gt; Fighters of Çerçiz Topulli in Albania report seeing a shiny object suspended in the air.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1909:&lt;/strong&gt; Moving lights are reported in the sky around Otago, New Zealand, followed by more sightings across the country.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1917:&lt;/strong&gt; Thousands gather in Fátima, Portugal, and claim to see bizarre solar activity, later interpreted as a mass UFO sighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1926:&lt;/strong&gt; Nicholas Roerich reports an oval object in the sky above his caravan in Tibet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1933:&lt;/strong&gt; Frank Smythe witnesses two spots hovering and pulsating in the sky near Mount Everest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1940s:&lt;/strong&gt; Allied fighter pilots report colorful balls of light following their aircraft during World War II (Foo fighters).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1941:&lt;/strong&gt; A local legend emerges in Cape Girardeau, Missouri, about a crashed flying saucer and its dying crew.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1942:&lt;/strong&gt; Anti-aircraft artillery fires thousands of rounds at an unidentified aerial object over Los Angeles, California (Battle of Los Angeles).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1942:&lt;/strong&gt; Control tower operator near Flying School, Columbus, Missouri observes two reddish colored round objects descend-hover-accelerate away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1944:&lt;/strong&gt; 468th Bomb Group reports an intense red or orange object that throbbed or vibrated constantly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1945:&lt;/strong&gt; Conflicting accounts emerge regarding an avocado-shaped craft piloted by insectoid aliens crashing at the Trinity nuclear test site in New Mexico.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1946:&lt;/strong&gt; Thousands of UFO sightings are reported over Europe (Ghost Rockets), prompting investigations by the Swedish and Greek governments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1946:&lt;/strong&gt; Swedish entrepreneur Gösta Carlsson commemorates a 1946 UFO encounter with a concrete monument in Ängelholm, Sweden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; Private pilot Kenneth Arnold reports seeing a group of reflective craft moving at high speeds near Mount Rainier, Washington, coining the term &amp;ldquo;flying saucers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; Over 800 similar sightings are reported throughout 1947 after the Kenneth Arnold sighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; A United Airlines crew witnesses nine unidentified objects en route from Boise, Idaho, to Pendleton, Oregon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; William Albert Rhodes takes photographs of a silent grey object in Phoenix, Arizona.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; Walter Haut issues a press release announcing the &amp;ldquo;capture&amp;rdquo; of a &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; near Roswell, New Mexico, later retracted as a weather balloon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; Fred Crisman mails an account of flying doughnut-shaped objects and threats from Men in Black to Raymond A. Palmer (Maury Island hoax).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; Reports of green flares streaking across the sky are investigated by the US Air Force (The Green Fireballs).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; Captain Thomas F. Mantell dies in the crash of his P-51 Mustang fighter plane near Franklin, Kentucky, after pursuing an unidentified flying object.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; Conmen Silas Newton and Leo Gebauer sell &amp;ldquo;magnetic oil-detecting machines&amp;rdquo; based on a story about replicated technology from a crashed spaceship (Aztec, New Mexico UFO hoax).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; Clarence Chiles and John Whitted report that their airplane nearly collided with a UFO near Montgomery, Alabama.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; A US Air Force pilot sights and pursues a UFO for 27 minutes over Fargo, North Dakota (Gorman dogfight).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;19501974&#34;&gt;1950–1974 &lt;a href=&#34;#19501974&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the mid to late 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1950:&lt;/strong&gt; A farmer takes pictures of a purported &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; near McMinnville, Oregon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1950:&lt;/strong&gt; The manager of Great Falls&amp;rsquo; pro baseball team took color film of two UFOs flying over Great Falls, Montana.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1951:&lt;/strong&gt; Two pilots and a military officer passenger aboard a commercial DC-3 reported being buzzed by an unidentified straight-winged plane over Sioux City, Iowa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1951:&lt;/strong&gt; Several lights in V-shaped formations were repeatedly spotted flying over the city of Lubbock, Texas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952:&lt;/strong&gt; Four American military personnel aboard two different B-29 bombers reported seeing an orange globe-shaped light over two different cities in northern Korea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952:&lt;/strong&gt; A series of sightings accompanied radar contacts in the Washington, D.C. area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952:&lt;/strong&gt; William B. Nash and William H. Fortenberry, pilots of a DC-4 airliner of Pan American Airways, radioed the Norfolk civil aviation authority to report eight large, round, glowing red objects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952:&lt;/strong&gt; Three local boys followed a bright object into the forest to what they believed was a UFO landing in Flatwoods, West Virginia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1954:&lt;/strong&gt; French metalworker Marius Dewilde claimed to have become a contactee in Quarouble, France.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1954:&lt;/strong&gt; A football game between Fiorentina and Pistoiese was under way at the Stadio Artemio Franchi in Florence when a group of UFOs traveling at high speed abruptly stopped over the stadium.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1955:&lt;/strong&gt; Eleven people witnessed creatures in the night at a rural farmhouse near Hopkinsville, Kentucky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1956:&lt;/strong&gt; United States Air Force (USAF) and Royal Air Force (RAF) radar operators detected up to 15 objects over Suffolk, England.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1956:&lt;/strong&gt; Elizabeth Klarer claimed detailed adventures with an alien race including having had an alien lover, Akon, who would have fathered her son Ayling in Drakens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO_sightings&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO_sightings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roswell incident</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_e0eebde49501/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_e0eebde49501/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-legend-caused-by-1947-balloon-crash-roswell-incident&#34;&gt;UFO Legend Caused by 1947 Balloon Crash: Roswell Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-legend-caused-by-1947-balloon-crash-roswell-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Roswell incident is a cornerstone of UFO lore, stemming from the recovery of debris near Roswell, New Mexico, in 1947. Initially reported as a &amp;ldquo;flying disc&amp;rdquo; capture, the U.S. Army quickly retracted the statement, claiming it was a weather balloon. This event, coupled with subsequent government explanations and retractions, fueled decades of conspiracy theories alleging a cover-up of extraterrestrial contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1947-military-balloon-crash&#34;&gt;1947 Military Balloon Crash &lt;a href=&#34;#1947-military-balloon-crash&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the initial event and its immediate aftermath. In 1947, rancher W.W. &amp;ldquo;Mac&amp;rdquo; Brazel discovered debris on his property near Corona, New Mexico. The debris consisted of tinfoil, rubber, tape, and wooden beams. Unaware of the ongoing &amp;ldquo;flying disc craze,&amp;rdquo; Brazel initially didn&amp;rsquo;t connect the debris to UFOs. However, after visiting Corona, his uncle suggested it could be from a &amp;ldquo;flying disk.&amp;rdquo; Brazel reported the findings to Sheriff George Wilcox, who contacted Roswell Army Air Field (RAAF).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RAAF sent Major Jesse Marcel and Captain Sheridan Cavitt to investigate. A press release issued by public information officer Walter Haut announced the military&amp;rsquo;s recovery of a &amp;ldquo;flying disc.&amp;rdquo; This announcement made international headlines but was quickly retracted. General Roger Ramey and weather officer Irving Newton identified the material as a weather balloon at a press conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufo-conspiracy-theories-19471978&#34;&gt;UFO Conspiracy Theories (1947–1978) &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-conspiracy-theories-19471978&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the period between the initial incident and the rise of modern Roswell conspiracy theories. The Roswell debris retrieval faded from public attention for three decades. However, belief in government UFO cover-ups grew, fueled by hoaxes and legends of crashed spaceships and alien bodies in New Mexico. The Aztec, New Mexico crashed saucer hoax introduced the idea of recovered alien bodies, which later became associated with Roswell. The concept of &amp;ldquo;Hangar 18,&amp;rdquo; a fictional location at Wright-Patterson Air Force Base, emerged as a storage site for alien craft and bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;roswell-conspiracy-theories-19781994&#34;&gt;Roswell Conspiracy Theories (1978–1994) &lt;a href=&#34;#roswell-conspiracy-theories-19781994&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the resurgence of interest in Roswell and the development of modern conspiracy theories. In 1978, ufologist Stanton Friedman interviewed Jesse Marcel, who stated that the &amp;ldquo;weather balloon&amp;rdquo; explanation was a cover story and that he believed the debris was extraterrestrial. This interview, along with subsequent media attention, reignited interest in the Roswell incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1980 book &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt; by Charles Berlitz and Bill Moore popularized Marcel&amp;rsquo;s account and added the claim of alien bodies found on the Plains of San Agustin. The book also connected Marcel&amp;rsquo;s account to Lydia Sleppy, a former teletype operator who claimed she was ordered to stop transmitting a story about crashed saucer wreckage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Majestic 12 hoax, involving faked government documents, emerged in the 1980s, further fueling conspiracy theories. Glenn Dennis, a former mortician, provided an account of extraterrestrial corpses, which was endorsed by prominent Roswell ufologists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competing accounts of the Roswell incident led to a schism among ufologists in the early 1990s. &lt;em&gt;UFO Crash at Roswell&lt;/em&gt; by Kevin Randle and Donald Schmitt added testimony from new witnesses. &lt;em&gt;Crash at Corona&lt;/em&gt; by Stanton Friedman and Don Berliner introduced the idea of two crashed saucers and eight aliens. &lt;em&gt;The Truth About the UFO Crash at Roswell&lt;/em&gt; by Randle and Schmitt proposed a new crash site and a different group of archaeologists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;air-force-response&#34;&gt;Air Force Response &lt;a href=&#34;#air-force-response&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the official government response to the growing Roswell conspiracy theories. Under pressure from New Mexico congressman Steven Schiff and the General Accounting Office (GAO), the Air Force published reports in the mid-1990s. The initial 1994 report admitted that the weather balloon explanation was a cover story for Project Mogul, a military surveillance program. The 1995 report, &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Report: Fact vs. Fiction in the New Mexico Desert&lt;/em&gt;, supported this with documentation that narrowed the cause of the debris to a specific Mogul balloon train. The 1997 report, &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Report: Case Closed&lt;/em&gt;, detailed how eyewitness accounts of military personnel loading aliens into &amp;ldquo;body bags&amp;rdquo; matched the Air Force&amp;rsquo;s procedures for retrieving parachute test dummies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;later-theories-and-hoaxes-1994present&#34;&gt;Later Theories and Hoaxes (1994–Present) &lt;a href=&#34;#later-theories-and-hoaxes-1994present&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the continued development of Roswell theories and hoaxes in recent decades. &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy: Fact or Fiction&lt;/em&gt;, a pseudo-documentary, played a major role in shaping popular opinion of Roswell. The film centered around Ray Santilli&amp;rsquo;s hoaxed footage of an alien autopsy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1997, retired army intelligence officer Philip J. Corso released &lt;em&gt;The Day After Roswell&lt;/em&gt;, alleging that he was shown a nonhuman body and helped oversee a project to reverse engineer recovered crash debris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other theories include Annie Jacobsen&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Area 51: An Uncensored History of America&amp;rsquo;s Top Secret Military Base&lt;/em&gt;, which featured a claim that Nazi doctor Josef Mengele was recruited by Soviet leader Joseph Stalin to produce &amp;ldquo;grotesque, child-size aviators.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;explanations&#34;&gt;Explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents the explanations for the Roswell incident, focusing on Project Mogul and anthropomorphic dummies. The Air Force reports identified Project Mogul as the source of the 1947 debris and concluded that other alien crash accounts were likely misidentified military programs or accidents. The 1997 Air Force report concluded that the alleged &amp;ldquo;bodies&amp;rdquo; reported by later eyewitnesses came from memories of accidents involving military casualties and memories of the recovery of anthropomorphic dummies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultural-impact&#34;&gt;Cultural Impact &lt;a href=&#34;#cultural-impact&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the impact of the Roswell incident on tourism, commercialization, and popular fiction. Roswell&amp;rsquo;s tourism industry is based on ufology museums and businesses, as well as alien-themed iconography. A yearly UFO festival has been held since 1995.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incident has been depicted in numerous films and television shows, including &lt;em&gt;Hangar 18&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Independence Day&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Roswell&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Widespread speculation of a cover-up led to United States presidents being questioned about the Roswell incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell_UFO_incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell_UFO_incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roswell incident</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_f555c61b161a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_f555c61b161a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;roswell-incident&#34;&gt;Roswell Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#roswell-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Roswell incident refers to the events surrounding the crash of a military balloon near Roswell, New Mexico, in 1947. This event later became the basis for widespread conspiracy theories alleging the recovery of an extraterrestrial spacecraft by the United States military. The article explores the initial event, the subsequent development of UFO conspiracy theories, and the official explanations provided by the United States Air Force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufo-legend-caused-by-1947-balloon-crash&#34;&gt;UFO Legend Caused by 1947 Balloon Crash &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-legend-caused-by-1947-balloon-crash&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces the Roswell incident, highlighting the initial newspaper headline that reported the &amp;ldquo;capture&amp;rdquo; of a &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; by the Roswell Army Air Field (RAAF). It sets the stage for the timeline of events, which occurred between June 4 and July 10, 1947, in Lincoln County, New Mexico. The section also mentions the &amp;ldquo;1947 flying disc craze&amp;rdquo; and lists related events such as the Kenneth Arnold sighting, the Flight 105 sighting, and various hoaxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;military-balloon-debris-recovered-in-1947&#34;&gt;Military Balloon Debris Recovered in 1947 &lt;a href=&#34;#military-balloon-debris-recovered-in-1947&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the initial event, explaining that military balloon debris was recovered near Roswell, New Mexico, in 1947. It clarifies that this debris later became the basis for conspiracy theories about a crashed extraterrestrial spacecraft. The balloon was part of the top-secret Project Mogul, operated from Alamogordo Army Air Field, designed to detect Soviet nuclear tests. The United States Army initially announced the possession of a &amp;ldquo;flying disc&amp;rdquo; but retracted the statement within a day, attributing the debris to a conventional weather balloon to obscure the true purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1947-military-balloon-crash&#34;&gt;1947 Military Balloon Crash &lt;a href=&#34;#1947-military-balloon-crash&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a detailed account of the events leading up to the Roswell incident. It explains that by 1947, the United States had launched thousands of top-secret Project Mogul balloons to listen for Soviet atomic tests. On June 4, researchers at Alamogordo Army Air Field in New Mexico launched a long train of these balloons, which they lost contact with near Corona, New Mexico, where W.W. &amp;ldquo;Mac&amp;rdquo; Brazel&amp;rsquo;s ranch was located. Brazel discovered tinfoil, rubber, tape, and thin wooden beams scattered across his ranch later that month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brazel, initially unaware of the &amp;ldquo;flying disc craze,&amp;rdquo; visited Corona on July 5, where his uncle suggested the debris could be from a &amp;ldquo;flying disk.&amp;rdquo; The next day, Brazel informed Sheriff George Wilcox of his discovery, who then contacted Roswell Army Air Field (RAAF). Major Jesse Marcel and Captain Sheridan Cavitt were assigned to gather the material. On July 8, RAAF public information officer Walter Haut issued a press release stating that the military had recovered a &amp;ldquo;flying disc&amp;rdquo; near Roswell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The section also describes the press conference where General Roger Ramey, Colonel Thomas DuBose, and weather officer Irving Newton identified the material as pieces of a weather balloon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufo-conspiracy-theories-19471978&#34;&gt;UFO Conspiracy Theories (1947–1978) &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-conspiracy-theories-19471978&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explains that the 1947 debris retrieval remained relatively obscure for three decades. Reporting ceased after the government provided a mundane explanation, and broader reporting on flying saucers declined rapidly after the Twin Falls saucer hoax. Despite this, belief in UFO cover-ups by the US government became widespread. Hoaxes, legends, and stories of crashed spaceships and alien bodies in New Mexico emerged that later formed elements of the Roswell myth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aztec-crashed-saucer-hoax&#34;&gt;Aztec Crashed Saucer Hoax &lt;a href=&#34;#aztec-crashed-saucer-hoax&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces the Aztec, New Mexico crashed saucer hoax in 1948, which introduced stories of recovered alien bodies that later became associated with Roswell. The hoax narrative included small grey humanoid bodies, metal stronger than any found on Earth, indecipherable writing, and a government coverup to prevent public panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hangar-18&#34;&gt;Hangar 18 &lt;a href=&#34;#hangar-18&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses &amp;ldquo;Hangar 18,&amp;rdquo; a non-existent location that many later conspiracy theories allege housed extraterrestrial craft or bodies recovered from Roswell. The idea of alien corpses from a crashed ship being stored in an Air Force morgue at the Wright-Patterson Air Force Base was mentioned in Scully&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Behind the Flying Saucers&lt;/em&gt;, expanded in the 1966 book &lt;em&gt;Incident at Exeter&lt;/em&gt;, and became the basis for a 1968 science-fiction novel &lt;em&gt;The Fortec Conspiracy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;roswell-conspiracy-theories-19781994&#34;&gt;Roswell Conspiracy Theories (1978–1994) &lt;a href=&#34;#roswell-conspiracy-theories-19781994&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the rekindling of interest in Roswell after ufologist Stanton Friedman interviewed Jesse Marcel in 1978. Marcel stated that the &amp;ldquo;weather balloon&amp;rdquo; explanation from the press conference was a cover story and that he now believed the debris was extraterrestrial. The tabloid &lt;em&gt;National Enquirer&lt;/em&gt; brought large-scale attention to the Marcel story the following February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-roswell-incident&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#the-roswell-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the first Roswell conspiracy book, &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt; by Charles Berlitz and Bill Moore, released in October 1980. The book argues that an extraterrestrial craft was flying over the New Mexico desert to observe nuclear weapons activity when a lightning strike killed the alien crew. It alleges that, after recovering the crashed alien technology, the US government engaged in a cover-up to prevent mass panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;majestic-12-hoax&#34;&gt;Majestic 12 Hoax &lt;a href=&#34;#majestic-12-hoax&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses Majestic 12, the purported organization behind faked government documents delivered anonymously to multiple ufologists in the 1980s. The anonymously delivered documents detailed the creation of a likely fictitious Majestic 12 group formed to handle Roswell debris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;role-of-glenn-dennis&#34;&gt;Role of Glenn Dennis &lt;a href=&#34;#role-of-glenn-dennis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces Glenn Dennis, a former mortician who provided an account of extraterrestrial corpses endorsed by prominent Roswell ufologists. Dennis claimed to have received calls from the Air Base with questions about body preservation and inquiries about small or hermetically sealed caskets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;competing-accounts-and-schism&#34;&gt;Competing Accounts and Schism &lt;a href=&#34;#competing-accounts-and-schism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explains that a proliferation of competing Roswell accounts led to a schism among ufologists in the early 1990s. The two leading UFO societies disagreed on the scenarios presented by Randle–Schmitt and Friedman–Berliner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;ufo-crash-at-roswell&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;UFO Crash at Roswell&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-crash-at-roswell&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on Kevin Randle and Donald Schmitt&amp;rsquo;s book, &lt;em&gt;UFO Crash at Roswell&lt;/em&gt;, published in 1991. The book claimed that General Arthur Exon had been aware of debris and bodies, and it included Glenn Dennis&amp;rsquo;s claims of an alien autopsy and Grady Barnett&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;alien body&amp;rdquo; accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;crash-at-corona&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crash at Corona&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#crash-at-corona&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses Stanton Friedman&amp;rsquo;s book, &lt;em&gt;Crash at Corona&lt;/em&gt;, co-authored with Don Berliner, released in 1992. The book introduced new &amp;ldquo;witnesses&amp;rdquo; and added to the narrative by doubling the number of flying saucers to two, and the number of aliens to eight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-truth-about-the-ufo-crash-at-roswell&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Truth About the UFO Crash at Roswell&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#the-truth-about-the-ufo-crash-at-roswell&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on Randle and Schmitt&amp;rsquo;s 1994 book, &lt;em&gt;The Truth About the UFO Crash at Roswell&lt;/em&gt;, which claimed a cargo plane delivered alien bodies to Dwight D. Eisenhower. The book abandoned the Barnett crash site on the Plains of San Agustin and proposed a new crash site 35 miles north of Roswell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;air-force-response&#34;&gt;Air Force Response &lt;a href=&#34;#air-force-response&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the Air Force&amp;rsquo;s official responses to Roswell conspiracy theories during the mid-1990s. The initial 1994 USAF report admitted that the weather balloon explanation was a cover story for Project Mogul, a military surveillance program. The following year, &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Report: Fact vs. Fiction in the New Mexico Desert&lt;/em&gt; supported this with extensive documentation that narrowed the cause of the debris to a specific Mogul balloon train launched on June 4, 1947, and lost near the Roswell debris field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;later-theories-and-hoaxes-1994present&#34;&gt;Later Theories and Hoaxes (1994–Present) &lt;a href=&#34;#later-theories-and-hoaxes-1994present&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses later theories and hoaxes related to the Roswell incident, including the &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; film and Philip J. Corso&amp;rsquo;s book, &lt;em&gt;The Day After Roswell&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-autopsy&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-autopsy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the pseudo-documentary &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy: Fact or Fiction&lt;/em&gt;, which claimed to have footage of an alien autopsy filmed after the 1947 Roswell crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-day-after-roswell&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Day After Roswell&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#the-day-after-roswell&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses Philip J. Corso&amp;rsquo;s book, &lt;em&gt;The Day After Roswell&lt;/em&gt;, released in 1997. Corso alleged that he was shown a purportedly nonhuman body suspended in liquid inside a glass coffin and that he helped oversee a project to reverse engineer recovered crash debris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-debunked-or-fringe-theories&#34;&gt;Related Debunked or Fringe Theories &lt;a href=&#34;#related-debunked-or-fringe-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions related debunked or fringe theories, including Annie Jacobsen&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Area 51: An Uncensored History of America&amp;rsquo;s Top Secret Military Base&lt;/em&gt;, which featured a claim that Nazi doctor Josef Mengele was recruited by Soviet leader Joseph Stalin to produce &amp;ldquo;grotesque, child-size aviators&amp;rdquo; to cause hysteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;explanations&#34;&gt;Explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides explanations for the Roswell incident, stating that secrecy around the 1947 debris recovery was due to Cold War military programs rather than aliens. It notes that UFO believers maintain that a spacecraft crashed near Roswell, and &amp;ldquo;Roswell&amp;rdquo; remains synonymous with UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-mogul&#34;&gt;Project Mogul &lt;a href=&#34;#project-mogul&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section identifies the crashed object from the 1947 incident as a Project Mogul device. Mogul was a military surveillance program employing high-altitude balloons to monitor nuclear tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;anthropomorphic-dummies&#34;&gt;Anthropomorphic Dummies &lt;a href=&#34;#anthropomorphic-dummies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explains that the 1947 Roswell accounts did not mention alien bodies. The 1997 Air Force report concluded that the alleged &amp;ldquo;bodies&amp;rdquo; reported by later eyewitnesses came&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell_Incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell_Incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Roswell Incident (1980 book)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_35f31e4c5c9f/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 19:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_35f31e4c5c9f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-roswell-incident-1980-book&#34;&gt;The Roswell Incident (1980 book) &lt;a href=&#34;#the-roswell-incident-1980-book&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry details the 1980 book &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt; by Charles Berlitz and William Moore, which significantly contributed to popularizing the Roswell incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for the Roswell incident, focusing on the events of 1947 and the renewed interest in the story in the late 1970s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;events-of-1947&#34;&gt;Events of 1947 &lt;a href=&#34;#events-of-1947&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection outlines the initial reports of the Roswell incident during the &amp;ldquo;flying disc craze&amp;rdquo; of 1947, Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting, the Roswell Army Air Field&amp;rsquo;s initial press release about recovering a crashed disc, and the subsequent retraction stating it was a weather balloon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;roswell-revisited&#34;&gt;Roswell revisited &lt;a href=&#34;#roswell-revisited&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explains how the Roswell story gained traction again in 1978 when retired lieutenant colonel Jesse Marcel claimed in an interview with ufologist Stanton Friedman that the debris he recovered was extraterrestrial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;authors&#34;&gt;Authors &lt;a href=&#34;#authors&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides background information on the authors of the book, Charles Berlitz and William Moore. It mentions Berlitz&amp;rsquo;s previous success with &lt;em&gt;The Bermuda Triangle&lt;/em&gt; and their collaboration on &lt;em&gt;The Philadelphia Experiment: Project Invisibility&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents &lt;a href=&#34;#contents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the book&amp;rsquo;s central argument: that an extraterrestrial craft crashed in New Mexico while observing nuclear weapons activity, and the US government engaged in a cover-up. It highlights accounts of debris described as &amp;ldquo;nothing made on this earth&amp;rdquo; and mentions witnesses like Bill Brazel, Floyd Proctor, and Walt Whitman Jr. The section also notes the book&amp;rsquo;s introduction of the idea that the debris shown in photos with Marcel was substituted as part of the cover-up. It also mentions the claim that the military sought to discredit the growing interest in flying saucers. The section also notes that the authors claimed to have interviewed over 90 witnesses, but only a fraction of those accounts appear in the book. The section also notes that the book elevated Marcel&amp;rsquo;s narrative above that of Cavitt, whose description of the debris contradicted Marcel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-bodies&#34;&gt;Alien bodies &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-bodies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the book&amp;rsquo;s introduction of the story about Barney Barnett and archaeology students encountering wreckage and &amp;ldquo;alien bodies&amp;rdquo; on the Plains of San Agustin. It also mentions the conflation of the Roswell incident with the Aztec, New Mexico, UFO incident, a hoaxed flying saucer crash promoted by Frank Scully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the reception of the book, noting that critics deemed it &amp;ldquo;a collection of wild hearsay&amp;rdquo; and that it &amp;ldquo;did not make the commercial impact its authors hoped.&amp;rdquo; It also mentions accusations against Moore regarding the Majestic 12 documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aftermath&#34;&gt;Aftermath &lt;a href=&#34;#aftermath&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions Moore&amp;rsquo;s admission at a 1989 MUFON conference that he had engaged in &amp;ldquo;disinformation&amp;rdquo; activities against Paul Bennewitz on behalf of the Air Force Office of Special Investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modern-views&#34;&gt;Modern views &lt;a href=&#34;#modern-views&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section references the 1993 inquiry by the General Accounting Office in response to US congressman Steven Schiff, which led to a 1994 Air Force report concluding that the recovered material was likely debris from Project Mogul, a military surveillance program using high-altitude balloons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Roswell_Incident_(1980_book)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Roswell_Incident_(1980_book)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
