<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Public Art on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/public-art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Public Art on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 17:36:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/public-art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien (sculpture)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_fdd30e01eb6d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 17:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_fdd30e01eb6d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-sculpture&#34;&gt;Alien (sculpture) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-sculpture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry focuses on the 2012 sculpture &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; by British artist David Breuer-Weil. It details the sculpture&amp;rsquo;s physical characteristics, its installation history, the artist&amp;rsquo;s inspiration, and its reception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description &lt;a href=&#34;#description&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sculpture &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; is a large-scale artwork created in 2012 by David Breuer-Weil. It depicts a giant humanoid figure, five times the size of a person, seemingly embedded head-first into the ground. The sculpture is made of glass reinforced plastic with a bronze powder coat. Key features include enlarged fingerprints and graffiti by the artist, and the name &amp;ldquo;Ernst&amp;rdquo; written on its surface. Its dimensions are 600 cm (240 in).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation-history&#34;&gt;Installation History &lt;a href=&#34;#installation-history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; was initially installed in Grosvenor Gardens in the City of Westminster in April 2013 as part of the City of Sculpture initiative. It remained there until April 13, 2015, after an extension to its initial six-month display period was approved. On September 7, 2015, the sculpture was moved to Mottisfont, a National Trust property in Hampshire, England, where it is currently located. The coordinates for its location at Mottisfont are provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inspiration-and-meaning&#34;&gt;Inspiration and Meaning &lt;a href=&#34;#inspiration-and-meaning&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Breuer-Weil drew inspiration for &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; from several sources. A significant influence was his grandfather, Ernst, who fled to England from Austria after the Nazi takeover in 1938 but was subsequently labeled an &amp;ldquo;enemy alien.&amp;rdquo; The name &amp;ldquo;Ernst&amp;rdquo; on the sculpture acknowledges this connection. The sculpture also incorporates a portrait of the fictional Kaiser of Nerac, a character from Breuer-Weil&amp;rsquo;s imaginary world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breuer-Weil intended &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; to evoke the surprise and shock of an alien landing. He also suggests that the sculpture explores themes of belonging and the human condition, with the &amp;ldquo;alien&amp;rdquo; representing something sudden and unexpected, like a new work of art. He connects the concept of being an alien to the Jewish experience, suggesting a sense of both belonging and being an outsider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; was well-received by both the public and critics. It was named one of &lt;em&gt;Time Out&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Top 10 Public Sculptures&amp;rdquo; in July 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_(sculpture)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_(sculpture)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
