<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CETI on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ceti/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CETI on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 13:24:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ceti/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Communication with extraterrestrial intelligence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_2e93b1dd3f75/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 13:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_2e93b1dd3f75/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;communication-with-extraterrestrial-intelligence-ceti&#34;&gt;Communication with Extraterrestrial Intelligence (CETI) &lt;a href=&#34;#communication-with-extraterrestrial-intelligence-ceti&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CETI is a branch of SETI (Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence) that focuses on composing and deciphering interstellar messages that could theoretically be understood by another technological civilization. A well-known CETI experiment is the 1974 Arecibo message composed by Frank Drake. The abbreviations CETI and SETI are generic and do not refer to any particular organization like the SETI Institute. CETI research focuses on mathematical languages, pictorial systems (like the Arecibo message), algorithmic communication systems (ACETI), and computational approaches to detecting and deciphering &amp;ldquo;natural&amp;rdquo; language communication. Research also addresses how to overcome problems of decipherment in interplanetary communication, similar to the challenges posed by undeciphered writing systems in human communication like Linear A. In 2015, scientists including Douglas Vakoch, David Grinspoon, Seth Shostak, and David Brin discussed active SETI and the potential risks of transmitting messages to extraterrestrials. A statement signed by many in the SETI community emphasized the need for a global discussion before sending any messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 19th century, speculation about inhabitants of other planets was common, with many believing intelligent beings lived on the Moon, Mars, and/or Venus. Before radio, proposals for signaling extraterrestrials included Carl Friedrich Gauss&amp;rsquo;s 1820 suggestion to draw a giant Pythagorean triangle on the Siberian tundra and Joseph Johann Littrow&amp;rsquo;s 1819 idea to use the Sahara as a &amp;ldquo;blackboard&amp;rdquo; with trenches filled with water and kerosene to create signals. Astronomers like Franz von Paula Gruithuisen also looked for signs of life, claiming to see cities and agriculture on the Moon and evidence of life on Venus. By the late 1800s, Mars became the focus after Giovanni Schiaparelli reported &amp;ldquo;canali&amp;rdquo; (channels) on Mars, which were mistranslated as &amp;ldquo;canals,&amp;rdquo; sparking enthusiasm about Martian life. Inventor Charles Cros sought funding for a giant mirror to signal Martians, while Nikola Tesla believed his inventions could be used for interplanetary communication and claimed to have observed extraterrestrial radio signals. The Guzman Prize was created, offering 100,000 francs to the first person to establish interplanetary communication, excluding Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;mathematical-and-scientific-languages&#34;&gt;Mathematical and Scientific Languages &lt;a href=&#34;#mathematical-and-scientific-languages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers artificial languages designed for interstellar communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lincos-lingua-cosmica&#34;&gt;Lincos (Lingua cosmica) &lt;a href=&#34;#lincos-lingua-cosmica&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hans Freudenthal&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Lincos: Design of a Language for Cosmic Intercourse&lt;/em&gt; (1960) expands upon Astraglossa to create a general-purpose language derived from basic mathematics and logic symbols. A dictionary resembling Lincos was featured in Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s novel &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; and its film adaptation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;astraglossa&#34;&gt;Astraglossa &lt;a href=&#34;#astraglossa&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lancelot Hogben&amp;rsquo;s 1963 essay &amp;ldquo;Astraglossa&amp;rdquo; describes a system for combining numbers and operators in a series of short and long pulses, where short pulses represent numbers and trains of long pulses represent symbols for addition, subtraction, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;carl-sagan&#34;&gt;Carl Sagan &lt;a href=&#34;#carl-sagan&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s 1985 science fiction novel &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; explores how a message might be constructed for communication with an alien civilization, using prime numbers as a starting point, followed by universal principles and facts of mathematics and science. Sagan also edited a nonfiction book on the subject, and an updated collection of articles was published in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-language-based-on-the-fundamental-facts-of-science&#34;&gt;A Language Based on the Fundamental Facts of Science &lt;a href=&#34;#a-language-based-on-the-fundamental-facts-of-science&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Devito and Richard Oehrle&amp;rsquo;s 1992 paper, &lt;em&gt;A language based on the fundamental facts of science&lt;/em&gt;, describes a language similar in syntax to Astraglossa and Lincos, but which builds its vocabulary around known physical properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;busch-general-purpose-binary-language-used-in-lone-signal-transmissions&#34;&gt;Busch General-Purpose Binary Language Used in Lone Signal Transmissions &lt;a href=&#34;#busch-general-purpose-binary-language-used-in-lone-signal-transmissions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2010, Michael W. Busch created a general-purpose binary language later used in the Lone Signal project to transmit crowdsourced messages to extraterrestrial intelligence (METI). This was followed by an attempt to extend the syntax used in the Lone Signal hailing message to communicate in a way that, while neither mathematical nor strictly logical, was nonetheless understandable given the prior definition of terms and concepts in the Lone Signal hailing message. The Lone Signal project sent messages to Gliese 526 (HD 119850) in the constellation Boötes, with the message sent on July 10, 2013, and expected to arrive in 2031.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;pictorial-messages&#34;&gt;Pictorial Messages &lt;a href=&#34;#pictorial-messages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictorial communication systems describe fundamental mathematical or physical concepts via simplified diagrams sent as bitmaps. These messages assume the recipient has similar visual capabilities and can understand basic mathematics and geometry. A critique is that they presume a shared understanding of shapes, which may not be the case with a species with substantially different vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pioneer-probes&#34;&gt;Pioneer Probes &lt;a href=&#34;#pioneer-probes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two etched plaques, known as the Pioneer plaques, were included aboard the Pioneer 10 and Pioneer 11 spacecraft when they launched in 1972 and 1973. The plaques depict the location of the Solar System within the galaxy and the Earth within the Solar System, as well as the form of the human body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;voyager-probes&#34;&gt;Voyager Probes &lt;a href=&#34;#voyager-probes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Launched in 1977, the Voyager probes carried two golden records that were inscribed with diagrams similar to the Pioneer plaques, depicting the human form, the Solar System, and its location. Also included were recordings of images and sounds from Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;arecibo-message&#34;&gt;Arecibo Message &lt;a href=&#34;#arecibo-message&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Arecibo message, transmitted in 1974, was a 1,679-pixel bitmap that, when properly arranged into 73 rows and 23 columns, shows the numbers one through ten; the atomic numbers of hydrogen, carbon, nitrogen, oxygen, and phosphorus; the formulas for the sugars and bases that make up the nucleotides of DNA; the number of nucleotides in the human genome; the double helix structure of DNA; a simple illustration of a human being and its height; the human population of Earth; a diagram of the Solar System; and an illustration of the Arecibo telescope with its diameter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cosmic-call-messages&#34;&gt;Cosmic Call Messages &lt;a href=&#34;#cosmic-call-messages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Cosmic Call&lt;/em&gt; messages consisted of digital sections – &amp;ldquo;Rosetta Stone&amp;rdquo;, a copy of the Arecibo Message, the Bilingual Image Glossary, and the Braastad message – as well as text, audio, video, and other image files submitted for transmission by people around the world. The &amp;ldquo;Rosetta Stone&amp;rdquo; was composed by Stéphane Dumas and Yvan Dutil, and represents a multi-page bitmap that builds a vocabulary of symbols representing numbers and mathematical operations. These messages were transmitted in 1999 and 2003 from Evpatoria Planetary Radar in Russia under the scientific guidance of Alexander L. Zaitsev. Richard Braastad coordinated the overall project. Star systems to which the messages were sent include 16 Cyg A, 15 Sge, HD 178428, Gl 777, Hip 4872, HD 245409, 55 Cnc, HD 10307, and 47 UMa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;multi-modal-messages&#34;&gt;Multi-Modal Messages &lt;a href=&#34;#multi-modal-messages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;teen-age-message&#34;&gt;Teen-Age Message &lt;a href=&#34;#teen-age-message&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Teen-Age Message&lt;/em&gt;, composed by Russian scientists (Zaitsev, Gindilis, Pshenichner, Filippova) and teens, was transmitted from the 70-m dish of Evpatoria Deep Space Center in Ukraine to six star systems resembling that of the Sun on August 29 and September 3 and 4, 2001. The message consists of three parts: a coherent-sounding radio signal with slow Doppler wavelength tuning, analog information representing musical melodies performed on the theremin, and Arecibo-like binary digital information. Star systems to which the message was sent are HD 197076, 47 UMa, 37 Gem, HD 126053, HD 76151, and HD 193664.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cosmic-call-2-cosmic-call-2003-message&#34;&gt;Cosmic Call 2 (Cosmic Call 2003) Message &lt;a href=&#34;#cosmic-call-2-cosmic-call-2003-message&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cosmic Call-2 message contained text, images, video, music, the Dutil/Dumas message, a copy of the 1974 Arecibo message, BIG = Bilingual Image Glossary, the AI program &lt;em&gt;Ella&lt;/em&gt;, and the Braastad message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;algorithmic-messages&#34;&gt;Algorithmic Messages &lt;a href=&#34;#algorithmic-messages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Algorithmic communication systems describe a small set of mathematic and logic symbols that form the basis for a rudimentary programming language that the recipient can run on a virtual machine. Advantages include localized communication, forward error correction, and the ability to embed proxy agents within the message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cosmicos&#34;&gt;CosmicOS &lt;a href=&#34;#cosmicos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CosmicOS&lt;/em&gt;, designed by Paul Fitzpatrick at MIT, describes a virtual machine that is derived from lambda calculus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;logic-gate-matrices&#34;&gt;Logic Gate Matrices &lt;a href=&#34;#logic-gate-matrices&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Logic Gate Matrices&lt;/em&gt; (LGM), developed by Brian McConnell, describes a universal virtual machine that is constructed by connecting coordinates in an n-dimensional space via mathematics and logic operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;natural-language-messages&#34;&gt;Natural Language Messages &lt;a href=&#34;#natural-language-messages&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research focuses on receiving a signal or message that is either not directed at us (eavesdropping) or one that is in its natural communicative form. Methods are being developed to detect if a signal has structure indicative of an intelligent source, categorize the type of structure detected, and then decipher its content. This structure modeling focuses on the search for generic human and inter-species language universals to devise computational methods by which language may be discriminated from non-language, and core structural syntactic elements of unknown languages may be detected. If a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communication_with_Extraterrestrial_Intelligence&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communication_with_Extraterrestrial_Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
