<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Psychosocial Hypothesis on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/psychosocial-hypothesis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Psychosocial Hypothesis on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 07:20:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/psychosocial-hypothesis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Psychosocial UFO hypothesis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_89f0f0eb48db/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 07:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_89f0f0eb48db/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;psychosocial-hypothesis-in-ufology&#34;&gt;Psychosocial Hypothesis in Ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#psychosocial-hypothesis-in-ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psychosocial hypothesis (PSH) in ufology posits that psychological and social factors best explain some UFO reports. It contrasts with the extraterrestrial hypothesis (ETH). This perspective is favored by UFO researchers in the UK, including David Clarke and Hilary Evans, and in France, following Michel Monnerie&amp;rsquo;s 1977 book. PSH researchers distinguish themselves from debunkers by maintaining a serious, albeit skeptical, interest in UFOs. The hypothesis suggests that mundane explanations combined with emotional climates distort perceptions, and that claims of contact with extraterrestrials from uninhabitable planets point to psychological processes like dreams and hallucinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;origin&#34;&gt;Origin &lt;a href=&#34;#origin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;psychosocial hypothesis&amp;rdquo; gained prominence in English UFO literature in 1984, with Jacques Scornaux and Peter Rogerson&amp;rsquo;s article in &lt;em&gt;Magonia&lt;/em&gt;. Scornaux&amp;rsquo;s use of the term originated from French UFO controversies sparked by Michel Monnerie&amp;rsquo;s challenge to the ETH. Rogerson&amp;rsquo;s adoption of the term marked a shift from paranormal explanations to normal psychological processes influenced by cultural myths and social conditioning. Writers for &lt;em&gt;Magonia&lt;/em&gt; had been exploring alternatives to the ETH since 1968, noting the failure of the ETH to account for high strangeness cases. Roger Sandell&amp;rsquo;s research on a 1905 Welsh UFO wave led him to believe that UFO reports were part of a larger complex of ghost stories and religious visions. Peter Rogerson advocated for a search for historical antecedents of UFO rumors and the social factors driving UFO flaps and social panics, noting a relationship between UFO waves and times of radical social change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;science-fiction-aspects-of-the-ufo-mythos&#34;&gt;Science Fiction Aspects of the UFO Mythos &lt;a href=&#34;#science-fiction-aspects-of-the-ufo-mythos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bertrand Méheust&amp;rsquo;s discovery of parallels between UFO experience narratives and pre-1947 science fiction literature led to a study of the science fiction aspects of UFO mythology. Méheust found numerous parallels, including wondrous effects and humanoid motives. Michel Monnerie integrated Meheust&amp;rsquo;s study into his historical critique of UFO mythology. Michel Meurger expanded Meheust&amp;rsquo;s thesis into a compendium of parallels. Jacques Vallee noted electromagnetic effects associated with UFOs in earlier fiction. Researchers have explored the cultural back-stories to various alien types, including Grays, insectoids, and reptoids. Other studies explore science fictional saucer esoterica along psychosocial and historical lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-saucer-rumor&#34;&gt;The Saucer Rumor &lt;a href=&#34;#the-saucer-rumor&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mystery of why flying saucers are the dominant shape in UFO reports was addressed by Martin Kottmeyer, who discovered that Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s initial sighting in 1947 was misinterpreted. Arnold&amp;rsquo;s description of the objects&amp;rsquo; motion, rather than their shape, led to the &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; label. This mistake shaped the UFO phenomenon for decades, influencing film imagery, saucer photography, UFO illustration, contactee tales, and abduction experiences. Kottmeyer&amp;rsquo;s findings, first reported in 1988, suggest a cultural origin for the flying saucer phenomenon. The principal counterargument is that flying saucers were seen before Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s story, but Kottmeyer argues that the dominance of the saucer shape after 1947 is the key issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flaps-of-flying-phantoms&#34;&gt;Flaps of Flying Phantoms &lt;a href=&#34;#flaps-of-flying-phantoms&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early researchers attempted to correlate UFO flaps with Mars&amp;rsquo; proximity, but these predictions failed. British researchers shifted focus to pre-1947 &amp;ldquo;waves,&amp;rdquo; examining social, religious, political, and scientific backgrounds. Roger Sandell&amp;rsquo;s work on a 1905 Welsh UFO outbreak revealed odd facets and high strangeness material. Nigel Watson reported on a 1909 panic involving German airships spying on Britain. Phantom airship flaps were catalogued from various locations, involving cigar-shaped craft and rumors of foreign spies. By the 1930s, phantom airships were replaced by phantom aeroplanes. Researchers have experimented with variations in these explanations, such as the 1905 Wales flap occurring during a time of social change. Researchers generally reject explanations involving mass hysteria, preferring to discuss flaps as collective delusions maintained by rumor and gossip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-modern-myth-of-jung&#34;&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Modern Myth&lt;/em&gt; of Jung &lt;a href=&#34;#the-modern-myth-of-jung&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Gustav Jung&amp;rsquo;s essay &lt;em&gt;Flying Saucers: A Modern Myth of Things Seen in the Skies&lt;/em&gt; is considered a foundational work for the PSH. Jung&amp;rsquo;s use of synchronicity has also led some to see him as a proponent of paranormal explanations. While Jung acknowledged the possibility of some UFOs being physical objects, he clarified that he was uncommitted on the issue of their reality. He expressed concern that news affirming the existence of UFOs was more welcome than skepticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychosocial_hypothesis&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychosocial_hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychosocial UFO hypothesis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_a235c7fbdf9b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 07:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_a235c7fbdf9b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;psychosocial-hypothesis-in-ufology&#34;&gt;Psychosocial Hypothesis in Ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#psychosocial-hypothesis-in-ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psychosocial hypothesis (PSH) in ufology suggests that some UFO reports are best explained by psychological or social factors rather than extraterrestrial origins. It contrasts with the extraterrestrial hypothesis (ETH) and is favored by UFO researchers in the UK and France. Proponents view UFOs as an interesting subject for study, even with skepticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;origin&#34;&gt;Origin &lt;a href=&#34;#origin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;psychosocial hypothesis&amp;rdquo; gained prominence in English UFO literature in 1984, influenced by French UFO controversies sparked by Michel Monnerie&amp;rsquo;s challenge to the ETH. &lt;em&gt;Magonia&lt;/em&gt; magazine played a key role in popularizing the term. Peter Rogerson&amp;rsquo;s adoption of the term marked a shift away from paranormal explanations towards normal psychological processes influenced by cultural myths and social conditioning. Writers associated with &lt;em&gt;Magonia&lt;/em&gt; had been exploring alternatives to the ETH since 1968, driven by the belief that it failed to account for high strangeness cases. Roger Sandell&amp;rsquo;s research on a 1905 Welsh UFO wave led him to conclude that UFO reports were part of a larger complex of ghost stories and religious visions. Peter Rogerson advocated for a search for historical antecedents of UFO rumors and the social factors driving UFO flaps and social panics, noting a relationship between UFO waves and times of radical social change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;science-fiction-aspects-of-the-ufo-mythos&#34;&gt;Science Fiction Aspects of the UFO Mythos &lt;a href=&#34;#science-fiction-aspects-of-the-ufo-mythos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bertrand Méheust&amp;rsquo;s study of science fiction parallels to UFO mythology revealed numerous similarities between UFO experience narratives and pre-1947 science fiction literature. These parallels include wondrous effects like invisible force-fields, teleportation, and engine-stopping rays, as well as humanoid motives for visiting Earth. Michel Monnerie integrated Meheust&amp;rsquo;s study into his historical critique of UFO mythology. Michel Meurger expanded Meheust&amp;rsquo;s thesis with a compendium of parallels. Jacques Vallee noted electromagnetic effects associated with UFOs in earlier fiction. Researchers have explored the cultural backstories to various alien types, including Grays, insectoids, and reptoids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-saucer-rumor&#34;&gt;The Saucer Rumor &lt;a href=&#34;#the-saucer-rumor&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psychosocial approach helped solve the mystery of why flying saucers are the dominant shape in UFO reports. Martin Kottmeyer discovered that the &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; label originated from a misinterpretation of Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s 1947 sighting. Arnold described the objects&amp;rsquo; motion as erratic, &amp;ldquo;like a saucer if you skip it across the water,&amp;rdquo; but the reporter misinterpreted this as describing the objects&amp;rsquo; shape. This mistake shaped the UFO phenomenon for decades, influencing film imagery, saucer photography, UFO illustration, contactee tales, and abduction experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flaps-of-flying-phantoms&#34;&gt;Flaps of Flying Phantoms &lt;a href=&#34;#flaps-of-flying-phantoms&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early researchers attempted to correlate UFO flaps with Mars&amp;rsquo; proximity, but these predictions failed. British researchers shifted focus to pre-1947 &amp;ldquo;waves,&amp;rdquo; examining social, religious, political, and scientific backgrounds. Nigel Watson researched a March–May 1909 panic involving German airships spying on Britain. Phantom airship flaps were cataloged in various locations, often accompanied by rumors of foreign spies. By the 1930s, phantom airships were replaced by phantom aeroplanes. Researchers have experimented with variations in these explanations, such as the 1905 Wales flap occurring during a time of rapid social change. Researchers generally reject explanations involving mass hysteria, preferring to discuss flaps as collective delusions maintained by rumor and gossip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-modern-myth-of-jung&#34;&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Modern Myth&lt;/em&gt; of Jung &lt;a href=&#34;#the-modern-myth-of-jung&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Gustav Jung&amp;rsquo;s essay &lt;em&gt;Flying Saucers: A Modern Myth of Things Seen in the Skies&lt;/em&gt; is considered a foundational work of the PSH. While some argue that Jung also considered the ETH, Jung himself refuted claims that he believed UFOs were physically real. He emphasized the psychological significance of the UFO phenomenon, regardless of its objective reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychosocial_UFO_hypothesis&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychosocial_UFO_hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
