<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Found Footage on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/found-footage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Found Footage on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 20:53:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/found-footage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO Abduction (film)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_cc76877738c6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 20:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_cc76877738c6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-abduction-film&#34;&gt;UFO Abduction (film) &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-abduction-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article provides information about the 1989 American found-footage science fiction horror film &lt;em&gt;UFO Abduction&lt;/em&gt;, also known as &lt;em&gt;The McPherson Tape&lt;/em&gt;. It details the film&amp;rsquo;s production, plot, cast, release, reception, and legacy, as well as its remake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;title-misconception&#34;&gt;Title Misconception &lt;a href=&#34;#title-misconception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section clarifies that the film, originally conceived as &lt;em&gt;UFO Abduction&lt;/em&gt;, is now more commonly known as &lt;em&gt;The McPherson Tape&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the film&amp;rsquo;s storyline, which centers on the Van Heese family in Connecticut during a birthday celebration on October 8, 1983. The family encounters extraterrestrials, leading to a night of terror and a supposed alien abduction. Key events include the initial sighting of a spacecraft, attempts by the aliens to enter the house, the shooting of an alien, and the family&amp;rsquo;s eventual disappearance. The film is presented as found footage, with the implication that the Van Heeses&amp;rsquo; whereabouts remain unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the actors who portrayed the Van Heese family members and the aliens. Key actors include Tommy Giavocchini, Patrick Kelley, Shirly McCalla, Stacey Shulman, Christine Staples, Laura Tomas, and Dean Alioto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the film&amp;rsquo;s production, noting that it was written, directed, filmed, and produced by Dean Alioto through IndieSyndicate Productions. It highlights the film&amp;rsquo;s low budget of $6,500 and its presentation as found footage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release-reception-and-legacy&#34;&gt;Release, Reception and Legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#release-reception-and-legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the film&amp;rsquo;s limited release through Axiom Films and its intended appearance as a genuine 1983 home video recording. It mentions the destruction of the film&amp;rsquo;s materials in a warehouse fire, hindering its wide release. It also notes criticisms of the original film&amp;rsquo;s sound quality, visual effects, and aesthetics. The section further mentions the film&amp;rsquo;s official DVD and Digital download release in 2018 and its Blu-ray re-release in 2020 by AGFA, including a new transfer and director&amp;rsquo;s commentary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;remake&#34;&gt;Remake &lt;a href=&#34;#remake&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions the 1998 remake of &lt;em&gt;UFO Abduction&lt;/em&gt; by Dean Alioto and Paul Chitlik, which had a larger budget and professional actors. The remake was originally titled &lt;em&gt;The McPherson Tape&lt;/em&gt; but was later changed to &lt;em&gt;Alien Abduction: Incident in Lake County&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to related topics, including the Kelly–Hopkinsville encounter and UFO conspiracy theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_Abduction_(film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_Abduction_(film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
