<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hoaxes on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/hoaxes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hoaxes on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/hoaxes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Autopsy (1995 television film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f41f4fadf611/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f41f4fadf611/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-autopsy-1995-television-film&#34;&gt;Alien Autopsy (1995 television film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-autopsy-1995-television-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the 1995 pseudo-documentary &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy: Fact or Fiction&lt;/em&gt;, which featured footage purporting to show an alien autopsy conducted after the Roswell incident. The program, hosted by Jonathan Frakes, aired on Fox and other networks worldwide, sparking intense debate before being thoroughly debunked as a hoax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section details the production of the &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; footage. Ray Santilli and Gary Shoefield admitted to creating the footage in a 2006 documentary. The simulated autopsy was filmed in a London living room using fabricated alien bodies constructed by artist John Humphreys. The alien bodies were made of plaster casts filled with offal, sheep brains, and raspberry jam. Alien artifacts were also created by Humphreys. A homeless man was paid to pose as the original cameraman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section outlines how &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; was received and referenced in popular culture. The footage was derided in the media and satirized in &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt;. In 1998, Fox aired a special debunking the footage. A fictionalized version of the creation and release of the footage was retold in the comedy film &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; (2006).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including books, news articles, and documentaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of additional resources for readers interested in learning more about the &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; film and the surrounding controversy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section includes links to external websites related to the film, including an article by Ray Santilli and a link to the film on YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Autopsy_(1995_film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Autopsy_(1995_film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
