<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hoaxes on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/hoaxes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hoaxes on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 09:18:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/hoaxes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Crop circle</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_990cc3fef0ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 09:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_990cc3fef0ed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;crop-circle&#34;&gt;Crop Circle &lt;a href=&#34;#crop-circle&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A crop circle, crop formation, or corn circle is a pattern created by flattening a crop, usually a cereal. The term was first coined in the early 1980s. While fringe theorists suggest obscure natural causes or alien origins, there is no scientific evidence for such explanations, and all crop circles are consistent with human causation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the historical accounts of crop circles and related phenomena, dividing it into periods before the 20th century, the 20th century, and the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;before-the-20th-century&#34;&gt;Before the 20th century &lt;a href=&#34;#before-the-20th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers early reports that could be considered precursors to modern crop circles. It mentions a 1678 news pamphlet, &lt;em&gt;The Mowing-Devil&lt;/em&gt;, which describes a crop whose stalks were cut in a circular pattern. It also references a 1686 report by naturalist Robert Plot on rings of mushrooms, proposing air flows as a cause. An 1880 letter to &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt; by John Rand Capron describes circles of flattened crops possibly caused by &amp;ldquo;cyclonic wind action.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;20th-century&#34;&gt;20th century &lt;a href=&#34;#20th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection details observations and reports of crop circles and similar phenomena throughout the 20th century. It mentions a 1932 observation by archaeologist E. C. Curwen of dark rings in a field. David Wood reported making crop circles in 1940. Patrick Moore described circular areas of flattened wheat near a crater in Wiltshire in 1963, suggesting air currents as a cause. Reports of UFO sightings and circular formations in swamp reeds and sugarcane fields in Tully, Queensland, Australia, and in Canada during the 1960s are noted. The 1966 Tully &amp;ldquo;saucer nest&amp;rdquo; case is described, where a farmer reported witnessing a saucer-shaped craft leaving a circular area of flattened grass. British pranksters Doug Bower and Dave Chorley claimed to have started creating crop circles in 1978, inspired by the Tully case. The 1974 film &lt;em&gt;Phase IV&lt;/em&gt; is mentioned as a possible inspiration for the pranksters. The late 1970s saw an increase in crop circle reports, which became widely known in the late 1980s. By 2001, approximately 10,000 crop circles had been reported internationally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;21st-century&#34;&gt;21st century &lt;a href=&#34;#21st-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection covers the evolution of crop circles in the 21st century. It notes that crop formations have increased in size and complexity, with some featuring thousands of shapes and incorporating complex mathematical and scientific characteristics. Jeremy Northcote&amp;rsquo;s research found that crop circles in the UK tend to appear near roads, populated areas, and cultural heritage monuments, suggesting human causation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bower-and-chorley&#34;&gt;Bower and Chorley &lt;a href=&#34;#bower-and-chorley&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on Doug Bower and Dave Chorley, who claimed to have started the crop circle phenomenon in 1978. They used simple tools like a plank of wood, rope, and a wire-fitted baseball cap. In 1991, they demonstrated their method to journalists. A &amp;ldquo;cereologist,&amp;rdquo; Pat Delgado, declared their circle authentic before it was revealed as a hoax. Bower and Chorley claimed responsibility for all circles made prior to 1987 and over 200 crop circles between 1978 and 1991.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;art-and-business&#34;&gt;Art and business &lt;a href=&#34;#art-and-business&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the artistic and commercial aspects of crop circles. It notes that after simple circles in the 1970s, increasingly complex geometric designs have been created, sometimes to attract tourists. The UK arts collective Circlemakers, founded by Rod Dickinson and John Lundberg, has been creating crop circles as art and for commercial clients. The Led Zeppelin Boxed Set features an image of a crop circle. A crop-circle-making competition was held in Berkshire in 1992. In 2002, the Discovery Channel commissioned MIT graduate students to create crop circles. In 2009, &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; reported that crop circle activity was waning in Wiltshire as makers preferred creating promotional crop circles for companies. The 2012 Summer Olympics opening ceremony featured crop circles in the shape of the Olympic rings. A Star Wars Rebel Alliance emblem crop circle was created in California in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;legal-implications&#34;&gt;Legal implications &lt;a href=&#34;#legal-implications&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the legal consequences related to creating crop circles. In 1992, Gábor Takács and Róbert Dallos were sued for creating a crop circle in Hungary, but the judge ruled they were only responsible for the damage within the circle itself. In 2000, Matthew Williams became the first person in the UK arrested for causing criminal damage after making a crop circle and was fined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;creation&#34;&gt;Creation &lt;a href=&#34;#creation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the various explanations for how crop circles are created, dividing it into human origins, natural origins, and alternative explanations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;human-origin&#34;&gt;Human origin &lt;a href=&#34;#human-origin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection details the scientific consensus that crop circles are constructed by humans as hoaxes, advertising, or art. The most common method involves using a rope and board to flatten the plants. Skeptics point out that all characteristics of crop circles are compatible with human creation. Bower and Chorley&amp;rsquo;s confession is mentioned, as well as the increasing complexity of circles after their revelation. The main criticism of non-human creation is the lack of evidence, while many are known to be human-made. Cases where researchers declared circles &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; only to be confronted with the hoaxers are noted. Carl Sagan concluded that crop circles were created by Bower and Chorley and their copycats. &lt;em&gt;Scientific American&lt;/em&gt; published an article by Matt Ridley, who described how easy it is to create convincing crop circles. Some crop formations are paid for by companies for advertising. Hoaxers have been caught in the process of making new circles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;natural-origins&#34;&gt;Natural origins &lt;a href=&#34;#natural-origins&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explores natural explanations for crop circles, including weather and animal activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;weather&#34;&gt;Weather &lt;a href=&#34;#weather&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sub-subsection discusses the suggestion that crop circles may be the result of meteorological phenomena like tornadoes or ball lightning, but there is no evidence of this. John Rand Capron blamed circles on a storm in 1880. Terence Meaden proposed that whirlwinds caused the circles. Stephen Hawking said that crop circles are either hoaxes or formed by vortex movement of air. Meaden conceded that complex designs were made by hoaxers after Bower and Chorley&amp;rsquo;s confession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;animal-activity&#34;&gt;Animal activity &lt;a href=&#34;#animal-activity&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sub-subsection mentions that wallabies in Tasmania have been found creating crop circles in fields of opium poppies after consuming them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alternative-explanations&#34;&gt;Alternative explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#alternative-explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers alternative, less conventional explanations for crop circles, including paranormal theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;paranormal&#34;&gt;Paranormal &lt;a href=&#34;#paranormal&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses paranormal, ufological, and anomalistic speculations about crop circles, ranging from bizarre meteorological phenomena to messages from extraterrestrial beings. Some speculate that crop circles are related to ley lines. Some paranormal advocates believe that ball lightning causes crop circles and that the patterns are controlled by some entity, such as Gaia, God, supernatural beings, the collective minds of humanity, or extraterrestrial beings. The Indonesian National Institute of Aeronautics and Space (LAPAN) described crop circles as &amp;ldquo;man-made.&amp;rdquo; Sceptical groups and scientists criticize hypothetical explanations as pseudoscientific. No credible evidence of extraterrestrial origin has been presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;changes-to-crops&#34;&gt;Changes to crops &lt;a href=&#34;#changes-to-crops&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection discusses claims by some scientists that there are differences between crops inside and outside the circles, suggesting they were not man-made. William Levengood published papers finding deformities in the grain inside the circles correlated to their position. Joe Nickell objected that correlation is not causation and criticized Levengood&amp;rsquo;s methods and assumptions. Advocates of non-human causes dismiss on-site evidence of human involvement as attempts to discredit the phenomena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;related-art&#34;&gt;Related art &lt;a href=&#34;#related-art&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section briefly mentions that patterns similar to crop circles can also be made in snow or sand. Images can be made in forests by cutting trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;folklore&#34;&gt;Folklore &lt;a href=&#34;#folklore&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the connection between modern crop circles and old folkloric tales. Crop circles are culture-dependent, appearing mostly in developed and secularized Western countries. Fungi can cause circular areas of crop to die, which may be the origin of tales of &amp;ldquo;fairie rings.&amp;rdquo; A 17th-century English woodcut, the &lt;em&gt;Mowing-Devil&lt;/em&gt;, depicts the devil mowing a circular design in a field of oats. In the 1948 German story &lt;em&gt;Die zwölf Schwäne&lt;/em&gt;, a farmer finds a circular ring of flattened grain in his field every morning, caused by princesses disguised as swans dancing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crop_circle&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crop_circle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of UFO-related hoaxes</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_345d7fc33b75/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 14:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_345d7fc33b75/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-ufo-related-hoaxes&#34;&gt;List of UFO-related Hoaxes &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-ufo-related-hoaxes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article provides a compilation of various hoaxes related to unidentified flying objects (UFOs). It categorizes these hoaxes into different types, including airship hoaxes, crashed UFO hoaxes, sighting hoaxes, and photographic hoaxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;airship-hoaxes&#34;&gt;Airship Hoaxes &lt;a href=&#34;#airship-hoaxes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details several instances of airship hoaxes, primarily from the late 19th century. Key events include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April Fool&amp;rsquo;s Day 1897, Omaha, Nebraska:&lt;/strong&gt; Two practical jokers launched a helium balloon with a burning wicker basket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 17, 1897, Dallas, Texas:&lt;/strong&gt; Three boys created a &amp;ldquo;mystery airship&amp;rdquo; sighting using a kerosene-soaked cotton ball attached to a turkey vulture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 19, 1897, Leroy, Kansas:&lt;/strong&gt; Alexander Hamilton reported an airship lassoing a heifer, which was later published in the &lt;em&gt;Yates Center Farmer’s Advocate&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1909 Airship Sighting Wave:&lt;/strong&gt; Wallace Tillinghast claimed to have built and flown an airship extensively over the Northeastern United States.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crashed-ufo-hoaxes&#34;&gt;Crashed UFO Hoaxes &lt;a href=&#34;#crashed-ufo-hoaxes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on hoaxes involving purported crashed UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1884, Dundy County, Nebraska:&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;em&gt;Nebraska State Journal&lt;/em&gt; published two hoax articles about a crashed UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-autopsy&#34;&gt;Alien Autopsy &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-autopsy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection details the Ray Santilli &amp;ldquo;Alien Autopsy&amp;rdquo; film hoax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1993:&lt;/strong&gt; Ray Santilli presented film footage allegedly showing an autopsy of an alien from the Roswell UFO incident in 1947.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1995:&lt;/strong&gt; The American Fox Broadcasting Company broadcast the footage in &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy: Fact or Fiction&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The footage was later revealed to be a hoax involving latex dummies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Santilli claimed he bought the film from Jack Barnett, who falsely claimed to be a commander in the US army.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1967-flying-saucer-hoax-in-england&#34;&gt;1967 Flying Saucer Hoax in England &lt;a href=&#34;#1967-flying-saucer-hoax-in-england&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes a hoax involving the placement of six &amp;lsquo;flying saucers&amp;rsquo; in southern England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 1967:&lt;/strong&gt; Apprentices from the Royal Aircraft Establishment at Farnborough placed six &amp;lsquo;flying saucers&amp;rsquo; between the Thames Estuary and the Bristol Channel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hoax was part of Rag Week and intended to raise money for charity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;british-roswell&#34;&gt;British Roswell &lt;a href=&#34;#british-roswell&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses a &amp;ldquo;miniature UFO&amp;rdquo; discovered in Sipho Moor near Scarborough, North Yorkshire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1957:&lt;/strong&gt; A small piece of metal with hieroglyphs was found.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experts deemed it most likely a hoax.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sighting-hoaxes&#34;&gt;Sighting Hoaxes &lt;a href=&#34;#sighting-hoaxes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists sighting hoaxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maury Island Incident (1947)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morristown UFO Hoax (2009)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;photographic-hoaxes&#34;&gt;Photographic Hoaxes &lt;a href=&#34;#photographic-hoaxes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on photographic hoaxes related to UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;photograph-of-an-alien-taken-at-ilkley-moor-1987&#34;&gt;Photograph of &amp;ldquo;an alien&amp;rdquo; taken at Ilkley Moor (1987) &lt;a href=&#34;#photograph-of-an-alien-taken-at-ilkley-moor-1987&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection details a photograph alleged to be of an alien taken in West Yorkshire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 1, 1987:&lt;/strong&gt; A photograph taken on Ilkley Moor was claimed to depict an alien.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Daily Star&lt;/em&gt; claimed to expose it as a hoax in 1989, identifying the &amp;ldquo;alien&amp;rdquo; as an insurance broker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Belgian investigators questioned how experienced investigators could have been misled by such a hoax.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to related Wikipedia articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of hoaxes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photograph of Petit-Rechain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO-related_hoaxes&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO-related_hoaxes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
