<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Manises on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/manises/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Manises on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 18:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/manises/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Manises UFO incident</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b169a302c85b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b169a302c85b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;manises-ufo-incident&#34;&gt;Manises UFO Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#manises-ufo-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the Manises UFO incident, a notable UFO sighting in Spain that occurred on November 11, 1979. The incident involved a commercial flight, a Spanish Air Force jet, and unidentified objects, leading to an emergency landing and a subsequent investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;incident-details&#34;&gt;Incident Details &lt;a href=&#34;#incident-details&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section recounts the events of the Manises UFO incident. A TAE Supercaravelle flight JK-297, carrying 109 passengers from Salzburg, Austria, to Las Palmas, experienced a close encounter with red lights while flying over Ibiza. Pilot Francisco Javier Lerdo de Tejada and his crew, unable to identify the lights and fearing a collision, made an emergency landing at Manises Airport in Valencia. Following the landing, radar detected three new UFO signals. A Spanish Air Force Mirage F1, piloted by Captain Fernando Cámara, was dispatched from Los Llanos Air Base to intercept the objects. Cámara made visual contact with a cone-shaped object, but it disappeared. He then pursued another object near Sagunto, experiencing electronic interference with his aircraft&amp;rsquo;s systems. The UFO eventually disappeared towards Africa, and Cámara, low on fuel, returned to base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;possible-explanations&#34;&gt;Possible Explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#possible-explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the aftermath and potential explanations for the incident. In September 1980, Enrique Múgica Herzog raised the issue in the Spanish Parliament, seeking an official explanation. The official report, declassified in 1994, attributed the sightings to optical illusions caused by lights from a distant chemical plant and celestial bodies. This explanation has been disputed by those involved. The report did not address the electronic malfunctions experienced by the Mirage F1. One theory suggests that the United States Sixth Fleet, conducting electronic warfare exercises during the Iran hostage crisis, might have caused the interference, but Captain Cámara dismissed this possibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bibliography&#34;&gt;Bibliography &lt;a href=&#34;#bibliography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the books that provide further information on the Manises UFO incident:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Incidente en Manises&lt;/em&gt; by Juan José Benítez (1980)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;El misterio Ovni: Un alto secreto al descubierto: investigaciones y evidencias&lt;/em&gt; by Bruno Cardeñosa Chao (2010)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;El expediente Manises&lt;/em&gt; by Juan Antonio Fernández Peris (2000)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the &amp;ldquo;List of reported UFO sightings&amp;rdquo; page on Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arturo Blay&amp;rsquo;s article &amp;ldquo;El piloto que persiguió un OVNI&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;Cadena SER&lt;/em&gt; (2015)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jaime Millás&amp;rsquo;s article &amp;ldquo;Un &amp;ldquo;ovni&amp;rdquo; forzó el aterrizaje de un Caravelle en Manises&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;El País&lt;/em&gt; (1979)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bill Cemlyn-Jones&amp;rsquo;s article &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;UFOs&amp;rsquo; force Spanish pilot to land&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; (2015)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Javier Cavanilles&amp;rsquo;s article &amp;ldquo;Caso Manises, descanse en paz&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;El Mundo&lt;/em&gt; (2009)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testimony of Fernando Cámara, pilot of the Mirage F1 (YouTube)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rational explanation of the phenomena, by the Anomaly Foundation (archived webpage)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Manises_UFO_incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Manises_UFO_incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
