<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alien Encounter on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/alien-encounter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alien Encounter on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 20:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/alien-encounter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aurora, Texas, UFO incident</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_5c69099a06fb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 20:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_5c69099a06fb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;aurora-texas-ufo-incident&#34;&gt;Aurora, Texas, UFO Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#aurora-texas-ufo-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the alleged UFO crash that reportedly occurred on April 17, 1897, near Aurora, Texas. Locals claimed a UFO crashed on a farm, resulting in the death of its pilot, an alien being. The pilot was purportedly buried in the Aurora Cemetery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-incident-as-reported&#34;&gt;The Incident as Reported &lt;a href=&#34;#the-incident-as-reported&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section recounts the details of the incident as reported in the &lt;em&gt;Dallas Morning News&lt;/em&gt; article written by S.E. Haydon. The article describes how a UFO crashed into a windmill on Judge J.S. Proctor&amp;rsquo;s property. The pilot, described as &amp;ldquo;not of this world,&amp;rdquo; was speculated to be from Mars by an Army Signal Service officer named T.J. Weems. The pilot was buried with Christian rites in the Aurora Cemetery, which now has a Texas Historical Commission marker mentioning the incident. The wreckage was reportedly dumped into a well on the property. Mr. Brawley Oates, who later purchased the property, sealed the well after developing severe arthritis, which he attributed to contamination from the wreckage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hoax-theory&#34;&gt;Hoax Theory &lt;a href=&#34;#hoax-theory&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents the theory that the Aurora incident was a hoax. It cites a 1980 &lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt; magazine interview with Etta Pegues, an Aurora resident, who claimed that S.E. Haydon fabricated the story to revive the town&amp;rsquo;s economy after the railroad bypassed it. Pegues also claimed that Judge Proctor never had a windmill on his property, a statement that was later challenged. Paranormal researcher Jerry Drake challenged the finding that the well was designed for use with a windmill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investigations&#34;&gt;Investigations &lt;a href=&#34;#investigations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the various investigations into the Aurora incident, including reports by KDFW, &lt;em&gt;UFO Files&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;UFO Hunters&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kdfw-report&#34;&gt;KDFW Report &lt;a href=&#34;#kdfw-report&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1998, KDFW aired a report featuring interviews with Jim Marrs and other locals who believed something crashed in Aurora. The report found no conclusive evidence of extraterrestrial life or technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ufo-files-investigation&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;UFO Files&lt;/em&gt; Investigation &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-files-investigation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;UFO Files&lt;/em&gt; episode, &amp;ldquo;Texas&amp;rsquo; Roswell,&amp;rdquo; featured a 1973 investigation led by Bill Case of the &lt;em&gt;Dallas Times Herald&lt;/em&gt; and MUFON. The investigation uncovered two new eyewitnesses: Mary Evans, who spoke of her parents&amp;rsquo; visit to the crash site and the discovery of the alien body, and Charlie Stephens, who saw the airship trailing smoke. MUFON investigated the Aurora Cemetery and found a grave marker that appeared to depict a flying saucer. They requested permission to exhume the site but were denied. The marker later disappeared, and metal readings from the grave vanished. The report concluded that the evidence was inconclusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ufo-hunters-investigation&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;UFO Hunters&lt;/em&gt; Investigation &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-hunters-investigation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;UFO Hunters&lt;/em&gt; episode, &amp;ldquo;First Contact,&amp;rdquo; featured Tim Oates, grandson of Brawley Oates, allowing investigators to unseal the well on his property. Water samples showed high levels of aluminum, but the well contained no significant debris. The remains of a windmill base were found near the well site. Ground-penetrating radar revealed an unmarked grave in the cemetery near other 1890s graves. The condition of the grave was badly deteriorated, and the radar could not conclusively prove what type of remains existed. The landowner provided pieces of metal containing mostly aluminum and an unknown element.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In Popular Culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section notes the dramatization of the incident in the 1986 film &lt;em&gt;The Aurora Encounter&lt;/em&gt; and its discussion in &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;. It also mentions an independent short movie titled &lt;em&gt;Aurora&lt;/em&gt; by Thomas Negovan and Aaron Shaps, which combines the incident with the Nazi conspiracy theory of Die Glocke. The Firesign Theatre&amp;rsquo;s comedy LP &lt;em&gt;Everything You Know Is Wrong&lt;/em&gt; satirizes the incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See Also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics, including &amp;ldquo;List of reported UFO sightings&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Mystery airship.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aurora,_Texas,_UFO_incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aurora,_Texas,_UFO_incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
