<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cult on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/cult/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cult on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 22:59:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/cult/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ground Crew Project</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8085248acddf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 22:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8085248acddf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ground-crew-project&#34;&gt;Ground Crew Project &lt;a href=&#34;#ground-crew-project&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ground Crew Project is a UFO religion originating in the United States, founded in the 1980s by Sheldan Nidle. It transitioned online in 1996 and later divided into the &amp;ldquo;Ground Crew&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Planetary Activation Organisation.&amp;rdquo; The group anticipates a cosmic transformation of Earth, facilitated by a passage through a &amp;lsquo;photon belt&amp;rsquo; and aided by the &amp;ldquo;Galactic Federation.&amp;rdquo; Members prepare for first contact, envisioning themselves as intermediaries between extraterrestrials and humanity. Despite failed predictions, the group maintains its belief in imminent contact and the need to elevate mankind&amp;rsquo;s consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sheldan-nidle&#34;&gt;Sheldan Nidle &lt;a href=&#34;#sheldan-nidle&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sheldan Nidle, born in 1946, claims to have had extraterrestrial encounters from a young age, including telepathic communication and learning aboard spacecraft with ETs from Sirius. He published &lt;em&gt;You’re Becoming a Galactic Human&lt;/em&gt; in 1994, detailing a childhood encounter. He claims regular communication with ETs since 1955, which he ceased at age 14 to fulfill his &amp;lsquo;star seed&amp;rsquo; mission. He later became involved with the Amateur Astronomers Club and a film about Nikola Tesla. Nidle holds advanced degrees from Ohio University and the University of Southern California. In the mid-1980s, he resumed contact with the &amp;ldquo;Galactic Federation&amp;rdquo; and became a lecturer representing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;galactic-federation&#34;&gt;Galactic Federation &lt;a href=&#34;#galactic-federation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Galactic Federation is described as an alliance of extraterrestrial civilizations within the Milky Way galaxy. This concept is popular in UFO religions and New Age movements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;haim-esheds-claims&#34;&gt;Haim Eshed&amp;rsquo;s claims &lt;a href=&#34;#haim-esheds-claims&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2020, Haim Eshed, former head of Israel&amp;rsquo;s military space program, claimed that aliens have contacted representatives of the United States and Israel, but humanity is not ready for contact. He stated that aliens are present on Earth and have formed a &amp;ldquo;Galactic Federation&amp;rdquo; to avoid mass hysteria until humanity is ready. NASA responded by stating that no extraterrestrial life has been found, but the search continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;photon-belt&#34;&gt;Photon Belt &lt;a href=&#34;#photon-belt&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning in 1996, Nidle channeled messages about an imminent apocalypse due to Earth&amp;rsquo;s planetary transformation. He claimed to lead a mission for the &amp;ldquo;Galactic Federation of Planets&amp;rdquo; to prepare the world for this transformation as the planet passes into a cosmic &amp;lsquo;photon belt&amp;rsquo;. This area of space supposedly has high energy properties that would transform Earth into a pristine state and restore superhuman abilities by altering human DNA to a 12-helix pattern. The pineal gland would be activated, and humans would regain cosmic abilities like rejuvenation, telepathy, and overcoming illness. The channeling claimed that human structures would be destroyed, and the only safe places would be underground or in spaceships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;imminent-landing&#34;&gt;Imminent Landing &lt;a href=&#34;#imminent-landing&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The narrative stated that a mass landing of 15 million starships of the &amp;ldquo;Galactic Federation&amp;rdquo; would occur no later than December 17, 1996, to raise humanity&amp;rsquo;s consciousness using advanced technology, achieving a galactic and divine society by 2012. The landing would involve advanced races like Pleiadians, Sirians, Cassopeans, and Arcturians, who would meet and placate human populations. Earthly weapons would be neutralized, mechanical devices shut down, and world government taken over by the Spiritual Hierarchy. The Earth transformation would include telepathy, airborne transport, and photon energy generators. This is considered a &amp;ldquo;cargoistic&amp;rdquo; belief, where alien &amp;ldquo;cargo&amp;rdquo; brings about human ascension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ground-crew&#34;&gt;Ground Crew &lt;a href=&#34;#ground-crew&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Ground Crew&amp;rdquo; refers to the virtual congregation who join the mission. Members were told they would assist humanity and the extraterrestrials as councillors and ambassadors. They would be trained by space forces and receive implants. After failed predictions, the emphasis shifted to spiritual development, requiring the Ground Crew to help raise humanity spiritually and assist in ecological restoration. This involved gathering humanity through world meditation days to harmonize vibrations and creating a &amp;rsquo;network of light&amp;rsquo; with other new age groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;landings-delayed&#34;&gt;Landings delayed &lt;a href=&#34;#landings-delayed&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The December 1996 mass landing did not occur, but Nidle continued to spread messages that spaceships would appear soon. Further dates, including the Gregorian New Year and spring of 1997, also passed without a landing. Delays were attributed to a solar storm and planetary instability. Details about the comet Hale-Bopp were communicated, and the number of spaceships in the landing fleet was increased to 25 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hale-bopp&#34;&gt;Hale-Bopp &lt;a href=&#34;#hale-bopp&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new landing date was set to coincide with the arrival of the Hale-Bopp comet on May 5, 1997. The comet was described as a large spaceship with cloaking and holographic systems, containing a crew of over 200,000 beings and 10,000 ambassadors. This would coincide with the mass landing by the Federation. After the mass suicide of Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate members, the Ground Crew distanced themselves from such acts. Instead of a mass landing, a meeting between a shuttle from the comet and a shuttle from the &amp;ldquo;Galactic Federation Fleet&amp;rdquo; took place near Ayers Rock in Australia, where a ceremony was conducted, and papers were exchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-re-scheduling-and-shift-in-focus&#34;&gt;Further re-scheduling and shift in focus &lt;a href=&#34;#further-re-scheduling-and-shift-in-focus&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nidle and the Ground Crew blamed repeated failed prophecies on external factors, such as dark forces conspiring with &amp;lsquo;planetary elites&amp;rsquo;. Messages began to deny the relevance of specific arrival dates and talked about &amp;ldquo;the right divine time.&amp;rdquo; The focus shifted to humans assisting in the planet&amp;rsquo;s transformation before galactic intervention. Salvation became a two-way street, determined by human attitudes. A more spiritual content appeared, referring to beings like Ashtar Sheran, Aaron Alaje, Megha Alcorn, Merku Alcorn, Great White Brotherhood, Ascended Masters, and archangels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;split&#34;&gt;Split &lt;a href=&#34;#split&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December 1997, Nidle split with Valerie Donnell, his secretary and the Ground Crew&amp;rsquo;s chief administrator. Donnell retained the Ground Crew name and website, posting channeled messages with a UFO content focused on personal spiritual transformation from a new age perspective. Nidle founded the Planetary Activation Organisation, restructuring it as the only source for messages about the Galactic Federation. He established a hierarchical system and created a &amp;ldquo;Web of Light&amp;rdquo; to unite like-minded groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;evolution-of-the-narrative&#34;&gt;Evolution of the narrative &lt;a href=&#34;#evolution-of-the-narrative&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Nidle&amp;rsquo;s channeling, the Federation remained dedicated to first contact, but the spiritual transformation of humans became the main focus. Earth rulers were identified as a secret cabal, but would be removed by the Federation. &amp;lsquo;Star Gates&amp;rsquo; were being placed in the upper atmosphere, and &amp;lsquo;Galactic and Medical Teams&amp;rsquo; were assisting people during sleep. Earth was portrayed as a vitally important planet due to humanity&amp;rsquo;s exalted role, acting as a switch in the spiritual transformation of the Milky Way. By 2000, the movement continued to develop its membership base, claiming hundreds of Planetary Activation Groups in over 29 countries. The Planetary Activation Organisation is classified as a progressive millennialist group promising collective salvation and a terrestrial paradise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;credibility&#34;&gt;Credibility &lt;a href=&#34;#credibility&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ground Crew employed strategies to avoid prophetic disconfirmation and cognitive dissonance, such as disclaimers and exploiting temporality. Nidle reconceptualized the movement through spiritualization, changing the focus from a UFO landing to the need for humans to raise their own spirituality. Due to the virtual nature of the group, it is impossible to accurately account for membership. The movement&amp;rsquo;s period of failed prophecy is no longer online. The online narrative functions like fiction, conveying a vivid imaginary world and apocalyptic expectancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galactic_Federation_(ufology)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galactic_Federation_(ufology)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
