<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Australia on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/australia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Australia on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:48:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/australia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in Australia</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ba780e1757b6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ba780e1757b6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-the-nation-of-australia&#34;&gt;List of alleged UFO sightings in the nation of Australia &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-the-nation-of-australia&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article lists alleged UFO sightings in Australia, spanning from the pre-1900s to recent times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pre-1900&#34;&gt;Pre 1900 &lt;a href=&#34;#pre-1900&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details an 1868 sighting in Parramatta, New South Wales, where Alderman Frederick Birmingham reported seeing an ark-like object floating in the sky before landing in Parramatta Park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1950s&#34;&gt;1950s &lt;a href=&#34;#1950s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions a 1954 sighting in Gawler, South Australia, where three people observed a white UFO flying overhead, followed by an RAAF jet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1960s&#34;&gt;1960s &lt;a href=&#34;#1960s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section includes two notable events:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A 1966 incident in Tully, Queensland, where a farmer reported a large saucer-shaped object and a &amp;ldquo;nest&amp;rdquo; of reeds in a swamp.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 1966 Westall High School UFO incident in Clayton South, Victoria, where many students and staff claimed to have witnessed a UFO flying over the school and descending into a paddock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1970s&#34;&gt;1970s &lt;a href=&#34;#1970s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the Valentich Disappearance in 1978. Frederick Valentich, a pilot, disappeared while flying a Cessna 182 over Bass Strait to King Island (Tasmania). He reported to Melbourne air traffic control that he was being accompanied by an unknown aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1980s&#34;&gt;1980s &lt;a href=&#34;#1980s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes a 1988 sighting in South Australia&amp;rsquo;s Nullarbor Plain. A family reported seeing a &amp;ldquo;big glowing ball&amp;rdquo; that resembled &amp;ldquo;an egg in an egg cup.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1990s&#34;&gt;1990s &lt;a href=&#34;#1990s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details two incidents:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 1993, Eric Thomason photographed a craft hovering around Maslin Beach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also in 1993, Kelly Cahill from Melbourne claimed to have seen a large craft over the road in the Dandenong Ranges near Belgrave, Victoria, and further claimed to have been abducted by aliens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2012&#34;&gt;2012 &lt;a href=&#34;#2012&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes an alleged encounter in Frankston South, Victoria. A resident, K.T., reported being hit by a blinding light and later encountering a tall, white humanoid being identifying as a &amp;ldquo;Paladeian&amp;rdquo; from the &amp;ldquo;Star Cluster Pladieas.&amp;rdquo; K.T. claimed to have communicated telepathically with the being, experiencing paralysis and lost time during the encounter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to related topics, including the Bass Strait Triangle and a general list of reported UFO sightings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including news articles and websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Australia&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Australia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Westall UFO</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b24ace289f7f/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 01:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b24ace289f7f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;westall-ufo&#34;&gt;Westall UFO &lt;a href=&#34;#westall-ufo&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Westall UFO incident refers to a reported UFO sighting that occurred on April 6, 1966, in Melbourne, Victoria, Australia. The event involved multiple witnesses, including students and a teacher from Westall High School. The incident has been commemorated through documentaries, reunions, and a UFO-themed playground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reports&#34;&gt;Reports &lt;a href=&#34;#reports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 6, 1966, students and a teacher at Westall High School (now Westall Secondary College) reported observing a round, white, grey, or silver object with a domed top. The object reportedly descended behind trees into the Grange, an open area south of the school. Some accounts mention the object being pursued by five unidentified aircraft. Shaun Matthews, who was on vacation at the Grange, described the object as having a slight purple hue and being about twice the size of a family car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Witness accounts varied, with some reporting the object taking off after landing, while others claimed it hovered. Students who went to the Grange after the sighting described a landing site with varying details, including a circle of grass described as burnt, &amp;ldquo;boiled,&amp;rdquo; or pressed down. The number of circles reported ranged from one to three. On April 9, 1966, air force personnel and UFO enthusiasts visited the field but found nothing of interest. The landowner subsequently burned the field to prevent further access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;explanations&#34;&gt;Explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Age&lt;/em&gt; newspaper initially suggested the object might have been a weather balloon released from Laverton. However, checks revealed that no commercial, private, or RAAF pilots reported anything unusual in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keith Basterfield proposed that a runaway balloon from the HIBAL high-altitude balloon project, used to monitor radiation levels after British nuclear tests at Maralinga, could be a likely explanation. He cited documents indicating a test balloon launched from Mildura may have drifted off course and landed near Westall High School. Basterfield noted that HIBAL balloons had a white silver appearance with a parachute and gas tube, consistent with witness descriptions. Reports also surfaced of &amp;ldquo;men in suits&amp;rdquo; cautioning witnesses against discussing the incident, suggesting a secret government exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brian Dunning suggested that a weather balloon could explain the initial sighting. He proposed that a nylon target drogue, towed by one plane for others to chase, could account for the second part of the event. Dunning also noted that over time, descriptions of the event have become mixed with fabricated details, making it difficult to discern accurate accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;media-coverage&#34;&gt;Media Coverage &lt;a href=&#34;#media-coverage&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentary &lt;em&gt;Westall &amp;lsquo;66&lt;/em&gt; focuses on the sighting, featuring interviews conducted by ufologist Shane Ryan. &lt;em&gt;Westall &amp;lsquo;66&lt;/em&gt; has been incorporated into the national history curriculum as a lesson on critical analysis of popular portrayals of historical events. &lt;em&gt;The Phenomenon&lt;/em&gt;, a documentary film directed and co-produced by ufologist James Fox, includes content related to the Westall UFO case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;local-culture&#34;&gt;Local Culture &lt;a href=&#34;#local-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A witness reunion was held at Westall Tennis Club Hall on April 8, 2006, to commemorate the 40th anniversary of the incident. The City of Kingston created Grange Reserve UFO Park at The Grange Reserve in Clayton South, featuring a silver UFO with red slides to reflect the 1966 Westall UFO Incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ariel School UFO incident&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Australian Ufology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bass Strait Triangle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disappearance of Frederick Valentich&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of UFO sightings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Westall_UFO&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Westall_UFO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
