<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>O&#39;Hare on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ohare/</link>
    <description>Recent content in O&#39;Hare on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 07:47:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ohare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2006 O&#39;Hare International Airport UFO sighting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_af46c6dc1b42/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 07:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_af46c6dc1b42/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chicago-ohare-ufo-sighting&#34;&gt;Chicago O&amp;rsquo;Hare UFO Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#chicago-ohare-ufo-sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This details a supposed paranormal event that occurred on November 7, 2006, around 4:15 p.m. at O&amp;rsquo;Hare International Airport. Twelve United Airlines employees and other witnesses reported seeing a UFO. The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) dismissed the incident as a &amp;ldquo;weather phenomenon&amp;rdquo; due to the object not being detected on radar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-sighting&#34;&gt;The Sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#the-sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7, 2006, at approximately 4:15 PM CST, a group of twelve airport employees at Chicago O&amp;rsquo;Hare International Airport reported witnessing a metallic, saucer-shaped craft hovering over Gate C-17. A ramp employee first spotted the object while pushing back United Airlines Flight 446, bound for Charlotte, North Carolina. The employee alerted the flight crew. Pilots, airline management, and mechanics also witnessed the object. Air traffic controllers did not see the object, and it did not appear on radar. Witnesses described the object as silent, dark gray, and ranging from 6 to 24 feet in diameter. Independent witnesses outside the airport also reported seeing the object. One witness described a disc-shaped craft hovering over the airport that shot through the clouds at high velocity, leaving a clear blue hole. Eyewitness accounts varied regarding the shape, height, movement, time, and number of objects sighted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reaction-from-the-federal-aviation-administration-and-united-airlines&#34;&gt;Reaction from the Federal Aviation Administration and United Airlines &lt;a href=&#34;#reaction-from-the-federal-aviation-administration-and-united-airlines&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, both United Airlines and the FAA denied having information about the sighting. The &lt;em&gt;Chicago Tribune&lt;/em&gt; filed a Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) request, prompting the FAA to conduct an internal review of air-traffic communications tapes. The review uncovered a call from a United supervisor to an FAA manager in the airport tower regarding the UFO sighting. The FAA concluded that the sighting was due to a &amp;ldquo;weather phenomenon&amp;rdquo; and would not investigate further. Astronomer Mark Hammergren suggested that weather conditions were conducive to a &amp;ldquo;hole-punch cloud.&amp;rdquo; UFO investigators argued that the FAA&amp;rsquo;s refusal to investigate contradicted its mandate to investigate potential security breaches at airports. Some witnesses expressed frustration that federal officials declined to investigate the matter further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;media-coverage&#34;&gt;Media Coverage &lt;a href=&#34;#media-coverage&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chicago O&amp;rsquo;Hare airport UFO story received coverage from major media outlets, including CNN, CBS, MSNBC, Fox News, the &lt;em&gt;Chicago Tribune&lt;/em&gt;, and NPR. The History Channel&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;UFO Hunters&lt;/em&gt; reviewed the incident in an episode titled &amp;ldquo;Aliens at the Airport&amp;rdquo; on February 11, 2009. The incident is also featured in &lt;em&gt;Hangar 1: The UFO Files&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In Popular Culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film &lt;em&gt;UFO&lt;/em&gt; and an episode of &lt;em&gt;Boston Legal&lt;/em&gt; reference the incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See Also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of reported UFO sightings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the various sources cited in the article, including articles from the &lt;em&gt;Chicago Tribune&lt;/em&gt;, History.com, and reports from NUFORC (National UFO Reporting Center) and NARCAP (National Aviation Reporting Center on Anomalous Phenomena).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External Links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external resources, including an interview with &lt;em&gt;Chicago Tribune&lt;/em&gt; reporter Jon Hilkevitch and a Skeptoid podcast episode about the sighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2006_O%27Hare_International_Airport_UFO_sighting&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2006_O%27Hare_International_Airport_UFO_sighting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
