<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>British Comic on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/british-comic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in British Comic on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 23:17:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/british-comic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Joe Alien</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_76dd0cdfb364/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 23:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_76dd0cdfb364/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;joe-alien&#34;&gt;Joe Alien &lt;a href=&#34;#joe-alien&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe Alien is a British comic book character who appeared in strips published by Fleetway Publications. He debuted in the preview issue of the science fiction anthology &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; in October 1988. The character&amp;rsquo;s strip was one of four linked serials in &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; and was later briefly featured in &lt;em&gt;Eagle&lt;/em&gt; after &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; was canceled. Joe Alien is the last survivor of the planet Xgangbe-4 and joins the &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; mission to help humanity find a new home, commanding the &lt;em&gt;Wildcat 2&lt;/em&gt; exploration shuttle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;creation&#34;&gt;Creation &lt;a href=&#34;#creation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barrie Tomlinson created Joe Alien as part of a new science fiction anthology, &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt;, for Fleetway Publications. The concept involved linking all five features in the comic to form an overall narrative centered on the spaceship &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt;. Tomlinson created four lead characters, including Joe Alien, to head exploration teams. Massimo Belardinelli was the initial artist for &amp;ldquo;Joe Alien,&amp;rdquo; with Tomlinson praising his ability to bring the story to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publishing-history&#34;&gt;Publishing history &lt;a href=&#34;#publishing-history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; began publication in October 1988, featuring &amp;ldquo;Joe Alien&amp;rdquo; as the color strip. Ron Smith took over as the artist from the third issue. &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; was canceled after 12 issues and merged with &lt;em&gt;Eagle&lt;/em&gt; in March 1989. &amp;ldquo;Joe Alien&amp;rdquo; continued in &lt;em&gt;Eagle&lt;/em&gt; for four weeks in May 1989 to complete the story arc and also featured in three episodes of &amp;ldquo;The Wildcat Complete&amp;rdquo; anthology. Rebellion Developments purchased the rights to &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; in 2016 and announced plans to reprint the contents in collected editions. As of 2025, only &amp;ldquo;Turbo Jones&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Loner&amp;rdquo; have been released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot-summary&#34;&gt;Plot summary &lt;a href=&#34;#plot-summary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe Alien joins the &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; mission after Turbo Jones realizes Earth is doomed. Joe, the last survivor of Xgangbe-4, possesses vast knowledge stored in an external brain-pack. He is selected for his intelligence and physical attributes. After the &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt; launches, Joe&amp;rsquo;s sensors locate a potential new home for the refugees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He leads the &lt;em&gt;Wildcat Two&lt;/em&gt; shuttle to scout Area 17, where his team encounters carnivorous vegetation and a two-headed alien. They discover that the plants are controlled by a mad human astronaut from a 2079 Mars mission, who is now worshipped as a god. Joe brokers an alliance with giant insects to escape and later participates in other expeditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe shares the story of the Xgangbe&amp;rsquo;s destruction by the Kargroz and his revenge. He is later chosen to find an alien shapeshifter on board the &lt;em&gt;Wildcat&lt;/em&gt;. Joe, along with Jones, Loner, and Magee, is kidnapped by a Gamemaster of the Glarzon race but is released after defeating the Glarzon&amp;rsquo;s troops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graham Kibble-White described Joe Alien as &amp;ldquo;dopily designed.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joe_Alien&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joe_Alien&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
