<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:22:44 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Abduction</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/alien-abduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 09:36:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/alien-abduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alien abduction (also called abduction phenomenon, alien abduction syndrome, or UFO abduction) refers to the phenomenon of people reporting what they believe to be the real experience of being kidnapped by extraterrestrial beings and subjected to physical and psychological experimentation.[1] People claiming to have been abducted are usually called &amp;ldquo;abductees&amp;rdquo;[2] or &amp;ldquo;experiencers&amp;rdquo;. Most scientists and mental health professionals explain these experiences by factors such as suggestibility (e.g. false memory syndrome), sleep paralysis, deception, and psychopathology.[3] Skeptic Robert Sheaffer sees similarity between some of the aliens described by abductees and those depicted in science fiction films, in particular Invaders From Mars (1953).[4]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typical claims involve forced medical examinations that emphasize the subject&amp;rsquo;s reproductive systems.[5] Abductees sometimes claim to have been warned against environmental abuses and the dangers of nuclear weapons,[6] or to have engaged in interspecies breeding.[7] The contents of the abduction narrative often seem to vary with the home culture of the alleged abductee.[4] Unidentified flying objects (UFOs), alien abduction, and mind control plots can also be part of radical political apocalyptic and millenarian narratives.[8]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;reference: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_abduction&#34;&gt;Alien Abduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dover Demon</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/dover-demon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 09:36:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/dover-demon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Dover Demon is a creature reportedly sighted on April 21–22, 1977, in Dover, Massachusetts, a town about 15 miles (24 km) southwest of downtown Boston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17-year-old William &amp;ldquo;Bill&amp;rdquo; Bartlett claimed that while driving on April 21, 1977, he saw a creature &amp;ldquo;about 4 feet tall with glowing orange eyes and no nose or mouth in a watermelon-shaped head&amp;rdquo; on top of a broken stone wall on Farm Street in Dover, Massachusetts. 15-year-old John Baxter reported seeing a similar creature on Miller Hill Road the same evening. Another 15-year-old, Abby Brabham, claimed to have seen the creature the following night on Springdale Avenue.[1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The teenagers all drew sketches of the alleged creature. Bartlett wrote on his sketch, &amp;ldquo;I, Bill Bartlett, swear on a stack of Bibles that I saw this creature.&amp;quot;[1] According to a local news report, &amp;ldquo;the locations of the sightings, plotted on a map, lay in a straight line over 2 miles [3.2 km]&amp;rdquo;.[1] The sightings were not made public until the first half of May.[2] At that time, a local &amp;ldquo;investigator of unexplained phenomenon&amp;rdquo; noted similarities to creatures in the Kelly–Hopkinsville encounter of 1955.[2] Even though none of the witnesses reported seeing a UFO, the sightings were also investigated by the Mutual UFO Network and associated groups.[3]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;reference: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dover_Demon&#34;&gt;Dover Demon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
