<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Memorial on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/memorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Memorial on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 17:33:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/memorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ängelholm UFO memorial</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_c78e1bc4d1a1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 17:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_c78e1bc4d1a1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ängelholm-ufo-memorial&#34;&gt;Ängelholm UFO memorial &lt;a href=&#34;#%c3%a4ngelholm-ufo-memorial&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ängelholm UFO memorial is a monument in Kronoskogen forest near Ängelholm, Sweden, commemorating an alleged UFO landing in 1946. It features a concrete model of a flying saucer, purported landing impressions, and copper plaques with eyewitness testimony. The monument is based on the account of Gösta Carlsson, who claimed his success was due to a UFO encounter. Erected in 1972, it is maintained by the local government and is a tourist destination and national heritage site, despite lacking corroborating evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the background of Gösta Carlsson, the man behind the alleged UFO encounter and the subsequent memorial. Carlsson (1918–2003) founded the herbal medicine company Cernelle in 1953, becoming known as &lt;em&gt;Pollenkungen&lt;/em&gt; due to his success with bee pollen extracts. He invested in the local ice hockey club, Rögle BK, and attributed his success to a May 1946 UFO encounter in Kronoskogen forest near Ängelholm. He claimed to have seen a disc-shaped craft with a crew, and that the encounter inspired him to experiment with pollen. He didn&amp;rsquo;t publicly discuss the encounter until the 1970s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statements&#34;&gt;Statements &lt;a href=&#34;#statements&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers statements made by Carlsson and others regarding the alleged UFO encounter. Carlsson first spoke publicly about the incident in a 1971 interview with journalist Eugen Semitjov. Semitjov visited the clearing with Carlsson and found no definitive marks. A quartz rod Carlsson claimed to have found at the site was analyzed and found to be ordinary. In 1995, ufologist Clas Svahn co-authored a book with Carlsson, &lt;em&gt;Mötet i gläntan&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The meeting in the clearing&lt;/em&gt;), but ultimately disbelieved the encounter while acknowledging Carlsson&amp;rsquo;s conviction. Historian Dick Harrison described Carlsson&amp;rsquo;s narrative as &amp;ldquo;alleged but not proven.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;monument&#34;&gt;Monument &lt;a href=&#34;#monument&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the physical features of the Ängelholm UFO memorial. At the center is a one-eighth-scale concrete model of a flying saucer, based on Carlsson&amp;rsquo;s sketches. Concrete paths depict landing impressions, and copper plaques on pillars provide eyewitness testimony. The monument is a Swedish National Heritage Board site (RAÄ Strövelstorp 47:1). Located near Ängelholm and the beach, it attracts tourists. Guided tours are common, often starting from the Skåne Line bunkers. Ängelholm Municipality maintains the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists other UFO-related memorials and incidents with Wikipedia articles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emilcin UFO memorial in Poland, commemorating an alleged alien abduction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert Taylor incident, commemorated by the Dechmont UFO Trail in Livingston, Scotland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A link to the List of reported UFO sightings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%C3%84ngelholm_UFO_memorial&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%C3%84ngelholm_UFO_memorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
