<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Experimental Aircraft on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/experimental-aircraft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Experimental Aircraft on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 09:29:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/experimental-aircraft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Area 51</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1bb36472371e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 09:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1bb36472371e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;area-51&#34;&gt;Area 51 &lt;a href=&#34;#area-51&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Area 51, officially called Homey Airport (KXTA) or Groom Lake, is a highly classified United States Air Force (USAF) facility located within the Nevada Test and Training Range. It&amp;rsquo;s administered by Edwards Air Force Base. While details of its operations are not public, it&amp;rsquo;s generally believed to support the development and testing of experimental aircraft and weapons systems. The USAF and CIA acquired the site in 1955, primarily for flight testing the Lockheed U-2 aircraft. The intense secrecy surrounding the base has made it a frequent subject of conspiracy theories and a central component of unidentified flying object (UFO) folklore. The CIA publicly acknowledged the base&amp;rsquo;s existence in 2013, following a Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) request. It&amp;rsquo;s located in southern Nevada, approximately 83 miles (134 km) north-northwest of Las Vegas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography &lt;a href=&#34;#geography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the physical location and surrounding areas of Area 51. The original base was a 6 by 10 mile rectangle, part of the larger &amp;ldquo;Groom box,&amp;rdquo; a 23 by 25 mile area of restricted airspace. It&amp;rsquo;s connected to the Nevada Test Site (NTS) road network, with roads leading to Mercury and Yucca Flat. Groom Lake Road runs northeast through the Jumbled Hills, past a security checkpoint, and eventually connects to State Route 375, the &amp;ldquo;Extraterrestrial Highway,&amp;rdquo; south of Rachel, Nevada. Area 51 shares a border with the Yucca Flat region of the Nevada Test Site, where many US nuclear tests were conducted. The Yucca Mountain nuclear waste repository is southwest of Groom Lake. Groom Lake itself is a salt flat used for runways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The origin of the name &amp;ldquo;Area 51&amp;rdquo; is uncertain. The CIA refers to the facility as Homey Airport (XTA/KXTA) and Groom Lake. Other nicknames include &amp;ldquo;Dreamland&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Paradise Ranch.&amp;rdquo; The special use airspace is Restricted Area 4808 North (R-4808N). Lead and silver were discovered in the Groom Range in 1864, and mining operations occurred until the early 1950s. The airfield began service in 1942 as Indian Springs Air Force Auxiliary Field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-2-program&#34;&gt;U-2 program &lt;a href=&#34;#u-2-program&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CIA established the Groom Lake test facility in April 1955 for Project AQUATONE, the development of the Lockheed U-2 strategic reconnaissance aircraft. Project director Richard M. Bissell Jr. sought a secure testing site. Lockheed&amp;rsquo;s Kelly Johnson found Groom Lake ideal due to the dry lake bed and surrounding mountain ranges. The CIA acquired the land from the AEC, designating it &amp;ldquo;Area 51.&amp;rdquo; Johnson named the area &amp;ldquo;Paradise Ranch.&amp;rdquo; A survey team arrived in May 1955, laying out a runway and base support facility. The Ranch initially consisted of shelters, workshops, and trailer homes. By July 1955, the base had a paved runway, three hangars, a control tower, and accommodations for personnel. The first U-2 delivery arrived on July 24, 1955. Regular flights were established between Area 51 and Lockheed&amp;rsquo;s Burbank offices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;oxcart-program&#34;&gt;OXCART program &lt;a href=&#34;#oxcart-program&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project OXCART was established in August 1959 for work on the Lockheed A-12. Groom Lake&amp;rsquo;s facilities were initially inadequate. Construction of &amp;ldquo;Project 51&amp;rdquo; began in September 1960, including a new 8,500 ft runway. Reynolds Electrical and Engineering Company (REECo) upgraded base facilities. A 10,000 ft runway (14/32) was built, and an Archimedean spiral was marked on the dry lake as an overrun. Three Navy hangars were erected, and the original U-2 hangars were converted to maintenance shops. Facilities included workshops, storage, administration buildings, a commissary, a control tower, a fire station, and housing. A permanent aircraft fuel tank farm was constructed for the JP-7 fuel required by the A-12. Security was enhanced, and the FAA expanded the restricted airspace. The CIA facility received USAF F-101 Voodoos, T-33 Shooting Star trainers, a C-130 Hercules, a U-3A, a helicopter, a Cessna 180, and an F-104 Starfighter. The first A-12 test aircraft arrived in February 1962 and made its first flight on April 26, 1962. By the end of 1963, nine A-12s were at Area 51, assigned to the CIA-operated &amp;ldquo;1129th Special Activities Squadron&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;d-21-tagboard&#34;&gt;D-21 Tagboard &lt;a href=&#34;#d-21-tagboard&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the loss of Gary Powers&amp;rsquo; U-2, discussions arose about using the A-12 OXCART as an unpiloted drone aircraft. The Air Force agreed to fund the study of a high-speed, high-altitude drone aircraft in October 1962, designated &amp;ldquo;Q-12,&amp;rdquo; later renamed the &amp;ldquo;D-21.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Tagboard&amp;rdquo; was the project&amp;rsquo;s code name. The D-21 was to be carried by a two-seat derivative of the A-12, designated the &amp;ldquo;M-21.&amp;rdquo; Difficulties were addressed throughout 1964 and 1965. The first D-21 launch was made on March 5, 1966, with a successful flight. An accident on July 30, 1966, caused the D-21 to collide with the M-21 launch aircraft, resulting in one crew member drowning. Kelly Johnson cancelled the program. The Air Force proposed launching them from a B-52H bomber. The test missions were flown out of Groom Lake, with the actual launches over the Pacific. Several more tests were made, none of which met with success. The D-21B program was cancelled on July 15, 1971. The remaining drones were transferred to the Davis-Monthan AFB Military Storage and Disposition Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;foreign-technology-evaluation&#34;&gt;Foreign technology evaluation &lt;a href=&#34;#foreign-technology-evaluation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the Cold War, the United States tested and evaluated captured Soviet fighter aircraft. Beginning in the late 1960s, Area 51 hosted Soviet-built aircraft. Munir Redfa&amp;rsquo;s defection with a Mikoyan-Gurevich MiG-21 led to the HAVE DOUGHNUT, HAVE DRILL and HAVE FERRY programs. The first MiGs flown in the United States were used to evaluate their performance and capabilities, pitting them against U.S. fighters. In August 1966, Iraqi Air Force fighter pilot Captain Munir Redfa defected, flying his MiG-21 to Israel. His aircraft was transferred to Groom Lake in late 1967 for study. In 1968, the US Air Force and Navy jointly formed a project known as HAVE DOUGHNUT. Comparisons between the F-4 and the MiG-21 indicated that the skill of the pilot was what made the difference. On August 12, 1968, two Syrian air force lieutenants landed at the Betzet Landing Field in northern Israel with a pair of MiG-17Fs. These MiG-17s were transferred from Israeli stocks and added to the Area 51 test fleet. The aircraft were given USAF designations and fake serial numbers. The data from the HAVE DOUGHNUT and HAVE DRILL tests were provided to the newly formed Top Gun school at NAS Miramar. In May 1973, Project HAVE IDEA was formed, and the project was transferred to the Tonopah Test Range Airport. Area 51 also hosted another foreign materiel evaluation program called HAVE GLIB. The Air Force began funding improvements to Area 51 in 1977 under project SCORE EVENT. In 1979, the CIA transferred jurisdiction of the Area 51 site to the Air Force Flight Test Center at Edwards AFB, California. In 2017, a USAF aircraft crashed at the site, killing the pilot, Lt. Colonel Eric &amp;ldquo;Doc&amp;rdquo; Schultz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;have-bluef-117-program&#34;&gt;Have Blue/F-117 program &lt;a href=&#34;#have-bluef-117-program&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lockheed Have Blue prototype stealth fighter first flew at Groom in December 1977. In 1978, the Air Force awarded a full-scale development contract for the F-117 to Lockheed Corporation&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Development Projects. On January 17, 1981, the Lockheed test team at Area 51 accepted delivery of the first full-scale development (FSD) prototype, designated YF-117A. On June 18, 1981, Lockheed Skunk Works test pilot Hal Farley lifted the nose of YF-117A off the runway of Area 51. Tactical Air Command (TAC) decided to set up a group-level organization to guide the F-117A to an initial operating capability, the 4450th Tactical Group, which officially activated on October 15, 1979, at Nellis AFB, Nevada, although the group was physically located at Area 51. The 4450th TG also operated the A-7D Corsair II as a surrogate trainer for the F-117A. On October 15, 1982, Major Alton C. Whitley Jr. became the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Area_51&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Area_51&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
