<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alien Encounters on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/alien-encounters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alien Encounters on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 01:11:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/alien-encounters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Close Encounters of the Third Kind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_c68085f81f67/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_c68085f81f67/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;close-encounters-of-the-third-kind&#34;&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind &lt;a href=&#34;#close-encounters-of-the-third-kind&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 1977 American science fiction drama film directed and written by Steven Spielberg. It tells the story of Roy Neary, an everyday blue-collar worker in Indiana, and Jillian, a single mother, whose lives are changed after encounters with unidentified flying objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1977, French scientist Claude Lacombe and his team examine Flight 19, found abandoned in the Sonoran Desert, and the SS Cotopaxi, found in the Gobi Desert. Near Indianapolis, Roy Neary has a close encounter with a UFO, becoming obsessed with a mountain shape. Jillian Guiler&amp;rsquo;s son, Barry, is abducted by a UFO. Lacombe&amp;rsquo;s team investigates increasing UFO activity, discovering a five-tone musical phrase. The coordinates point to Devils Tower in Wyoming. Roy and Jillian, along with others experiencing visions, head to Devils Tower, which is being evacuated by the US Army. They reach the site as UFOs appear. Scientists communicate with the UFOs using light and sound. A mothership arrives, releasing humans and animals, including Barry. Roy is chosen to join the extraterrestrials, entering the mothership as it departs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Dreyfuss stars as Roy Neary, an electrical lineman. François Truffaut plays Claude Lacombe, a French scientist. Teri Garr is Ronnie Neary, Roy&amp;rsquo;s wife, and Melinda Dillon portrays Jillian Guiler. Cary Guffey plays Barry Guiler, Jillian&amp;rsquo;s son. Bob Balaban appears as David Laughlin, Lacombe&amp;rsquo;s assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;development&#34;&gt;Development &lt;a href=&#34;#development&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film&amp;rsquo;s inspiration came from Steven Spielberg&amp;rsquo;s childhood experience watching a meteor shower. He developed a deal with Columbia Pictures in 1973. J. Allen Hynek, a UFO consultant, was hired. NASA declined to cooperate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;filming&#34;&gt;Filming &lt;a href=&#34;#filming&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Principal photography began in May 1976. Filming locations included Burbank, California; Devils Tower National Monument in Wyoming; airship hangars in Mobile, Alabama; and a railroad depot in Bay Minette, Alabama. The Sonora Desert sequence was filmed at the Dumont Dunes, California, and the Dharmsala-India exteriors were filmed near Mumbai, India. Technical and budgetary problems arose during filming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;visual-effects&#34;&gt;Visual effects &lt;a href=&#34;#visual-effects&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Douglas Trumbull served as the visual effects supervisor, and Carlo Rambaldi designed the extraterrestrials. The mothership was designed by Ralph McQuarrie and built by Greg Jein. The look of the ship was inspired by an oil refinery Spielberg saw at night in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;post-production&#34;&gt;Post-production &lt;a href=&#34;#post-production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Kahn was the film editor. Pick-ups were commissioned, with John A. Alonzo, László Kovács, and Douglas Slocombe working on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;Music &lt;a href=&#34;#music&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Williams composed the film score, including the iconic five-tone motif. Spielberg called Williams&amp;rsquo;s work &amp;ldquo;When You Wish Upon a Star meets science fiction.&amp;rdquo; Phillip Dodds from ARP Instruments installed the synthesizer on set and was cast as Jean Claude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes &lt;a href=&#34;#themes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film explores themes of humanity&amp;rsquo;s readiness to join the cosmos, the impact of new technologies, and spiritual yearning. Judeo-Christian analogies are present, with Devils Tower paralleling Mount Sinai. Communication and tolerance are also highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release-and-reception&#34;&gt;Release and reception &lt;a href=&#34;#release-and-reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;box-office&#34;&gt;Box office &lt;a href=&#34;#box-office&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film premiered in New York City on November 16, 1977, and was released nationally in December. It became a box office success, grossing over $300 million worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;critical-reception&#34;&gt;Critical reception &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviews were mostly positive, with praise for Spielberg&amp;rsquo;s vision and the film&amp;rsquo;s climax. Some critics noted a lack of warmth compared to &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reissues-and-home-media&#34;&gt;Reissues and home media &lt;a href=&#34;#reissues-and-home-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several versions of the film have been released, including the original theatrical version, the Special Edition (1980), and the Director&amp;rsquo;s Cut (1998). The Special Edition added scenes, including the interior of the mothership, while the Director&amp;rsquo;s Cut removed the mothership interior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;accolades&#34;&gt;Accolades &lt;a href=&#34;#accolades&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received numerous awards and nominations, including Academy Awards, British Academy Film Awards, and Golden Globe Awards. It was selected for preservation in the National Film Registry in 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legacy&#34;&gt;Legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Close Encounters&lt;/em&gt; is credited with launching the reemergence of science fiction films in the 1980s. Spielberg donated to the Planetary Society for extraterrestrial research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Close_Encounters_of_the_Third_Kind&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Close_Encounters_of_the_Third_Kind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
