<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aliens on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/aliens/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aliens on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 07:12:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/aliens/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO (British TV series)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6106319ec4a7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 07:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6106319ec4a7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-british-tv-series&#34;&gt;UFO (British TV series) &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-british-tv-series&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A British science fiction television series that aired from 1970 to 1971, focusing on Earth&amp;rsquo;s defense against an alien invasion in the then-future of 1980.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;premise&#34;&gt;Premise &lt;a href=&#34;#premise&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1980, Earth is under threat from aliens from a dying planet who are abducting humans for their organs. SHADO (Supreme Headquarters Alien Defence Organisation), a secret international military agency operating under the guise of a movie studio, is formed to defend Earth. SHADO utilizes advanced technology, including a space intruder detection satellite (SID), lunar interceptors, a submarine/aircraft called Skydiver, and ground-based SHADO Mobiles. The aliens are humanoid, requiring a green oxygenated liquid and special contact lenses. Their UFOs can travel faster than light but have limited time in Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast-and-characters&#34;&gt;Cast and characters &lt;a href=&#34;#cast-and-characters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series features a large ensemble cast with frequent changes. Ed Bishop as Commander Ed Straker is the only actor to appear in every episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;main-characters&#34;&gt;Main characters &lt;a href=&#34;#main-characters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commander Edward Straker (Ed Bishop):&lt;/strong&gt; The head of SHADO, posing as the head of Harlington-Straker Film Studios.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colonel Paul Foster (Michael Billington):&lt;/strong&gt; A former test pilot recruited into SHADO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lieutenant Gay Ellis (Gabrielle Drake):&lt;/strong&gt; Moonbase commander.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colonel Alec Freeman (George Sewell):&lt;/strong&gt; SHADO&amp;rsquo;s second-in-command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General James Henderson (Grant Taylor):&lt;/strong&gt; Straker&amp;rsquo;s superior and president of the International Astrophysical Commission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colonel Virginia Lake (Wanda Ventham):&lt;/strong&gt; A SHADO operative who later becomes first officer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captain Peter Carlin (Peter Gordeno):&lt;/strong&gt; First commander of Skydiver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lieutenant Nina Barry (Dolores Mantez):&lt;/strong&gt; Moonbase operative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captain Lew Waterman (Gary Myers):&lt;/strong&gt; Second commander of Skydiver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lieutenant Keith Ford (Keith Alexander):&lt;/strong&gt; Communications officer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lieutenant Ayshea Johnson (Ayshea Brough):&lt;/strong&gt; SHADO headquarters officer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctor Douglas Jackson (Vladek Sheybal):&lt;/strong&gt; SHADO psychiatrist and science officer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lieutenant Joan Harrington (Antonia Ellis):&lt;/strong&gt; Moonbase operative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miss Ealand (Norma Ronald):&lt;/strong&gt; Straker&amp;rsquo;s secretary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lieutenant Mark Bradley (Harry Baird):&lt;/strong&gt; Interceptor pilot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;minor-characters&#34;&gt;Minor characters &lt;a href=&#34;#minor-characters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shakira Baksh (later Michael Caine&amp;rsquo;s wife) played Joanna, a Moonbase operative. Steven Berkoff played Interceptor pilot Steve Minto, and Georgina Moon played Lieutenant Sylvia Howell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 26 episodes were broadcast in a non-chronological order by ITV. The list provides the original ATV (Midlands) broadcast order, along with director, writer, original air date, and production code. Episode titles include &amp;ldquo;Identified,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Exposed,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;The Cat with Ten Lives,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Conflict,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;A Question of Priorities,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;The Long Sleep.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alternative-viewing-orders&#34;&gt;Alternative viewing orders &lt;a href=&#34;#alternative-viewing-orders&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different viewing orders exist, including production order, ATV broadcast order, and recommended orders by UFO Series, Fanderson, and ITC. A table compares these different orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lew Grade approached Gerry Anderson to create a live-action TV series, resulting in &lt;em&gt;UFO&lt;/em&gt;. The series was influenced by UFO sightings and Christiaan Barnard&amp;rsquo;s transplant operations. Sylvia Anderson designed the costumes, including the purple wigs for female Moonbase staff. The Harlington-Straker Studio was the actual studio where the series was filmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;filming&#34;&gt;Filming &lt;a href=&#34;#filming&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Filming began in April 1969 at MGM-British Studios, then moved to Pinewood Studios in June 1970. George Sewell and Gabrielle Drake left after the studio change. Harry Baird and Peter Gordeno also left the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;costumes&#34;&gt;Costumes &lt;a href=&#34;#costumes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Female Moonbase personnel wore purple wigs, silver catsuits, and heavy eye makeup for a futuristic look. Ed Bishop initially bleached his hair, then wore a white wig. Other male characters also wore wigs. Only two alien suits were made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;special-effects&#34;&gt;Special effects &lt;a href=&#34;#special-effects&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derek Meddings supervised the special effects, using techniques like double-walled visors and underwater effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vehicle-design&#34;&gt;Vehicle design &lt;a href=&#34;#vehicle-design&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derek Meddings and Mike Trim designed the vehicles. The gull-winged cars were originally built for &lt;em&gt;Doppelgänger&lt;/em&gt;. The blue SHADO Jeeps were built on Mini Moke chassis. Few original props and miniatures have survived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;broadcast&#34;&gt;Broadcast &lt;a href=&#34;#broadcast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Broadcasters were unsure if &lt;em&gt;UFO&lt;/em&gt; was for adults or children. In the UK, episodes were shown in the late afternoon and Saturday mornings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviews of &lt;em&gt;UFO&lt;/em&gt; are mixed. Some praise the visuals, music, and costumes, while others criticize the writing and pacing. Some reviews note the series&amp;rsquo; mix of adult themes and science fiction elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aborted-second-series&#34;&gt;Aborted second series &lt;a href=&#34;#aborted-second-series&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ITC commissioned a second series, &lt;em&gt;UFO 2&lt;/em&gt;, set entirely on the Moon. However, when ratings dropped, ITC cancelled the plans. Gerry Anderson then created &lt;em&gt;Space: 1999&lt;/em&gt; from the pre-production work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;merchandise&#34;&gt;Merchandise &lt;a href=&#34;#merchandise&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series generated a range of toys, including Dinky die-cast vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;compilation-films&#34;&gt;Compilation films &lt;a href=&#34;#compilation-films&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several episodes were compiled into films, including &lt;em&gt;Invasion: UFO&lt;/em&gt;. Italian producers also created compilation films with mixed reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;home-media&#34;&gt;Home media &lt;a href=&#34;#home-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Channel 5 and ITC released VHS collections. The complete series was released on DVD in 2002.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;proposed-feature-film&#34;&gt;Proposed feature film &lt;a href=&#34;#proposed-feature-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2009, a feature film adaptation was announced, but it did not enter production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-other-media&#34;&gt;In other media &lt;a href=&#34;#in-other-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stories set in the &lt;em&gt;UFO&lt;/em&gt; universe have appeared in novels, comics, and video games. Julian Gollop cited &lt;em&gt;UFO&lt;/em&gt; as an influence for &lt;em&gt;UFO: Enemy Unknown&lt;/em&gt;. Yoshiyuki Sadamoto drew inspiration from &lt;em&gt;UFO&lt;/em&gt; for character designs in &lt;em&gt;Neon Genesis Evangelion&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;translations&#34;&gt;Translations &lt;a href=&#34;#translations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series has been translated into French, German, Japanese, Italian, Spanish, and Brazilian Portuguese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_(British_TV_series)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_(British_TV_series)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien Nation</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ecb551d0af0a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 03:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ecb551d0af0a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-nation&#34;&gt;Alien Nation &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-nation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt; is an American science fiction media franchise created by Rockne S. O&amp;rsquo;Bannon, known for &lt;em&gt;Farscape&lt;/em&gt;. The franchise, owned by 20th Century Studios, encompasses film, television, novels, and comics centered around alien refugees living on Earth. It blends science fiction with elements of drama, police procedural, and buddy cop genres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting&#34;&gt;Setting &lt;a href=&#34;#setting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The franchise is set in the near future in the United States, specifically starting in 1991. A flying saucer crashes in the Mojave Desert, revealing the Tenctonese, an extraterrestrial race referred to as &amp;ldquo;Newcomers.&amp;rdquo; These aliens are escaping slavery from a cruel Overseer race. The Tenctonese resemble humans but possess anatomical differences and enhanced physical and intellectual capabilities due to selective breeding. The core concept revolves around the Newcomers&amp;rsquo; integration into American society, exploring themes of multiculturalism and acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;film&#34;&gt;Film &lt;a href=&#34;#film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The franchise began with the 1988 film &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt;, released by 20th Century Fox. The film depicts the integration of the Tenctonese refugees, or Newcomers, into human society in Los Angeles. It combines science fiction and police drama elements. The film stars Mandy Patinkin as Sam &amp;ldquo;George&amp;rdquo; Francisco, a Newcomer detective in the Los Angeles Police Department, and James Caan as Matthew Sykes, his initially reluctant human partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;television&#34;&gt;Television &lt;a href=&#34;#television&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1989, Fox adapted the film into a television series, also called &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt;. The series follows the same premise as the film, focusing on the Newcomers&amp;rsquo; integration after their ship crashes on Earth. Eric Pierpoint stars as George Francisco, and Gary Graham as Matthew Sikes. The series explores themes of racism and the treatment of minority ethnic groups. The series ran for one season of 21 episodes and a pilot episode, ending in 1990. Fox abruptly cancelled the series after the season. Beginning in 1994, the network continued the story in five TV movies, which brought back the entire cast. The installments include &lt;em&gt;Dark Horizon&lt;/em&gt; (1994), &lt;em&gt;Body and Soul&lt;/em&gt; (1995), &lt;em&gt;Millennium&lt;/em&gt; (1996), &lt;em&gt;The Enemy Within&lt;/em&gt; (1996), and &lt;em&gt;The Udara Legacy&lt;/em&gt; (1997).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;novels&#34;&gt;Novels &lt;a href=&#34;#novels&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pocket Books, a division of Simon &amp;amp; Schuster, published a novel series connected to the franchise starting in 1993. Judith and Garfield Reeves-Stevens, known for their work in &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;, wrote a novel entitled &lt;em&gt;Day of Descent&lt;/em&gt;. Some novels served as prequels to the movie sequels, such as K.W. Jeter&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Cross of Blood&lt;/em&gt;, a tie-in to the &lt;em&gt;Dark Horizon&lt;/em&gt; film, and Peter David&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Body and Soul&lt;/em&gt;, which became one of the sequels of the same name. The novels regularly addressed racism and discrimination with extraterrestrial themes. K. W. Jeter and Barry B. Longyear were regular contributors to the series with novels like, &lt;em&gt;The Change&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Slag Like Me&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comics&#34;&gt;Comics &lt;a href=&#34;#comics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 1990 to 1992, Malibu Comics published several comics adapting the &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt; storyline. Among the first released titles were &lt;em&gt;The Spartans&lt;/em&gt;, created with the help of author Bill Spangler and illustrator James Tucker, and &lt;em&gt;A Breed Apart&lt;/em&gt;, authored by Steve Jones. Other titles included &lt;em&gt;Public Enemy&lt;/em&gt;, authored by Sandy Carruthers and illustrated by Lowell Cunningham, and a crossover series with the &lt;em&gt;Planet of the Apes&lt;/em&gt; franchise titled &lt;em&gt;Ape Nation&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;Ape Nation&lt;/em&gt; series included four different adventures called &lt;em&gt;Plans&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Pasts&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Pawns&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Pains&lt;/em&gt; along with a collector&amp;rsquo;s edition. Other contributors to the series included illustrators Terry Pallott and Leonard Kirk to titles like, &lt;em&gt;The Skin Trade&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;remake&#34;&gt;Remake &lt;a href=&#34;#remake&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On March 25, 2015, Fox announced a remake with Art Marcum and Matt Holloway writing. On September 9, 2016, &lt;em&gt;Deadline&lt;/em&gt; reported that Jeff Nichols would write and direct the film. On January 25, 2021, it was announced that Jeff Nichols would remake the film as a ten-part television series. On June 21, 2024, it was reported Nichols was developing an original sci-fi feature film for Paramount instead of an Alien Nation project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Nation&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Nation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roswell, New Mexico</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cc35dd7d6510/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cc35dd7d6510/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;roswell-new-mexico&#34;&gt;Roswell, New Mexico &lt;a href=&#34;#roswell-new-mexico&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roswell is a city located in Chaves County, New Mexico, serving as its county seat. It&amp;rsquo;s known for the alleged Roswell incident and is home to the New Mexico Military Institute (NMMI) and an Eastern New Mexico University campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The area was first settled by pioneers from Missouri in 1865, though they abandoned the site due to lack of water. Van C. Smith and Aaron Wilburn established a general store and post office in 1869, which marked the beginning of the modern city. Smith named the town after his father, Roswell Smith. Captain Joseph Calloway Lea and his family acquired the land in 1877. The discovery of a major aquifer in 1890 and the arrival of the Pecos Valley Railroad in 1892 spurred growth. During World War II, a prisoner-of-war camp was located nearby, with German POWs contributing to infrastructure projects. Walker Air Force Base was important from 1941 to 1967, after which Roswell transitioned into a retirement community. The city has capitalized on the Roswell UFO incident, attracting tourists interested in UFOs and aliens. In 2024, Roswell was chosen to host the Reno Air Races starting in 2025. Felix Baumgartner&amp;rsquo;s record-breaking skydive occurred in Roswell in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography &lt;a href=&#34;#geography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roswell is situated in the High Great Plains of southeastern New Mexico, west of the Pecos River. U.S. Routes 70, 285, and 380 intersect in the city, providing connections to other cities like Clovis, Alamogordo, Santa Fe, Carlsbad, Brownfield, and Socorro. The city&amp;rsquo;s total area is approximately 29.776 square miles, with a small percentage covered by water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;climate&#34;&gt;Climate &lt;a href=&#34;#climate&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roswell has a cold semi-arid climate with four distinct seasons. Winters are cool and sunny, with occasional snowfall. Summers are hot, with temperatures exceeding 100 °F on average 30 days per year. The North American monsoon brings torrential downpours and thunderstorms during the summer. Fall is warm and pleasant. The record low is −24 °F, and the record high is 114 °F.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;demographics&#34;&gt;Demographics &lt;a href=&#34;#demographics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The population was 48,422 at the 2020 census. The racial and ethnic composition is diverse, with a significant Hispanic or Latino population. The median household income was $48,298, and the per capita income was $25,906 (2018–2022 in 2022 dollars).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education &lt;a href=&#34;#education&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public schools are managed by the Roswell Independent School District, which includes Goddard High School and Roswell High School. Private schools include All Saints Catholic School and Gateway Christian School. Higher education institutions include Eastern New Mexico University-Roswell and New Mexico Military Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sports&#34;&gt;Sports &lt;a href=&#34;#sports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Roswell Invaders play in the Pecos League of professional baseball. Joe Bauman set a minor-league record of 72 home runs for the Roswell Rockets in 1954. Willie Stargell played for the Roswell Pirates in 1959.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transportation&#34;&gt;Transportation &lt;a href=&#34;#transportation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roswell Air Center is served by American Airlines via American Eagle. Pecos Trails Transit provides bus routes. Greyhound Lines offers intercity services. Major highways include U.S. Route 70, U.S. Route 285, and U.S. Route 380. BNSF Railway provides freight services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;local-industry&#34;&gt;Local Industry &lt;a href=&#34;#local-industry&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leprino Foods, one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest mozzarella factories, is located in Roswell. The city was also home to the Transportation Manufacturing Corporation factory, known for producing RTS city buses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultural-attractions&#34;&gt;Cultural Attractions &lt;a href=&#34;#cultural-attractions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roswell&amp;rsquo;s tourism industry revolves around aerospace engineering and ufology museums and businesses, with alien-themed iconography. The International UFO Museum and Research Center is a major attraction. An annual UFO festival has been held since 1995. The Roswell Museum maintains an exhibit on Robert H. Goddard&amp;rsquo;s rocket engine development. The Anderson Museum of Contemporary Art features works by artists from the Roswell Artist-in-Residence program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notable-residents&#34;&gt;Notable Residents &lt;a href=&#34;#notable-residents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notable residents include businessman and philanthropist Robert O. Anderson, federal appellate judge Bobby Baldock, football player and sportscaster Tom Brookshier, pioneer John Chisum, politician Louise Holland Coe, singer John Denver, TV journalist Sam Donaldson, sheriff Pat Garrett, rocket pioneer Robert H. Goddard, opera singer Susan Graham, businessman J.J. Hagerman, politician James F. Hinkle, golfer Nancy Lopez, actor Jody McCrea, actress Demi Moore, Army colonel Sergio de la Peña, golfer Gerina Piller, actress Priscilla Presley, Marine Corps Sergeant Major Clinton A. Puckett, Lieutenant General James P. Riseley, jockey Mike E. Smith, actor Austin St. John, and quarterback Roger Staubach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell,_New_Mexico&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell,_New_Mexico&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cattle mutilation</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_0fbabb4e9f81/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 18:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_0fbabb4e9f81/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;cattle-mutilation&#34;&gt;Cattle Mutilation &lt;a href=&#34;#cattle-mutilation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cattle mutilation refers to the killing and mutilation of cattle (and other animals) under unusual and often bloodless circumstances. The phenomenon is often linked to paranormal or supernatural explanations, including cults, government agencies, cryptids like the chupacabra, and extraterrestrials. Mutilations typically involve the removal of specific body parts such as ears, eyeballs, jaw flesh, tongues, lymph nodes, genitals, and rectums. Two independent federal investigations in the United States have been conducted into these incidents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-history&#34;&gt;Early History &lt;a href=&#34;#early-history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documented reports of unexplained livestock deaths date back to 1606 in England, with sheep being slaughtered and only tallow and inward parts removed. Charles Fort collected accounts of cattle mutilations in England during the late 19th and early 20th centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-snippy-horse-death-of-1967&#34;&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Snippy&amp;rdquo; Horse Death of 1967 &lt;a href=&#34;#the-snippy-horse-death-of-1967&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case of &amp;ldquo;Snippy,&amp;rdquo; a horse found mutilated in Alamosa, Colorado, in 1967, brought widespread attention to unexplained livestock deaths. The horse&amp;rsquo;s head and neck were skinned and defleshed, with precise cuts and no blood at the scene. Agnes King and her son Harry discovered the body. The incident fueled speculation about extraterrestrial involvement. Wadsworth Ayer&amp;rsquo;s investigation for the Condon Committee found no evidence of abnormal causes. Sheriff Ben Phillips initially suggested a lightning strike. Later, two students confessed to shooting the horse weeks after the publicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cattle-mutilations-19731980&#34;&gt;Cattle Mutilations 1973–1980 &lt;a href=&#34;#cattle-mutilations-19731980&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This period saw waves of cattle mutilations reported in Kansas, Nebraska, Colorado, and New Mexico. In April 1973, sheriffs in Western Iowa reported unidentified helicopters involved in cattle and pig rustling. Similar rustling was reported in Missouri in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1973-kansas-wave&#34;&gt;1973 Kansas Wave &lt;a href=&#34;#1973-kansas-wave&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June 1973, Cloud County sheriff Fred Modlin warned the public about a caller posing as a USDA official. A series of butchered cows were found on farms near Munden, Kansas, with right ears removed. Local press speculated about a &amp;ldquo;Mad Dog&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;phantom&amp;rdquo; Butcher. By December, law enforcement reported 40 mutilations across Kansas and Nebraska, with sexual organs removed. State Senator Ross Doyen reported a mutilation on his ranch. The Kansas Brand Commissioner&amp;rsquo;s office attributed most deaths to natural causes, a conclusion disputed by Modlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1974-nebraska-wave&#34;&gt;1974 Nebraska Wave &lt;a href=&#34;#1974-nebraska-wave&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports resumed in April 1974 with a mutilated and blood-drained cow in Nebraska. The North American Newspaper Alliance reported on the 1973 mutilations and helicopter sightings. In May, mutilations were reported in Mills County, Iowa, with coyotes suggested as the cause. By June, mutilations were reported in Lancaster County, Nebraska. Custer County reported helicopter sightings and armed patrols. In August, an unidentified helicopter was spotted hovering above a field where a mutilated cow was later found near Agnew, Nebraska. Knox County Sheriff Herbert Thompson reported armed civilian patrols. Cloud County Attorney William Walsh suggested devil-worshiping cultists were responsible. State Sen. John Decamp called for a coordinated investigation. By late August, 25 mutilations were reported across five Nebraska counties. In September, authorities ordered helicopters to fly above 1000 feet after a commercial helicopter was shot at. A meeting of law enforcement officials from 24 counties estimated 27 out of 80 cow deaths were suspected mutilations. South Dakota Attorney General Kermit Sande reported mutilations in his state. UFO expert J. Allen Hynek denied any link between UFOs and mutilations. In December 1974, mutilations were reported in Minnesota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1975-colorado&#34;&gt;1975 Colorado &lt;a href=&#34;#1975-colorado&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1975, the Colorado Associated Press voted the mutilations as the state&amp;rsquo;s top story. Senator Floyd K. Haskell contacted the FBI, claiming 130 mutilations in Colorado and reports across nine states. A 1979 FBI report estimated 8,000 mutilations in Colorado, causing $1 million in damages. Donald E. Flickinger of the Michigan ATF investigated possible links to a &amp;ldquo;Hell-oriented biker gang.&amp;rdquo; The Colorado Bureau of Investigation opened an investigation under Carl Whiteside. The New York Times published a story examining cattle mutilations across 11 states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1976-dulce-new-mexico&#34;&gt;1976 Dulce, New Mexico &lt;a href=&#34;#1976-dulce-new-mexico&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 13, 1976, Dulce rancher Manuel Gomez reported a mutilation to Officer Gabe Valdez of the New Mexico State Patrol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1979-public-meeting&#34;&gt;1979 Public Meeting &lt;a href=&#34;#1979-public-meeting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 20, 1979, U.S. Attorney R. E. Thompson and US Senator Harrison Schmidt held a public meeting about cattle mutilations. Paul Bennewitz reported seeing unidentified lights over Kirtland Air Force Base. In May 1979, Valdez reported finding tranquilizers and anticoagulants in a mutilated bull. In June 1981, investigators found a mutilated cow at the Gomez ranch with radar chaff nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;later-incidents&#34;&gt;Later Incidents &lt;a href=&#34;#later-incidents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many cases of mutilation have been reported worldwide since 1967, chiefly in the Americas and Australia. In South America, an estimated 3,500 incidents have occurred since 2002.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1993, photographic evidence surfaced of a mutilated human corpse found near the Guarapiranga reservoir of São Paulo, Brazil, in 1988.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;characteristics&#34;&gt;Characteristics &lt;a href=&#34;#characteristics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unusual cattle deaths are characterized by the absence of sex organs, udders, tongues, anus, rectum, and sometimes ears or eyes. Cuts are described as &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;surgical.&amp;rdquo; Some animals are reported to have been drained of blood with no sign of blood in the immediate area. Howard Burgess stated that nearly 90 percent of mutilated cattle are between four and five years old. Strange marks or imprints near the site have been found. In the &amp;ldquo;Snippy&amp;rdquo; case, there was an absence of tracks and several small holes were found seemingly &amp;ldquo;punched&amp;rdquo; in the ground. In Rio Arriba County, New Mexico, a &amp;ldquo;trail of suction cup-like impressions&amp;rdquo; was found leading from a mutilated cow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;laboratory-reports&#34;&gt;Laboratory Reports &lt;a href=&#34;#laboratory-reports&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laboratory reports on some mutilated animals have shown unusual levels of vitamins or minerals in tissue samples, and the presence of chemicals not normally found in animals. In a case documented by New Mexico police and the FBI involving a bull belonging to Manuel Gomez of Dulce, New Mexico, the animal displayed &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo; mutilation signs. The animal&amp;rsquo;s heart, bone, and muscle samples were sent to the Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, while liver samples were sent to private laboratories. The liver was found to be completely devoid of copper and to contain 4 times the normal level of zinc, potassium, and phosphorus. Blood samples were reported to be &amp;ldquo;light pink in color&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Did not clot after several days.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;helicopter-sightings&#34;&gt;Helicopter Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#helicopter-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On July 15, 1974, two unregistered helicopters were reported to have opened fire on Robert Smith Jr. in Honey Creek, Iowa. On August 20, 1974, the &lt;em&gt;Lincoln Journal Star&lt;/em&gt; reported that residents had seen unidentified helicopters shining spotlights into fields where mutilated cows were later found. By 1975, some ranchers formed armed vigilante groups. In 1976, two Cache County, Utah, police officers reportedly confronted men in an unmarked U.S. Army helicopter. On April 8, 1979, three police officers in Dulce, New Mexico, reported a mysterious aircraft resembling a U.S. military helicopter hovering around a site following a wave of alleged mutilation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;official-investigations&#34;&gt;Official Investigations &lt;a href=&#34;#official-investigations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New Mexico Livestock Board sought assistance from the Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory. Colorado Bureau of Investigation agents went undercover to investigate. Oklahoma convened a task force. Federal authorities launched a comprehensive investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bureau-of-alcohol-tobacco-and-firearms&#34;&gt;Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms &lt;a href=&#34;#bureau-of-alcohol-tobacco-and-firearms&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January 1975, the Minnesota field office of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms (ATF) launched an investigation headed by Agent Donald Flickinger, tasked with investigating possible connections between cults and cattle mutilation. Flickinger recorded unusual incidents and circumstantial evidence but found insufficient evidence of cult involvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;colorado-bureau-of-investigation&#34;&gt;Colorado Bureau of Investigation &lt;a href=&#34;#colorado-bureau-of-investigation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May 1975, the Colorado Bureau of Investigation opened an investigation under the leadership of Carl Whiteside. 19 animals underwent necropsies at Colorado State University but no conclusive results emerged. The US Bureau of Land Management was forced to ground all helicopters in Eastern Colorado. By December, the CBI had investigated 203 reports of cattle mutilations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-mexico-state-police&#34;&gt;New Mexico State Police &lt;a href=&#34;#new-mexico-state-police&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 13, 1976, the New Mexico State Police began an investigation headed by Officer Gabe Valdez with the assistance of Cattle Inspector Jim Dyad and Officer Howard Johnston of the New Mexico Department of Game and Fish. On the night of July 5, Burgess and Valdez screened the Gomez herd; five animals were found to have been marked with a chemical that fluoresced under ultraviolet light. On June 14, 1981, intact radar chaff was found near a mutilated cow on the Gomez ranch. This investigation reported finding evidence that some mutilated animals had been tranquilized and treated with an anti-coagulant prior to their mutilation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rommel-investigation&#34;&gt;Rommel Investigation &lt;a href=&#34;#rommel-investigation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning in May 1979, an investigation was funded by a grant from the Law Enforcement Assistance Administration and was headed by recently-retired FBI agent Kenneth Rommel. Rommel&amp;rsquo;s final report, released in June 1980, concluded that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle_mutilations&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle_mutilations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alienoid (2022 film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8384e2f45a9f/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8384e2f45a9f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alienoid-2022-film&#34;&gt;Alienoid (2022 film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alienoid-2022-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2022 South Korean science fiction action film directed by Choi Dong-hoon, starring Ryu Jun-yeol, Kim Woo-bin, and Kim Tae-ri. The film involves time travel between the Goryeo era and the present day, with the appearance of aliens. It was released in IMAX and 4DX formats. A sequel, &lt;em&gt;Alienoid: Return to the Future&lt;/em&gt;, was released in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot alternates between the modern day and the Goryeo era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prologue-1380-ad&#34;&gt;Prologue: 1380 A.D. &lt;a href=&#34;#prologue-1380-ad&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monk warriors fail to defeat an alien and its human host. Guard and Thunder, humanoid robots from the future, extract the alien. The dying host asks Guard to care for her baby, but Guard initially refuses due to non-interference policies. Thunder smuggles the infant back with them to the modern day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;timeline-1-2012-2022-ad&#34;&gt;Timeline 1: 2012-2022 A.D. &lt;a href=&#34;#timeline-1-2012-2022-ad&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guard raises the baby girl, Yi-an, without revealing his true identity. Yi-an becomes suspicious and discovers the truth about Guard, Thunder, and her origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yi-an finds her way to Jisan Hospital, the site of an incoming alien prisoner transport. Guard and Thunder explain alien imprisonment mechanics. A prisoner-aligned alien ship arrives, planning to awaken the Controller and release haava to transform Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere, awakening all alien prisoners and poisoning humanity. The pilot awakens the Controller and releases haava, devastating the city and awakening other prisoners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guard, Thunder, and Yi-an kill the alien pilot and prevent further haava release. Badly wounded, Yi-an travels back in time with the aliens, intending to strand them in the past. Guard is destroyed, Thunder sinks in a river, and the Controller is forced to abandon its host.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;timeline-2-1391-ad&#34;&gt;Timeline 2: 1391 A.D. &lt;a href=&#34;#timeline-2-1391-ad&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten years after Thunder crash-lands, a Taoist bounty hunter named Mureuk pursues the Divine Blade (Guard&amp;rsquo;s power source). Mureuk meets martial arts figures like the Monk Guru, the Dual Mages, and Dogturd. He also meets Yi-an (the &amp;ldquo;Girl Who Shoots Thunder&amp;rdquo;) and Suiter and Ja-jang, aliens from the future who have taken over a local cult. The Divine Blade and Thunder&amp;rsquo;s location are key to controlling the haava release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A chaotic battle ensues. Yi-an lures one alien away, while the other is defeated. Yi-an approaches Thunder&amp;rsquo;s location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monk Guru, the Dual Mages, and Dogturd were all near the initial alien crash and are potential hosts for the Controller. However, Mureuk, Monk Guru&amp;rsquo;s apprentice, rescued Yi-an and became the Controller&amp;rsquo;s new host, losing his memories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ryu Jun-yeol&lt;/strong&gt; as Mureuk, a Taoist bounty hunter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kim Woo-bin&lt;/strong&gt; as Guard and Thunder, supernatural beings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kim Tae-ri&lt;/strong&gt; as Yi-an, a woman who shoots thunder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So Ji-sub&lt;/strong&gt; as Moon Do-seok, a detective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yum Jung-ah&lt;/strong&gt; as Heug-seol, a mage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jo Woo-jin&lt;/strong&gt; as Cheong-woon, a mage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kim Eui-sung&lt;/strong&gt; as Ja-jang, a masked man.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lee Hanee&lt;/strong&gt; as Min Gae-in, a curious woman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shin Jung-geun&lt;/strong&gt; as Right King, a follower of Mureuk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lee Si-hoon&lt;/strong&gt; as Left King, a follower of Mureuk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ji Kun-woo&lt;/strong&gt; as Suiter, a man in a modern suit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kim Dae-myung&lt;/strong&gt; as the voice of Thunder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shim Dal-gi&lt;/strong&gt; as a bride replaced by Yi-an.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yoon Byung-hee&lt;/strong&gt; as a shaman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kim Ki-cheon&lt;/strong&gt; as Dogturd, a man who knows the location of the divine sword.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yoon Kyung-ho&lt;/strong&gt; as a patient at Jisan Hospital.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ok Ja-yeon&lt;/strong&gt; as a doctor at Jisan Hospital.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lee Seon-hee&lt;/strong&gt; as an inn owner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yoo Jae-myung&lt;/strong&gt; as Hyun-gam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kim Hae-sook&lt;/strong&gt; as an old woman in Goryeo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jeon Yeo-been&lt;/strong&gt; as Hong Eon-nyeon, a woman with an alien prisoner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Filming took place over 13 months, with both parts filmed simultaneously. Choi Dong-hoon spent two and a half years writing the script. Jang Young-gyu and Kim Tae-kyung were in charge of music and cinematography, respectively. Yoo Sang-seop and Ryu Seong-cheol served as martial arts directors. Ryu Seong-hee and Lee Ha-jun were the art directors. Dexter Studio handled the CG. Filming locations included Andong, North Gyeongsang Province. The production cost for both parts was estimated at 40 billion won.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alienoid&lt;/em&gt; was released on July 20, 2022, in South Korea in IMAX and 4DX formats by CJ E&amp;amp;M. Well Go USA acquired North American distribution rights. It was the closing film at the 21st New York Asian Film Festival and screened at the 26th Fantasia International Film Festival. It became available for streaming on Netflix from December 28, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received mixed reviews from South Korean critics, with some praising its unique worldview and others criticizing its confusing characters and lore. It was compared to Choi Dong-hoon&amp;rsquo;s previous film, &lt;em&gt;Jeon Woo-chi: The Taoist Wizard&lt;/em&gt;. The film was a box-office failure, requiring 7 million admissions to break even.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;sequel&#34;&gt;Sequel &lt;a href=&#34;#sequel&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alienoid: Return to the Future&lt;/em&gt; was released in January 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;accolades&#34;&gt;Accolades &lt;a href=&#34;#accolades&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received nominations for several awards, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baeksang Arts Awards: Yum Jung-ah nominated for Best Supporting Actress – Film&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue Dragon Film Awards: Nominated for Technical Award&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buil Film Awards: Yum Jung-ah nominated for Best Supporting Actress, also nominated for Best Music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chunsa Film Art Awards: Nominated for Technical Award (VFX)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Director&amp;rsquo;s Cut Awards: Choi Dong-hoon nominated for Best Director in film&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grand Bell Awards: Won Best Art Direction and Best Visual Effects, also nominated for Best Film Editing, Best Costume Design, and Best Music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alienoid&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alienoid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aliens Ate My Homework (2018 film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6d7845805a4a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 23:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6d7845805a4a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;aliens-ate-my-homework-2018-film&#34;&gt;Aliens Ate My Homework (2018 film) &lt;a href=&#34;#aliens-ate-my-homework-2018-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2018 American science fiction comedy film directed by Sean McNamara, based on the novel of the same name by Bruce Coville. The film features an ensemble cast including Jayden Greig, William Shatner, Dan Payne, and Alex Zahara. It premiered on Netflix on March 6, 2018, and was followed by a sequel, &lt;em&gt;Aliens Stole My Body&lt;/em&gt; (2020).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rod and his cousin Elspeth encounter a group of extraterrestrial lawmen, the Galactic Patrol, after a spaceship crashes through his window and lands on his homework. They must assist the aliens in stopping the plans of the interplanetary criminal BKR, who is disguised on Earth as Billy Becker, a school bully who torments Rod.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jayden Greig&lt;/strong&gt; as Rod Allbright&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;William Shatner&lt;/strong&gt; as the voice of Phil the Plant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dan Payne&lt;/strong&gt; as Grakker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tristan Risk&lt;/strong&gt; as Madame Pong&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alex Zahara&lt;/strong&gt; as Tar Gibbons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lauren McNamara&lt;/strong&gt; as Elspeth McMasters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ty Consiglio&lt;/strong&gt; as Billy Becker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kirsten Robek&lt;/strong&gt; as Gwen Allbright&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christian Convery&lt;/strong&gt; as Eric Allbright&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carmela Guizzo&lt;/strong&gt; as Linda Allbright&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christine Lee&lt;/strong&gt; as Ms. Maloney&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sean Quan&lt;/strong&gt; as Mickey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sandy Robson&lt;/strong&gt; as Art Allbright&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brad Proctor&lt;/strong&gt; as Phil the Plant puppeteer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jamie Swettenham&lt;/strong&gt; as Plink puppeteer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bruce Coville, the author of the original novel, appears as J. Carter, the principal of Rod&amp;rsquo;s school, &amp;ldquo;Coville Elementary.&amp;rdquo; He has a non-speaking role until a mid-credits scene where he reads his own book and narrates the fate of the villain, BKR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Universal Pictures Home Entertainment acquired distribution rights to the film in March 2018, releasing it on March 6, 2018. The film&amp;rsquo;s estimated domestic DVD sales reached $46,603.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A list of sources cited in the article, including news articles and database entries, providing verification for the information presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aliens Ate My Homework&lt;/em&gt; at IMDb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliens Ate My Homework on Instagram&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aliens Ate My Homework&amp;rdquo; at Rotten Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aliens_Ate_My_Homework_(2018_film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aliens_Ate_My_Homework_(2018_film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Parents Are Aliens</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_54e389674a99/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_54e389674a99/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-parents-are-aliens&#34;&gt;My Parents Are Aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#my-parents-are-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My Parents Are Aliens&lt;/em&gt; is a British children&amp;rsquo;s television sitcom created by Andy Watts and produced by Yorkshire Television/Granada Yorkshire. It aired on ITV from November 8, 1999, to December 18, 2006, spanning eight series. The show requires additional citations for verification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show centers on the lives of orphaned siblings Mel, Josh, and Lucy Barker, who are fostered by Brian and Sophie Johnson. The children discover that their new parents are aliens from the planet Valux who crash-landed on Earth. The house they live in is a morphed form of their spaceship. Brian and Sophie have limited knowledge of Earth customs, and the children help them navigate human life while keeping their alien identities secret. The show&amp;rsquo;s humor is surreal and subversive, appealing to both children and older viewers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series consists of 106 episodes across eight series. Series 1 has 6 episodes, Series 2 has 10 episodes, Series 3 has 10 episodes, Series 4 has 13 episodes, Series 5 has 13 episodes, Series 6 has 20 episodes, Series 7 has 20 episodes, and Series 8 has 14 episodes. The episodes aired between November 8, 1999, and December 18, 2006.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;characters&#34;&gt;Characters &lt;a href=&#34;#characters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;parents&#34;&gt;Parents &lt;a href=&#34;#parents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brian Johnson (Tony Gardner):&lt;/strong&gt; A Valuxian alien and the cause of the crash-landing. He is childlike, amoral, and ignorant of Earth culture but an excellent scientist. He has an allergy to ice cream that causes him to grow moose antlers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sophie Johnson (Barbara Durkin/Carla Mendonça):&lt;/strong&gt; Brian&amp;rsquo;s wife, also a Valuxian alien. She has more common sense than Brian but is still clueless. She can only morph when eating ice cream. Carla Mendonça replaced Barbara Durkin in the role after Sophie morphs into a new shape at the beginning of the third series and is unable to return to her previous form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;series-17-the-barkers&#34;&gt;Series 1–7: The Barkers &lt;a href=&#34;#series-17-the-barkers&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Melanie ‘Mel’ Barker (Danielle McCormack):&lt;/strong&gt; The oldest Barker sibling, a sarcastic teenager with a protective nature. She eventually moves to Canada on an exchange program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joshua ‘Josh’ Barker (Alex Kew):&lt;/strong&gt; The middle sibling, a devious and scheming boy who constantly invents scams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lucia ‘Lucy’ Barker (Charlotte Francis):&lt;/strong&gt; The youngest and most intelligent Barker, excelling in Maths and Science.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C.J. (Olisa Odele):&lt;/strong&gt; An orphan adopted into the family after discovering Brian and Sophie are aliens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harriet ‘Harry’ Barker (Stephanie Fearon):&lt;/strong&gt; Adopted after Mel leaves, similar to Mel in personality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-characters&#34;&gt;Other characters &lt;a href=&#34;#other-characters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pete Walker (Patrick Niknejad):&lt;/strong&gt; One of Josh&amp;rsquo;s friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frankie Perkins (Jordan Maxwell):&lt;/strong&gt; Another of Josh&amp;rsquo;s friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wendy Richardson (Isabella Melling):&lt;/strong&gt; Lucy&amp;rsquo;s friend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Terence ‘Trent’ Clements (Keith Warwick):&lt;/strong&gt; Mel&amp;rsquo;s friend and eventual boyfriend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr Graham Whiteside (Dan O&amp;rsquo;Brien):&lt;/strong&gt; A grumpy teacher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mrs Alison Hardman (Beatrice Kelley):&lt;/strong&gt; Another of Josh&amp;rsquo;s and Lucy&amp;rsquo;s teachers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poppy Manning (Kirsha Southward):&lt;/strong&gt; A rival to Josh and Lucy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tania Thomas (Zoe Thorne/Emily Fleeshman/Sasha Tilley):&lt;/strong&gt; The object of Josh&amp;rsquo;s affections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mikey (Chris Cornwell):&lt;/strong&gt; One of Josh&amp;rsquo;s friends in the first series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave Locket (Julian Triandafyllou):&lt;/strong&gt; A popular boy in school.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andy ‘the Freak’ (Danny Robinson):&lt;/strong&gt; A geeky boy in love with Mel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scott Taylor (Marco Williamson):&lt;/strong&gt; A popular boy who Mel had a date with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;series-8-the-bennetts&#34;&gt;Series 8: The Bennetts &lt;a href=&#34;#series-8-the-bennetts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jacqueline ‘Jaq’ Bennett (Jessica Woods):&lt;/strong&gt; The oldest of the new foster children.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dan Bennett (Daniel Feltham):&lt;/strong&gt; Becky&amp;rsquo;s twin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Becky Bennett (Katie Pearson):&lt;/strong&gt; Dan&amp;rsquo;s twin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eddie Bennett (Jake Young):&lt;/strong&gt; The youngest member of the family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show was filmed in Studio 4 at The Leeds Studios. A laugh track was added from series 4 onwards. The last episode of series 7 featured the original cast and concluded ongoing plots. Series 8 introduced a new family, the Bennetts, after Brian and Sophie&amp;rsquo;s memories were erased. ITV closed its in-house children&amp;rsquo;s production unit, ending the show after series 8. Nickelodeon purchased the rights to make an American version, but the pilot never entered production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;broadcast&#34;&gt;Broadcast &lt;a href=&#34;#broadcast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Series 1 to 7 was repeated regularly on CITV from the channel&amp;rsquo;s launch in 2006 up until late 2017, while series 8 repeats were discontinued by early 2010. Entertainment Rights Distribution handled worldwide distribution rights to the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;home-media&#34;&gt;Home media &lt;a href=&#34;#home-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A VHS release containing all six Series One episodes was released in 2000 by Video Collection International and Granada Media. A single-release DVD containing two episodes from Series 2 and four from Series 3 titled &lt;em&gt;The Best Of&lt;/em&gt; was released in 2006 by Right Entertainment/Universal Pictures Video UK. Right/Universal also released Series 1 and 2 in a box-set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;awards-and-nominations&#34;&gt;Awards and nominations &lt;a href=&#34;#awards-and-nominations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show won a Royal Television Society Award for Best Children&amp;rsquo;s Drama in 2000 and 2006. It was nominated for a Children&amp;rsquo;s BAFTA Award for Best Drama in 2001, 2003, and 2004. It also won Best Children&amp;rsquo;s Program at the Banff Television Festival and Best Children&amp;rsquo;s Fiction in 2002.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Parents_Are_Aliens&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Parents_Are_Aliens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of alien races in DC Comics</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_4454114f2841/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 23:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_4454114f2841/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alien-races-in-dc-comics&#34;&gt;List of Alien Races in DC Comics &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alien-races-in-dc-comics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Wikipedia article provides a comprehensive list of fictional extraterrestrial races that have appeared in DC Comics publications and related media. It includes brief descriptions and citations for each race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents &lt;a href=&#34;#contents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the alphabetical index of alien races covered in the article, from 0-9 to Z, along with links to &amp;ldquo;See also,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;References,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;External links&amp;rdquo; sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces the concept of the vast number of extraterrestrial races in the DC Comics universe, noting that the majority are humanoid in structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;united-planets&#34;&gt;United Planets &lt;a href=&#34;#united-planets&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the United Planets, a governing body active from the 21st to the 31st centuries. It mentions known members like planets of the Solar System, Htrae, buffer planets seeded by Mon-El, and neighboring empires. It also notes that in the 21st century, the United Planets are led by the corrupt Durlan Thaaros. The section is marked as needing expansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;0-9&#34;&gt;0-9 &lt;a href=&#34;#0-9&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists alien races whose names begin with numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5th-dimensional-imps&#34;&gt;5th Dimensional Imps &lt;a href=&#34;#5th-dimensional-imps&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the 5th Dimensional Imps from the planet Zrfff, including notable characters like Mister Mxyzptlk, Miss Gsptlsnz, Vyndktvx, Bat-Mite, and Zook. It also mentions their appearances in other media, such as the &lt;em&gt;Supergirl&lt;/em&gt; TV series, where Mxyzptlk and Nyxlygsptlnz appear, and a &lt;em&gt;Supergirl&lt;/em&gt; crossover with &lt;em&gt;The Flash&lt;/em&gt;, where the Music Meister is revealed to be an imp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a&#34;&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;#a&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists alien races whose names begin with the letter &amp;ldquo;A.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;adaptoids&#34;&gt;Adaptoids &lt;a href=&#34;#adaptoids&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the Adaptoids, blob-like creatures from the vicinity of Arcturus who attempted to wipe out the human race on Earth-One. They were defeated by the Justice League when exposed to the Thanagarian equalizing disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aellans&#34;&gt;Aellans &lt;a href=&#34;#aellans&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the Aellans, yellow-skinned reptilian humanoids from Aello, Demonia, and Harpis. Harpis and Doc of Aello were members of the Omega Men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-invaders&#34;&gt;Alien Invaders &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-invaders&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section identifies the Alien Invaders as the nameless primary antagonists of &lt;em&gt;Armageddon: The Alien Agenda&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;almeraci&#34;&gt;Almeraci &lt;a href=&#34;#almeraci&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the Almeraci, a humanoid race of technologically advanced warriors with psionic abilities, ruled by the matriarchal House of the Blood Royale. Key figures include Maxima, Queen of Almerac, her handmaiden Sazu, and Ultraa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aloi&#34;&gt;Aloi &lt;a href=&#34;#aloi&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the Aloi, blue-skinned aliens with ridged foreheads at war with the Margoi over a device called the &amp;ldquo;Grayl.&amp;rdquo; Tumlat represents them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alstairans&#34;&gt;Alstairans &lt;a href=&#34;#alstairans&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the Alstairans of Alstair, plantlike humanoids with leaves instead of hair, constantly at war with other races in the Antares system. Their ruler is Hyathis, an alien plant elemental.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;anasazi&#34;&gt;Anasazi &lt;a href=&#34;#anasazi&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section identifies the Anasazi as metahumans resettled to the planet Starhaven, represented by Dawnstar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;andromedans&#34;&gt;Andromedans &lt;a href=&#34;#andromedans&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the Andromedans of the Andromeda Galaxy, a race of superhumans similar to Kryptonians and Daxamites, with red hair, albino skin, and blue eyes. Karb-Brak, an Andromedan exiled to Earth, is mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;angtuans&#34;&gt;Angtuans &lt;a href=&#34;#angtuans&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the Angtuans, inhabitants of the planet Angtu, which was destroyed by the mutated Mano in the 30th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;anunnake&#34;&gt;Anunnake &lt;a href=&#34;#anunnake&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section identifies the Anunnake as reptilian aliens who claim to have killed off the dinosaurs, also known as the Hunter/Gatherers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;anndrann&#34;&gt;Anndrann &lt;a href=&#34;#anndrann&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the Anndrann, green-skinned military geniuses from Anndranna, famed for their weapons of war. Iron has a negative effect on their cognitive abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;appellaxians&#34;&gt;Appellaxians &lt;a href=&#34;#appellaxians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the Appellaxians of Appellax, technologically advanced energy aliens with the ability to create powerful artificial host bodies. The seven Appellaxians that invaded created bodies named Golden Roc, Wood King, Stone-God, Crystal Creature, Fire-Lord, Glass-Man, and Mercury Monster. Their invasion led to the formation of the Justice League. The section also mentions their appearance in &lt;em&gt;Young Justice&lt;/em&gt;, where Bruno Mannheim combines them into a Golem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aipitons&#34;&gt;Aipitons &lt;a href=&#34;#aipitons&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section identifies the Aipitons as small flying insects from the planet Apaiton, represented by the deceased Green Lantern Bzzd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aquoids&#34;&gt;Aquoids &lt;a href=&#34;#aquoids&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section identifies the Aquoids as natives of planet Beltair IV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aranes&#34;&gt;Aranes &lt;a href=&#34;#aranes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the Aranes of Arane II, light blue-skinned humanoids with tiny blue horns. Rolind Siepur of Arane II is a member of the Dark Circle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ardenans&#34;&gt;Ardenans &lt;a href=&#34;#ardenans&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section identifies the Ardenans as orange scaly-skinned humanoids from the planet Arden, represented by the deceased Green Lanterns Lodar and Meeno Monak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;astonians&#34;&gt;Astonians &lt;a href=&#34;#astonians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the Astonians, a minor alien race saved from extinction by the Blue Lantern Saint Walker, who is of this race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;azarathians&#34;&gt;Azarathians &lt;a href=&#34;#azarathians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section identifies the Azarathians as people belonging to the parallel universe of Azarath. Raven is an Azarathian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;b&#34;&gt;B &lt;a href=&#34;#b&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists alien races whose names begin with the letter &amp;ldquo;B.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;barrions&#34;&gt;Barrions &lt;a href=&#34;#barrions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the Barrions of Barrio III, silicon-based lifeforms represented by the Green Lantern Chaselon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bellatrix-bombers&#34;&gt;Bellatrix Bombers &lt;a href=&#34;#bellatrix-bombers&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section identifies the Bellatrix Bombers as alien warlords featured in &lt;em&gt;Green Lantern&lt;/em&gt; (vol. 3) #20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bgztlians&#34;&gt;Bgztlians &lt;a href=&#34;#bgztlians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the Bgztlians, humans from the colony Bgztl who possess the metahuman ability of intangibility. Phantom Girl of the Legion of Super-Heroes represents them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;blight&#34;&gt;Blight &lt;a href=&#34;#blight&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the Blight, a cybernetic race with rotting flesh, villains of the &lt;em&gt;Legion of Super-Heroes&lt;/em&gt;. Their leader is Atrophos, who sought immortality from M&amp;rsquo;onel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bloodline-parasites&#34;&gt;Bloodline Parasites &lt;a href=&#34;#bloodline-parasites&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the Bloodline Parasites, extraterrestrial lifeforms capable of activating the human metagene while feeding on spinal fluid. They have exoskeletons, strength, and the ability to duplicate human form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;braalians&#34;&gt;Braalians &lt;a href=&#34;#braalians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the Braalians, humans from the colony Braal who possess the metahuman ability of electromagnetic field manipulation. Cosmic Boy and Magno of the Legion of Super-Heroes represent them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;brain-parasites-of-planet-x&#34;&gt;Brain-Parasites of Planet X &lt;a href=&#34;#brain-parasites-of-planet-x&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the Brain-Parasites of Planet X, who steal knowledge from other races using Knowledge-Extractors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;branx&#34;&gt;Branx &lt;a href=&#34;#branx&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the Branx of Emana Branx, gray-skinned, four-armed warriors who serve the Citadelians. They are native to the Vega star system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;brylyx&#34;&gt;Brylyx &lt;a href=&#34;#brylyx&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section identifies the Brylyx as white-skinned aliens featured in &lt;em&gt;Green Lantern: Mosaic&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-bolovax-vikians&#34;&gt;The Bolovax Vikians &lt;a href=&#34;#the-bolovax-vikians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the Bolovax Vikians, a highly communal and technologically advanced race. Kilowog of the Green Lantern Corps is the last surviving member. The section also mentions a holographic Bolovax Vikian appearing in &lt;em&gt;My Adventures with Superman&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bugs-of-new-genesis&#34;&gt;Bugs of New Genesis &lt;a href=&#34;#bugs-of-new-genesis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the Bugs of New Genesis, an insectoid race spread on New Genesis during their war with Apokolips. Forager and Mantis are prominent members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;c&#34;&gt;C &lt;a href=&#34;#c&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists alien races whose names begin with the letter &amp;ldquo;C.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cairnians&#34;&gt;Cairnians &lt;a href=&#34;#cairnians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section identifies the Cairnians as members of L.E.G.I.O.N.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;calatonians&#34;&gt;Calatonians &lt;a href=&#34;#calatonians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the Calatonians, an ancient monarchy on the planet Calaton ravaged by Doomsday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;canopians&#34;&gt;Canopians &lt;a href=&#34;#canopians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section identifies the Canopians as members of Atari Force. Canopians such as Morphea are from New Earth in a parallel universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;carggites&#34;&gt;Carggites &lt;a href=&#34;#carggites&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the Carggites, humans from the colony Cargg who possess the metahuman ability of duplication. Triplicate Girl of the Legion of Super-Heroes represents them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;catherix&#34;&gt;Catherix &lt;a href=&#34;#catherix&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the Cathexis, alien super-scientists from the &amp;ldquo;sixth dimension&amp;rdquo; who created self-aware reality-endangering technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;changralynians&#34;&gt;Changralynians &lt;a href=&#34;#changralynians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the Changralynians of Changralyn, silicon-based pacifists represented by Broot of the Omega Men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chietain&#34;&gt;Chietain &lt;a href=&#34;#chietain&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is marked as needing expansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;children-of-tanjent&#34;&gt;Children of Tanjent &lt;a href=&#34;#children-of-tanjent&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section identifies the Children of Tanjent as a psionic race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;circadians&#34;&gt;Circadians &lt;a href=&#34;#circadians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the peaceful insectoid Circadians of Circadia, who established a joint human/Circadian settlement known as Pax Colony. Circadia Senius is a Chronarch Research Fellow and friend of Brainiac 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chthalonians&#34;&gt;Chthalonians &lt;a href=&#34;#chthalonians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is marked as needing expansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;citadelians&#34;&gt;Citadelians &lt;a href=&#34;#citadelians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the Citadelians of the Citadel, sadistic imperialistic clones whose intellect degrades with each generation. They use Gordanians and Branx Warriors as enforcers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;clementians&#34;&gt;Clementians &lt;a href=&#34;#clementians&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parademon&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parademon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien Nation</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_eed570f8ae8c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 03:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_eed570f8ae8c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-nation&#34;&gt;Alien Nation &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-nation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A science fiction police procedural television series that aired on Fox from 1989 to 1990. It&amp;rsquo;s based on the 1988 film &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series is set in the near future, beginning in 1990, after a flying saucer crashes in the Mojave Desert. The ship contains the Tenctonese, a race of extraterrestrials escaping slavery. They are accepted as immigrants to the US, and the series explores their integration into American society. Storylines often address themes of racism and bigotry, using the Newcomers as a stand-in for discriminated minorities. The series uses social commentary to illustrate what it means to be human and the often bizarre rituals we observe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detective Matthew &amp;ldquo;Matt&amp;rdquo; Sikes:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Gary Graham, a human detective partnered with George Francisco.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detective George Francisco:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Eric Pierpoint, a Newcomer detective partnered with Matthew Sikes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Susan Francisco:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Michele Scarabelli, George&amp;rsquo;s wife, a Newcomer advertising businesswoman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emily Francisco:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Lauren Woodland, George and Susan&amp;rsquo;s young daughter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buck Francisco:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Sean Six, George and Susan&amp;rsquo;s initially delinquent teenage son.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cathy Frankel:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Terri Treas, Matt&amp;rsquo;s Newcomer neighbor and on-off girlfriend, a bio-chemist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Albert Einstein:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Jeff Marcus, a timid Newcomer janitor working at the police department.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cpt. Bryon Grazer:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Ron Fassler, Matt and George&amp;rsquo;s human superior officer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beatrice Zepeda:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Jenny Gago, a human detective in Matt and George&amp;rsquo;s squad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Burns:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Jeff Doucette, a human photographer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sergeant Dobbs:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Lawrence Hilton-Jacobs, a human police officer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jill:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by Molly Morgan, a human girl and Emily&amp;rsquo;s friend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uncle Moodri:&lt;/strong&gt; Played by James Greene, an eccentric but wise Newcomer and member of the Francisco family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenneth Johnson, responsible for other science-fiction television series, was approached for the television adaptation of the 1988 film &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt;. He initially had no interest in the project but was later inspired to create a series focusing on social commentary about the integration of a new minority group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;changes-from-the-film&#34;&gt;Changes from the film &lt;a href=&#34;#changes-from-the-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several changes were made from the original film. The human detective Matthew Sykes was played by James Caan in the film, but Gary Graham in the TV series. Detective George Francisco was played by Mandy Patinkin in the film, but Eric Pierpoint in the TV series. The TV series explores Newcomer culture more deeply than the film. Francisco&amp;rsquo;s family also differs, with a daughter, Emily, added to the TV series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cancellation&#34;&gt;Cancellation &lt;a href=&#34;#cancellation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series ran for one season on Fox. Despite building a strong fan base, the show was cancelled due to the network&amp;rsquo;s financial difficulties. The season ended on a cliffhanger, and popular demand led to the unproduced second season premiere being adapted as a novel and comic book. Years later, Fox produced five television films to continue the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series consists of 22 episodes, each dealing with the integration of the Newcomers into human society and the challenges they face. The episodes often involve police procedural elements, with Sikes and Francisco investigating crimes involving both humans and Newcomers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;television-films&#34;&gt;Television films &lt;a href=&#34;#television-films&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five television films continued the story after the series&amp;rsquo; cancellation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation: Dark Horizon&lt;/em&gt; (1994)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation: Body and Soul&lt;/em&gt; (1995)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation: Millennium&lt;/em&gt; (1996)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation: The Enemy Within&lt;/em&gt; (1996)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation: The Udara Legacy&lt;/em&gt; (1997)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;home-media&#34;&gt;Home media &lt;a href=&#34;#home-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complete series was released on DVD by 20th Century Fox in 2006. The five television films were later released as a collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;revival&#34;&gt;Revival &lt;a href=&#34;#revival&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2009, Syfy announced a new take on the series with Tim Minear writing. However, the series was later cancelled. In 2015, a remake was reported to be in the works with Art Marcum and Matt Holloway writing the script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Nation_(TV_series)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Nation_(TV_series)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien TV (2019 TV series)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f9ec66618d5e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f9ec66618d5e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-tv-2019-tv-series&#34;&gt;Alien TV (2019 TV series) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-tv-2019-tv-series&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien TV&lt;/em&gt; is a live-action/CG animation television series that premiered on 9Go! in Australia on November 23, 2019, and on Netflix. The show was created by Ian Brown and developed by Doug Hadders and Adam Rotstein. The series follows a television news crew of extraterrestrials named Ixbee, Pixbee, and Squee, who are sent to Earth to learn about the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main voice cast includes Rob Tinkler as Ixbee, Julie Lemieux as Pixbee, John Cleland as Squee, Kyle Dooley as Squood, and Rupert Degas as the Translator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series consists of two seasons. Season 1 was released on August 21, 2020, and Season 2 was released on March 19, 2021. There are no plans for a season 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;series-overview&#34;&gt;Series Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#series-overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series is divided into two seasons, with 13 episodes each. Season 1 was released in 2020, and Season 2 in 2021. Each episode contains three segments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-1-2020&#34;&gt;Season 1 (2020) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-1-2020&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season 1 consists of 13 episodes, each containing three segments. Each segment focuses on the aliens&amp;rsquo; experiences with different aspects of Earth culture and activities, such as bicycles, gymnastics, camping, playgrounds, art, gum, gyms, birthdays, restaurants, BBQs, offices, Halloween, pizza, magic, cleaning, arcades, dumplings, presents, junkyards, spas, love, movies, kindergarten, sickness, babies, supermarkets, tea, weddings, Loch Ness, soccer, skateboards, mannequins, survival, toyshops, laundromats, yoga, Santa, trophies, and makeup. Each segment is directed by Ian Brown and written by various writers, including Doug Hadders, Adam Rotstein, Jeff Sager, Brian Hartigan, Shawn Kalb, Cleon Prineas, Laurie Elliott, Bruce Griffiths, Simon Dodd, Jennifer Daley, Thomas Duncan-Watt and Naomi Jardine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;season-2-2021&#34;&gt;Season 2 (2021) &lt;a href=&#34;#season-2-2021&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season 2 also consists of 13 episodes, each containing three segments. The segments continue to explore the aliens&amp;rsquo; interactions with Earth, featuring topics such as trains, barbershops, gnomes, florists, fashion, teeth, pools, dinner parties, skiing, joke shops, the Outback, fire halls, baby showers, yard sales, aquariums, dance, international games, shopping, school, holidays, lucha libre, cars, sleep, golf, airplanes, water parks, mail, music, bowling, gardening, museums, Bollywood, castles, ballet, energy, leprechauns, glasses, trials, and scary things. Ian Brown directs all segments, and the writing credits include Naomi Jardine, Jerome Simpson, Bruce Griffiths, Jennifer Daley, Jeff Sager, Kyle Dooley, Simon Dodd, Cleon Prineas, Brian Hartigan, and Gina Roncoli Bruce Griffiths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_TV&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_TV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien Raiders (2008 Film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_502036f64f2e/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 01:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_502036f64f2e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-raiders-2008-film&#34;&gt;Alien Raiders (2008 Film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-raiders-2008-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article provides information about the 2008 American science fiction horror film, &lt;em&gt;Alien Raiders&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot centers around a group of armed individuals who take hostages in a grocery store, claiming to hunt alien parasites. The group, led by Ritter, seeks to eliminate the parasites, which arrived on Earth via a meteorite, by identifying and killing infected individuals. They use a gruesome method of cutting off fingers to test for infection. A police officer, Seth, whose stepdaughter works at the store, becomes involved and tries to negotiate with Ritter. The situation escalates with deaths, revelations about the parasites&amp;rsquo; hierarchy (females and a king), and the introduction of Charlotte, a former member of Ritter&amp;rsquo;s group with the ability to identify the infected. The climax involves the discovery that the &amp;ldquo;king&amp;rdquo; parasite is hosted by Seth&amp;rsquo;s stepdaughter, Whitney.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film stars Carlos Bernard as Aaron Ritter, Mathew St. Patrick as Seth Steadman, and Rockmond Dunbar as Kane. Other notable cast members include Courtney Ford as Sterling, Jeffrey Licon as Benny, and Samantha Streets as Whitney. Bonita Friedericy plays Charlotte. The cast list provides a comprehensive overview of the actors and the characters they portray in the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Raiders&lt;/em&gt; premiered at Fantastic Fest on September 21, 2008, and was subsequently released directly to DVD by Warner Home Video under the Raw Feed label in September 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received positive reviews, holding a 100% approval rating on Rotten Tomatoes based on six reviews. Critics praised the unexpectedly high quality of the effects and acting, especially considering its low-budget horror film status. The title of the film was criticized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources used to compile the information presented in the article. These include links to Screen Rant, Rotten Tomatoes, and Dread Central.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The external links section provides links to the film&amp;rsquo;s official website, its IMDb page, and its Rotten Tomatoes page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Raiders&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Raiders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of songs about close encounters with aliens</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_48e3eeb2bb26/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 19:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_48e3eeb2bb26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-songs-about-close-encounters-with-aliens&#34;&gt;List of Songs About Close Encounters with Aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-songs-about-close-encounters-with-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a compilation of songs across various decades that explore lyrical themes related to close encounters with extraterrestrial aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1940s&#34;&gt;1940s &lt;a href=&#34;#1940s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights the earliest example on the list, &amp;ldquo;(When You See) Those Flying Saucers&amp;rdquo; by The Buchanan Brothers, released in July 1947. Its release coincided with the beginning of the flying saucer era, shortly after the Kenneth Arnold UFO sighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1950s&#34;&gt;1950s &lt;a href=&#34;#1950s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists songs from the 1950s that deal with the theme of flying saucers and aliens. Key songs include &amp;ldquo;The Flying Saucer Parts 1 &amp;amp; 2&amp;rdquo; by Bill Buchanan and Dickie Goodman, &amp;ldquo;My Flying Saucer&amp;rdquo; by Woodie Guthrie, &amp;ldquo;The Purple People Eater&amp;rdquo; by Sheb Wooley, &amp;ldquo;Two Little Men In A Flying Saucer&amp;rdquo; by Ella Fitzgerald, and &amp;ldquo;Flyin&amp;rsquo; Saucers Rock &amp;amp; Roll&amp;rdquo; by Billy Lee Riley and Jerry Lee Lewis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1960s&#34;&gt;1960s &lt;a href=&#34;#1960s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section includes songs from the 1960s that explore themes of space and extraterrestrial encounters. Notable songs include &amp;ldquo;Let There Be More Light&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Set the Controls for the Heart of the Sun&amp;rdquo; by Pink Floyd, &amp;ldquo;Mr. Spaceman&amp;rdquo; by The Byrds, &amp;ldquo;Voices Green and Purple&amp;rdquo; by The Bees, &amp;ldquo;It Came Out of the Sky&amp;rdquo; by Creedence Clearwater Revival, &amp;ldquo;Have You Seen the Saucers&amp;rdquo; by Jefferson Airplane, and &amp;ldquo;U.F.O.&amp;rdquo; by Jim Sullivan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1970s&#34;&gt;1970s &lt;a href=&#34;#1970s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists songs from the 1970s that deal with the theme of alien encounters. Key songs include &amp;ldquo;After the Gold Rush&amp;rdquo; by Neil Young, &amp;ldquo;Calling Occupants of Interplanetary Craft&amp;rdquo; by Klaatu (covered by The Carpenters), &amp;ldquo;Childhood&amp;rsquo;s End&amp;rdquo; by Pink Floyd, &amp;ldquo;Come Sail Away&amp;rdquo; by Styx, &amp;ldquo;Here Come the Martian Martians&amp;rdquo; by Jonathan Richman and the Modern Lovers, &amp;ldquo;Horsell Commons and the Heat Ray&amp;rdquo; by Jeff Wayne, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve Seen the Saucers&amp;rdquo; by Elton John, &amp;ldquo;Longer Boats&amp;rdquo; by Cat Stevens, &amp;ldquo;Martian Boogie&amp;rdquo; by Brownsville Station, &amp;ldquo;Mothership Connection&amp;rdquo; by Parliament, &amp;ldquo;Starman&amp;rdquo; by David Bowie, &amp;ldquo;Starship Trooper&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Arriving UFO&amp;rdquo; by Yes, &amp;ldquo;Waiting for the UFOs&amp;rdquo; by Graham Parker, &amp;ldquo;Silver Lights&amp;rdquo; by Sammy Hagar, &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; by Johnny Rivers, &amp;ldquo;Children of the Sun&amp;rdquo; by Billy Thorpe, &amp;ldquo;Starrider&amp;rdquo; by Foreigner, &amp;ldquo;Strange Ships&amp;rdquo; by Fox, and &amp;ldquo;Ships in the Sky&amp;rdquo; by Wishbone Ash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1980s&#34;&gt;1980s &lt;a href=&#34;#1980s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section includes songs from the 1980s that explore themes of UFOs and aliens. Notable songs include &amp;ldquo;Fire Of Unknown Origin&amp;rdquo; by Blue Öyster Cult, &amp;ldquo;Books about UFOs&amp;rdquo; by Hüsker Dü, &amp;ldquo;Flying Saucers&amp;rdquo; by Nina Hagen, &amp;ldquo;Love Walks In&amp;rdquo; by Van Halen, &amp;ldquo;Loving the Alien&amp;rdquo; by David Bowie, &amp;ldquo;No Doubt About It&amp;rdquo; by Hot Chocolate, &amp;ldquo;Nobody Told Me&amp;rdquo; by John Lennon, &amp;ldquo;Rapture&amp;rdquo; by Blondie, &amp;ldquo;Zero Zero UFO&amp;rdquo; by The Ramones, &amp;ldquo;I Ran (So Far Away)&amp;rdquo; by A Flock of Seagulls, &amp;ldquo;Caught in the Crossfire&amp;rdquo; by April Wine, and &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t Be Late&amp;rdquo; by Saga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1990s&#34;&gt;1990s &lt;a href=&#34;#1990s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists songs from the 1990s that deal with the theme of alien encounters. Key songs include &amp;ldquo;The Alien Song (For Those Who Listen)&amp;rdquo; by Mila Jovovich, &amp;ldquo;El Aparato (&amp;ldquo;The Apparatus&amp;rdquo;)&amp;rdquo; by Café Tacvba, &amp;ldquo;Alien (I Am)&amp;rdquo; by Hawkwind, &amp;ldquo;Aliens Exist&amp;rdquo; by Blink-182, &amp;ldquo;Alien Visitors&amp;rdquo; by Man or Astro-man?, &amp;ldquo;Another Sunday&amp;rdquo; by I Mother Earth, &amp;ldquo;Fell in Love with an Alien&amp;rdquo; by the Kelly Family, &amp;ldquo;Hangar 18&amp;rdquo; by Megadeth, &amp;ldquo;Hat Too Flat&amp;rdquo; by Walter Becker, &amp;ldquo;I Made Love to a Martian&amp;rdquo; by Mustard Plug, &amp;ldquo;Girl from Mars&amp;rdquo; by Ash, &amp;ldquo;Martian Dance Invasion&amp;rdquo; by Brainiac, &amp;ldquo;Motorway to Roswell&amp;rdquo; by Pixies, &amp;ldquo;Scent of a Mule&amp;rdquo; by Phish, &amp;ldquo;Shades of Grey&amp;rdquo; by Stuart Davis, &amp;ldquo;Spaceman&amp;rdquo; by Babylon Zoo, &amp;ldquo;Subterranean Homesick Alien&amp;rdquo; by Radiohead, &amp;ldquo;The Happening&amp;rdquo; by Pixies, &amp;ldquo;Who&amp;rsquo;s There?&amp;rdquo; by Smash Mouth, &amp;ldquo;Spaceman&amp;rdquo; by Bif Naked, &amp;ldquo;Is That You Mo-Dean?&amp;rdquo; by The B-52s, &amp;ldquo;Men in Black&amp;rdquo; by Will Smith, and &amp;ldquo;Calgone&amp;rdquo; by Incubus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2000s-to-present&#34;&gt;2000s to present &lt;a href=&#34;#2000s-to-present&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section includes songs from the 2000s to the present that explore themes of UFOs and aliens. Notable songs include &amp;ldquo;Fracture&amp;rdquo; by Edison&amp;rsquo;s Children, &amp;ldquo;The Aliens Are Here&amp;rdquo; by The Hippos, &amp;ldquo;And You Thought the Doctor&amp;rsquo;s Probe Hurt&amp;rdquo; by Belvedere, &amp;ldquo;Jaadoo, Jaadoo&amp;rdquo; by Rajesh Roshan, &amp;ldquo;Concerning the UFO sighting near Highland, Illinois&amp;rdquo; by Sufjan Stevens, &amp;ldquo;Aliens&amp;rdquo; by Doctor Octagon, &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; by Sneaky Sound System, &amp;ldquo;Rosetta Stoned&amp;rdquo; by Tool, &amp;ldquo;Fallout of the 4th Kind&amp;rdquo; by Edison&amp;rsquo;s Children, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re Not Alone&amp;rdquo; by Nas, &amp;ldquo;Spaceman&amp;rdquo; by The Killers, &amp;ldquo;Venus Ambassador&amp;rdquo; by Bryan Scary &amp;amp; The Shredding Tears, &amp;ldquo;E.T.&amp;rdquo; by Katy Perry, &amp;ldquo;Zopilotes&amp;rdquo; by Café Tacuba, &amp;ldquo;A Million Miles Away (I Wish I Had A Time Machine)&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;The Awakening&amp;rdquo; by Edison&amp;rsquo;s Children, &amp;ldquo;Ancient Aliens&amp;rdquo; by Lemon Demon, &amp;ldquo;Decks Dark&amp;rdquo; by Radiohead, &amp;ldquo;Hey Aliens&amp;rdquo; by The Bouncing Souls, &amp;ldquo;Spaceship&amp;rdquo; by Kesha, &amp;ldquo;Herd Culling&amp;rdquo; by Porcupine Tree, &amp;ldquo;Silver Circles&amp;rdquo; by Upchurch, &amp;ldquo;End of the World&amp;rdquo; by Tom MacDonald, &amp;ldquo;Staring at the Stars&amp;rdquo; by Dan Marfisi and Glenn Jordan, &amp;ldquo;An Alien Abduction Story (The Probing)&amp;rdquo; by The Schnooks, and &amp;ldquo;Down Bad&amp;rdquo; by Taylor Swift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes &lt;a href=&#34;#notes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a note indicating that certain songs are used as bumper music on the &lt;em&gt;StarTalk&lt;/em&gt; UFO episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the various sources used to compile the list of songs, including articles from publications like &lt;em&gt;Cultural and Social History&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The A.V. Club&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Huffington Post&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;NPR&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Salon.com&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Cambridge University Press&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Citadel Press&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;YouTube&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;WKXW&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Chrome Dreams&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;tor.com&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;chorus.fm&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;loudersound.com&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;setlist.fm&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Global News&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Apple Music&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;SoundCloud&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a reference to a book for further reading on the topic of alien rock and the extraterrestrial connection in rock &amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo; roll. The book is &amp;ldquo;Alien Rock: The Rock &amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo; Roll Extraterrestrial Connection&amp;rdquo; by M. Luckman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_songs_about_close_encounters_with_aliens&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_songs_about_close_encounters_with_aliens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of songs about close encounters with aliens</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a6f27fcf591b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 19:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a6f27fcf591b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-songs-about-close-encounters-with-aliens&#34;&gt;List of Songs About Close Encounters with Aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-songs-about-close-encounters-with-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a compilation of songs across various decades that explore lyrical themes related to close encounters with extraterrestrial aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1940s&#34;&gt;1940s &lt;a href=&#34;#1940s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights the earliest example on the list, &amp;ldquo;(When You See) Those Flying Saucers&amp;rdquo; by The Buchanan Brothers, released in July 1947. Its release coincided with the beginning of the flying saucer era, shortly after the Kenneth Arnold UFO sighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1950s&#34;&gt;1950s &lt;a href=&#34;#1950s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1950s saw a surge in songs about flying saucers and aliens. Notable entries include &amp;ldquo;The Flying Saucer Parts 1 &amp;amp; 2&amp;rdquo; by Bill Buchanan and Dickie Goodman, &amp;ldquo;My Flying Saucer&amp;rdquo; with lyrics by Woodie Guthrie, &amp;ldquo;The Purple People Eater&amp;rdquo; by Sheb Wooley, &amp;ldquo;Two Little Men In A Flying Saucer&amp;rdquo; by Ella Fitzgerald, and &amp;ldquo;Flyin&amp;rsquo; Saucers Rock &amp;amp; Roll&amp;rdquo; by Billy Lee Riley and Jerry Lee Lewis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1960s&#34;&gt;1960s &lt;a href=&#34;#1960s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists songs from the 1960s that touch on extraterrestrial themes. Key songs include &amp;ldquo;Let There Be More Light&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Set the Controls for the Heart of the Sun&amp;rdquo; by Pink Floyd, &amp;ldquo;Mr. Spaceman&amp;rdquo; by The Byrds, &amp;ldquo;Voices Green and Purple&amp;rdquo; by The Bees, &amp;ldquo;It Came Out of the Sky&amp;rdquo; by Creedence Clearwater Revival, &amp;ldquo;Have You Seen the Saucers&amp;rdquo; by Jefferson Airplane, and &amp;ldquo;U.F.O.&amp;rdquo; by Jim Sullivan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1970s&#34;&gt;1970s &lt;a href=&#34;#1970s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1970s brought a diverse range of songs exploring alien encounters. Highlights include &amp;ldquo;After the Gold Rush&amp;rdquo; by Neil Young, &amp;ldquo;Calling Occupants of Interplanetary Craft&amp;rdquo; by Klaatu (covered by The Carpenters), &amp;ldquo;Childhood&amp;rsquo;s End&amp;rdquo; by Pink Floyd, &amp;ldquo;Come Sail Away&amp;rdquo; by Styx, &amp;ldquo;Here Come the Martian Martians&amp;rdquo; by Jonathan Richman and the Modern Lovers, &amp;ldquo;Horsell Commons and the Heat Ray&amp;rdquo; by Jeff Wayne, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve Seen the Saucers&amp;rdquo; by Elton John, &amp;ldquo;Longer Boats&amp;rdquo; by Cat Stevens, &amp;ldquo;Martian Boogie&amp;rdquo; by Brownsville Station, &amp;ldquo;Mothership Connection&amp;rdquo; by Parliament, &amp;ldquo;Starman&amp;rdquo; by David Bowie, &amp;ldquo;Starship Trooper&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Arriving UFO&amp;rdquo; by Yes, &amp;ldquo;Waiting for the UFOs&amp;rdquo; by Graham Parker, &amp;ldquo;Silver Lights&amp;rdquo; by Sammy Hagar, &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; by Johnny Rivers, &amp;ldquo;Children of the Sun&amp;rdquo; by Billy Thorpe, &amp;ldquo;Starrider&amp;rdquo; by Foreigner, &amp;ldquo;Strange Ships&amp;rdquo; by Fox, and &amp;ldquo;Ships in the Sky&amp;rdquo; by Wishbone Ash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1980s&#34;&gt;1980s &lt;a href=&#34;#1980s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers songs from the 1980s with alien or UFO themes. Noteworthy songs include &amp;ldquo;Fire Of Unknown Origin&amp;rdquo; by Blue Öyster Cult, &amp;ldquo;Books about UFOs&amp;rdquo; by Hüsker Dü, &amp;ldquo;Flying Saucers&amp;rdquo; by Nina Hagen, &amp;ldquo;Love Walks In&amp;rdquo; by Van Halen, &amp;ldquo;Loving the Alien&amp;rdquo; by David Bowie, &amp;ldquo;No Doubt About It&amp;rdquo; by Hot Chocolate, &amp;ldquo;Nobody Told Me&amp;rdquo; by John Lennon, &amp;ldquo;Rapture&amp;rdquo; by Blondie, &amp;ldquo;Zero Zero UFO&amp;rdquo; by The Ramones, &amp;ldquo;I Ran (So Far Away)&amp;rdquo; by A Flock of Seagulls, &amp;ldquo;Caught in the Crossfire&amp;rdquo; by April Wine, and &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t Be Late&amp;rdquo; by Saga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1990s&#34;&gt;1990s &lt;a href=&#34;#1990s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1990s entries include &amp;ldquo;The Alien Song (For Those Who Listen)&amp;rdquo; by Mila Jovovich, &amp;ldquo;El Aparato (&amp;ldquo;The Apparatus&amp;rdquo;)&amp;rdquo; by Café Tacvba, &amp;ldquo;Alien (I Am)&amp;rdquo; by Hawkwind, &amp;ldquo;Aliens Exist&amp;rdquo; by Blink-182, &amp;ldquo;Alien Visitors&amp;rdquo; by Man or Astro-man?, &amp;ldquo;Another Sunday&amp;rdquo; by I Mother Earth, &amp;ldquo;Fell in Love with an Alien&amp;rdquo; by the Kelly Family, &amp;ldquo;Hangar 18&amp;rdquo; by Megadeth, &amp;ldquo;Hat Too Flat&amp;rdquo; by Walter Becker, &amp;ldquo;I Made Love to a Martian&amp;rdquo; by Mustard Plug, &amp;ldquo;Girl from Mars&amp;rdquo; by Ash, &amp;ldquo;Martian Dance Invasion&amp;rdquo; by Brainiac, &amp;ldquo;Motorway to Roswell&amp;rdquo; by Pixies, &amp;ldquo;Scent of a Mule&amp;rdquo; by Phish, &amp;ldquo;Shades of Grey&amp;rdquo; by Stuart Davis, &amp;ldquo;Spaceman&amp;rdquo; by Babylon Zoo, &amp;ldquo;Subterranean Homesick Alien&amp;rdquo; by Radiohead, &amp;ldquo;The Happening&amp;rdquo; by Pixies, &amp;ldquo;Who&amp;rsquo;s There?&amp;rdquo; by Smash Mouth, &amp;ldquo;Spaceman&amp;rdquo; by Bif Naked, &amp;ldquo;Is That You Mo-Dean?&amp;rdquo; by The B-52s, &amp;ldquo;Men in Black&amp;rdquo; by Will Smith, and &amp;ldquo;Calgone&amp;rdquo; by Incubus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2000s-to-present&#34;&gt;2000s to present &lt;a href=&#34;#2000s-to-present&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists songs from the 2000s to the present day. It includes &amp;ldquo;Fracture&amp;rdquo; by Edison&amp;rsquo;s Children (Neil Armstrong&amp;rsquo;s son&amp;rsquo;s band), &amp;ldquo;The Aliens Are Here&amp;rdquo; by The Hippos, &amp;ldquo;And You Thought the Doctor&amp;rsquo;s Probe Hurt&amp;rdquo; by Belvedere, &amp;ldquo;Jaadoo, Jaadoo&amp;rdquo; by Rajesh Roshan, &amp;ldquo;Concerning the UFO sighting near Highland, Illinois&amp;rdquo; by Sufjan Stevens, &amp;ldquo;Aliens&amp;rdquo; by Doctor Octagon, &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; by Sneaky Sound System, &amp;ldquo;Rosetta Stoned&amp;rdquo; by Tool, &amp;ldquo;Fallout of the 4th Kind&amp;rdquo; by Edison&amp;rsquo;s Children, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re Not Alone&amp;rdquo; by Nas, &amp;ldquo;Spaceman&amp;rdquo; by The Killers, &amp;ldquo;Venus Ambassador&amp;rdquo; by Bryan Scary &amp;amp; The Shredding Tears, &amp;ldquo;E.T.&amp;rdquo; by Katy Perry featuring Kanye West, &amp;ldquo;Zopilotes&amp;rdquo; by Café Tacuba, &amp;ldquo;A Million Miles Away (I Wish I Had A Time Machine)&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;The Awakening&amp;rdquo; by Edison&amp;rsquo;s Children, &amp;ldquo;Ancient Aliens&amp;rdquo; by Lemon Demon, &amp;ldquo;Decks Dark&amp;rdquo; by Radiohead, &amp;ldquo;Hey Aliens&amp;rdquo; by The Bouncing Souls, &amp;ldquo;Spaceship&amp;rdquo; by Kesha, &amp;ldquo;Herd Culling&amp;rdquo; by Porcupine Tree, &amp;ldquo;Silver Circles&amp;rdquo; by Upchurch, &amp;ldquo;End of the World&amp;rdquo; by Tom MacDonald, &amp;ldquo;Staring at the Stars&amp;rdquo; by Dan Marfisi and Glenn Jordan, &amp;ldquo;An Alien Abduction Story (The Probing)&amp;rdquo; by The Schnooks, and &amp;ldquo;Down Bad&amp;rdquo; by Taylor Swift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes &lt;a href=&#34;#notes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a note indicating that certain songs are used as bumper music on the &lt;em&gt;StarTalk&lt;/em&gt; podcast UFO episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the various sources used to compile the list of songs, including articles from publications like &lt;em&gt;The A.V. Club&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Huffington Post&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;NPR&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Salon.com&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, and books on UFOs and alien encounters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section suggests a book for further exploration of the topic: &lt;em&gt;Alien Rock: The Rock &amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo; Roll Extraterrestrial Connection&lt;/em&gt; by M. Luckman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/(When_You_See)_Those_Flying_Saucers&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/(When_You_See)_Those_Flying_Saucers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barlowe&#39;s Guide to Extraterrestrials</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1aa9be759342/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 04:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1aa9be759342/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;barlowes-guide-to-extraterrestrials&#34;&gt;Barlowe&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Extraterrestrials &lt;a href=&#34;#barlowes-guide-to-extraterrestrials&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Barlowe&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Extraterrestrials&lt;/em&gt; is a science fiction book published in 1979, with a second edition in 1987. The book is authored by artist Wayne Barlowe, with text contributions from Ian Summers and Beth Meacham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary &lt;a href=&#34;#summary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a listing of the extraterrestrial species featured in the book. Each entry includes the alien&amp;rsquo;s name, the author who created it, and the specific work of science fiction in which the alien appears. Some of the notable aliens included are the Abyormenite from Hal Clement&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Cycle of Fire&lt;/em&gt;, the Athshean from Ursula K. Le Guin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Word for World Is Forest&lt;/em&gt;, the Black Cloud from Fred Hoyle&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Black Cloud&lt;/em&gt;, and the Guild Steersman from Frank Herbert&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Dune Messiah&lt;/em&gt;. The list continues with numerous other aliens from a wide range of science fiction novels and stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the critical reception of &lt;em&gt;Barlowe&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Extraterrestrials&lt;/em&gt;. Wendy Bousfield in &lt;em&gt;Library Journal&lt;/em&gt; offered a mixed review, praising the colorful drawings but finding them somewhat static and artificial. She also noted the omission of publication details for the novels from which the aliens were drawn. Claudia J. Morner in &lt;em&gt;School Library Journal&lt;/em&gt; gave a positive review, highlighting the colorful drawings and the fold-out size chart. The book was nominated for an American Book Award and the Hugo Award for Best Related Work in 1980.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited within the article. These include the book itself, reviews from &lt;em&gt;Library Journal&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;School Library Journal&lt;/em&gt;, and links to the Hugo Awards website and a &lt;em&gt;Kirkus Reviews&lt;/em&gt; article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external resources related to &lt;em&gt;Barlowe&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Extraterrestrials&lt;/em&gt;, including its listing on the Internet Speculative Fiction Database and its entry in Open Library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barlowe%27s_Guide_to_Extraterrestrials&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barlowe%27s_Guide_to_Extraterrestrials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
