<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Triton on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/triton/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Triton on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 20:17:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/triton/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Trident  A Proposed Mission to Neptune and Triton</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_473b60939e78/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 20:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_473b60939e78/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;trident-a-proposed-mission-to-neptune-and-triton&#34;&gt;Trident: A Proposed Mission to Neptune and Triton &lt;a href=&#34;#trident-a-proposed-mission-to-neptune-and-triton&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the &lt;em&gt;Trident&lt;/em&gt; mission, a proposed NASA space probe designed to study Neptune and its moon Triton. It outlines the mission&amp;rsquo;s objectives, timeline, scientific payload, and its selection process within NASA&amp;rsquo;s Discovery Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mission-overview&#34;&gt;Mission Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#mission-overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trident&lt;/em&gt; was a proposed reconnaissance mission to the outer solar system, specifically targeting Neptune and its moon Triton. The mission aimed to capitalize on a rare 13-year alignment of Jupiter and Neptune to enable efficient gravity assists. The primary goal was to study Triton, building upon the limited data obtained during Voyager 2&amp;rsquo;s flyby in 1989. The mission was proposed to NASA&amp;rsquo;s Discovery Program in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section recounts the context for the &lt;em&gt;Trident&lt;/em&gt; mission, emphasizing the importance of Triton as a geologically active moon with cryovolcanoes and a thin atmosphere. It highlights that Voyager 2 only observed about 40% of Triton&amp;rsquo;s surface. The &lt;em&gt;Trident&lt;/em&gt; mission concept emerged from NASA&amp;rsquo;s Ocean Worlds Exploration Program to address unanswered questions from the Voyager 2 flyby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the mission&amp;rsquo;s scientific objectives and planned trajectory. &lt;em&gt;Trident&lt;/em&gt; aimed to take advantage of a favorable gravity assist alignment between Jupiter and Neptune, which occurs once every 13 years. This alignment would allow the spacecraft to reach Neptune and Triton in 2038. The mission would map Triton&amp;rsquo;s surface, analyze its plume activity, and assess the potential existence of an internal ocean. The principal investigator for the &lt;em&gt;Trident&lt;/em&gt; mission was Louise Prockter, director of the Lunar and Planetary Institute in Houston, Texas. The proposed launch vehicle was the Atlas V 401, potentially replaced by the Vulcan rocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;payload&#34;&gt;Payload &lt;a href=&#34;#payload&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the scientific instruments that &lt;em&gt;Trident&lt;/em&gt; would carry to study Neptune and Triton. The payload includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An infrared spectrometer for compositional mapping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Narrow and wide-angle cameras for high-resolution imaging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A triaxial magnetometer for ocean detection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Radio science equipment for atmospheric and gravimetry observations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A plasma spectrometer for analyzing atmospheric charged particles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The instruments have heritage from previous missions like &lt;em&gt;New Horizons&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Cassini&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Psyche&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;MESSENGER&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Rosetta&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;JUICE&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;objects-that-trident-would-visit&#34;&gt;Objects that &lt;em&gt;Trident&lt;/em&gt; would visit &lt;a href=&#34;#objects-that-trident-would-visit&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the celestial bodies that &lt;em&gt;Trident&lt;/em&gt; would fly by during its mission. These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Venus (for a gravity assist)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Earth (for multiple gravity assists)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jupiter and its moon Io (for a gravity assist)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neptune and its moon Triton (the primary targets)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related space missions and concepts, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Argo&lt;/em&gt;, a 2009 Triton flyby mission concept.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interstellar Express&lt;/em&gt;, a Chinese probe with a planned Neptune and Triton flyby.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;New Horizons&lt;/em&gt;, which performed a Pluto flyby.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;New Horizons 2&lt;/em&gt;, a mission proposal that might have included a Triton flyby.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Triton Hopper&lt;/em&gt;, a lander concept for Triton.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trident_(spacecraft)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trident_(spacecraft)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
