<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Water_Ice on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/water_ice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Water_Ice on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 12:13:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/water_ice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Phoenix (NASA Mars Lander)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_50661880e09e/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 12:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_50661880e09e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;phoenix-nasa-mars-lander&#34;&gt;Phoenix (NASA Mars Lander) &lt;a href=&#34;#phoenix-nasa-mars-lander&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; was a NASA uncrewed space probe that landed on Mars on May 25, 2008, and operated until November 2, 2008. It was designed to assess the local habitability and research the history of water on Mars. The mission was part of the Mars Scout Program and cost $420 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mission-overview&#34;&gt;Mission Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#mission-overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mission had two primary goals: to study the geological history of water on Mars and to evaluate past or potential planetary habitability in the ice-soil boundary. &lt;em&gt;Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; was the first mission to return data from either of the Martian poles and contributed to NASA&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Follow the water&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; strategy for Mars exploration. The primary mission was planned to last 90 sols (Martian days), but it exceeded this by two months. It was a fixed lander rather than a rover to reduce costs and allow for more scientific instruments. The mission also aimed to determine the biological potential or habitability of the Martian arctic&amp;rsquo;s soils, considering the presence of methane gas on Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Mars Odyssey&lt;/em&gt; orbiter detected hydrogen, suggesting water ice below the surface, which led to the funding of the &lt;em&gt;Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; mission. In August 2003, NASA selected the University of Arizona&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Phoenix&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; mission for launch in 2007. Peter H. Smith of the University of Arizona Lunar and Planetary Laboratory led the mission. The spacecraft used modified components from the canceled Mars Surveyor 2001 Lander and the Mars Polar Lander. Lockheed Martin kept the lander in a clean room from 2001 until the mission was funded. The mission was a partnership of universities, NASA centers, and the aerospace industry. The Canadian Space Agency provided a meteorological station. NASA approved the mission to proceed as planned on June 2, 2005, following a critical review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;specifications&#34;&gt;Specifications &lt;a href=&#34;#specifications&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; had a launch mass of 670 kg, including the lander, aeroshell, parachutes, and cruise stage. The lander itself weighed 350 kg and was about 5.5 meters long with deployed solar panels. It used X-band and UHF communications. Power was generated by solar panels and a NiH2 battery. The lander systems included a RAD6000-based computer system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scientific-payload&#34;&gt;Scientific Payload &lt;a href=&#34;#scientific-payload&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; carried improved versions of cameras and volatiles-analysis instruments from the Mars Polar Lander, as well as experiments from the canceled Mars Surveyor 2001 Lander. This included a robotic arm, wet chemistry laboratories, and optical and atomic force microscopes. The science payload also included a descent imager and meteorological instruments. During entry, descent, and landing (EDL), the Atmospheric Structure Experiment used accelerometer and gyroscope data to create a vertical profile of the atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;robotic-arm-and-camera&#34;&gt;Robotic Arm and Camera &lt;a href=&#34;#robotic-arm-and-camera&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The robotic arm could extend 2.35 meters and dig down to 0.5 meters below the surface to collect samples. It was designed and built for the Jet Propulsion Laboratory by &lt;em&gt;Alliance Spacesystems, LLC&lt;/em&gt;. A rotating rasp-tool was used to cut into the permafrost. The Robotic Arm Camera (RAC) took full-color pictures of the area and verified the samples. The camera was made by the University of Arizona and Max Planck Institute for Solar System Research, Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;surface-stereo-imager&#34;&gt;Surface Stereo Imager &lt;a href=&#34;#surface-stereo-imager&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Surface Stereo Imager (SSI) was the primary camera on the lander. It is a stereo camera that took stereo images of the Martian Arctic and measured atmospheric distortion. The camera was provided by the University of Arizona in collaboration with the Max Planck Institute for Solar System Research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;thermal-and-evolved-gas-analyzer&#34;&gt;Thermal and Evolved Gas Analyzer &lt;a href=&#34;#thermal-and-evolved-gas-analyzer&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Thermal and Evolved Gas Analyzer (TEGA) combined a high-temperature furnace with a mass spectrometer. It baked samples of Martian dust to determine the composition of the resulting vapors. It had eight ovens to analyze separate samples. TEGA measured water vapor, carbon dioxide, water ice, minerals, and organic volatiles. TEGA was built by the University of Arizona and University of Texas at Dallas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mars-descent-imager&#34;&gt;Mars Descent Imager &lt;a href=&#34;#mars-descent-imager&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mars Descent Imager (MARDI) was intended to take pictures of the landing site during the last three minutes of descent. However, a potential data corruption problem was discovered, and it was decided not to use MARDI during the mission. It was built by Malin Space Science Systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;microscopy-electrochemistry-and-conductivity-analyzer&#34;&gt;Microscopy, Electrochemistry, and Conductivity Analyzer &lt;a href=&#34;#microscopy-electrochemistry-and-conductivity-analyzer&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Microscopy, Electrochemistry, and Conductivity Analyzer (MECA) was an instrument package originally designed for the canceled Mars Surveyor 2001 Lander mission. It consisted of a wet chemistry lab (WCL), optical and atomic force microscopes, and a thermal and electrical conductivity probe. The Jet Propulsion Laboratory built MECA. A Swiss consortium led by the University of Neuchatel contributed the atomic force microscope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sample-wheel-and-translation-stage&#34;&gt;Sample Wheel and Translation Stage &lt;a href=&#34;#sample-wheel-and-translation-stage&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This instrument presents 6 of 69 sample holders to an opening in the MECA instrument to which the robotic arm delivers the samples and then brings the samples to the optical microscope and the atomic force microscope. Imperial College London provided the microscope sample substrates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;optical-microscope&#34;&gt;Optical Microscope &lt;a href=&#34;#optical-microscope&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The optical microscope, designed by the University of Arizona, is capable of making images of the Martian regolith with a resolution of 256 pixels/mm or 16 micrometers/pixel. The field of view of the microscope is a 2 mm × 2 mm sample holder to which the robotic arm delivers the sample.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;atomic-force-microscope&#34;&gt;Atomic Force Microscope &lt;a href=&#34;#atomic-force-microscope&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The atomic force microscope has access to a small area of the sample delivered to the optical microscope. The instrument scans over the sample with one of 8 silicon crystal tips and measures the repulsion of the tip from the sample. The maximum resolution is 0.1 micrometers. A Swiss consortium led by the University of Neuchatel contributed the atomic force microscope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;wet-chemistry-laboratory-wcl&#34;&gt;Wet Chemistry Laboratory (WCL) &lt;a href=&#34;#wet-chemistry-laboratory-wcl&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wet chemistry lab (WCL) sensor assembly and leaching solution were designed and built by Thermo Fisher Scientific. Tufts University developed the reagent pellets, barium ISE, and ASV electrodes, and performed the preflight characterization of the sensor array. The robotic arm scooped up some soil and put it in one of four wet chemistry lab cells, where water was added, and, while stirring, an array of electrochemical sensors measured a dozen dissolved ions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;thermal-and-electrical-conductivity-probe-tecp&#34;&gt;Thermal and Electrical Conductivity Probe (TECP) &lt;a href=&#34;#thermal-and-electrical-conductivity-probe-tecp&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MECA contains a Thermal and Electrical Conductivity Probe (TECP). The TECP, designed by Decagon Devices, has four probes that made the following measurements: Martian soil temperature, relative humidity, thermal conductivity, electrical conductivity, dielectric permittivity, wind speed, and atmospheric temperature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;meteorological-station&#34;&gt;Meteorological Station &lt;a href=&#34;#meteorological-station&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Meteorological Station (MET) recorded the daily weather of Mars during the course of the &lt;em&gt;Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; mission. It is equipped with a wind indicator and pressure and temperature sensors. The MET also contains a lidar (light detection and ranging) device for sampling the number of dust particles in the air. It was designed in Canada by Optech and MDA, supported by the Canadian Space Agency. A team initially led by York University&amp;rsquo;s Professor Diane Michelangeli, then by Professor James Whiteway, oversaw the science operations of the station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mission-highlights&#34;&gt;Mission Highlights &lt;a href=&#34;#mission-highlights&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;launch&#34;&gt;Launch &lt;a href=&#34;#launch&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; was launched on August 4, 2007, from Cape Canaveral Air Force Station on a Delta II 7925 launch vehicle. The launch was nominal with no significant anomalies. The &lt;em&gt;Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; lander was placed on a trajectory of such precision that its first trajectory course correction burn was only 18 m/s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cruise&#34;&gt;Cruise &lt;a href=&#34;#cruise&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This section is empty in the original article.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;entry-descent-and-landing&#34;&gt;Entry, Descent, and Landing &lt;a href=&#34;#entry-descent-and-landing&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jet Propulsion Laboratory made adjustments to the orbits of its two active satellites around Mars, Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter and Mars Odyssey, and the European Space Agency similarly adjusted the orbit of its Mars Express spacecraft to observe &lt;em&gt;Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; as it entered the atmosphere and landed. &lt;em&gt;Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; entered the Martian atmosphere at nearly 21,000 km/h and decreased its speed to 8 km/h before touching down. Confirmation of atmospheric entry was received at 4:46 p.m. PDT. Radio signals confirmed that &lt;em&gt;Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; had survived its descent and landed 15 minutes earlier. &lt;em&gt;Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s High Resolution Imaging Science Experiment (HiRISE) camera photographed &lt;em&gt;Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; suspended from its parachute. &lt;em&gt;Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; landed in the Green Valley of Vastitas Borealis on May 25, 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;surface-mission&#34;&gt;Surface Mission &lt;a href=&#34;#surface-mission&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;communications-from-the-surface&#34;&gt;Communications from the Surface &lt;a href=&#34;#communications-from-the-surface&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The robotic arm&amp;rsquo;s first movement was delayed by one day when commands from Earth were not relayed to the &lt;em&gt;Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; lander on Mars. The robotic arm was a critical part of the &lt;em&gt;Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; Mars mission. On May 28, scientists sent commands to unstow its robotic arm and take more images of its landing site. The lander&amp;rsquo;s robotic arm touched soil on Mars for the first time on May 31, 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;presence-of-shallow-subsurface-water-ice&#34;&gt;Presence of Shallow Subsurface Water Ice &lt;a href=&#34;#presence-of-shallow-subsurface-water-ice&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The polygonal cracking at the landing zone had previously been observed from orbit and is similar to patterns seen in permafrost areas on Earth. &lt;em&gt;Phoenix&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s robotic arm camera took an image underneath the lander that shows patches of a smooth bright surface uncovered when thruster exhaust blew off overlying loose soil. On June 19, 2008, NASA announced that dice-sized clumps of bright material in the &amp;ldquo;Dodo-Goldilocks&amp;rdquo; trench had vaporized over four days, implying&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phoenix_(spacecraft)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phoenix_(spacecraft)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
