<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crash on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/crash/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crash on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 04:18:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/crash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aztec crashed saucer hoax</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_50b52be166f2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 04:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_50b52be166f2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;aztec-crashed-saucer-hoax&#34;&gt;Aztec Crashed Saucer Hoax &lt;a href=&#34;#aztec-crashed-saucer-hoax&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Aztec crashed saucer hoax refers to an alleged flying saucer crash that supposedly occurred in 1948 near Aztec, New Mexico. The story, initially popularized by journalist Frank Scully, was later exposed as a fraud perpetrated by Silas M. Newton and Leo A. Gebauer. Despite its debunking, some ufologists have attempted to revive the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;story&#34;&gt;Story &lt;a href=&#34;#story&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the original narrative of the alleged crash. According to Frank Scully&amp;rsquo;s account, based on information from Newton and Gebauer, a 99-foot diameter aerial craft containing sixteen humanoid bodies was recovered by the military in Hart Canyon, near Aztec, New Mexico, in March 1948. Scully claimed the craft and others captured by the government originated from Venus and operated using &amp;ldquo;magnetic principles.&amp;rdquo; The occupants supposedly carried concentrated food wafers and &amp;ldquo;heavy water.&amp;rdquo; Martin Gardner criticized Scully&amp;rsquo;s account as scientifically unsound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hoax&#34;&gt;Hoax &lt;a href=&#34;#hoax&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section exposes the fraudulent nature of the Aztec saucer crash story. Silas Newton and Leo A. Gebauer, while traveling through Aztec, attempted to sell &amp;ldquo;doodlebugs&amp;rdquo; for finding oil, gas, and gold, claiming they were based on alien technology from the crashed saucer. J. P. Cahn of the &lt;em&gt;San Francisco Chronicle&lt;/em&gt; exposed their claims by revealing a sample of &amp;ldquo;alien metal&amp;rdquo; to be ordinary aluminum. Frank Scully published their story in &lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt; and later in his book &lt;em&gt;Behind the Flying Saucers&lt;/em&gt;. The hoax was fully exposed in &lt;em&gt;True&lt;/em&gt; magazine in 1952 and 1956, leading to Newton and Gebauer&amp;rsquo;s conviction for fraud in 1953 after millionaire Herman Flader pressed charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;influence-on-ufology&#34;&gt;Influence on ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#influence-on-ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the impact of the hoax on the field of ufology. Initially discredited, the Aztec story resurfaced in the late 1970s. Leonard Stringfield claimed the incident was real and the craft was one of many captured by the U.S. military. Accounts of the Roswell crash later incorporated the Aztec story, alleging the craft was impervious to heat and contained humanoid bodies between 36 and 42 inches tall. Ufologists claim the military removed all evidence, including the bodies, to Hangar 18 at Wright-Patterson Air Force Base. Robert Spencer Carr also claimed alien bodies recovered near Aztec were stored at &amp;ldquo;Hangar 18&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fbi-memo&#34;&gt;FBI memo &lt;a href=&#34;#fbi-memo&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines the &amp;ldquo;Hottel memo&amp;rdquo; found in the FBI&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Vault&amp;rdquo; website. The memo, written by FBI agent Guy Hottel to J. Edgar Hoover, recounts a story about a crashed saucer and alien bodies. The memo&amp;rsquo;s details trace back to a January 6, 1950, article in &lt;em&gt;the Wyandotte Echo&lt;/em&gt;, a Kansas City, Kansas, legal newspaper, which in turn related the account of a local car salesman and radio station advertising manager. The FBI issued a press release in 2013 clarifying that the memo was a second- or third-hand claim never investigated by the bureau and possibly related to the hoax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fundraiser&#34;&gt;Fundraiser &lt;a href=&#34;#fundraiser&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions the Aztec UFO Symposium, a fundraiser run by the Aztec, New Mexico, library from 1997 to 2011, inspired by the alleged incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aztec,_New_Mexico_UFO_hoax&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aztec,_New_Mexico_UFO_hoax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trinity UFO Case</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7fc9b9a381a2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 20:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7fc9b9a381a2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;trinity-ufo-case&#34;&gt;Trinity UFO Case &lt;a href=&#34;#trinity-ufo-case&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the alleged Trinity UFO case, a story about a crashed unidentified object near the Trinity test site in New Mexico in August 1945. The narrative centers around claims made by José Padilla and Remigio Baca, who, as young boys, reported witnessing the crash and its aftermath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for the Trinity UFO case by referencing the broader history of UFO conspiracy theories. It mentions the Kenneth Arnold UFO sighting, the 1947 flying disc craze, the Roswell incident, and the Aztec, New Mexico crashed saucer hoax. It also introduces Jacques Vallée, a ufologist and author who publicized the Trinity case, noting his involvement in the film &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-context&#34;&gt;The Context &lt;a href=&#34;#the-context&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the setting of the alleged incident, focusing on the Padilla family&amp;rsquo;s ranch near the Trinity test site. It details the family&amp;rsquo;s lifestyle, including Faustino Padilla&amp;rsquo;s work and José&amp;rsquo;s responsibilities on the ranch. It also mentions the impact of the Trinity test on the local population, including Inez Padilla&amp;rsquo;s loss of eyesight. The section touches on the backgrounds of both the Padilla and Baca families, noting their Spanish and Apache heritage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;claims-by-padilla-and-baca&#34;&gt;Claims by Padilla and Baca &lt;a href=&#34;#claims-by-padilla-and-baca&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the specific claims made by José Padilla and Remigio Baca regarding their alleged encounter with a crashed UFO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;first-day&#34;&gt;First day &lt;a href=&#34;#first-day&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection details the initial sighting of the crashed object by Padilla and Baca on August 16, 1945. It describes their search for a lost cow, the loud bang they heard, and their discovery of a groove in the ground leading to an &amp;ldquo;avocado-shaped&amp;rdquo; object. They report seeing small, insect-like creatures near the object, which they compared to a praying mantis, Jerusalem cricket, and fire ant. The boys estimated the object&amp;rsquo;s size and described its metallic appearance, as well as the appearance of the creatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;third-day&#34;&gt;Third day &lt;a href=&#34;#third-day&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection recounts the boys&amp;rsquo; return to the crash site with José Padilla&amp;rsquo;s father, Faustino Padilla, and Eddie Apodaca, a state police officer. It states that the adults entered the object but were visibly disturbed afterward, warning the boys to remain silent. The boys later returned alone and witnessed soldiers collecting debris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fourth-day&#34;&gt;Fourth day &lt;a href=&#34;#fourth-day&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection describes a visit to the Padilla family by Sergeant R. Avila, who requested permission to access the property to recover an &amp;ldquo;experimental weather balloon.&amp;rdquo; Avila emphasized the need for secrecy and the use of heavy equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-fifth-and-the-following-days&#34;&gt;The fifth and the following days &lt;a href=&#34;#the-fifth-and-the-following-days&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection details the alleged military operation to recover the crashed object. It describes the construction of a road and gate, the arrival of a lowboy trailer, and the use of a crane to lift the object. Padilla and Baca claim to have secretly observed the military&amp;rsquo;s activities. They also describe how they obtained a &amp;ldquo;souvenir&amp;rdquo; from inside the object, a metal piece they named &amp;ldquo;Tesoro.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;after-the-recovery&#34;&gt;After the recovery &lt;a href=&#34;#after-the-recovery&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the aftermath of the alleged recovery operation. It mentions the removal of the object, the clearing of the crash site, and the hiding of the &amp;ldquo;Tesoro&amp;rdquo; by the boys. It also touches on the atmosphere of secrecy and fear in the area, with rumors of government intervention for those who spoke too much about the events. Vallée draws parallels between this case and the Roswell incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication &lt;a href=&#34;#publication&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the publication history of the Trinity UFO case. It mentions Ben Moffett&amp;rsquo;s initial reporting in 2003, the analysis of the &amp;ldquo;Tesoro&amp;rdquo; metal piece, Timothy Good&amp;rsquo;s mention of the incident in his book, and Paola Harris&amp;rsquo;s awareness of the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;criticisms-and-responses&#34;&gt;Criticisms and responses &lt;a href=&#34;#criticisms-and-responses&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents criticisms of the Trinity UFO case, primarily from skeptical writer Brian Dunning, who characterizes the story as a hoax. Dunning cites inconsistencies in the story, such as the claim that Eddie Apodaca was a state trooper at the time of the incident, when he was actually serving in World War II. It also includes responses from Jacques Vallée, who defends the case and addresses the criticisms raised by Douglas Dean Johnson. Vallée acknowledges some inaccuracies in the original reporting but maintains that the core story is valid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists related topics, specifically the Roswell incident and the Aztec, New Mexico crashed saucer hoax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bibliography&#34;&gt;Bibliography &lt;a href=&#34;#bibliography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the books cited in the article, including &lt;em&gt;Need to Know&lt;/em&gt; by Timothy Good and &lt;em&gt;Trinity: The Best-Kept Secret&lt;/em&gt; by Jacques Vallée and Paola L. Harris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of citations used in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trinity_UFO_Case&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trinity_UFO_Case&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
