<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nebraska on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/nebraska/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nebraska on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 20:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/nebraska/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dundy County UFO hoax</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b31c98c9c76b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 20:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b31c98c9c76b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;dundy-county-ufo-hoax&#34;&gt;Dundy County UFO Hoax &lt;a href=&#34;#dundy-county-ufo-hoax&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dundy County UFO hoax was a fabricated story published by the &lt;em&gt;Nebraska State Journal&lt;/em&gt; in 1884. The story detailed the discovery of a cylindrical object by cowboys in Dundy County, Nebraska, near Max, following a supposed meteor crash. The newspaper later admitted the story was a hoax in 1927, though some people still believe the sighting was real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;report-and-revelation-of-hoax&#34;&gt;Report and Revelation of Hoax &lt;a href=&#34;#report-and-revelation-of-hoax&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the original report published by the &lt;em&gt;Nebraska State Journal&lt;/em&gt; on June 8, 1884. It describes how cowboys in Dundy County, near Max, Nebraska, found the remains of a large meteor. One of the cowboys, Alf Williamson, suffered blisters, hair loss, and eyesight damage upon approaching the site. The heat was so intense that the cowboys couldn&amp;rsquo;t investigate further until the next day. They returned with other locals to find a long, cylindrical tube, approximately 50-60 feet long and 10-12 feet in diameter. Rancher John Ellis intended to claim the land. Two days later, the newspaper reported that rain had dissolved the remains into congealed pools of machinery, which then washed away, leaving only a faint, sweetish smell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The section also covers the immediate reaction to the story, noting that it was widely considered a hoax or joke soon after publication and was parodied during the 1884 presidential election campaign. The &lt;em&gt;Laramie Boomerang&lt;/em&gt; initially carried the story but later reported it was a political allegory for the temperance movement. The hoax predates the mass reports of mystery airships in the late 1890s, some of which occurred in Nebraska.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the &lt;em&gt;Nebraska State Journal&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s 1927 admission, some people still believe the sighting was legitimate. The &lt;em&gt;McCook Gazette&lt;/em&gt; continues to receive inquiries about the event. In 2013, searches in Red Willow County and the reported discovery of a green material fueled further belief in the story&amp;rsquo;s authenticity. Some modern ufologists consider the report a genuine UFO sighting. A 1997 &lt;em&gt;Lincoln Journal Star&lt;/em&gt; article listed the Dundy County sighting as one of the earliest in the state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the citations used in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;citations&#34;&gt;Citations &lt;a href=&#34;#citations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection lists the specific citations used as footnotes throughout the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bibliography&#34;&gt;Bibliography &lt;a href=&#34;#bibliography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection provides a list of sources used in the article, including newspaper articles, academic papers, and online resources. Key sources include articles from the &lt;em&gt;Daily Nebraskan&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;McCook Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Lincoln Journal Star&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Nebraska History&lt;/em&gt;, and a speech by Dale Bacon from the Nebraska State Historical Society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dundy_County_UFO_hoax&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dundy_County_UFO_hoax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
