<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Space Exploration on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/space-exploration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Space Exploration on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 21:51:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/space-exploration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spacecraft</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_c3ed943147b3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 21:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_c3ed943147b3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;spacecraft&#34;&gt;Spacecraft &lt;a href=&#34;#spacecraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spacecraft is a vehicle or machine designed to fly and operate in outer space. It serves various purposes, including communications, Earth observation, meteorology, navigation, space colonization, planetary exploration, and transporting humans and cargo. Spacecraft typically require a launch vehicle to reach space, except for single-stage-to-orbit vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The history of spacecraft begins with the German V-2 rocket, which reached an altitude of 189 km in June 1944 in Peenemünde, Germany. Sputnik 1, launched by the Soviet Union on October 4, 1957, was the first artificial satellite, marking the start of the Space Age. Sputnik 1&amp;rsquo;s launch initiated new political, military, technological, and scientific developments. It also helped identify the density of the upper atmospheric layer and provided data on radio-signal distribution in the ionosphere. While Sputnik 1 was the first spacecraft to orbit the Earth, other human-made objects had previously reached an altitude of 100 km, the Kármán line, which is the height required by the international organization Fédération Aéronautique Internationale to count as a spaceflight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crewed-and-uncrewed-spacecraft&#34;&gt;Crewed and Uncrewed Spacecraft &lt;a href=&#34;#crewed-and-uncrewed-spacecraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spacecraft are categorized into crewed and uncrewed vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;crewed-spacecraft&#34;&gt;Crewed Spacecraft &lt;a href=&#34;#crewed-spacecraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of 2016, only Russia, the United States, and China have flown crewed spacecraft. Vostok 1, carrying Soviet cosmonaut Yuri Gagarin in 1961, was the first crewed spacecraft to complete a full Earth orbit. The second crewed spacecraft was &lt;em&gt;Freedom 7&lt;/em&gt;, which performed a sub-orbital spaceflight in 1961 carrying American astronaut Alan Shepard. Other crewed spacecraft include the Soviet Voskhod and Soyuz, the American Gemini and Apollo spacecraft, the Skylab space station, the Space Shuttle, and the Chinese Shenzhou. The International Space Station (ISS), crewed since November 2000, is a joint venture between Russia, the United States, Canada, and other countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;uncrewed-spacecraft&#34;&gt;Uncrewed Spacecraft &lt;a href=&#34;#uncrewed-spacecraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncrewed spacecraft operate autonomously or telerobotically, often preferred for cost-effectiveness and lower risk. They are used for missions unsuitable for humans, such as exploring Venus or the outer planets. Robotic spacecraft used for scientific research are space probes, while those orbiting a planetary body are artificial satellites. Examples include the Hubble Space Telescope and cargo spacecraft like the Jules Verne Automated Transfer Vehicle (ATV).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other&#34;&gt;Other &lt;a href=&#34;#other&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some spacecraft, like the Buran spaceplane and SpaceX Dragon 2, can operate as both crewed and uncrewed vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;types-of-spacecraft&#34;&gt;Types of Spacecraft &lt;a href=&#34;#types-of-spacecraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spacecraft are designed for various specific purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;communications-satellite&#34;&gt;Communications Satellite &lt;a href=&#34;#communications-satellite&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communications satellites relay and amplify radio telecommunication signals between a source transmitter and a receiver on Earth. They are used for television, telephone, radio, internet, and military applications. Many are in geostationary orbit, while others form satellite constellations in low Earth orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cargo-spacecraft&#34;&gt;Cargo Spacecraft &lt;a href=&#34;#cargo-spacecraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cargo spacecraft are robotic vehicles designed to carry cargo, such as food, propellant, and other supplies, to support space station operations. Automated cargo spacecraft have serviced Salyut 6, Salyut 7, Mir, the International Space Station, and Tiangong space station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;space-probes&#34;&gt;Space Probes &lt;a href=&#34;#space-probes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space probes are robotic spacecraft sent to explore deep space or astronomical bodies other than Earth. They have visited every planet in the Solar System and Pluto. The Voyager probes, launched in 1977, took advantage of a rare alignment of Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, and Neptune to visit all four planets in one mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;voyager-program&#34;&gt;Voyager Program &lt;a href=&#34;#voyager-program&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Voyager probes, launched in 1977, took advantage of a rare planetary alignment to visit Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, and Neptune. Voyager 1 and Voyager 2 are now escaping the Solar System, providing valuable data from interstellar space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;space-telescopes&#34;&gt;Space Telescopes &lt;a href=&#34;#space-telescopes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space telescopes are telescopes in outer space used to observe astronomical objects, avoiding the filtering and distortion of electromagnetic radiation and light pollution. Examples include the Hubble Space Telescope and the James Webb Space Telescope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;landers&#34;&gt;Landers &lt;a href=&#34;#landers&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Landers are spacecraft that make a soft landing on the surface of an astronomical body other than Earth. They use various techniques, including fuel supply and aerobraking, to achieve a safe landing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;space-capsules&#34;&gt;Space Capsules &lt;a href=&#34;#space-capsules&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space capsules are spacecraft that can return from space at least once. They have a blunt shape and do not possess wings. The Vostok capsule, built by the Soviet Union, carried the first person in space, Yuri Gagarin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;spaceplanes&#34;&gt;Spaceplanes &lt;a href=&#34;#spaceplanes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spaceplanes are spacecraft built in the shape of airplanes. The North American X-15 was an early example, while the Space Shuttle orbiter was the first reusable orbital spaceplane. The Buran-class shuttle, launched by the USSR, was the first autonomous reusable spaceplane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;space-shuttle&#34;&gt;Space Shuttle &lt;a href=&#34;#space-shuttle&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Space Shuttle was a reusable Low Earth Orbital launch system consisting of two reusable Solid Rocket Boosters, a Space Shuttle Orbiter, and a throwaway Space Shuttle external tank. It flew 135 times from 1981 to 2011, supporting Mir, the Hubble Space Telescope, and the International Space Station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-1&#34;&gt;Other &lt;a href=&#34;#other-1&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some spacecraft do not fit neatly into the general categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;spacex-starship&#34;&gt;SpaceX Starship &lt;a href=&#34;#spacex-starship&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starship is a spacecraft and second stage under development by SpaceX, designed to transport crew and cargo to Earth orbit, the Moon, Mars, and beyond. It will also be capable of point-to-point transport on Earth and refueling other Starship vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;mission-extension-vehicle&#34;&gt;Mission Extension Vehicle &lt;a href=&#34;#mission-extension-vehicle&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mission Extension Vehicle is a robotic spacecraft designed to prolong the life of another spacecraft by docking to it and correcting its orientation or orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;subsystems&#34;&gt;Subsystems &lt;a href=&#34;#subsystems&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spacecraft&amp;rsquo;s astrionics system comprises various subsystems, including attitude determination and control, guidance, navigation and control, communications, command and data handling, power, thermal control, propulsion, and structures. Spacecraft intended for human spaceflight must also include a life support system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;spacecraft-records&#34;&gt;Spacecraft Records &lt;a href=&#34;#spacecraft-records&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spacecraft records include achievements such as speed and distance from the Sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fastest-spacecraft&#34;&gt;Fastest Spacecraft &lt;a href=&#34;#fastest-spacecraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parker Solar Probe (estimated 700,000 km/h at final perihelion)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helios I and II Solar Probes (252,792 km/h)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;furthest-spacecraft-from-the-sun&#34;&gt;Furthest Spacecraft from the Sun &lt;a href=&#34;#furthest-spacecraft-from-the-sun&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voyager 1 (156.13 AU as of April 2022)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pioneer 10 (122.48 AU as of December 2018)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voyager 2 (122.82 AU as of January 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pioneer 11 (101.17 AU as of December 2018)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spacecraft&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spacecraft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncrewed spacecraft</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ac2b10a2dfa0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ac2b10a2dfa0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;uncrewed-spacecraft&#34;&gt;Uncrewed Spacecraft &lt;a href=&#34;#uncrewed-spacecraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Wikipedia article discusses spacecraft that operate without human presence, often referred to as robotic spacecraft. These vehicles can be remotely controlled, guided, or pre-programmed for autonomous operation. They are essential for space exploration due to lower costs, reduced risks, and the ability to explore environments too hostile for humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the historical development of uncrewed spacecraft, beginning with the launch of &lt;em&gt;Sputnik&lt;/em&gt; by the Soviet Union in 1957. Key events include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1951:&lt;/strong&gt; The Soviet Union launches the first robotic spacecraft on a suborbital flight with two dogs, Dezik and Tsygan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1957:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Sputnik 1&lt;/em&gt;, the first artificial satellite, is launched by the USSR. &lt;em&gt;Sputnik 2&lt;/em&gt; follows, carrying the dog Laika, the first animal in orbit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1958:&lt;/strong&gt; The United States launches its first satellite, &lt;em&gt;Explorer 1&lt;/em&gt;, which confirms the existence of the Van Allen belts. &lt;em&gt;Vanguard 1&lt;/em&gt; is also launched.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1959:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Luna 1&lt;/em&gt; becomes the first lunar probe to orbit the Moon and then the Sun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1962:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Mariner 2&lt;/em&gt; studies Venus, revealing its high temperature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1965:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Mariner 4&lt;/em&gt; captures the first images of Mars&amp;rsquo; cratered surface. &lt;em&gt;Luna 9&lt;/em&gt; sends images from the Moon&amp;rsquo;s surface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1967:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Surveyor 3&lt;/em&gt; gathers crucial data about the Moon&amp;rsquo;s surface for the Apollo 11 mission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1977:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Voyager 1&lt;/em&gt; is launched, entering interstellar space in 2012, followed by &lt;em&gt;Voyager 2&lt;/em&gt; in 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The section also mentions other countries that have successfully launched satellites using their own launch vehicles, including France, Japan, China, the United Kingdom, India, Israel, Iran, North Korea, and South Korea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design &lt;a href=&#34;#design&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the design considerations for uncrewed spacecraft, dividing the vehicle into the mission payload and the bus (or platform). The bus provides essential functions such as physical structure, thermal control, electrical power, attitude control, and telemetry. JPL&amp;rsquo;s division of the &amp;ldquo;flight system&amp;rdquo; into subsystems is also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;structure&#34;&gt;Structure &lt;a href=&#34;#structure&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The physical structure provides mechanical integrity and supports spacecraft components, ensuring they withstand launch loads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-handling&#34;&gt;Data Handling &lt;a href=&#34;#data-handling&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The command and data subsystem stores command sequences, maintains the spacecraft clock, and collects and reports telemetry and mission data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;attitude-determination-and-control&#34;&gt;Attitude Determination and Control &lt;a href=&#34;#attitude-determination-and-control&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This system maintains the spacecraft&amp;rsquo;s orientation in space, compensating for external disturbances and repositioning movable parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;entry-descent-and-landing&#34;&gt;Entry, Descent, and Landing &lt;a href=&#34;#entry-descent-and-landing&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrated sensing uses image transformation algorithms to interpret land data, detect and avoid terrain hazards, and increase landing accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;landing-on-hazardous-terrain&#34;&gt;Landing on Hazardous Terrain &lt;a href=&#34;#landing-on-hazardous-terrain&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key processes for safe landing on a planet&amp;rsquo;s surface include entry into the gravity field and atmosphere, descent through the atmosphere, and a safe landing. The spacecraft must estimate its position, assess hazards, and adjust its trajectory in real time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;telecommunications&#34;&gt;Telecommunications &lt;a href=&#34;#telecommunications&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The telecommunications subsystem includes radio antennas, transmitters, and receivers for communicating with ground stations or other spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;electrical-power&#34;&gt;Electrical Power &lt;a href=&#34;#electrical-power&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electric power is supplied by photovoltaic (solar) cells or radioisotope thermoelectric generators, with batteries for storage and distribution circuitry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;temperature-control-and-protection-from-the-environment&#34;&gt;Temperature Control and Protection from the Environment &lt;a href=&#34;#temperature-control-and-protection-from-the-environment&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spacecraft are protected from temperature fluctuations with insulation, mirrors, and sunshades. Shielding is also used to protect against micrometeoroids and orbital debris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;propulsion&#34;&gt;Propulsion &lt;a href=&#34;#propulsion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spacecraft propulsion generates thrust for space travel, with various systems including monopropellant, bipropellant, and ion propulsion. Rocket engines are commonly used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;monopropellant&#34;&gt;Monopropellant &lt;a href=&#34;#monopropellant&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monopropellant propulsion uses a fuel with a chemically bonded oxidizer, requiring only a fuel line and a catalyst for combustion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bipropellant&#34;&gt;Bipropellant &lt;a href=&#34;#bipropellant&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bipropellant propulsion uses liquid propellants that spontaneously combust upon contact, offering high density and space efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;ion&#34;&gt;Ion &lt;a href=&#34;#ion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ion propulsion generates thrust by electron bombardment or ion acceleration, providing efficient velocity maintenance for deep-space travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mechanical-devices&#34;&gt;Mechanical Devices &lt;a href=&#34;#mechanical-devices&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mechanical components are moved for deployment or landing, often controlled by pyrotechnic devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;robotic-vs-uncrewed-spacecraft&#34;&gt;Robotic vs. Uncrewed Spacecraft &lt;a href=&#34;#robotic-vs-uncrewed-spacecraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robotic spacecraft are designed for specific hostile environments, while uncrewed spacecraft operate without personnel via automatic or remote control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;control&#34;&gt;Control &lt;a href=&#34;#control&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses how robotic spacecraft use telemetry to transmit data and status information back to Earth. Early spacecraft lacked remote control, but command systems were later developed. Increased autonomy is crucial for distant probes due to light travel time delays. Probes like &lt;em&gt;Cassini–Huygens&lt;/em&gt; and the Mars Exploration Rovers operate autonomously for extended periods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;space-probes-and-observatories&#34;&gt;Space Probes and Observatories &lt;a href=&#34;#space-probes-and-observatories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A space probe is a robotic spacecraft that explores outer space without orbiting Earth. These probes carry scientific instruments and can fly by, orbit, or land on planetary bodies, or even enter interstellar space. Space telescopes or observatories are telescopes in space that avoid atmospheric distortion and light pollution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cargo-spacecraft&#34;&gt;Cargo Spacecraft &lt;a href=&#34;#cargo-spacecraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cargo or resupply spacecraft transport supplies to space stations. Automated cargo spacecraft have supported missions to &lt;em&gt;Salyut 6&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Salyut 7&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Mir&lt;/em&gt;, the International Space Station (ISS), and the Tiangong space station. Currently, the ISS relies on &lt;em&gt;Progress&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Cargo Dragon 2&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Cygnus&lt;/em&gt; spacecraft, while Tiangong is supplied by &lt;em&gt;Tianzhou&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;Dream Chaser&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;HTV-X&lt;/em&gt; are under development for future use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cargo_spacecraft&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cargo_spacecraft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture of extraterrestriality</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_446ae6ad1e1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 04:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_446ae6ad1e1a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;culture-of-extraterrestriality&#34;&gt;Culture of Extraterrestriality &lt;a href=&#34;#culture-of-extraterrestriality&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The culture of extraterrestriality encompasses the cultural imagination and depiction of otherworldliness, alienness, or outer space. It characterizes &amp;ldquo;the other&amp;rdquo; through extraterrestrial space, going beyond mere extraterritoriality or periphery. It involves the space imagined or described as extraterrestrial, or any space outside a described land, creating conditions of spatially set apart otherness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extraterrestriality has been a feature of many past and contemporary cultures. Politically, it has been an element of utopianism and colonialism, particularly in the formation of colonies as products in extraterrestrial space. These histories inform contemporary cultures of extraterrestriality, influencing space exploration, the reception of its findings, space colonization, and the search for extraterrestrial life. Colonialism was associated with extraterrestrial space as early as the 17th century when John Wilkins suggested that future adventurers like Francis Drake and Christopher Columbus might reach the Moon and people to live there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists related topics for further exploration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extraterrestrials in fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search for extraterrestrial intelligence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potential cultural impact of extraterrestrial contact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expatriate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anthropocentrism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of citations used in the article, including links to external sources. Some of the sources include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Britain&amp;rsquo;s Extraterrestrial Empire: Colonial Ambition, Anxiety, and Ambivalence in Early Modern Literature&amp;rdquo; by Mark Edward Wisniewski, discussing colonial ambition in early modern literature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Where do aliens come from?&amp;rdquo; by Justin Smith-Ruiu, exploring the origins of aliens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Conditio extraterrestris&amp;rdquo; from UZH, a German-language resource.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Extraterrestrial culture: How we express ourselves through space…&amp;rdquo; from The Planetary Society, discussing how we express ourselves through space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Other Worlds: The Cultural Significance of the Extraterrestrial Life Debate&amp;rdquo; by Steven J. Dick, discussing the cultural significance of the extraterrestrial life debate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;THE RACIST LANGUAGE OF SPACE EXPLORATION&amp;rdquo; by Caroline Haskins, discussing the racist language of space exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Culture_of_extraterrestriality&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Culture_of_extraterrestriality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
