<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1947 Sightings on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/1947-sightings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1947 Sightings on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 09:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/1947-sightings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rhodes UFO photographs</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cdc6eca3dba9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 09:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cdc6eca3dba9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;rhodes-ufo-photographs&#34;&gt;Rhodes UFO Photographs &lt;a href=&#34;#rhodes-ufo-photographs&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rhodes UFO photographs, also known as the shoe-heel UFO photographs, are two images purportedly showing a disc-like object flying over Phoenix, Arizona, in 1947. These photographs, taken by William Albert Rhodes, gained notoriety as some of the earliest UFO photographs during the 1947 flying disc craze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for the Rhodes photographs by referencing the Kenneth Arnold UFO sighting and the broader 1947 flying disc craze. It mentions Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s report of seeing nine objects over Washington State, which led to the term &amp;ldquo;flying saucers.&amp;rdquo; The section also notes sightings in Arizona leading up to the Rhodes photographs, including reports of a &amp;ldquo;circular object&amp;rdquo; in Tempe and &amp;ldquo;silvery balls&amp;rdquo; north of Phoenix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication &lt;a href=&#34;#publication&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the initial publication of the Rhodes photographs in &lt;em&gt;The Arizona Republic&lt;/em&gt; on July 9, 1947. The headline described the object as a &amp;ldquo;Mystery &amp;lsquo;Whatsis&amp;rsquo;,&amp;rdquo; and the newspaper characterized it as being &amp;ldquo;the shape of a heel of a shoe, with a small hole in the center.&amp;rdquo; The article portrays Rhodes as an amateur radio operator and model airplane manufacturer. It recounts Rhodes&amp;rsquo;s story of hearing a loud &amp;ldquo;whoosh,&amp;rdquo; grabbing his camera, and taking two photographs of the object, which he said made three passes over his home and left vapor trails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investigation&#34;&gt;Investigation &lt;a href=&#34;#investigation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the official investigation into Rhodes and his photographs. It mentions that Kenneth Arnold was shown the Rhodes pictures and told they were considered possibly authentic. The FBI obtained copies of the photographs, and Rhodes was interviewed by the FBI and the Army&amp;rsquo;s Counterintelligence Corps. He provided them with photographs and negatives. The Air Force also investigated the incident, and Project Blue Book designated the case &amp;ldquo;Incident 40.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;explanations&#34;&gt;Explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents explanations for the Rhodes photographs, primarily focusing on the Air Force&amp;rsquo;s conclusion that the object was likely windblown debris. It mentions that expert photographers disagreed on the possibility of filming such an object under the described conditions. The report also notes inconsistencies in Rhodes&amp;rsquo;s behavior and statements. Irving Langmuir studied the photographs and suggested the object was a piece of paper swept up by the wind after a thunderstorm. The section also explores the possibility of a hoax, suggesting Rhodes may have been influenced by a story about atomic-powered Soviet craft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legacy&#34;&gt;Legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the lasting impact of the Rhodes photographs on UFO lore. It highlights Raymond A. Palmer, a magazine editor and publisher who used the photographs as evidence of his UFO theories in publications like &lt;em&gt;Fate&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Coming of the Saucers&lt;/em&gt;. Palmer claimed the government tried to suppress the photographs. The section also mentions Gerald Heard&amp;rsquo;s discussion of the photographs in his book &lt;em&gt;The Riddle of the Flying Saucers&lt;/em&gt;. A reporter for &lt;em&gt;The Arizona Republic&lt;/em&gt; claimed to have seen a similar object near White Sands, New Mexico. Rhodes was interviewed in 1998, and his photographs continue to be discussed in Arizona media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rhodes_UFO_photographs&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rhodes_UFO_photographs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
