<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Category = &#34;Ufology&#34;\ntags = [&#34;UAPs&#34;, &#34;Disclosure&#34;, &#34;Pentagon&#34;]\nmedia_type = None\npeople = [&#34;Michael Shellenberger&#34;, &#34;Matthew Brown&#34;, &#34;Elizabeth Vargas&#34;]\nlocations = [&#34;Pentagon&#34;, &#34;U.S.&#34;]\n on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/category--ufology%5Cntags--uaps-disclosure-pentagon%5Cnmedia_type--none%5Cnpeople--michael-shellenberger-matthew-brown-elizabeth-vargas%5Cnlocations--pentagon-u.s.%5Cn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Category = &#34;Ufology&#34;\ntags = [&#34;UAPs&#34;, &#34;Disclosure&#34;, &#34;Pentagon&#34;]\nmedia_type = None\npeople = [&#34;Michael Shellenberger&#34;, &#34;Matthew Brown&#34;, &#34;Elizabeth Vargas&#34;]\nlocations = [&#34;Pentagon&#34;, &#34;U.S.&#34;]\n on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 06:54:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/category--ufology%5Cntags--uaps-disclosure-pentagon%5Cnmedia_type--none%5Cnpeople--michael-shellenberger-matthew-brown-elizabeth-vargas%5Cnlocations--pentagon-u.s.%5Cn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Immaculate Constellation  Alleged Pentagon UFO Data Concealment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_307d06c67fa6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 06:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_307d06c67fa6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;immaculate-constellation-alleged-pentagon-ufo-data-concealment&#34;&gt;Immaculate Constellation: Alleged Pentagon UFO Data Concealment &lt;a href=&#34;#immaculate-constellation-alleged-pentagon-ufo-data-concealment&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses claims made by investigative journalist Michael Shellenberger regarding a classified U.S. defense initiative, reportedly named &amp;ldquo;Immaculate Constellation,&amp;rdquo; which is alleged to have collected and concealed a vast amount of data related to Unidentified Aerial Phenomena (UAPs), commonly known as UFOs. Shellenberger asserts that the Pentagon is hiding significant photographic, video, and sensor-based evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;shellenbergers-claims-and-sources&#34;&gt;Shellenberger&amp;rsquo;s Claims and Sources &lt;a href=&#34;#shellenbergers-claims-and-sources&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Shellenberger, a journalist and whistleblower advocate, alleges that the Pentagon is concealing a massive archive of high-quality data on UAPs. He bases his claims on information from government insiders and whistleblowers, including former intelligence contractor Matthew Brown. These sources suggest that the data held by &amp;ldquo;Immaculate Constellation&amp;rdquo; is far more extensive than what has been publicly released by the Department of Defense. Shellenberger emphasizes the high quality and diverse nature of the data, including photos, videos, radar data, and infrared sensor readings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scale-of-concealment&#34;&gt;Scale of Concealment &lt;a href=&#34;#scale-of-concealment&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shellenberger estimates that less than 1% of the total information gathered by the Pentagon on UFOs has been made public. He criticizes the excessive secrecy surrounding UAP-related information, citing heavily redacted documents and the blocking of information even from Congress. He argues that taxpayers funded this research and have a right to access the findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;congressional-interest-and-bipartisan-support&#34;&gt;Congressional Interest and Bipartisan Support &lt;a href=&#34;#congressional-interest-and-bipartisan-support&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article highlights the bipartisan interest in UAP transparency among U.S. lawmakers. Congressional hearings on UAPs have garnered significant attention and support from both Democrats and Republicans, who are pushing for greater disclosure. Shellenberger, who has testified before Congress, notes the growing frustration among lawmakers regarding the Pentagon&amp;rsquo;s reluctance to share information, even with oversight committees. The article emphasizes that UAP transparency is no longer a fringe issue but a matter of serious debate at the highest levels of government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;potential-turning-point-for-disclosure&#34;&gt;Potential Turning Point for Disclosure &lt;a href=&#34;#potential-turning-point-for-disclosure&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The revelations about &amp;ldquo;Immaculate Constellation&amp;rdquo; and the alleged scale of hidden data are presented as a potential turning point in the movement for UFO disclosure. The call for transparency has expanded beyond civilian researchers and enthusiasts to include serious consideration within the government. Shellenberger calls for executive leadership to respond to public and congressional pressure and provide the full story on UAPs. The article concludes by suggesting that the mystery surrounding UAPs may be closer to being solved due to mounting evidence and growing political interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latest-ufo-sightings.net/2025/05/immaculate-constellation-journalist-claims-pentagon-hiding-massive-ufo-evidence.html&#34;&gt;https://www.latest-ufo-sightings.net/2025/05/immaculate-constellation-journalist-claims-pentagon-hiding-massive-ufo-evidence.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
