<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>United States on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/united-states/</link>
    <description>Recent content in United States on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 17:06:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/united-states/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in the United States</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8d3b71993ef9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 17:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_8d3b71993ef9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-the-united-states&#34;&gt;List of Alleged UFO Sightings in the United States &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-the-united-states&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a comprehensive list of alleged UFO sightings in the United States, presented in a tabular format. Each entry includes the date, city, state, a link to a main article (if available), and a brief description of the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;table-of-sightings&#34;&gt;Table of Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#table-of-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This table chronologically lists alleged UFO sightings in the United States. Each entry provides key details about the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 1865, Cadotte Pass, Montana:&lt;/strong&gt; Trapper James Lumley reported seeing a craft crash, describing sulfur smells and hieroglyphics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1896–1897, Multiple Locations, Multiple States:&lt;/strong&gt; Sightings of airship-like vehicles were reported across the United States, known as the Mystery Airships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 17, 1897, Aurora, Texas:&lt;/strong&gt; Residents claimed an airship crashed, and the alien pilot was buried in the local cemetery, known as the Aurora, Texas, UFO incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 24, 1942, Los Angeles, California:&lt;/strong&gt; The &amp;ldquo;Battle of Los Angeles&amp;rdquo; involved an alleged enemy attack and anti-aircraft artillery barrage. Initially thought to be a Japanese attack, it was later attributed to &amp;ldquo;war nerves&amp;rdquo; and a weather balloon. Key figures include Secretary of the Navy Frank Knox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 1945, Jornada del Muerto, New Mexico:&lt;/strong&gt; Two boys reported seeing an &amp;ldquo;avocado-shaped&amp;rdquo; object crash, containing insect-like alien creatures, known as the Trinity UFO Case. This occurred shortly after the first atomic bomb detonation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June 21, 1947, Maury Island, Washington:&lt;/strong&gt; This incident involved reports of an encounter with &amp;ldquo;men in black&amp;rdquo; and occurred before the Kenneth Arnold sighting, known as the Maury Island incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June 24, 1947, Mount Rainier, Washington:&lt;/strong&gt; Kenneth Arnold reported seeing nine unusual objects flying in formation near Mount Rainier, describing them as bright and erratic, known as the Kenneth Arnold UFO sighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 1947, Roswell, New Mexico:&lt;/strong&gt; The Roswell UFO Incident involved the recovery of materials near Roswell, sparking intense speculation. The military claims it was a research balloon, while ufologists believe it was an alien craft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 7, 1948, Maysville, Kentucky:&lt;/strong&gt; The Mantell Incident involved the death of Captain Thomas F. Mantell, a Kentucky Air National Guard pilot, while pursuing a UFO. Historian David Michael Jacobs noted this case marked a shift in public and governmental perceptions of UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 24, 1948, Montgomery, Alabama:&lt;/strong&gt; The Chiles-Whitted UFO Encounter involved two commercial pilots reporting a near-collision with a torpedo-shaped object. It was investigated by Project Sign.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 1, 1948, Fargo, North Dakota:&lt;/strong&gt; The Gorman Dogfight involved a US Air Force pilot sighting and pursuing a UFO for 27 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 11, 1950, McMinnville, Oregon:&lt;/strong&gt; The McMinnville UFO photographs were taken by Paul and Evelyn Trent on their farm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 29, 1950, Mount Vernon, Maryland:&lt;/strong&gt; Captain Willis Sperry and crewmembers on an American Airlines DC-6 reported seeing a &amp;ldquo;brilliant, diffused, bluish light.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 15, 1950, Great Falls, Montana:&lt;/strong&gt; The Mariana UFO incident garnered national media attention during a period of high interest in UFOs and alien invasion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 25, 1951, Lubbock, Texas:&lt;/strong&gt; The Lubbock Lights were a V-shaped formation of lights seen over the town.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 24, 1952, Burbank, California:&lt;/strong&gt; Orfeo Angelucci claimed to encounter flying saucers and friendly pilots during his drives home from an aircraft plant, as detailed in his book &lt;em&gt;The Secret of the Saucers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 13, 1952, Washington, D.C.:&lt;/strong&gt; The 1952 Washington D.C. UFO incident involved multiple UFO reports over the city, with sightings by pilots and radar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 12, 1952, Flatwoods, West Virginia:&lt;/strong&gt; Six boys and a woman reported seeing a UFO landing and a bizarre creature, known as the Flatwoods monster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 23, 1953, Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan:&lt;/strong&gt; Felix Moncla, Jr., a US Air Force pilot, disappeared with 2nd Lt. Robert Wilson while pursuing a UFO over Lake Superior. The US Air Force claimed it was a misidentified Canadian Air Force plane, but the Royal Canadian Air Force disputed this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 2, 1957, Levelland, Texas:&lt;/strong&gt; The Levelland UFO case involved multiple reports of a UFO sighting in the small town.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 19, 1961, Lancaster, New Hampshire:&lt;/strong&gt; Betty and Barney Hill claimed to have been abducted by extraterrestrials, known as the Betty and Barney Hill abduction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 24, 1964, Socorro, New Mexico:&lt;/strong&gt; Lonnie Zamora, a New Mexico police officer, reported a UFO close encounter, known as the Lonnie Zamora incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 3, 1965, Exeter, New Hampshire:&lt;/strong&gt; The Exeter incident involved a large UFO sighting by a teenager and two police officers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 9, 1965, Kecksburg, Pennsylvania:&lt;/strong&gt; The Kecksburg UFO incident involved a large fireball seen over multiple states and Canada, with reports of metal debris.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1969, Leary, Georgia:&lt;/strong&gt; Jimmy Carter claimed to have seen a UFO and filed a report with the International UFO Bureau, known as the Jimmy Carter UFO incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 11, 1973, Pascagoula, Mississippi:&lt;/strong&gt; Charles Hickson and Calvin Parker claimed to have been abducted, known as the Pascagoula Abduction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 12, 1975, North Bergen, New Jersey:&lt;/strong&gt; The Stonehenge incident occurred near the Stonehenge apartment building in North Bergen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 5, 1975, Snowflake, Arizona:&lt;/strong&gt; Travis Walton claimed to have been abducted by a UFO while working on a logging crew, known as the Travis Walton UFO incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 17, 1977, Council Bluffs, Iowa:&lt;/strong&gt; Residents reported seeing a reddish fireball and a grass fire with molten metal, which was later identified as common high-carbon steel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 27, 1979, Stephen, Minnesota:&lt;/strong&gt; Deputy Sheriff Val Johnson&amp;rsquo;s patrol car was struck by a ball of light, known as the Val Johnson incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 29, 1980, Dayton, Texas:&lt;/strong&gt; The Cash-Landrum Incident involved a reported UFO sighting and subsequent health issues for the witnesses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 11, 1987, Gulf Breeze, Florida:&lt;/strong&gt; The Gulf Breeze UFO incident occurred.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March 8, 1994, Multiple Locations, Michigan:&lt;/strong&gt; Over 100 witnesses reported seeing multiple objects with colored lights, known as the 1994 Lake Michigan UFO event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March 13, 1997, Phoenix, Arizona:&lt;/strong&gt; The Phoenix Lights involved a series of optical phenomena seen by thousands. The USAF identified them as flares, but former Governor Fife Symington claimed to have seen a delta-shaped craft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 5, 2000, Highland, Illinois:&lt;/strong&gt; The &amp;ldquo;St. Clair Triangle&amp;rdquo; sighting involved multiple police officers and witnesses reporting a massive, silent, triangular aircraft, known as the Black Triangle (UFO).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 21, 2004, Chicago, Illinois:&lt;/strong&gt; A triangular formation of reddish lights was seen by hundreds of witnesses over Chicago suburbs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 7, 2006, Chicago, Illinois:&lt;/strong&gt; Employees at Chicago O&amp;rsquo;Hare International Airport reported seeing a metallic, saucer-shaped craft, known as the Chicago O&amp;rsquo;Hare UFO sighting 2006.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 5, 2009, Morristown, New Jersey:&lt;/strong&gt; Five unidentified red objects were seen. Joe Rudy and Chris Russo later admitted it was a hoax, known as the Morristown UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 19, 2018, Desert, Arizona:&lt;/strong&gt; Commercial pilots reported seeing an unidentified object, later attributed to a &amp;ldquo;high-altitude research balloon.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 21, 2021, Clayton, New Mexico:&lt;/strong&gt; A pilot reported seeing a long cylindrical object moving rapidly, confirmed by American Airlines. The FAA did not detect any object on radar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 10, 2023, Deadhorse, Alaska:&lt;/strong&gt; A high-altitude object was shot down over the Beaufort Sea by the U.S. Air Force, known as the 2023 Alaska high-altitude object.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 12, 2023, Lake Huron, Michigan:&lt;/strong&gt; An octagonal object was shot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_the_United_States&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_the_United_States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
