<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Refugees on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/refugees/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Refugees on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 03:42:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/refugees/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Nation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_ecb551d0af0a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 03:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_ecb551d0af0a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-nation&#34;&gt;Alien Nation &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-nation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt; is an American science fiction media franchise created by Rockne S. O&amp;rsquo;Bannon, known for &lt;em&gt;Farscape&lt;/em&gt;. The franchise, owned by 20th Century Studios, encompasses film, television, novels, and comics centered around alien refugees living on Earth. It blends science fiction with elements of drama, police procedural, and buddy cop genres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting&#34;&gt;Setting &lt;a href=&#34;#setting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The franchise is set in the near future in the United States, specifically starting in 1991. A flying saucer crashes in the Mojave Desert, revealing the Tenctonese, an extraterrestrial race referred to as &amp;ldquo;Newcomers.&amp;rdquo; These aliens are escaping slavery from a cruel Overseer race. The Tenctonese resemble humans but possess anatomical differences and enhanced physical and intellectual capabilities due to selective breeding. The core concept revolves around the Newcomers&amp;rsquo; integration into American society, exploring themes of multiculturalism and acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;film&#34;&gt;Film &lt;a href=&#34;#film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The franchise began with the 1988 film &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt;, released by 20th Century Fox. The film depicts the integration of the Tenctonese refugees, or Newcomers, into human society in Los Angeles. It combines science fiction and police drama elements. The film stars Mandy Patinkin as Sam &amp;ldquo;George&amp;rdquo; Francisco, a Newcomer detective in the Los Angeles Police Department, and James Caan as Matthew Sykes, his initially reluctant human partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;television&#34;&gt;Television &lt;a href=&#34;#television&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1989, Fox adapted the film into a television series, also called &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt;. The series follows the same premise as the film, focusing on the Newcomers&amp;rsquo; integration after their ship crashes on Earth. Eric Pierpoint stars as George Francisco, and Gary Graham as Matthew Sikes. The series explores themes of racism and the treatment of minority ethnic groups. The series ran for one season of 21 episodes and a pilot episode, ending in 1990. Fox abruptly cancelled the series after the season. Beginning in 1994, the network continued the story in five TV movies, which brought back the entire cast. The installments include &lt;em&gt;Dark Horizon&lt;/em&gt; (1994), &lt;em&gt;Body and Soul&lt;/em&gt; (1995), &lt;em&gt;Millennium&lt;/em&gt; (1996), &lt;em&gt;The Enemy Within&lt;/em&gt; (1996), and &lt;em&gt;The Udara Legacy&lt;/em&gt; (1997).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;novels&#34;&gt;Novels &lt;a href=&#34;#novels&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pocket Books, a division of Simon &amp;amp; Schuster, published a novel series connected to the franchise starting in 1993. Judith and Garfield Reeves-Stevens, known for their work in &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;, wrote a novel entitled &lt;em&gt;Day of Descent&lt;/em&gt;. Some novels served as prequels to the movie sequels, such as K.W. Jeter&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Cross of Blood&lt;/em&gt;, a tie-in to the &lt;em&gt;Dark Horizon&lt;/em&gt; film, and Peter David&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Body and Soul&lt;/em&gt;, which became one of the sequels of the same name. The novels regularly addressed racism and discrimination with extraterrestrial themes. K. W. Jeter and Barry B. Longyear were regular contributors to the series with novels like, &lt;em&gt;The Change&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Slag Like Me&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comics&#34;&gt;Comics &lt;a href=&#34;#comics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 1990 to 1992, Malibu Comics published several comics adapting the &lt;em&gt;Alien Nation&lt;/em&gt; storyline. Among the first released titles were &lt;em&gt;The Spartans&lt;/em&gt;, created with the help of author Bill Spangler and illustrator James Tucker, and &lt;em&gt;A Breed Apart&lt;/em&gt;, authored by Steve Jones. Other titles included &lt;em&gt;Public Enemy&lt;/em&gt;, authored by Sandy Carruthers and illustrated by Lowell Cunningham, and a crossover series with the &lt;em&gt;Planet of the Apes&lt;/em&gt; franchise titled &lt;em&gt;Ape Nation&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;Ape Nation&lt;/em&gt; series included four different adventures called &lt;em&gt;Plans&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Pasts&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Pawns&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Pains&lt;/em&gt; along with a collector&amp;rsquo;s edition. Other contributors to the series included illustrators Terry Pallott and Leonard Kirk to titles like, &lt;em&gt;The Skin Trade&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;remake&#34;&gt;Remake &lt;a href=&#34;#remake&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On March 25, 2015, Fox announced a remake with Art Marcum and Matt Holloway writing. On September 9, 2016, &lt;em&gt;Deadline&lt;/em&gt; reported that Jeff Nichols would write and direct the film. On January 25, 2021, it was announced that Jeff Nichols would remake the film as a ten-part television series. On June 21, 2024, it was reported Nichols was developing an original sci-fi feature film for Paramount instead of an Alien Nation project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Nation&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Nation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
