<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 13:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien abduction</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_85a477e6d898/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_85a477e6d898/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-abduction&#34;&gt;Alien Abduction &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-abduction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alien abduction, also known as abduction phenomenon, alien abduction syndrome, or UFO abduction, is the subjective experience of individuals reporting being kidnapped by extraterrestrial beings and subjected to physical and psychological experimentation. These individuals are often referred to as &amp;ldquo;abductees&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;experiencers.&amp;rdquo; While most scientists and mental health professionals attribute these experiences to factors like suggestibility, sleep paralysis, deception, and psychopathology, some researchers give credence to the claims. Typical claims involve forced medical examinations, often focusing on reproductive systems, warnings about environmental abuses and nuclear weapons, or interspecies breeding. The content of these narratives often varies with the abductee&amp;rsquo;s cultural background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainstream scientists generally reject the literal interpretation of alien abduction claims. However, some, like psychiatrist John E. Mack, argue that many abductees are sane individuals, with psychopathology only present in some cases. Detailed abduction reports have led to the development of a subculture with support groups and a complex mythos explaining the roles, origins, and motivations of various alien types, such as Greys, Reptilians, and Nordics. Some abductees engage in independent research and attribute the lack of wider awareness to extraterrestrial or governmental cover-ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;paleo-abductions&#34;&gt;Paleo-abductions &lt;a href=&#34;#paleo-abductions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the widespread attention to alien abduction in the 1960s, some older stories have been reinterpreted as possible early cases, termed &amp;ldquo;paleo-abductions&amp;rdquo; by UFO researcher Jerome Clark. One example is Colonel H. G. Shaw&amp;rsquo;s 1896 claim of being harassed by tall, slender humanoids. An article from 1953 asked if flying saucers were kidnapping humans for zoological specimens or vivisection. The 1955 publication of Harold T. Wilkins&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Flying Saucers Uncensored&lt;/em&gt; reported speculation that Karl Hunrath and Wilbur Wilkinson, who claimed alien contact, disappeared due to abduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;two-landmark-cases&#34;&gt;Two landmark cases &lt;a href=&#34;#two-landmark-cases&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Antônio Vilas-Boas case in Brazil during the mid-1950s was an early claim but received limited attention initially. The Betty and Barney Hill abduction in 1961 gained widespread publicity, including a 1975 television film. The Hill incident is considered a prototypical abduction case, possibly the first to describe beings later known as the Greys and explicitly identify an extraterrestrial origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;later-developments&#34;&gt;Later developments &lt;a href=&#34;#later-developments&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R. Leo Sprinkle, a psychologist at the University of Wyoming, became interested in the phenomenon in the 1960s and linked abductions to cattle mutilation. Budd Hopkins became a key figure in the abductee subculture in the 1970s, using hypnosis to uncover details of remembered events. The 1980s saw increased mainstream attention, with works by Hopkins, Whitley Strieber, David M. Jacobs, and John E. Mack presenting alien abduction as a plausible experience. Thomas E. Bullard&amp;rsquo;s comparative analysis of nearly 300 alleged abductees was also published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jacobs and Hopkins argued that alien abduction was more common than previously thought, estimating tens of thousands of North Americans had been abducted. They also proposed an alien effort to create human-alien hybrids. While anecdotal reports of phantom pregnancies related to UFO encounters existed earlier, Hopkins and Jacobs popularized the idea of widespread interbreeding efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Boston Globe&lt;/em&gt; writer Linda Rodriguez McRobbie, alien abduction stories have declined in mainstream media. Michael Shermer suggests that the ubiquity of camera phones has increased the burden of evidence, contributing to the decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;john-e-mack&#34;&gt;John E. Mack &lt;a href=&#34;#john-e-mack&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harvard psychiatry professor John E. Mack believed in the credibility of alien abduction claims. Niall Boyce, writing in &lt;em&gt;The Lancet&lt;/em&gt;, suggested that Mack&amp;rsquo;s work in hypnotic regression helped spread the Grey aliens meme. Mack interviewed over 800 people and wrote two books on the subject. His professional reputation suffered due to his belief and promotion of abduction claims, leading to a Harvard review in 1994.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abductees&#34;&gt;Abductees &lt;a href=&#34;#abductees&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The precise number of alleged abductees is uncertain. Early studies found 1,700 claimants, while contested surveys suggested 5–6 percent of the general population claim to have been abducted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;demographics&#34;&gt;Demographics &lt;a href=&#34;#demographics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While abduction reports are usually made by adults, children sometimes report similar experiences. These reports often share specific details with adult reports, including circumstances, narrative, entities, and aftermaths. Young abductees often have family members who have reported abduction experiences, and family involvement in the military or residence near a military base is also common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mental-health&#34;&gt;Mental health &lt;a href=&#34;#mental-health&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some studies suggest that abductees have psychological characteristics that render their testimony suspect, while others show that abductees are not different from the general population in terms of psychopathology prevalence. Elizabeth Slater&amp;rsquo;s blind study found abductees prone to &amp;ldquo;mildly paranoid thinking,&amp;rdquo; nightmares, and weak sexual identity, while Richard McNally&amp;rsquo;s study concluded that none of the abductees suffered from psychiatric illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;political-conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;Political conspiracy theories &lt;a href=&#34;#political-conspiracy-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Political scientist Michael Barkun highlights links between radical politics and conspiracy theories involving UFOs, alien visitation, environmental pollution, hidden groups, and government takeover. He observed the rise of &amp;ldquo;improvisional millenarism.&amp;rdquo; UFO and abduction stories can be part of stigmatized knowledge narratives. UFO and alien-related conspiracy theories emerged in far-right politics from the 1980s onwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Barkun, TV shows like &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt; included aliens as part of coverup conspiracies, with militias and black helicopters, and demonized FEMA. Political scientist Jodi Dean noted that the stigma of alien abduction stories is seductive to dismiss &amp;ldquo;consensus reality&amp;rdquo; in favor of deviant alternative realities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-described abduction victims often join self-help communities and may resort to questionable regression therapy. Some espouse conspiracy theories of technological mind control, including implants, to force them to serve a New World Order or for the purposes of the antichrist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abduction-narrative&#34;&gt;Abduction narrative &lt;a href=&#34;#abduction-narrative&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various researchers have noted common points in report narratives. CUFOS defines an abductee as someone taken against their will by non-human beings to an extraterrestrial place or spaceship, subjected to examination or communication, with memories that may be conscious or recovered through hypnosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although cases vary, some UFO researchers argue that there is a fairly consistent sequence and description of events that make up the typical &amp;ldquo;close encounter of the fourth kind.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bullard argues most abduction accounts feature the following events:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capture&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductee is rendered incapable of resisting and taken to an alien spacecraft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Examination and Procedures&lt;/strong&gt;: Invasive physiological and psychological procedures, and on occasion simulated behavioral situations, training &amp;amp; testing, or sexual liaisons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conference&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductors communicate with the abductee or direct them to interact with specific individuals for some purpose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tour&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductees are given a tour of their captors&amp;rsquo; vessel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loss of Time&lt;/strong&gt;: Abductees often rapidly forget the majority of their experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Return&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductees are returned to earth, occasionally in a different location or with new injuries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theophany&lt;/strong&gt;: Abductees may have a profound sense of love, a &amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo; similar to those induced by certain drugs, or a &amp;ldquo;mystical experience&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aftermath&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductee must cope with the psychological, physical, and social effects of the experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David M. Jacobs says that the entire abduction event is precisely orchestrated, with predetermined procedures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;capture&#34;&gt;Capture &lt;a href=&#34;#capture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abduction claimants report unusual feelings preceding the onset of an abduction experience, such as a compulsive desire to be at a certain place or expectations that something &amp;ldquo;familiar yet unknown&amp;rdquo; will occur. They also report feeling severe anxiety. Eventually, the experiencer will undergo an apparent &amp;ldquo;shift&amp;rdquo; into an altered state of consciousness. External sounds cease to have any significance, and they report feeling introspective and unusually calm. As consciousness shifts, lights are alleged to appear, occasionally accompanied by a strange mist. As the alleged abduction proceeds, claimants say they will walk or be levitated into an alien craft, often through solid objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;examination&#34;&gt;Examination &lt;a href=&#34;#examination&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The examination phase is characterized by medical procedures and examinations by alien beings against the will of the experiencer. Such procedures often focus on sex and reproductive biology. The entity in charge of the operation is often taller than the others and may appear to be of a different species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miller notes different areas of emphasis between human medicine and what is reported as being practiced by the abductors. The abductors&amp;rsquo; areas of interest appear to be the cranium, nervous system, skin, reproductive system, and joints. Systems given less attention include the cardiovascular system, the respiratory system below the pharynx, and the lymphatic system. The abductors also appear to ignore the upper region of the abdomen in favor of the lower one. The abductors do not appear to wear gloves during the &amp;ldquo;examination.&amp;rdquo; Other constants of terrestrial medicine like pills and tablets are missing from abduction narratives, although sometimes abductees are asked to drink liquids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;subsequent-procedures&#34;&gt;Subsequent procedures &lt;a href=&#34;#subsequent-procedures&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the medical exam, the alleged abductees often report other procedures being performed with the entities. Common among these post-examination procedures are imaging, envisioning, staging, and testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Imaging&amp;rdquo; procedures consist of an abductee being made to view screens displaying images and scenes that appear to be specially chosen with the intent to provoke certain emotional responses in the abductee. &amp;ldquo;Envisioning&amp;rdquo; is a similar procedure, with the primary difference being that the images being viewed, rather than being on a screen, actually seem to be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_abduction&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_abduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of UFO religions</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_c138a4063c7d/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_c138a4063c7d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-religions&#34;&gt;UFO Religions &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-religions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFO religions are groups that incorporate beliefs about communication with extraterrestrial beings into their religious doctrines. These groups often interpret major religions as being based on supernatural beings from heaven. Communication methods include telepathy and astral projection. A common belief is that humanity can be saved through education provided by aliens, leading to societal improvement. Alien abduction experiences can also contribute to the formation of these religions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for understanding UFO religions. It highlights that these religions generally involve belief in communication with extraterrestrial beings, often through physical contact, telepathy, or astral projection. These groups typically believe that aliens will save humanity by teaching them a better way to live, sometimes by taking believers to a more positive location. UFO religions emphasize spiritual growth and the evolution of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. Gordon Melton is identified as considering the &amp;ldquo;I AM&amp;rdquo; Activity, founded by Guy Ballard, as the first UFO religion. However, Christopher Hugh Partridge views it as a theosophical religion rather than a UFO religion. Partridge emphasizes the belief within UFO religions that supreme beings originate from other planets or planes, not from Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Roswell incident of 1947 is identified as a key event in the history of UFO spirituality, marking the emergence of UFOs into public consciousness. UFO religion is placed within the context of theosophical esotericism and New Age thought, with many groups believing that extraterrestrial beings are heralds of a new era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Aetherius Society, founded by George King in 1955, is described as one of the first and most enduring UFO cults. Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate and the Order of the Solar Temple are mentioned as controversial groups combining UFO beliefs with contactee assertions. Scientology is also discussed as a UFO religion due to its Xenu cosmogony and space opera elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;list&#34;&gt;List &lt;a href=&#34;#list&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a table listing various UFO religions, their founders, and the year they were founded. The list includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aetherius Society:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by George King in 1955.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ashtar Galactic Command:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Thelma B. Terrill (&amp;ldquo;Tuella&amp;rdquo;) in 1977.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CEIRUS:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Jean Miguères in 1987.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chen Tao:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Hon-ming Chen in 1993.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christ Brotherhood:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Wallace C. Halsey in 1956.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cosmic Circle of Fellowship:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by William R. Ferguson in 1955.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fiat Lux:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Uriella in 1980.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freie Interessengemeinschaft für Grenz- und Geisteswissenschaften und Ufologiestudien:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Billy Meier in the 1970s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ground Crew Project:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Sheldon Nidle in the 1980s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Marshall Applewhite and Bonnie Nettles in the 1970s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;I AM&amp;rdquo; Activity:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Guy Ballard in the 1930s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industrial Church of the New World Comforter:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Allen Michael in 1973.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark-Age:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Charles Boyd Gentzel and Pauline Sharpe in 1962.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nation of Islam:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Wallace Fard Muhammad in 1930.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Néo-Phare:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Arnaud Mussy in 2001.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nuwaubian Nation:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Dwight York in the 1970s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Order of the Solar Temple:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Joseph Di Mambro and Luc Jouret in 1984.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raëlism:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Raël in 1974.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rational Culture:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Manoel Jacintho Coelho in the 1930s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sanctuary of Thought:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Truman Bethurum in the 1950s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Seekers:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Charles Laughead (aka &amp;ldquo;Dr. Armstrong&amp;rdquo;) or Dorothy Martin (aka &amp;ldquo;Marian Keech&amp;rdquo;) in 1953.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Siderella:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Jean-Paul Appel-Guéry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scientology:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by L. Ron Hubbard in 1952.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unarius:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Ernest Norman and Ruth Norman in 1954.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universe People:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Ivo A. Benda in 1997.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Urantia movement:&lt;/strong&gt; Authorship of &lt;em&gt;The Urantia Book&lt;/em&gt; is unknown and disputed. The book alleges it was written by celestial beings. Founded between 1924 and 1955.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vale do Amanhecer:&lt;/strong&gt; Founded by Neiva Chaves Zelaya in the 1960s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics and links for further exploration, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Religion portal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outer space portal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doomsday cult&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of new religious movements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of ufologists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of UFO organizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO_religions&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO_religions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nordic aliens</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7c6654f96aa5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 22:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7c6654f96aa5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alleged-humanoid-extraterrestrials&#34;&gt;Alleged humanoid extraterrestrials &lt;a href=&#34;#alleged-humanoid-extraterrestrials&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry focuses on &amp;ldquo;Nordics,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Nordic aliens,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Tall Whites,&amp;rdquo; which are names given in ufology to humanoid races purportedly from the Pleiades star cluster. These beings are described as resembling Nordic, Germanic, or Scandinavian humans, with features like tall stature (6-7 ft), blond hair, blue eyes, and fair skin. Some accounts mention pale-blue/grey or pastel purple skin tones. George Adamski is noted as one of the first to report contact with these beings in the 1950s. The mythology surrounding them often includes telepathy, benevolence, and physical beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the historical context and cultural influences related to the Nordic alien phenomenon. David J. Skal suggests that the 1951 film &lt;em&gt;The Day the Earth Stood Still&lt;/em&gt; may have inspired early stories. Stephanie Kelley-Romano describes alien abduction beliefs as a &amp;ldquo;living myth,&amp;rdquo; associating Nordic aliens with spiritual growth and protection. These aliens are often portrayed as benevolent beings concerned with Earth&amp;rsquo;s ecology and world peace, possessing telepathic powers and described as paternal and youthful. While popular in the 1950s, claims of encounters became less common as the grey alien archetype rose to prominence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publications-by-those-claiming-to-have-been-contacted&#34;&gt;Publications by those claiming to have been contacted &lt;a href=&#34;#publications-by-those-claiming-to-have-been-contacted&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists books written by individuals who claim to have had personal contact with Nordic aliens. These include &lt;em&gt;Flying Saucers Have Landed&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Inside the Space Ships&lt;/em&gt; by George Adamski, &lt;em&gt;From Outer Space to You&lt;/em&gt; by Howard Menger, &lt;em&gt;The Walton Experience&lt;/em&gt; by Travis Walton, and &lt;em&gt;Millennial Hospitality&lt;/em&gt; by Charles James Hall (adapted into the film &lt;em&gt;Walking with the Tall Whites&lt;/em&gt;). The UFO religion Universe People also publishes interactions as &amp;ldquo;Talks with Teachings from my Cosmic Friends.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics and figures in ufology, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Space Brothers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Truman Bethurum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elizabeth Klarer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Billy Meier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linda Moulton Howe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of alleged extraterrestrial beings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star people (New Age)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arcturians (New Age)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFOs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFO religion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including books and academic papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to Wikimedia Commons for media related to Nordic aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_aliens&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_aliens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nordic aliens</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cf4950bfe155/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 22:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_cf4950bfe155/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alleged-humanoid-extraterrestrials&#34;&gt;Alleged humanoid extraterrestrials &lt;a href=&#34;#alleged-humanoid-extraterrestrials&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry focuses on &amp;ldquo;Nordics,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Nordic aliens,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Tall Whites,&amp;rdquo; a type of humanoid extraterrestrial beings often discussed in ufology. These beings are said to originate from the Pleiades star cluster and are described as resembling Nordic, Germanic, or Scandinavian humans. They are typically depicted as taller than average humans (6-7 ft), with blond hair, blue eyes, and fair skin. Some accounts mention skin tones of pale blue/grey or pastel purple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;George Adamski, a Polish-American ufologist, is noted as one of the first to publicly claim contact with Nordic beings in the 1950s. The mythology surrounding these beings often includes themes of telepathy, benevolence, beauty, and grace. Telepathy is often described as the primary form of communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the historical context and cultural influences surrounding the Nordic alien narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cultural historian David J. Skal suggests that the 1951 film &lt;em&gt;The Day the Earth Stood Still&lt;/em&gt; may have inspired early stories of Nordic-type aliens. The film features an extraterrestrial arriving on Earth to warn humanity about the dangers of atomic weapons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bates College professor Stephanie Kelley-Romano describes alien abduction beliefs as a &amp;ldquo;living myth,&amp;rdquo; noting that Nordic aliens are often associated with spiritual growth, love, and protection among believers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nordic aliens are often portrayed as benevolent beings concerned about Earth&amp;rsquo;s ecology and world peace, possessing telepathic powers and described as paternal, watchful, smiling, affectionate, and youthful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Claims of encounters with Nordic aliens were common in Europe during the 1950s but became less frequent in later decades, as the grey alien became more prevalent in extraterrestrial encounter accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;publications-by-those-claiming-to-have-been-contacted&#34;&gt;Publications by those claiming to have been contacted &lt;a href=&#34;#publications-by-those-claiming-to-have-been-contacted&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists books written by individuals who claim to have had personal contact with Nordic aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The books mentioned include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flying Saucers Have Landed&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Inside the Space Ships&lt;/em&gt; by George Adamski&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Outer Space to You&lt;/em&gt; by Howard Menger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Walton Experience&lt;/em&gt; by Travis Walton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Millennial Hospitality&lt;/em&gt; by Charles James Hall (adapted into the film &lt;em&gt;Walking with the Tall Whites&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UFO religion Universe People also publishes interactions as &amp;ldquo;Talks with Teachings from my Cosmic Friends&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics and figures within the realm of ufology and extraterrestrial beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Space Brothers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Truman Bethurum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elizabeth Klarer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Billy Meier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linda Moulton Howe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of alleged extraterrestrial beings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star people (New Age)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arcturians (New Age)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFOs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFO religion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the references used in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to media related to Nordic aliens on Wikimedia Commons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_alien&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_alien&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for extraterrestrial intelligence</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1448d6266380/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_1448d6266380/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence-seti&#34;&gt;Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence (SETI) &lt;a href=&#34;#search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence-seti&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The search for extraterrestrial intelligence (SETI) encompasses various scientific projects aimed at detecting signals or evidence of intelligent life beyond Earth. These efforts involve monitoring electromagnetic radiation, searching for optical signals, and investigating potential extraterrestrial artifacts. Some initiatives, like NASA&amp;rsquo;s Golden Record, have also attempted to send messages to hypothetical alien civilizations. Despite decades of searching, no confirmed evidence of alien intelligence has been found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the historical progression of SETI efforts, from early speculations to modern scientific projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-work&#34;&gt;Early Work &lt;a href=&#34;#early-work&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early searches for extraterrestrial intelligence within the Solar System are highlighted. Nikola Tesla suggested using his wireless electrical transmission system to contact beings on Mars in 1896. In 1899, he thought he detected a signal from Mars at his Colorado Springs experimental station. Guglielmo Marconi, Lord Kelvin, and David Peck Todd also believed radio could be used to contact Martians in the early 1900s. In 1924, during a close opposition of Mars, the United States observed a &amp;ldquo;National Radio Silence Day&amp;rdquo; to listen for Martian signals, with William F. Friedman assigned to translate any potential messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-ozma-and-early-radio-astronomy&#34;&gt;Project Ozma and Early Radio Astronomy &lt;a href=&#34;#project-ozma-and-early-radio-astronomy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possibility of searching the microwave spectrum was first pointed out in a 1959 paper by Philip Morrison and Giuseppe Cocconi. In 1960, Frank Drake performed the first modern SETI experiment, Project Ozma, at Green Bank, West Virginia, examining the stars Tau Ceti and Epsilon Eridani. Soviet scientists also took a strong interest in SETI during the 1960s. Iosif Shklovsky wrote the book &lt;em&gt;Universe, Life, Intelligence&lt;/em&gt; (1962), which was expanded upon by Carl Sagan as &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Life in the Universe&lt;/em&gt; (1966). John D. Kraus&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Big Ear&amp;rdquo; radio telescope at Ohio State University began the world&amp;rsquo;s first continuous SETI program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-cyclops-and-the-wow-signal&#34;&gt;Project Cyclops and the Wow! Signal &lt;a href=&#34;#project-cyclops-and-the-wow-signal&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1971, NASA funded a SETI study that proposed the construction of an Earth-based radio telescope array with 1,500 dishes known as Project Cyclops. The project was not built, but the report formed the basis of much SETI work that followed. The Ohio State SETI program gained fame on August 15, 1977, when Jerry Ehman witnessed a strong signal, the Wow! signal, which is considered by some to be the best candidate for a radio signal from an extraterrestrial source ever discovered. In May 2023, a test extraterrestrial signal was transmitted to radio telescopes on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sentinel-meta-and-beta&#34;&gt;Sentinel, META, and BETA &lt;a href=&#34;#sentinel-meta-and-beta&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1980, Carl Sagan, Bruce Murray, and Louis Friedman founded the U.S. Planetary Society, partly as a vehicle for SETI studies. In the early 1980s, Harvard University physicist Paul Horowitz proposed the design of a spectrum analyzer specifically intended to search for SETI transmissions. This work led to &amp;ldquo;Suitcase SETI&amp;rdquo; in 1981, followed by Project META in 1985, and Project BETA in 1995. On March 23, 1999, the 26-meter radio telescope on which Sentinel, META and BETA were based was blown over by strong winds and seriously damaged, forcing the BETA project to cease operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mop-and-project-phoenix&#34;&gt;MOP and Project Phoenix &lt;a href=&#34;#mop-and-project-phoenix&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1978, the NASA SETI program was heavily criticized by Senator William Proxmire, and funding for SETI research was removed from the NASA budget by Congress in 1981. In 1992, the U.S. government funded an operational SETI program, in the form of the NASA Microwave Observing Program (MOP). MOP was canceled one year after its start. In 1995, the SETI Institute resurrected the MOP program under the name of Project Phoenix, under the direction of Jill Tarter. From 1995 through March 2004, Phoenix conducted observations at the Parkes radio telescope in Australia, the National Radio Astronomy Observatory in Green Bank, West Virginia, and the Arecibo Observatory in Puerto Rico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ongoing-radio-searches&#34;&gt;Ongoing Radio Searches &lt;a href=&#34;#ongoing-radio-searches&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the current state of radio-based SETI projects and the rationale behind focusing on radio frequencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many radio frequencies penetrate Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere well, leading to the development of radio telescopes. Human endeavors emit considerable electromagnetic radiation, which could be recognizable as artificial signals. Earth has been sending radio waves into space for over 100 years, reaching over 1,000 stars. Many international radio telescopes are currently being used for radio SETI searches, including the Low Frequency Array (LOFAR) in Europe, the Murchison Widefield Array (MWA) in Australia, and the Lovell Telescope in the United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;allen-telescope-array&#34;&gt;Allen Telescope Array &lt;a href=&#34;#allen-telescope-array&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SETI Institute collaborated with the Radio Astronomy Laboratory at the Berkeley SETI Research Center to develop the Allen Telescope Array (ATA). The array has 42 operational dishes at the Hat Creek Radio Observatory in rural northern California. The SETI Institute&amp;rsquo;s Center for SETI Research (CSR) uses ATA in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence, observing 12 hours a day, 7 days a week. Berkeley astronomers used the ATA to pursue several science topics until 2011, when the collaboration between the University of California, Berkeley and the SETI Institute was terminated. In 2012, the ATA was revitalized with a donation by Franklin Antonio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;serendip&#34;&gt;SERENDIP &lt;a href=&#34;#serendip&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SERENDIP (Search for Extraterrestrial Radio Emissions from Nearby Developed Intelligent Populations) is a SETI program launched in 1979 by the Berkeley SETI Research Center. SERENDIP analyzes deep space radio telescope data that it obtains while other astronomers are using the telescopes. The most recently deployed SERENDIP spectrometer, SERENDIP VI, was installed at both the Arecibo Telescope and the Green Bank Telescope in 2014–2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;breakthrough-listen&#34;&gt;Breakthrough Listen &lt;a href=&#34;#breakthrough-listen&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Breakthrough Listen&lt;/em&gt; is a ten-year initiative with $100 million funding begun in July 2015 to actively search for intelligent extraterrestrial communications in the universe. The science program for Breakthrough Listen is based at Berkeley SETI Research Center. The project is observing for thousands of hours every year on two major radio telescopes, the Green Bank Observatory in West Virginia, and the Parkes Observatory in Australia. Frank Drake was one of the scientists on the project&amp;rsquo;s advisory committee. In October 2019, Breakthrough Listen started a collaboration with scientists from the TESS team to look for signs of advanced extraterrestrial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fast&#34;&gt;FAST &lt;a href=&#34;#fast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China&amp;rsquo;s 500 meter Aperture Spherical Telescope (FAST) lists &lt;em&gt;detecting interstellar communication signals&lt;/em&gt; as part of its science mission. FAST is the first radio observatory built with SETI as a core scientific goal. On 14 June 2022, astronomers, working with China&amp;rsquo;s FAST telescope, reported the possibility of having detected artificial signals, but cautioned that further studies were required to determine if a natural radio interference may be the source. Dan Werthimer noted, &amp;ldquo;These signals are from radio interference; they are due to radio pollution from earthlings, not from E.T.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ucla&#34;&gt;UCLA &lt;a href=&#34;#ucla&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2016, University of California Los Angeles (UCLA) undergraduate and graduate students have been participating in radio searches for technosignatures with the Green Bank Telescope. Targets include the Kepler field, TRAPPIST-1, and solar-type stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;community-seti-projects&#34;&gt;Community SETI Projects &lt;a href=&#34;#community-seti-projects&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights SETI projects that rely on the contributions of volunteers and the general public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;setihome&#34;&gt;SETI@home &lt;a href=&#34;#setihome&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SETI@home project used volunteer computing to analyze signals acquired by the SERENDIP project. The SETI@home project was launched by the Berkeley SETI Research Center at the University of California, Berkeley, in May 1999. The project is run by director David P. Anderson and chief scientist Dan Werthimer. On March 31, 2020, the project stopped sending out new work to SETI@home users, bringing this particular SETI effort to an indefinite hiatus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;seti-net&#34;&gt;SETI Net &lt;a href=&#34;#seti-net&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SETI Network was the only fully operational private search system. SETI Net started operation in the early 1980s as a way to learn about the science of the search, and developed several software packages for the amateur SETI community. SETI Net went dark and was decommissioned on 2021-12-04.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-seti-league-and-project-argus&#34;&gt;The SETI League and Project Argus &lt;a href=&#34;#the-seti-league-and-project-argus&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1994 in response to the United States Congress cancellation of the NASA SETI program, The SETI League, Incorporated is a membership-supported nonprofit organization. This grass-roots alliance of amateur and professional radio astronomers is headed by executive director emeritus H. Paul Shuch. The organization concentrates on coordinating a global network of small, amateur-built radio telescopes under Project Argus, an all-sky survey seeking to achieve real-time coverage of the entire sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;optical-experiments&#34;&gt;Optical Experiments &lt;a href=&#34;#optical-experiments&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the search for extraterrestrial intelligence using optical wavelengths, such as lasers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some SETI researchers have considered the possibility that alien civilizations might be using powerful lasers for interstellar communications at optical wavelengths. There are two problems with optical SETI: lasers are highly &amp;ldquo;monochromatic&amp;rdquo;, and lasers are highly directional&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SETI&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SETI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancient astronauts</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_96b21753a786/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 08:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_96b21753a786/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ancient-astronauts&#34;&gt;Ancient Astronauts &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-astronauts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ancient astronauts, also known as ancient aliens, is a pseudoscientific belief that intelligent extraterrestrial beings visited Earth in ancient times and influenced human civilization. Proponents suggest that these aliens affected the development of cultures, technologies, religions, and even human biology. A common idea is that deities in many religions were actually extraterrestrials, and their advanced technologies were seen as divine powers by early humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This idea is rejected by academics and archaeologists, who consider it pseudoarchaeology and unscientific. Claims are often based on distorted or fabricated evidence. Some critics argue that ancient astronaut theories have racist implications, diminishing the achievements of indigenous cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notable proponents in the late 20th century include Robert Charroux, Jacques Bergier, Jean Sendy, Erich von Däniken, Alexander Kazantsev, Zecharia Sitchin, Robert K. G. Temple, Giorgio A. Tsoukalos, David Hatcher Childress, Peter Kolosimo, and Mauro Biglino.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various terms are used to describe claims about ancient astronauts, including ancient aliens, ancient ufonauts, ancient space pilots, paleocontact, astronaut- or alien gods, and paleo- or biblical-SETI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believers often claim that humans are descendants or creations of extraterrestrial intelligence that landed on Earth in the past. They suggest that human knowledge, religion, and culture originated from these ancient alien visitors, who acted as a &amp;ldquo;mother culture.&amp;rdquo; Proponents also claim that extraterrestrials built or helped humans build structures like the Egyptian pyramids and the Moai stone heads of Easter Island. Evidence is said to come from gaps in historical and archaeological records, as well as artifacts that are considered anachronistic and beyond the technical capabilities of ancient people. These &amp;ldquo;out-of-place artifacts&amp;rdquo; include artwork and legends reinterpreted to support extraterrestrial contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is featured in fringe media, such as the History Channel series &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;. The show mixes fact with fiction to promote theories of an alternate past, often incorporating white supremacist, nativist, imperialist, settler-colonial, and Christian Identity beliefs. Proponents portray themselves as an oppressed minority of academics challenging mainstream archaeology, despite lacking credentials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like past archaeological endeavors, the focus is on monumental structures, suggesting that indigenous people could not have built them without alien help. However, some indigenous voices argue that ancient alien theory supports their stories of extraterrestrial origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common theme is the portrayal of aliens as light-skinned or Aryan, as claimed by Erich von Däniken. Some proponents are associated with white supremacism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainstream archaeologists have largely ignored these claims, while popular science explainers and skeptics have criticized them. Carl Sagan noted that cases of apparent interest have reasonable alternative explanations, misreporting, or are hoaxes and distortions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34;&gt;History of Ancient Aliens Beliefs and Their Proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paleocontact narratives appeared in early science fiction of the late 19th and early 20th centuries, including &lt;em&gt;Edison&amp;rsquo;s Conquest of Mars&lt;/em&gt; (1898) and the works of H.P. Lovecraft. Harold T. Wilkins proposed the idea in earnest in 1954. It gained popularity in the 1960s due to the Space Race and Erich von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s works. Critics emerged in the 1970s, discrediting Von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s claims. By the early 1980s, support dwindled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;shklovskii-and-sagan&#34;&gt;Shklovskii and Sagan &lt;a href=&#34;#shklovskii-and-sagan&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Sagan co-authored &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Life in the Universe&lt;/em&gt; (1966) with Soviet astrophysicist Iosif Shklovsky. In &lt;em&gt;Broca&amp;rsquo;s Brain&lt;/em&gt; (1979), Sagan expressed disapproval of writers like von Däniken who treated speculations as valid evidence of extraterrestrial contact. Sagan noted that many legends, artifacts, and out-of-place artifacts cited in support of ancient astronaut hypotheses could be explained with conventional hypotheses. He reiterated that extraterrestrial visits were possible but unproven and improbable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;erich-von-däniken&#34;&gt;Erich von Däniken &lt;a href=&#34;#erich-von-d%c3%a4niken&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erich von Däniken became a leading proponent in the late 1960s and early 1970s with his book &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; (1968) and its sequels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Von Däniken argued that certain artifacts required more advanced technology than was available to ancient cultures. He claimed that these artifacts were constructed by extraterrestrial visitors or humans who learned from them. Examples include Stonehenge, Pumapunku, the Moai of Easter Island, the Great Pyramid of Giza, and the ancient Baghdad electric batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He wrote that ancient art and iconography depict air and space vehicles, intelligent non-human creatures, ancient astronauts, and advanced technology. He also stated that geographically separated cultures share artistic themes, implying a common origin. One example is his interpretation of the sarcophagus lid from the tomb of Pacal the Great in Palenque, which he saw as a seated astronaut, while Maya texts identify it as a portrait of the ruler with the World Tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Von Däniken interpreted the origins of many religions as reactions to encounters with an alien race, whose technology was seen as supernatural. He stated that religious traditions contain references to alien visitors, such as Ezekiel&amp;rsquo;s revelation, which he interpreted as a landing spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His hypotheses became popularized in the U.S. through the NBC-TV documentary &lt;em&gt;In Search of Ancient Astronauts&lt;/em&gt; and the film &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critics argue that von Däniken misrepresented data, made unfounded claims, and failed to validate his core claims. Christian creationists also criticized his work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the Nazca Lines, von Däniken stated that they resembled an airfield when seen from the air. Kenneth L. Feder argues that readers seeing the Nazca Lines in a book about aliens would be more likely to associate them with extraterrestrial origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1970, von Däniken admitted that the Nazca markings could have been laid out using a system of coordinates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;zecharia-sitchin&#34;&gt;Zecharia Sitchin &lt;a href=&#34;#zecharia-sitchin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zecharia Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Earth Chronicles&lt;/em&gt; series revolves around his interpretation of ancient Sumerian and Middle Eastern texts, megalithic sites, and artifacts. He hypothesized that the gods of Mesopotamia were astronauts from the planet Nibiru, which the Sumerians believed to be a remote &amp;ldquo;12th planet&amp;rdquo; associated with the god Marduk. According to Sitchin, Nibiru orbits the Sun on a 3,600-year elongated orbit. Modern astronomy has found no evidence to support these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitchin argued that Sumerian texts tell the story of 50 Anunnaki from Nibiru who came to Earth approximately 400,000 years ago to mine raw materials, especially gold. They genetically engineered laborers, creating &lt;em&gt;Homo sapiens sapiens&lt;/em&gt;: the &amp;ldquo;Adapa&amp;rdquo; or Adam of later mythology. Sitchin contended that the Anunnaki were active in human affairs until their culture was destroyed by global catastrophes caused by the end of the last ice age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His work has not received mainstream scholarly support and has been criticized by professionals. Semitic languages scholar Michael S. Heiser says that many of Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s translations are inconsistent with Mesopotamian cuneiform dictionaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alan F. Alford, author of &lt;em&gt;Gods of the New Millennium&lt;/em&gt;, initially adhered to Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s hypotheses but later found fault, stating that the gods personified the falling sky and that the descent of the gods was a poetic rendition of the cataclysm myth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;robert-temple&#34;&gt;Robert Temple &lt;a href=&#34;#robert-temple&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert K. G. Temple&amp;rsquo;s 1976 book, &lt;em&gt;The Sirius Mystery,&lt;/em&gt; argues that the Dogon people of northwestern Mali preserved an account of extraterrestrial visitation from around 5,000 years ago. He cites advanced astronomical knowledge, descriptions, and comparative belief systems with ancient civilizations. His work draws on the studies of cultural anthropologists Marcel Griaule and Germaine Dieterlen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His conclusions have been criticized by scientists, who point out discrepancies and suggest that the Dogon may have received their astronomical information recently from European sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ufo-religions&#34;&gt;UFO Religions &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-religions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various new religious movements, including some branches of Theosophy, Scientology, Raëlism, Aetherius Society, and Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate, believe in ancient and present-day contact with extraterrestrial intelligence. Many see ancient scriptures and recent revelations as connected with the action of aliens. Psychologists have found that UFO religions have similarities suggesting that members associate enchantment with science fiction memes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;claims-of-proponents&#34;&gt;Claims of Proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#claims-of-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientific consensus is that the ancient astronaut hypothesis is not impossible, but unjustified and unnecessary. The &amp;ldquo;mysteries&amp;rdquo; cited as evidence can be explained without invoking ancient astronauts. Since ancient astronauts are unnecessary, Occam&amp;rsquo;s razor should be applied and the hypothesis rejected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ancient-religious-texts&#34;&gt;Ancient Religious Texts &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-religious-texts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proponents cite ancient mythologies, suggesting that creation myths of gods descending from the heavens to create or instruct humanity are representations of alien visitors. They draw an analogy to cargo cults, where isolated cultures believed Western ships and cargo were sent from the gods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ancient Sumerian myth of &lt;em&gt;Enûma Eliš&lt;/em&gt; says humankind was created to serve gods called the &amp;ldquo;Annunaki.&amp;rdquo; Proponents believe that the Annunaki were aliens who came to Earth to mine gold and created the human race as slaves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;ramayana&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ramayana&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#ramayana&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Hindu mythology, the gods and their avatars travel in flying vehicles called Vimana. The &lt;em&gt;Ramayana&lt;/em&gt; mentions these flying objects, used by the Lankan king Ravana from Sri Lanka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples from the &lt;em&gt;Ramayana&lt;/em&gt; include descriptions of the Pushpak chariot, a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Roswell Incident (1980 book)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_35f31e4c5c9f/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 19:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_35f31e4c5c9f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-roswell-incident-1980-book&#34;&gt;The Roswell Incident (1980 book) &lt;a href=&#34;#the-roswell-incident-1980-book&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry details the 1980 book &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt; by Charles Berlitz and William Moore, which significantly contributed to popularizing the Roswell incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides context for the Roswell incident, focusing on the events of 1947 and the renewed interest in the story in the late 1970s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;events-of-1947&#34;&gt;Events of 1947 &lt;a href=&#34;#events-of-1947&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection outlines the initial reports of the Roswell incident during the &amp;ldquo;flying disc craze&amp;rdquo; of 1947, Kenneth Arnold&amp;rsquo;s sighting, the Roswell Army Air Field&amp;rsquo;s initial press release about recovering a crashed disc, and the subsequent retraction stating it was a weather balloon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;roswell-revisited&#34;&gt;Roswell revisited &lt;a href=&#34;#roswell-revisited&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection explains how the Roswell story gained traction again in 1978 when retired lieutenant colonel Jesse Marcel claimed in an interview with ufologist Stanton Friedman that the debris he recovered was extraterrestrial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;authors&#34;&gt;Authors &lt;a href=&#34;#authors&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides background information on the authors of the book, Charles Berlitz and William Moore. It mentions Berlitz&amp;rsquo;s previous success with &lt;em&gt;The Bermuda Triangle&lt;/em&gt; and their collaboration on &lt;em&gt;The Philadelphia Experiment: Project Invisibility&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents &lt;a href=&#34;#contents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the book&amp;rsquo;s central argument: that an extraterrestrial craft crashed in New Mexico while observing nuclear weapons activity, and the US government engaged in a cover-up. It highlights accounts of debris described as &amp;ldquo;nothing made on this earth&amp;rdquo; and mentions witnesses like Bill Brazel, Floyd Proctor, and Walt Whitman Jr. The section also notes the book&amp;rsquo;s introduction of the idea that the debris shown in photos with Marcel was substituted as part of the cover-up. It also mentions the claim that the military sought to discredit the growing interest in flying saucers. The section also notes that the authors claimed to have interviewed over 90 witnesses, but only a fraction of those accounts appear in the book. The section also notes that the book elevated Marcel&amp;rsquo;s narrative above that of Cavitt, whose description of the debris contradicted Marcel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alien-bodies&#34;&gt;Alien bodies &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-bodies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the book&amp;rsquo;s introduction of the story about Barney Barnett and archaeology students encountering wreckage and &amp;ldquo;alien bodies&amp;rdquo; on the Plains of San Agustin. It also mentions the conflation of the Roswell incident with the Aztec, New Mexico, UFO incident, a hoaxed flying saucer crash promoted by Frank Scully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the reception of the book, noting that critics deemed it &amp;ldquo;a collection of wild hearsay&amp;rdquo; and that it &amp;ldquo;did not make the commercial impact its authors hoped.&amp;rdquo; It also mentions accusations against Moore regarding the Majestic 12 documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aftermath&#34;&gt;Aftermath &lt;a href=&#34;#aftermath&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions Moore&amp;rsquo;s admission at a 1989 MUFON conference that he had engaged in &amp;ldquo;disinformation&amp;rdquo; activities against Paul Bennewitz on behalf of the Air Force Office of Special Investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modern-views&#34;&gt;Modern views &lt;a href=&#34;#modern-views&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section references the 1993 inquiry by the General Accounting Office in response to US congressman Steven Schiff, which led to a 1994 Air Force report concluding that the recovered material was likely debris from Project Mogul, a military surveillance program using high-altitude balloons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Roswell_Incident_(1980_book)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Roswell_Incident_(1980_book)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien Planet (2005 TV series)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e77076cc2caf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 06:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_e77076cc2caf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-planet-2005-tv-series&#34;&gt;Alien Planet (2005 TV series) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-planet-2005-tv-series&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2005 docufiction TV special created for the Discovery Channel, based on Wayne Barlowe&amp;rsquo;s 1990 book &lt;em&gt;Expedition&lt;/em&gt;. It explores the imagined extraterrestrial life of the fictional planet Darwin IV in the style of a nature documentary. It features scientists and science fiction figures discussing Darwin IV as if it had actually been discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Von Braun&lt;/em&gt; interstellar spacecraft travels to Darwin IV, 6.5 light-years away. It deploys the &lt;em&gt;Darwin Reconnaissance Orbiter&lt;/em&gt; to find landing sites for probes. The first probe, &lt;em&gt;Balboa&lt;/em&gt;, explodes during entry. Backup probes &lt;em&gt;Leonardo da Vinci&lt;/em&gt; (Leo) and &lt;em&gt;Isaac Newton&lt;/em&gt; (Ike) land successfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The robotic probes, called Horus Probes, are equipped with inflatable balloons, solar receptors, computers, sensors, and smaller robots. They have limited AI and are programmed with different personalities. Ike is cautious, while Leo is a risk-taker. They are equipped with a holographic message for any sentient life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The probes encounter various lifeforms, including Arrowtongues, Gyrosprinters, Trunk Suckers, Daggerwrists, and Unths. Ike studies plant life, while Leo goes after big game. A massive storm hits, and Ike launches weather balloons. Leo finds Bladderhorns and attempts to present the holographic message, but is interrupted. Ike encounters Grovebacks, Littoralopes, Skewers, Beach Quills, and Prongheads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leo briefly re-establishes contact with &lt;em&gt;Von Braun&lt;/em&gt; until a mysterious creature interferes. Ike is ordered to search for Leo. Ike finds a sea that is Amoebic in nature and encounters giant Sea Striders. Ike finds Leo&amp;rsquo;s last known location, where a Skewer is killed by a spear. Ike finds Leo and the sapient Eosapiens. Ike presents the holographic message to the Eosapiens, but one of them destroys the camera disk, and the Eosapiens attack Ike. The wrecked camera disk records the Eosapiens carrying Ike away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commentary from Michio Kaku, Stephen Hawking, Jack Horner, James B. Garvin, and George Lucas is interspersed throughout the special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien Planet&lt;/em&gt; is based on &lt;em&gt;Expedition&lt;/em&gt; (1990) by Wayne Barlowe. Barlowe served as one of the executive producers. Scientists and other figures were assembled to comment on the life on Darwin IV. The documentary gives the appearance of the featured scientists having designed Darwin IV and its animals, most of what is shown of the actual planet and its life follows what is described in &lt;em&gt;Expedition&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike &lt;em&gt;Expedition&lt;/em&gt;, which is set in the mid-24th century, &lt;em&gt;Alien Planet&lt;/em&gt; is set in the near future, and the planet is explored using sophisticated probes. The technology featured is more advanced than present-day technology, but is based on current trends and informed speculation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dwayne A. Day of &lt;em&gt;The Space Review&lt;/em&gt; gave the special a positive review. Some criticism was leveled at the strangeness of the creatures showcased. Day stated that the animals are bizarre and frequently border on the implausible. A review in &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; stated that a few too many of the creatures seem like cartoonish monsters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lists related speculative evolution, similar documentaries, and topics related to astrobiology and xenology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citations for reviews and articles related to the production and reception of &lt;em&gt;Alien Planet&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links to the IMDb page, archived Discovery Channel page, and the Internet Archive page for &lt;em&gt;Alien Planet&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Planet&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Planet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in Canada</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_5b4d89bc641c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 07:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_5b4d89bc641c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-canada&#34;&gt;List of Alleged UFO Sightings in Canada &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-canada&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article presents a compilation of reported UFO sightings in Canada, spanning from the mid-20th century to recent years. It includes details of specific incidents, locations, and any investigations or cultural responses associated with these events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1951-gander-newfoundland&#34;&gt;1951, Gander, Newfoundland &lt;a href=&#34;#1951-gander-newfoundland&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details an incident on February 10, 1951, where a U.S. Navy aircraft flying from Gander, Newfoundland, to Iceland reported a near-collision with a large, orange, circular UFO. The UFO reportedly circled the American aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1960-clan-lake-northwest-territories&#34;&gt;1960, Clan Lake, Northwest Territories &lt;a href=&#34;#1960-clan-lake-northwest-territories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section recounts a report from June 18, 1960, where a prospector informed the Yellowknife RCMP detachment about a UFO sighting at Clan Lake, 30 miles north of Yellowknife. The prospector and his partner claimed to have seen a hovering object that hit the lake&amp;rsquo;s surface. The RCMP investigated but found nothing. Chris Rutkowski, a UFOlogist, is mentioned in connection with this incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1967-falcon-lake-manitoba&#34;&gt;1967, Falcon Lake, Manitoba &lt;a href=&#34;#1967-falcon-lake-manitoba&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the Falcon Lake Incident, where Stefan Michalak claimed to have been burned by a flying saucer on May 19, 1967, near Falcon Lake, Manitoba. The section mentions grid-like burn marks on Michalak&amp;rsquo;s chest and T-shirt. Ufologists consider this one of the most documented UFO stories in Canada. Two books about the incident are listed. Skeptic Aaron Sakulich suggests Michalak&amp;rsquo;s burns were likely caused by an accident related to alcohol consumption, and the story was fabricated to deter other prospectors. The Royal Canadian Mint released a commemorative coin depicting the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1967-shag-harbour-nova-scotia&#34;&gt;1967, Shag Harbour, Nova Scotia &lt;a href=&#34;#1967-shag-harbour-nova-scotia&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the Shag Harbour incident, involving the purported crash of a UFO in Shag Harbour, Nova Scotia, in October 1967. The Royal Canadian Mint also released a glow-in-the-dark coin depicting this sighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1969-prince-george-british-columbia&#34;&gt;1969, Prince George, British Columbia &lt;a href=&#34;#1969-prince-george-british-columbia&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details a sighting in Prince George, British Columbia, on January 1, 1969, where three unrelated witnesses reported a strange, round object radiating a yellow-orange light in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1974-langenburg-saskatchewan&#34;&gt;1974, Langenburg, Saskatchewan &lt;a href=&#34;#1974-langenburg-saskatchewan&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section recounts the experience of Edwin Fuhr, a farmer from Langenburg, Saskatchewan, who claimed to have seen five saucer-shaped objects hovering near a slough on September 1, 1974. An RCMP report confirmed the presence of five circles matching Fuhr&amp;rsquo;s description. The Royal Canadian Mint commemorated the event with a silver coin in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;19751976-southern-manitoba&#34;&gt;1975–1976, Southern Manitoba &lt;a href=&#34;#19751976-southern-manitoba&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions multiple sightings of a red glowing UFO in Southern Manitoba during 1975 and 1976. The UFO was nicknamed &amp;ldquo;Charlie Redstar.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1978-clarenville-newfoundland-and-labrador&#34;&gt;1978, Clarenville, Newfoundland and Labrador &lt;a href=&#34;#1978-clarenville-newfoundland-and-labrador&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes a UFO sighting in Clarenville, Newfoundland and Labrador, on October 26, 1978, witnessed by twelve individuals. Constable James Blackwood of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police also observed the object. The Royal Canadian Mint released a glow-in-the-dark coin depicting the sighting. A separate sighting in Clarenville in 2016 is also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1990-montreal-quebec&#34;&gt;1990, Montreal, Quebec &lt;a href=&#34;#1990-montreal-quebec&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details a sighting on November 7, 1990, in Montreal, Quebec, where witnesses reported a round, metallic object with lights forming a circle over the Bonaventure Hotel. The phenomenon lasted three hours. The sighting was commemorated on a Royal Canadian Mint coin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1997-trail-bc&#34;&gt;1997, Trail, BC &lt;a href=&#34;#1997-trail-bc&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes an event on July 1st in Trail, BC, where two women witnessed three small lights above them that quickly took off down the Columbia River.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2010-harbour-mille-newfoundland-and-labrador&#34;&gt;2010, Harbour Mille, Newfoundland and Labrador &lt;a href=&#34;#2010-harbour-mille-newfoundland-and-labrador&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section recounts multiple UFO sighting reports in Harbour Mille, Newfoundland and Labrador, on January 25, 2010. Initial reports of a missile launch were retracted, and the French Government denied any military activity. Gerry Byrne, a Member of Parliament, pressed the government for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2014-kensington-prince-edward-island&#34;&gt;2014, Kensington, Prince Edward Island &lt;a href=&#34;#2014-kensington-prince-edward-island&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details a sighting by John Sheppard in Kensington, Prince Edward Island, on June 4, 2014. Sheppard captured unusual lights on his cellphone. MUFON confirmed the sighting, and CBC covered the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2014-north-york-ontario&#34;&gt;2014, North York, Ontario &lt;a href=&#34;#2014-north-york-ontario&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes multiple UFO sighting reports in North York, Ontario, on July 26, 2014. Sarah Chun recorded videos of flashing lights. Toronto Police received several calls. Various explanations were offered, including quadcopters and Chinese lanterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;canadian-ufo-survey-results&#34;&gt;Canadian UFO Survey results &lt;a href=&#34;#canadian-ufo-survey-results&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the 2002 Canadian UFO Survey, noting that Toronto had the most sightings, followed by Vancouver and Terrace, B.C. It also mentions that the Canadian Federal Government directs UFO sightings to Chris Rutkowski of Ufology Research of Manitoba. A 2018 study by Ufology Research reported over 1,000 UFO sightings in Canada in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related links to people and projects associated with UFOs, including Dan Aykroyd, Stanton T. Friedman, Paul Hellyer, Peter Millman, lists of ufologists and reported UFO sightings, and Projects Magnet and Second Storey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, providing links to external websites and publications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Canada&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Canada&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dover Demon</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_670cdf070164/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 16:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_670cdf070164/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;dover-demon&#34;&gt;Dover Demon &lt;a href=&#34;#dover-demon&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dover Demon is a creature reportedly sighted in Dover, Massachusetts, in April 1977.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sightings&#34;&gt;Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the reported sightings of the Dover Demon in April 1977. William &amp;ldquo;Bill&amp;rdquo; Bartlett, John Baxter, and Abby Brabham, all teenagers at the time, independently reported seeing a strange creature. Bartlett described it as about 4 feet tall with glowing orange eyes and no nose or mouth, with a watermelon-shaped head. Baxter reported a similar sighting on Miller Hill Road, and Brabham claimed to have seen the creature the following night on Springdale Avenue. The teenagers drew sketches of the creature, with Bartlett swearing on a stack of Bibles to the accuracy of his drawing. The locations of the sightings, when plotted on a map, formed a straight line over 2 miles. The sightings became public in May, and a local investigator noted similarities to the creatures in the Kelly–Hopkinsville encounter. The Mutual UFO Network also investigated the sightings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;possible-explanations&#34;&gt;Possible explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#possible-explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores potential explanations for the Dover Demon sightings. One suggestion is that the creature was a foal or a moose calf. Skeptic Joe Nickell proposes that the creature was likely a snowy owl, citing its size and plumage, which could reflect yellow headlights. The &amp;ldquo;long spindly arms&amp;rdquo; could be the partially opened wings of the owl. Police suggested the sightings were a school vacation hoax. Ben Radford suggests the sightings may have been influenced by the release of &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt; in 1977.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the Dover Demon&amp;rsquo;s appearances in popular culture. It was featured in an episode of the American horror television series &lt;em&gt;Lost Tapes&lt;/em&gt; on Animal Planet in 2009. The Dover Demon appears as a character in the comic book series &lt;em&gt;Proof&lt;/em&gt;, where it can see into the future, and in &lt;em&gt;The Perhapanauts&lt;/em&gt;. It also made appearances in &lt;em&gt;The Pound: Ghouls Night Out&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Hack/Slash: Entry Wound&lt;/em&gt;. A Dover Demon appears in the webcomic &lt;em&gt;Gunnerkrigg Court&lt;/em&gt;. In the manga series &lt;em&gt;Dandadan&lt;/em&gt;, an alien known as Dover Demon takes the form of a bipedal crustacean-like alien.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dover_Demon&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dover_Demon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
