<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Boston-MA on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/boston-ma/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Boston-MA on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 09:36:26 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/boston-ma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dover Demon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/dover-demon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 09:36:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/dover-demon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Dover Demon is a creature reportedly sighted on April 21–22, 1977, in Dover, Massachusetts, a town about 15 miles (24 km) southwest of downtown Boston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17-year-old William &amp;ldquo;Bill&amp;rdquo; Bartlett claimed that while driving on April 21, 1977, he saw a creature &amp;ldquo;about 4 feet tall with glowing orange eyes and no nose or mouth in a watermelon-shaped head&amp;rdquo; on top of a broken stone wall on Farm Street in Dover, Massachusetts. 15-year-old John Baxter reported seeing a similar creature on Miller Hill Road the same evening. Another 15-year-old, Abby Brabham, claimed to have seen the creature the following night on Springdale Avenue.[1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The teenagers all drew sketches of the alleged creature. Bartlett wrote on his sketch, &amp;ldquo;I, Bill Bartlett, swear on a stack of Bibles that I saw this creature.&amp;quot;[1] According to a local news report, &amp;ldquo;the locations of the sightings, plotted on a map, lay in a straight line over 2 miles [3.2 km]&amp;rdquo;.[1] The sightings were not made public until the first half of May.[2] At that time, a local &amp;ldquo;investigator of unexplained phenomenon&amp;rdquo; noted similarities to creatures in the Kelly–Hopkinsville encounter of 1955.[2] Even though none of the witnesses reported seeing a UFO, the sightings were also investigated by the Mutual UFO Network and associated groups.[3]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;reference: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dover_Demon&#34;&gt;Dover Demon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
