<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Single on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/single/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Single on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 22:28:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/single/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Flying Saucer (song)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_24579ade6819/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 22:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_24579ade6819/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-flying-saucer-song&#34;&gt;The Flying Saucer (song) &lt;a href=&#34;#the-flying-saucer-song&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry focuses on the 1956 novelty record &amp;ldquo;The Flying Saucer&amp;rdquo; by Bill Buchanan and Dickie Goodman. It details the song&amp;rsquo;s genre, release information, structure, reception, legacy, and chart performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;single-information&#34;&gt;Single Information &lt;a href=&#34;#single-information&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section identifies &amp;ldquo;The Flying Saucer&amp;rdquo; as a single by Bill Buchanan and Dickie Goodman, released in July 1956 on the Luniverse label. It classifies the song&amp;rsquo;s genre as mashup, novelty, break-in, and sound collage. The song&amp;rsquo;s length is 4:17 (both parts). It also provides a chronology of Buchanan and Goodman&amp;rsquo;s singles, placing &amp;ldquo;The Flying Saucer&amp;rdquo; between their previous and subsequent releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Flying Saucer&amp;rdquo; is a novelty record and the first in a series of break-in records by Bill Buchanan and Dickie Goodman. It&amp;rsquo;s considered an early example of a mashup, using segments of popular songs intertwined with spoken &amp;ldquo;news&amp;rdquo; commentary to tell a story about a UFO visit. Bill Buchanan plays the radio announcer, and Dickie Goodman plays reporter John Cameron-Cameron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;structure&#34;&gt;Structure &lt;a href=&#34;#structure&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explains the song&amp;rsquo;s construction using a reel-to-reel tape recorder. It&amp;rsquo;s described as a two-part sound collage and an audio adaptation of Orson Welles&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;The War of the Worlds,&amp;rdquo; but comedic. The song intersperses popular song lyrics into a broadcast to describe Martians landing on Earth. Buchanan&amp;rsquo;s radio disc jockey character is based on Alan Freed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The song uses clips from 17 different songs, all top 20 hits from 1955 or 1956. The section lists these songs in order of appearance, divided by side one and side two of the record. Artists include Nappy Brown, The Platters, The Teenagers featuring Frankie Lymon, Little Richard, Fats Domino, Elvis Presley, The Penguins, Smiley Lewis, Don Cherry, Carl Perkins, Chuck Berry, and Bill Haley &amp;amp; His Comets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The section also highlights the song&amp;rsquo;s technological significance, comparing it to the work of musique concrète composers like Pierre Schaeffer, Pierre Boulez, and Karlheinz Stockhausen, who also used tape manipulation in the early 1950s. It&amp;rsquo;s also described as an early, less avant-garde example of a sample collage, compared to James Tenney&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Collage #1&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release-and-reception&#34;&gt;Release and Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#release-and-reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extensive sampling in &amp;ldquo;The Flying Saucer&amp;rdquo; led to copyright lawsuits against Buchanan and Goodman in July 1956. The duo faced criticism, but they responded with a follow-up song, &amp;ldquo;Buchanan and Goodman on Trial.&amp;rdquo; In November 1956, a judge ruled the song artful and clever, refusing to issue an injunction against sales. This ruling was significant because it essentially considered the record a new work, paving the way for legal sampling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the single and the trial record, Buchanan and Goodman created more &amp;ldquo;Flying Saucer&amp;rdquo; records, forming a &amp;ldquo;UFO comedy series.&amp;rdquo; Other artists, including Dewey, George and Jack and the Belltones, Alan Freed, Steve Allen, Al &amp;ldquo;Jazzbo&amp;rdquo; Collins and the Modernaires, and Sid Noel, released their own versions of &amp;ldquo;The Flying Saucer.&amp;rdquo; The success of &amp;ldquo;The Flying Saucer&amp;rdquo; increased sales of songs excerpted in the pastiche, such as The Penguins&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;Earth Angel&amp;rdquo; and Little Richard&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Long Tall Sally.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legacy&#34;&gt;Legacy &lt;a href=&#34;#legacy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Flying Saucer&amp;rdquo; is recognized as the first song to sample the work of other artists. It&amp;rsquo;s considered an early instance of sampling and industry litigation. The lawsuits against Buchanan and Goodman made them trailblazers in sampling and related litigation. The song is considered a musical concept that is now a part of popular music. It is also considered the first acknowledged example of a mashup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The song paved the way for artists like Public Enemy, Freelance Hellraiser, Negativland, and Danger Mouse, who also faced litigation for sample-based copyright infringement. Steinski cited &amp;ldquo;The Flying Saucer&amp;rdquo; as a formative influence. The record&amp;rsquo;s influence stretches to pop music built on samplings and comedy routines that take answers out of context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;charts&#34;&gt;Charts &lt;a href=&#34;#charts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides the chart performance of &amp;ldquo;The Flying Saucer,&amp;rdquo; noting that it reached a peak position of 3 on the US Best Sellers in Stores chart in Billboard in 1956.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Flying_Saucer_(song)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Flying_Saucer_(song)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
