<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Documentary on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/documentary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Documentary on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 01:11:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/documentary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Age of Disclosure</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_bede4bc9e3eb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_bede4bc9e3eb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-age-of-disclosure&#34;&gt;The Age of Disclosure &lt;a href=&#34;#the-age-of-disclosure&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2025 American documentary film directed and produced by Dan Farah, exploring the alleged existence and cover-up of extraterrestrial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film premiered at SXSW (South by Southwest Film &amp;amp; TV Festival) on March 9, 2025. This section highlights the film&amp;rsquo;s debut at a major film festival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received &amp;ldquo;mixed or average&amp;rdquo; reviews, earning a score of 52 out of 100 on Metacritic based on four critics. Owen Gleiberman of &lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt; questioned the film&amp;rsquo;s evidence, expressing skepticism about the quality and authenticity of the presented footage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including articles from &lt;em&gt;Hollywood Reporter&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;People&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;, the SXSW 2025 schedule, and Metacritic. These references provide verification for the information presented about the film&amp;rsquo;s production, release, and reception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to the film&amp;rsquo;s official website and its IMDb page. These links offer additional resources for those interested in learning more about the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Age_of_Disclosure&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Age_of_Disclosure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO (1956 film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_72b8a32dc29d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 02:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_72b8a32dc29d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-1956-film&#34;&gt;UFO (1956 film) &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-1956-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 1956 American semi-documentary film that explores the development of the UFO phenomenon in the United States. It is noted for its use of documentary clips that have been featured in other UFO-related media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;origins-and-plot&#34;&gt;Origins and plot &lt;a href=&#34;#origins-and-plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1952, Hollywood producer Clarence Greene, after witnessing an unusual aerial object, contacted US Air Force public information officer Albert M. Chop. Intrigued, Greene decided to create a documentary about UFOs, using film footage provided by Chop. The film begins in 1947, covering early UFO sightings like the Kenneth Arnold sighting, the Mantell UFO incident, and the Gorman Dogfight. It follows the evolution of UFOs as a cultural fad and a concern for the US Air Force, including the history of Project Sign. The film then focuses on Albert M. Chop, who is assigned as the public information officer at Wright-Patterson Air Force Base in Dayton, Ohio. Chop initially debunks UFOs but gradually changes his views, believing they are unknown aircraft, possibly extraterrestrial. By 1952, Chop is in Washington, D.C., as the press spokesman for Project Blue Book. The documentary analyzes the Mariana UFO Incident of 1950 and the 1952 UFO film taken near the Great Salt Lake in Utah by Delbert Newhouse. The film concludes with the 1952 Washington, D.C. UFO incident, where Chop played a central role, ultimately stating his belief that UFOs are a real, physical phenomenon of unknown origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cast includes Willis Sperry, Nicholas Mariana, Delbert Newhouse, Wendell Swanson, and U.S. Air Force General John A. Samford as themselves. Tom Towers plays Albert M. (Al) Chop, Floyd Burton plays Major Dewey Fournet, Gene Coughlan plays an editor from the &lt;em&gt;Dayton Daily News&lt;/em&gt;, Bert Freed plays a Colonel, Stan Gordon plays a reporter, Marie Kenna plays Mrs. Albert Chop, Harry Morgan provides voices, Robert Phillips plays Captain Edward Ruppelt, William Solomon plays a German scientist, and Olan Soule is a narrator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;trivia&#34;&gt;Trivia &lt;a href=&#34;#trivia&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actor Harry Morgan, known for his roles in &lt;em&gt;M*A*S*H&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Dragnet 1967&lt;/em&gt;, voices the pilot of &amp;ldquo;Air Force 216&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Red Dog One&amp;rdquo; during key scenes, including the 1952 Washington, D.C. UFO incident. Morgan&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Dragnet 1967&lt;/em&gt; co-star Jack Webb produced and narrated the 1978 television series &lt;em&gt;Project U.F.O.&lt;/em&gt;, which recreated Project Bluebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lists similar media, including the book &lt;em&gt;The Report On Unidentified Flying Objects&lt;/em&gt; (1956), the film &lt;em&gt;UFOs: Past, Present, and Future&lt;/em&gt; (1976), and the TV broadcast &lt;em&gt;UFO Cover Up? Live&lt;/em&gt; (1988).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lists the references used in the article, including articles from the &lt;em&gt;Los Angeles Times&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Turner Classic Movies&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Christian Science Monitor&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post and Times-Herald&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provides links to the film&amp;rsquo;s IMDb page, TCM Movie Database page, and a full film available at the Internet Archive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_(1956_film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_(1956_film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO (Television Documentary Series)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_9913cf9600c1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 06:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_9913cf9600c1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-television-documentary-series&#34;&gt;UFO (Television Documentary Series) &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-television-documentary-series&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A four-part television documentary series about unidentified flying objects (UFOs). It was produced by J.J. Abrams&amp;rsquo; production company, Bad Robot, and aired on Showtime in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces the documentary series, stating its genre as a television documentary, its subject matter as unidentified flying objects, the number of episodes (4), the production company (Bad Robot), and the original network (Showtime). It also mentions J.J. Abrams as the producer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a link to the &amp;ldquo;List of Showtime original programming&amp;rdquo; Wikipedia page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the citations used in the article. These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; article by Alexis Soloski, titled &amp;ldquo;How Much Watching Time Do You Have This Weekend?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;Daily Beast&lt;/em&gt; article by Nick Schager, titled &amp;ldquo;J.J. Abrams&amp;rsquo; Mission to Expose the Truth About UFOs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;Paste&lt;/em&gt; article titled &amp;ldquo;Showtime&amp;rsquo;s Compelling UFO Docuseries Deserves to Be on Your Radar.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the series&amp;rsquo; page on IMDb (Internet Movie Database).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_(American_TV_series)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_(American_TV_series)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
