<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Movie/Film on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/movie/film/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Movie/Film on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/movie/film/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Autopsy (1995 television film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f41f4fadf611/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f41f4fadf611/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-autopsy-1995-television-film&#34;&gt;Alien Autopsy (1995 television film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-autopsy-1995-television-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the 1995 pseudo-documentary &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy: Fact or Fiction&lt;/em&gt;, which featured footage purporting to show an alien autopsy conducted after the Roswell incident. The article distinguishes the original footage from the 2006 feature film &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt;, which is based on the events surrounding the creation of the hoax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section details the production of the &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; footage. It highlights Ray Santilli and Gary Shoefield&amp;rsquo;s admission in the 2006 documentary &lt;em&gt;Eamonn Investigates: Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; that they created the 1995 footage. The section describes how they filmed a simulated autopsy on a fabricated alien in a set constructed in a London living room. Artist and sculptor John Humphreys constructed two dummy alien bodies filled with raspberry jam, sheep brains, chicken entrails, and knuckle joints. Humphreys also played the role of the chief examiner. The section also mentions the creation of alien artifacts and the recruitment of a homeless man to play the role of the cameraman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section explores how &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; was received and satirized in the media. It mentions &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt; referencing the footage and later satirizing it in the episode &amp;ldquo;Jose Chung&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;From Outer Space&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. It also notes Fox airing a special debunking the footage and the release of the comedy film &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; (2006), which fictionalized the creation of the footage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including books, news articles, and documentaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of additional resources for readers interested in learning more about the &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; film and the surrounding controversy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external resources, including Ray Santilli&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;My Story&amp;rdquo; on VJ Enterprises, his IMDb page, and a YouTube link to &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy: Fact or Fiction?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Autopsy_(1995_film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Autopsy_(1995_film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nordic aliens</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7c6654f96aa5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 22:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_7c6654f96aa5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;nordic-aliens&#34;&gt;Nordic Aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#nordic-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In ufology, &amp;ldquo;Nordics,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Nordic aliens,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Tall Whites&amp;rdquo; are terms used to describe alleged humanoid extraterrestrial races from the Pleiades star cluster. These beings are said to resemble Nordic, Germanic, or Scandinavian humans, with features like tall stature (6-7 ft), blond hair, blue eyes, and fair skin. Some reports describe their skin tone as pale blue/grey or pastel purple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cultural historian David J. Skal suggests that early stories of Nordic aliens may have been inspired by the 1951 film &lt;em&gt;The Day the Earth Stood Still&lt;/em&gt;. Stephanie Kelley-Romano describes alien abduction beliefs as a &amp;ldquo;living myth,&amp;rdquo; noting that believers often associate Nordic aliens with spiritual growth and protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In ufology, Nordic aliens are often portrayed as benevolent beings concerned about Earth&amp;rsquo;s ecology and world peace, possessing telepathic powers and described as paternal, watchful, smiling, affectionate, and youthful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the 1950s, many people, especially in Europe, claimed encounters with these beings. However, such claims became less common in later decades as the grey alien became more prevalent in extraterrestrial encounter accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publications-by-those-claiming-to-have-been-contacted&#34;&gt;Publications by Those Claiming to Have Been Contacted &lt;a href=&#34;#publications-by-those-claiming-to-have-been-contacted&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several books detail alleged personal contact with Nordic aliens, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flying Saucers Have Landed&lt;/em&gt; by Desmond Leslie and George Adamski&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inside the Space Ships&lt;/em&gt; by George Adamski&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Outer Space to You&lt;/em&gt; by Howard Menger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Walton Experience&lt;/em&gt; by Travis Walton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Millennial Hospitality&lt;/em&gt; by Charles James Hall (adapted into the film &lt;em&gt;Walking with the Tall Whites&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UFO religion Universe People also publishes interactions with &amp;ldquo;Cosmic Friends.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See Also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists related topics, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Space Brothers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Truman Bethurum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elizabeth Klarer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Billy Meier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linda Moulton Howe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of alleged extraterrestrial beings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star people (New Age)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arcturians (New Age)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFOs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFO religion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of cited sources used in the article, including books, articles, and websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_aliens&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_aliens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancient astronauts</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_96b21753a786/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 08:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_96b21753a786/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ancient-astronauts&#34;&gt;Ancient Astronauts &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-astronauts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ancient astronauts, also known as ancient aliens, is a pseudoscientific belief that intelligent extraterrestrial beings visited Earth in ancient times and influenced the development of human civilization. Proponents suggest that these aliens affected modern cultures, technologies, religions, and human biology. A common idea is that deities from religions are extraterrestrial in origin, with advanced technologies interpreted as divine status by early humans. Academics and archaeologists dismiss these claims as pseudoarchaeological and unscientific, lacking credible peer-reviewed studies. Evidence presented is often distorted or fabricated. Some argue that these theories have racist undertones, diminishing the accomplishments of indigenous cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Various terms are used to describe claims about ancient astronauts, including ancient aliens, ancient ufonauts, ancient space pilots, paleocontact, astronaut- or alien gods, and paleo- or biblical-SETI. Believers maintain that humans are descendants or creations of extraterrestrial intelligence who landed on Earth in the past. Human knowledge, religion, and culture are said to have originated from these visitors, who acted as a &amp;ldquo;mother culture.&amp;rdquo; Proponents claim that structures like the Egyptian pyramids and the Moai stone heads of Easter Island were built by extraterrestrials or with their aid. Evidence is drawn from documentary gaps in historical and archaeological records, as well as artifacts believed to be anachronistic and beyond the technical capabilities of ancient people. These &amp;ldquo;out-of-place artifacts&amp;rdquo; include artwork and legends reinterpreted to support extraterrestrial contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is often featured in fringe media, such as the History Channel series &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;. Such shows mix fact with fiction to spread theories of an alternate past, often aligning with white supremacist, nativist, imperialist, settler-colonial, and Christian Identity beliefs. Proponents portray themselves as an oppressed minority of academics, claiming a conspiracy by &amp;lsquo;big archaeology&amp;rsquo; to disenfranchise them, while lacking credentials. They focus on monumental archaeological structures, implying that non-white indigenous people could not have built them without extraterrestrial intervention. However, some indigenous voices argue that ancient alien theory supports their beliefs in extraterrestrial origins, countering &amp;ldquo;Indigenous erasure.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common feature in the stories portrays the aliens as light-skinned or Aryan in complexion, as prominent alien astronaut proponent Erich von Däniken claims in his foundational work &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; Some ancient astronaut proponents are thus associated with white supremacism, although their theories are sometimes applied to European cultures as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until recently, mainstream archaeologists essentially ignored these claims as absurdities. Those who did offer opinions universally panned them. Carl Sagan noted that cases of apparent interest have reasonable alternative explanations, misreporting, prevarications, hoaxes, and distortions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34;&gt;History of ancient aliens beliefs and their proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paleocontact narratives first appeared in early science fiction of the late 19th and early 20th centuries, including &lt;em&gt;Edison&amp;rsquo;s Conquest of Mars&lt;/em&gt; (1898) and the works of H.P. Lovecraft. Harold T. Wilkins proposed the idea in earnest in 1954. It grew in popularity in the 1960s due to the Space Race and the success of Erich von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s works, although it also received limited consideration as a serious hypothesis. Critics emerged throughout the 1970s, discrediting Von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s claims. Ufologists separated the idea from the UFO controversy. By the early 1980s little remaining support could be found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;shklovskii-and-sagan&#34;&gt;Shklovskii and Sagan &lt;a href=&#34;#shklovskii-and-sagan&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Carl Sagan co-authored &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Life in the Universe&lt;/em&gt; (1966) with Soviet astrophysicist Iosif Shklovsky. In &lt;em&gt;Broca&amp;rsquo;s Brain&lt;/em&gt; (1979), Sagan suggested that he and Shklovsky might have inspired the wave of 1970s ancient astronaut books, expressing disapproval of &amp;ldquo;von Däniken and other uncritical writers&amp;rdquo; who seemingly built on these ideas not as guarded speculations but as &amp;ldquo;valid evidence of extraterrestrial contact.&amp;rdquo; Sagan pointed out that while many legends, artifacts, and purported out-of-place artifacts were cited in support of ancient astronaut hypotheses, &amp;ldquo;very few require more than passing mention&amp;rdquo; and could be easily explained with more conventional hypotheses. Sagan also reiterated his earlier conclusion that extraterrestrial visits to Earth were possible but unproven and improbable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;erich-von-däniken&#34;&gt;Erich von Däniken &lt;a href=&#34;#erich-von-d%c3%a4niken&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Erich von Däniken was a leading proponent of this hypothesis in the late 1960s and early 1970s, gaining a large audience through the 1968 publication of his best-selling book &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; and its sequels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to von Däniken, certain artifacts require a more sophisticated technological ability in their construction than that which was available to the ancient cultures who constructed them. Von Däniken maintains that these artifacts were constructed either directly by extraterrestrial visitors or by humans who learned the necessary knowledge from said visitors. These include Stonehenge, Pumapunku, the Moai of Easter Island, the Great Pyramid of Giza, and the ancient Baghdad electric batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Von Däniken writes that ancient art and iconography throughout the world illustrates air and space vehicles, non-human but intelligent creatures, ancient astronauts, and artifacts of an anachronistically advanced technology. Von Däniken also states that geographically separated historical cultures share artistic themes, which he argues imply a common origin. One such example is von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s interpretation of the sarcophagus lid recovered from the tomb of the Classic-era Maya ruler of Palenque, Pacal the Great. Von Däniken writes that the design represented a seated astronaut. The iconography and accompanying Maya text, however, identifies it as a portrait of the ruler himself with the World Tree of Maya mythology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The origins of many religions are interpreted by von Däniken as reactions to encounters with an alien race. According to his view, humans considered the technology of the aliens to be supernatural and the aliens themselves to be gods. Von Däniken states that the oral and written traditions of most religions contain references to alien visitors in the way of descriptions of stars and vehicular objects traveling through air and space. One such is Ezekiel&amp;rsquo;s revelation, which Däniken interprets as a detailed description of a landing spacecraft (&lt;em&gt;The Spaceships of Ezekiel&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s hypotheses became popularized in the U.S. after the NBC-TV documentary &lt;em&gt;In Search of Ancient Astronauts&lt;/em&gt; hosted by Rod Serling, and the film &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critics argue that von Däniken misrepresented data, that many of his claims were unfounded, and that none of his core claims have been validated. In particular the Christian creationist community is highly critical of most of von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s work. Young Earth creationist author Clifford A. Wilson published &lt;em&gt;Crash Go the Chariots&lt;/em&gt; in 1972 in which he attempted to discredit all the claims made in &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt;, regarding the Nazca Lines, von Däniken states that &amp;ldquo;Seen from the air, the clear-cut impression that the 60 km [37-mile] long plain of Nazca made on me was that of an airfield.&amp;rdquo; Considering he was in the process of seeking evidence of ancient aliens, von Däniken exhibits confirmation bias, as he does not consider the Nazca Lines to be man-made until after the publication of &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; This etic perspective that he presents could be easily accepted by a reader familiar with air travel, and an undeveloped knowledge of the nature of the geoglyphs. Furthermore, since the majority of readers of &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; are not educated in viewing artifacts from ancient civilizations, their interpretations are highly subject to von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s opinions of the artifacts. Kenneth L. Feder argues a reader seeing the Nazca Lines for the first time in a book about aliens would be much more likely to associate those features with extraterrestrial origins, rather than from a civilization that existed on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1970, von Däniken admitted that the Nazca markings &amp;ldquo;could have been laid out on their gigantic scale by working from a model using a system of coordinates.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;zecharia-sitchin&#34;&gt;Zecharia Sitchin &lt;a href=&#34;#zecharia-sitchin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zecharia Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s series &lt;em&gt;The Earth Chronicles&lt;/em&gt;, beginning with &lt;em&gt;The 12th Planet&lt;/em&gt;, revolves around Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s unique interpretation of ancient Sumerian and Middle Eastern texts, megalithic sites, and artifacts from around the world. He hypothesizes that the gods of old Mesopotamia were astronauts from the planet &amp;ldquo;Nibiru&amp;rdquo;, which Sitchin states the Sumerians believed to be a remote &amp;ldquo;12th planet&amp;rdquo; (counting the Sun, Moon, and Pluto as planets) associated with the god Marduk. According to Sitchin, Nibiru continues to orbit the Sun on a 3,600-year elongated orbit. Modern astronomy has found no evidence to support Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitchin argues that there are Sumerian texts that tell the story that 50 Anunnaki, inhabitants of a planet named Nibiru, came to Earth approximately 400,000 years ago with the intent of mining raw materials, especially gold, for transport back to Nibiru. With their small numbers they soon grew tired of the task and set out to genetically engineer laborers to work the mines. After much trial and error they eventually created &lt;em&gt;Homo sapiens sapiens&lt;/em&gt;: the &amp;ldquo;Adapa&amp;rdquo; (model man) or Adam of later mythology. Sitchin contended the Anunnaki were active&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
