<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alien Life on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/alien-life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alien Life on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:57:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/alien-life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial (TV program)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6ae4a656d588/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6ae4a656d588/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-tv-program&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial (TV program) &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-tv-program&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry details a British-American two-part television documentary miniseries, also known as &lt;em&gt;Alien Worlds&lt;/em&gt; in the UK, which aired in 2005. The program, produced by Big Wave Productions Ltd., explores the hypothetical evolution of alien life on extrasolar planets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;series-concept-and-scientific-basis&#34;&gt;Series concept and scientific basis &lt;a href=&#34;#series-concept-and-scientific-basis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentary speculates about life on extrasolar planets, prompted by the discovery of such planets starting in 1989. It highlights the importance of the habitable zone, where temperatures allow liquid water to exist. The program mentions exoplanets Gliese 667 Cc and Gliese 581g (disputed) as examples, noting the challenges in detecting smaller, terrestrial planets. The cancellation of NASA&amp;rsquo;s Terrestrial Planet Finder (TPF) project is discussed, along with the shift in focus towards red dwarf stars and binary systems as potential locations for life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episode-1-aurelia&#34;&gt;Episode 1: Aurelia &lt;a href=&#34;#episode-1-aurelia&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This episode focuses on Aurelia, a hypothetical Earth-sized extrasolar planet orbiting a red dwarf star.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;planetary-concept&#34;&gt;Planetary concept &lt;a href=&#34;#planetary-concept&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientists theorize that red dwarf stars, despite being dimmer, offer long lifespans suitable for life evolution. The close proximity required for habitability around a red dwarf would likely result in tidal locking. The program challenges traditional assumptions about tidally locked planets, suggesting they can retain an atmosphere, albeit with unusual characteristics. Aurelia would lack seasons and a day/night cycle, with one side in perpetual darkness and the other experiencing a constant hurricane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lifeforms-of-aurelia&#34;&gt;Lifeforms of Aurelia &lt;a href=&#34;#lifeforms-of-aurelia&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The episode speculates on potential lifeforms, assuming carbon-based biology. A plant-like creature called a Stinger Fan is presented as the primary autotroph, with six-legged, beaver-like Mudpods feeding on them. Gulphogs, large, emu-like predators, hunt the Mudpods. Hysteria, tiny, orange creatures similar to tadpoles and piranhas, can form super-organisms to paralyze and consume other animals. All organisms have adaptations to detect and avoid deadly solar flares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episode-2-blue-moon&#34;&gt;Episode 2: Blue Moon &lt;a href=&#34;#episode-2-blue-moon&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This episode explores the Blue Moon, a fictional moon orbiting a gas giant in a binary star system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;planetary-concept-1&#34;&gt;Planetary concept &lt;a href=&#34;#planetary-concept-1&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Blue Moon is covered in water and has a dense atmosphere, allowing for the evolution of enormous flying creatures. It orbits a Water Cloud Jovian planet in a binary star system. The moon&amp;rsquo;s thick atmosphere maintains constant temperatures, and a greenish haze is present due to floating moss and algae. The denser atmosphere allows for massive airborne creatures like Skywhales, which evolved from sea-going animals. High oxygen levels (30%) create a risk of spontaneous combustion during lightning storms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lifeforms-of-the-blue-moon&#34;&gt;Lifeforms of the Blue Moon &lt;a href=&#34;#lifeforms-of-the-blue-moon&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skywhales are preyed upon by insect-like Caped Stalkers, colony-living predators with specialized tasks. Giant Kites, parasol-like grazers, also inhabit the skies. The land is dominated by pagoda trees and balloon plants. The pagoda trees interconnect to reach great heights, collecting rainwater in their hollow leaves. Balloon plants release hydrogen-filled seeds for dispersal. The forest floor features a bioluminescent ecosystem with fungi and other creatures. Mass wildfires pose a threat to the Blue Moon&amp;rsquo;s ecosystem, with balloon plants exploding and releasing seeds during fires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;home-video-releases&#34;&gt;Home video releases &lt;a href=&#34;#home-video-releases&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Channel 4 released a DVD of the documentary in January 2005.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_(TV_program)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_(TV_program)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
