<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spain on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/spain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spain on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 18:21:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/spain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in Spain</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f657a0ae4ba0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 18:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f657a0ae4ba0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufo-sightings-in-spain&#34;&gt;UFO Sightings in Spain &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-sightings-in-spain&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article documents alleged UFO sightings in Spain, organized chronologically by year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1976&#34;&gt;1976 &lt;a href=&#34;#1976&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details an incident at the Talavera la Real Air Base in Badajoz province on November 12, 1976. Two soldiers, José María Trejo and Juan Carrizosa Luján, reported encountering a being of unknown origin. They heard unusual noises and saw a bright light. They described the being as approximately 3 meters tall, human-shaped, with a small head, long arms, and no apparent hands or feet. The soldiers claimed to have fired 40 to 50 bullets at the being, which then disappeared. An investigation by the Air Force confirmed that the soldiers fired their weapons, but no bullet casings or holes were found. Spanish Army veteran Vicente Juan suggests the soldiers experienced a hallucination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1979&#34;&gt;1979 &lt;a href=&#34;#1979&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section refers to the Manises UFO Incident, which occurred on November 11, 1979. This event involved a commercial flight making an emergency landing at Manises airport in Valencia due to a reported UFO encounter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1981&#34;&gt;1981 &lt;a href=&#34;#1981&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section mentions an event on July 24, 1981, where Prudencio Muguruza reportedly saw a bright light crash near Ochate. He took a photo of the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1994&#34;&gt;1994 &lt;a href=&#34;#1994&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section notes a Tunguska-like event that occurred on January 18 in Cando, Galicia, Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to related Wikipedia articles, including the &amp;ldquo;List of reported UFO sightings&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;UFO sightings in the Canary Islands.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including articles from &lt;em&gt;El Mundo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Mundo Misterioso&lt;/em&gt;. The references provide verification and further information on the events described.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section includes a link to MUFON (Mutual UFO Network) for recent UFO sightings and pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Spain&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Spain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
