<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Britney Spears on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/britney-spears/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Britney Spears on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 23:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/britney-spears/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien (Britney Spears song)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_773d00a9caad/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 23:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_773d00a9caad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-britney-spears-song&#34;&gt;Alien (Britney Spears song) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-britney-spears-song&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Alien&amp;rdquo; is a song by Britney Spears from her 2013 album &lt;em&gt;Britney Jean&lt;/em&gt;. The song is a mid-tempo dance-pop track about Spears&amp;rsquo; feelings of loneliness. It received positive reviews from music critics, who praised its production and personal nature. Despite not being released as a single, it charted on the US Bubbling Under Hot 100 and the French Singles Chart. Spears performed the song during her &amp;ldquo;Britney: Piece of Me&amp;rdquo; residency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After her time as a judge on &lt;em&gt;The X Factor&lt;/em&gt;, Spears began working on her eighth studio album in December 2012. William Orbit was announced as a producer for the project in May 2013. Spears described &amp;ldquo;Alien,&amp;rdquo; her collaboration with Orbit, as &amp;ldquo;really cool&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;really great.&amp;rdquo; There were initial rumors of a collaboration with Lady Gaga, but this did not happen. A demo version of the song leaked online before the album&amp;rsquo;s release, which Orbit stated had incorrect chorus notes that were fixed in the final version. Spears considered releasing &amp;ldquo;Alien&amp;rdquo; as a single, as revealed in her documentary &lt;em&gt;I Am Britney Jean&lt;/em&gt;, but this never materialized. In July 2014, an unedited vocal track of Spears singing the song leaked, drawing criticism for her uncorrected vocals. Orbit defended Spears, stating that the leaked audio was a vocal warm-up and not intended for public release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;composition&#34;&gt;Composition &lt;a href=&#34;#composition&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Alien&amp;rdquo; is a midtempo dance-pop song co-written by Spears, William Orbit, Dan Traynor, Ana Diaz, and Anthony Preston, and produced by Orbit and HyGrade. The song&amp;rsquo;s musical style has been compared to Madonna&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Ray of Light&lt;/em&gt; album, which was also produced by Orbit. Lyrically, the song explores themes of loneliness. A vocal glitch at 2:14 in the song sparked discussion, with Orbit joking that it was due to an alien abduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;critical-reception&#34;&gt;Critical Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Alien&amp;rdquo; was generally well-received by music critics, who praised its production and personal themes. Critics highlighted Orbit&amp;rsquo;s production and Spears&amp;rsquo; vulnerability on the track. Some reviewers compared the song favorably to Madonna&amp;rsquo;s work with Orbit. However, one critic felt that Spears&amp;rsquo; vocal performance did not match the song&amp;rsquo;s solemn production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;live-performances&#34;&gt;Live Performances &lt;a href=&#34;#live-performances&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spears performed &amp;ldquo;Alien&amp;rdquo; during her &amp;ldquo;Britney: Piece of Me&amp;rdquo; residency at Planet Hollywood Las Vegas. One performance was notable because Spears was caught lip-syncing when the backing track continued playing after she missed her cue. The song was later removed from the setlist but was briefly re-added following Spears&amp;rsquo; breakup with her boyfriend David Lucado.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;credits-and-personnel&#34;&gt;Credits and Personnel &lt;a href=&#34;#credits-and-personnel&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lists the people involved in the creation of the song, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Songwriters:&lt;/strong&gt; Britney Spears, William Orbit, Dan Traynor, Ana Diaz, Anthony Preston&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Producers:&lt;/strong&gt; William Orbit, HyGrade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engineers:&lt;/strong&gt; Alan O&amp;rsquo;Connell, Alan Tilston, John Hanes, Serban Ghenea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional Vocals:&lt;/strong&gt; Ana Diaz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recording took place at Guerrilla Studios in London and was mixed at MixStar Studios in Virginia Beach, Virginia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;charts&#34;&gt;Charts &lt;a href=&#34;#charts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Alien&amp;rdquo; charted on the French Singles Chart and the US Billboard Bubbling Under Hot 100 chart. It reached number 147 in France and number 8 on the Bubbling Under Hot 100 in the US. It also charted in South Korea, reaching number 90 on the Gaon Music Chart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_(Britney_Spears_song)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_(Britney_Spears_song)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
