<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xenoscience on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/xenoscience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Xenoscience on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 19:55:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/xenoscience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Evolving the Alien  The Science of Extraterrestrial Life</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ddbbb643349b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 19:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ddbbb643349b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;evolving-the-alien-the-science-of-extraterrestrial-life&#34;&gt;Evolving the Alien: The Science of Extraterrestrial Life &lt;a href=&#34;#evolving-the-alien-the-science-of-extraterrestrial-life&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article provides information about the book &amp;ldquo;Evolving the Alien: The Science of Extraterrestrial Life&amp;rdquo; by Jack Cohen and Ian Stewart. It covers various aspects of the book, including its publication details, synopsis, and reception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;synopsis&#34;&gt;Synopsis &lt;a href=&#34;#synopsis&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the central argument of the book, which challenges the assumption that extraterrestrial life must resemble life on Earth or exist in Earth-like environments. Cohen and Stewart advocate for a broader perspective in the search for extraterrestrial life, suggesting that life forms could be radically different from what we know. The section introduces the concepts of &amp;ldquo;exobiology&amp;rdquo; versus &amp;ldquo;xenoscience&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;parochials&amp;rdquo; versus &amp;ldquo;universals&amp;rdquo; as key contrasts explored in the book. It also mentions the inclusion of science fiction references, including plot summaries of classic stories, to supplement the scientific content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reception&#34;&gt;Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes critical responses to &amp;ldquo;Evolving the Alien.&amp;rdquo; The &lt;em&gt;London Review of Books&lt;/em&gt; praised the book&amp;rsquo;s speculative approach for exposing conventional errors and its educational value regarding current scientific knowledge. However, it criticized the authors&amp;rsquo; optimism about future space travel technology. Lawrence M. Krauss, in &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;, noted the book&amp;rsquo;s potential as a counterpoint to the &amp;ldquo;Rare Earth&amp;rdquo; hypothesis presented in Peter Ward and Donald Brownlee&amp;rsquo;s book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evolving_the_Alien&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evolving_the_Alien&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
