<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unexplained on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/unexplained/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unexplained on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 19:42:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/unexplained/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kelly–Hopkinsville encounter</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_12e4ff60c21c/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 19:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_12e4ff60c21c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;kellyhopkinsville-encounter&#34;&gt;Kelly–Hopkinsville Encounter &lt;a href=&#34;#kellyhopkinsville-encounter&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kelly–Hopkinsville encounter, also known as the Hopkinsville Goblins Case or Kelly Green Men Case, is a claimed close encounter with extraterrestrial beings that allegedly occurred near Kelly and Hopkinsville in Christian County, Kentucky, on August 21–22, 1955. Ufologists consider it a significant and well-documented UFO incident, while skeptics attribute the reports to misidentification of natural phenomena and &amp;ldquo;the effects of excitement.&amp;rdquo; The United States Air Force&amp;rsquo;s Project Blue Book classified the encounter as a hoax. Psychologists use the incident as an example of pseudoscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;claims&#34;&gt;Claims &lt;a href=&#34;#claims&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the evening of August 21, 1955, several adults and children reported to the Hopkinsville police that their farmhouse was under attack by small alien creatures from a spaceship. Elmer Sutton and Billy Ray Taylor claimed to have shot at the creatures, which repeatedly appeared at the doorway and windows. The &lt;em&gt;Kentucky New Era&lt;/em&gt; reported the number of creatures as &amp;ldquo;12 to 15.&amp;rdquo; Police officers, state troopers, deputy sheriffs, and military police from Fort Campbell investigated the Sutton farmhouse near Kelly, Kentucky, but found no evidence except for broken windows and holes in screens. The residents, including Glennie Lankford and her family, left the house the next day, claiming the creatures had returned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;press-coverage&#34;&gt;Press Coverage &lt;a href=&#34;#press-coverage&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The family&amp;rsquo;s claims received widespread local and national press coverage. Early articles did not initially describe the creatures as &amp;ldquo;little green men,&amp;rdquo; but the color was later added. Descriptions of the creatures varied, but common details included their small size (2 to 4 feet), large pointed ears, claw-like hands, glowing yellow eyes, and spindly legs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;explanations&#34;&gt;Explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychologists Rodney Schmaltz and Scott Lilienfeld use the incident as an example of pseudoscience to teach critical thinking. They suggest intoxication may have played a role in the sighting. Skeptic Joe Nickell proposes that the family misidentified great horned owls, which are nocturnal, have yellow eyes, and can be aggressive. Nickell also notes that meteor sightings occurred around the same time, which could explain Billy Ray Taylor&amp;rsquo;s claim of seeing a bright light in the sky. Brian Dunning also supports the great horned owl theory, noting the similarities in size and behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufologists&#34;&gt;UFOlogists &lt;a href=&#34;#ufologists&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;French UFOlogist Renaud Leclet suggests that the residents likely saw great horned owls. Jerome Clark describes the creatures as &amp;ldquo;floating&amp;rdquo; and the sound of bullets hitting them as &amp;ldquo;resembling bullets striking a metal bucket.&amp;rdquo; Clark mentions a luminous patch and a green light, which could be explained by foxfire. He also claims that police, Air Force officers, and civilian ufologists found no evidence of a hoax, but Brian Dunning disputes the involvement of Air Force investigators. Allan Hendry notes the case&amp;rsquo;s duration and the number of witnesses. Project Blue Book classified the case as a hoax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In Popular Culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kelly–Hopkinsville encounter has inspired several works of fiction. Steven Spielberg used the event as the basis for his unproduced horror film &lt;em&gt;Night Skies&lt;/em&gt;. The 1986 film &lt;em&gt;Critters&lt;/em&gt; is loosely based on the encounter. The Pokémon Sableye is believed to be inspired by the alleged goblins. The &amp;ldquo;hobkins&amp;rdquo; gremlins in the &lt;em&gt;Pathfinder Roleplaying Game&lt;/em&gt; are based on the goblins. The Annoyance Theater in Chicago created a musical called &amp;ldquo;It Came From Kentucky&amp;rdquo; based on the event. A 2020 episode of the television series &lt;em&gt;Project Blue Book&lt;/em&gt; focused on the encounter. The community of Kelly celebrates the event annually with the Little Green Men Days Festival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kelly%E2%80%93Hopkinsville_encounter&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kelly%E2%80%93Hopkinsville_encounter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in France</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_2b7da8d75dba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 17:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_2b7da8d75dba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-france&#34;&gt;List of Alleged UFO Sightings in France &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-france&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article catalogues alleged UFO sightings within France, spanning from the early Middle Ages to the late 20th century. It provides brief descriptions of each event, including locations, dates, and key witnesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;815&#34;&gt;815 &lt;a href=&#34;#815&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details an account from 815 in Lyons, Auvergne-Rhône-Alpes, referencing the writings of Carolingian archbishop Agobard of Lyons. Agobard&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;De Grandine et Tonitruis&lt;/em&gt; describes beliefs in a region called Magonia, from which ships supposedly came in the clouds, transporting fruits lost to hail and storms. The account also mentions people who claimed to have captured individuals who fell from these ships and were about to be stoned before the truth prevailed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1952&#34;&gt;1952 &lt;a href=&#34;#1952&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on an event in Oloron-Sainte-Marie on October 17, 1952. Multiple witnesses reported seeing a cigar-shaped UFO accompanied by approximately 30 disc-shaped objects. These objects allegedly dropped a white siliceous cotton-like substance that covered trees and roofs. The event was met with skepticism, with some suggesting it was an optical phenomenon or caused by migrating spiders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1954&#34;&gt;1954 &lt;a href=&#34;#1954&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights the Marius Dewilde case from September 10, 1954, in Quarouble, Nord. Railway worker Marius Dewilde claimed to have witnessed two small beings boarding a UFO before it flew into the sky. The incident garnered significant media attention, and strange occurrences were reported in the area in the days following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1965&#34;&gt;1965 &lt;a href=&#34;#1965&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details two separate incidents. The first is the Valensole incident on July 1, 1965, in Alpes-de-Haute-Provence, involving farmer Maurice Masse. Masse claimed to have encountered two small beings near a spherical vehicle that had landed in his field. He said he was paralyzed by one of the beings and observed them making grunting sounds while examining plants. Masse considered the encounter a spiritual experience. UFOlogists cite &amp;ldquo;landing gear impressions&amp;rdquo; as evidence. The second incident occurred in Fort-de-France, Martinique, in late September 1965. Hundreds of witnesses saw a ball or disk of light moving slowly across the sky, leaving a glowing trail. Michel Figuet, a helmsman in the French fleet, reported the sighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1967&#34;&gt;1967 &lt;a href=&#34;#1967&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the Close encounter of Cussac on August 29, 1967, in Cantal. Two young children claimed to have witnessed a UFO and its occupants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1976&#34;&gt;1976 &lt;a href=&#34;#1976&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section recounts an event on November 5, 1976, near Rives/Voreppe, Isère. A French physicist, Dr. S., reported seeing a luminous disk moving in the sky, brighter than the full moon. The object&amp;rsquo;s distance was estimated between 9 and 36 kilometers. The same phenomenon was observed by multiple people over a 250-kilometer stretch from Clermont-Ferrand to Grenoble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1978&#34;&gt;1978 &lt;a href=&#34;#1978&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details an incident on June 19, 1978, in Gujan-Mestras, Gironde. Several people witnessed a UAP that allegedly caused a city-wide blackout. The local police and GEPAN investigated the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1981&#34;&gt;1981 &lt;a href=&#34;#1981&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the Trans-en-Provence Case from January 8, 1981, in Var. This case is considered significant by UFOlogists due to alleged material traces left by a UFO. Skeptics dismiss the event as a joke and attribute the traces to tires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1982&#34;&gt;1982 &lt;a href=&#34;#1982&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes an event on October 21, 1982, in Nancy, France. A biologist witnessed an ovoid object descending into a garden and hovering above the ground. After 20 minutes, the object silently ascended. The witness reported that the grass under the object stood up straight and nearby amaranth plants withered. The Gendarmerie investigated and took samples, which GEPAN analyzed, finding dehydration but no radiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to other relevant Wikipedia articles, including the &amp;ldquo;List of reported UFO sightings.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited within the article, including books, news articles, and online resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external websites, including the CNES-GEIPAN (French government UFO research organization) website and the MUFON (Mutual UFO Network) website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_France&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_France&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
