<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unexplained on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/unexplained/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unexplained on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 17:54:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/unexplained/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in France</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_2b7da8d75dba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 17:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_2b7da8d75dba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-france&#34;&gt;List of Alleged UFO Sightings in France &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-france&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article catalogues alleged UFO sightings within France, spanning from the early Middle Ages to the late 20th century. It provides brief descriptions of each event, including locations, dates, and key witnesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;815&#34;&gt;815 &lt;a href=&#34;#815&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details an account from 815 in Lyons, Auvergne-Rhône-Alpes, referencing the writings of Carolingian archbishop Agobard of Lyons. Agobard&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;De Grandine et Tonitruis&lt;/em&gt; describes beliefs in a region called Magonia, from which ships supposedly came in the clouds, transporting fruits lost to hail and storms. The account also mentions people who claimed to have captured individuals who fell from these ships and were about to be stoned before the truth prevailed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1952&#34;&gt;1952 &lt;a href=&#34;#1952&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on an event in Oloron-Sainte-Marie on October 17, 1952. Multiple witnesses reported seeing a cigar-shaped UFO accompanied by approximately 30 disc-shaped objects. These objects allegedly dropped a white siliceous cotton-like substance that covered trees and roofs. The event was met with skepticism, with some suggesting it was an optical phenomenon or caused by migrating spiders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1954&#34;&gt;1954 &lt;a href=&#34;#1954&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights the Marius Dewilde case from September 10, 1954, in Quarouble, Nord. Railway worker Marius Dewilde claimed to have witnessed two small beings boarding a UFO before it flew into the sky. The incident garnered significant media attention, and strange occurrences were reported in the area in the days following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1965&#34;&gt;1965 &lt;a href=&#34;#1965&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details two separate incidents. The first is the Valensole incident on July 1, 1965, in Alpes-de-Haute-Provence, involving farmer Maurice Masse. Masse claimed to have encountered two small beings near a spherical vehicle that had landed in his field. He said he was paralyzed by one of the beings and observed them making grunting sounds while examining plants. Masse considered the encounter a spiritual experience. UFOlogists cite &amp;ldquo;landing gear impressions&amp;rdquo; as evidence. The second incident occurred in Fort-de-France, Martinique, in late September 1965. Hundreds of witnesses saw a ball or disk of light moving slowly across the sky, leaving a glowing trail. Michel Figuet, a helmsman in the French fleet, reported the sighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1967&#34;&gt;1967 &lt;a href=&#34;#1967&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes the Close encounter of Cussac on August 29, 1967, in Cantal. Two young children claimed to have witnessed a UFO and its occupants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1976&#34;&gt;1976 &lt;a href=&#34;#1976&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section recounts an event on November 5, 1976, near Rives/Voreppe, Isère. A French physicist, Dr. S., reported seeing a luminous disk moving in the sky, brighter than the full moon. The object&amp;rsquo;s distance was estimated between 9 and 36 kilometers. The same phenomenon was observed by multiple people over a 250-kilometer stretch from Clermont-Ferrand to Grenoble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1978&#34;&gt;1978 &lt;a href=&#34;#1978&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details an incident on June 19, 1978, in Gujan-Mestras, Gironde. Several people witnessed a UAP that allegedly caused a city-wide blackout. The local police and GEPAN investigated the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1981&#34;&gt;1981 &lt;a href=&#34;#1981&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the Trans-en-Provence Case from January 8, 1981, in Var. This case is considered significant by UFOlogists due to alleged material traces left by a UFO. Skeptics dismiss the event as a joke and attribute the traces to tires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1982&#34;&gt;1982 &lt;a href=&#34;#1982&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes an event on October 21, 1982, in Nancy, France. A biologist witnessed an ovoid object descending into a garden and hovering above the ground. After 20 minutes, the object silently ascended. The witness reported that the grass under the object stood up straight and nearby amaranth plants withered. The Gendarmerie investigated and took samples, which GEPAN analyzed, finding dehydration but no radiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to other relevant Wikipedia articles, including the &amp;ldquo;List of reported UFO sightings.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited within the article, including books, news articles, and online resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external websites, including the CNES-GEIPAN (French government UFO research organization) website and the MUFON (Mutual UFO Network) website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_France&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_France&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
