<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nuclear Missiles on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/nuclear-missiles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nuclear Missiles on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 13:32:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/nuclear-missiles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Malmstrom UFO incident</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_d3683887b604/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 13:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_d3683887b604/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;malmstrom-ufo-incident&#34;&gt;Malmstrom UFO Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#malmstrom-ufo-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the alleged Malmstrom UFO incident, focusing on claims that a UFO sighting was connected to a weapons failure at a nuclear missile complex in Montana in 1967. It presents claims made by retired Air Force personnel, skeptical counterarguments, and the incident&amp;rsquo;s coverage in media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1967-missile-complex-malfunction&#34;&gt;1967 Missile Complex Malfunction &lt;a href=&#34;#1967-missile-complex-malfunction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the 1967 incident at the Echo Flight missile complex, located between Hilger and Winifred, Montana, and operated by personnel from Malmstrom Air Force Base. On March 16, 1967, all sites in Echo Flight experienced a shutdown with &amp;ldquo;No-Go&amp;rdquo; indications, causing all launch facilities to lose strategic alert nearly simultaneously. An Air Force report mentioned rumors of UFOs around the area but stated they were disproven. A Mobile Strike Team reported no unusual activity or sightings. The malfunction, termed the &amp;ldquo;Echo Flight Incident,&amp;rdquo; was resolved within a day by maintenance crews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;public-claims-by-robert-salas&#34;&gt;Public Claims by Robert Salas &lt;a href=&#34;#public-claims-by-robert-salas&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the claims made by Robert Salas, a 26-year-old Air Force Lieutenant at the time of the 1967 malfunction. In a 1996 Great Falls Tribune article, Salas recounted how a security guard reported flying objects performing strange maneuvers and a glowing red object hovering above the front gate. Shortly after, the complex&amp;rsquo;s ten Minuteman nuclear missiles went offline. Salas emphasized he was not a &amp;ldquo;UFO junkie&amp;rdquo; and sought answers to the mystery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;promotion-in-media&#34;&gt;Promotion in Media &lt;a href=&#34;#promotion-in-media&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the media coverage of the Malmstrom UFO incident. It notes coverage in regional papers starting in 2000, including the Missoula Independent in 2001 and 2002. Air Force documents related to the incident were released under the Freedom of Information Act. Robert Salas authored &lt;em&gt;Faded Giant&lt;/em&gt; in 2005, speculating about a government cover-up to exploit extraterrestrial technology. In 2008, UFO author Robert Hastings discussed the incident in his book &lt;em&gt;UFOs and Nukes&lt;/em&gt;, which Salas defended. Salas appeared at the National Press Club in 2010 with other UFO speakers and authored &lt;em&gt;Unidentified: The UFO Phenomenon&lt;/em&gt; in 2014 and &lt;em&gt;UAPs and the Nuclear Puzzle&lt;/em&gt; in 2023. The Great Falls Tribune marked the event&amp;rsquo;s 50th anniversary in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;skeptical-views&#34;&gt;Skeptical Views &lt;a href=&#34;#skeptical-views&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents skeptical perspectives on the Malmstrom UFO incident. Science writer Mick West argues that the military investigated the incident and found no connection to UFO sightings, attributing the story&amp;rsquo;s persistence to Salas&amp;rsquo;s promotional efforts. Brian Dunning points out discrepancies between Salas&amp;rsquo;s memories and records from the 341st Strategic Missile Wing, suggesting the missile restart was due to a commonplace power failure and unrelated to later UFO reports. Michael Shermer, appearing with Salas on CNN, suggested that people can be unreliable observers and that extraordinary claims require extraordinary evidence. Robert Sheaffer suggests the UFO sighting was likely Mars and unrelated to the missile malfunction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malmstrom_UFO_incident&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malmstrom_UFO_incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
