<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science Fiction Universe on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/science-fiction-universe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science Fiction Universe on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 05:10:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/science-fiction-universe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alliance–Union universe</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_beba5dc8e508/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 05:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_beba5dc8e508/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;allianceunion-universe&#34;&gt;Alliance–Union Universe &lt;a href=&#34;#allianceunion-universe&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article provides an overview of the Alliance–Union universe, a fictional setting created by C. J. Cherryh for her science fiction novels and short stories. It details the universe&amp;rsquo;s history, key factions, technologies, and alien species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description &lt;a href=&#34;#description&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section introduces the Alliance–Union universe as a future history spanning the third and fourth millennia, focusing on humanity&amp;rsquo;s expansion into space. It identifies the three major economic and political powers: Earth Company, the Alliance (a confederation of interstellar trade merchants), and the Union (a breakaway government based on Cyteen). The section highlights the Company Wars, Earth Company&amp;rsquo;s failed attempts to control space expansion, and the Union&amp;rsquo;s use of cloned humans (&lt;em&gt;azi&lt;/em&gt;) in its quest for territory. It also mentions that the Alliance–Union universe includes other series like &lt;em&gt;Faded Sun&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Chanur&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Morgaine&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Merovingen Nights&lt;/em&gt;. Patricia Monk&amp;rsquo;s concept of a &amp;ldquo;megatext&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;collage novel&amp;rdquo; is introduced, suggesting that linking these series creates a larger, interconnected narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the chronological development of the Alliance–Union universe. It begins with the establishment of space stations by the Earth Company and the emergence of distinct stationer and merchanter cultures. The discovery of Pell&amp;rsquo;s World in the Tau Ceti system, with its hospitable environment and alien life (the Hisa), disrupts the existing power balance. The development of faster-than-light (FTL) travel leads to Earth&amp;rsquo;s attempts to reassert control, culminating in the Company Wars. The Union, centered at the Cyteen system, declares independence and uses genetically engineered clones (&lt;em&gt;azi&lt;/em&gt;) in its military. The conflict reaches a turning point at Pell Station, leading to the formation of the Alliance as a neutral power. Conrad Mazian, commander of the Earth Company Fleet, refuses to accept peace and becomes a renegade. Signy Mallory, one of his captains, defects to the Alliance. The Mazianni are eventually driven off, but a new rivalry emerges between the Alliance and Union. The section concludes by mentioning the political factions within Union and the role of scientist Ariane Emory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;genre&#34;&gt;Genre &lt;a href=&#34;#genre&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section classifies the various works within the Alliance–Union universe by genre. Many stories set in space are considered space opera, while those on planets are planetary romances. Works like &lt;em&gt;Cyteen&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Downbelow Station&lt;/em&gt; are also hard science fiction. The &amp;ldquo;Company Wars&amp;rdquo; novels and the &lt;em&gt;Faded Sun&lt;/em&gt; trilogy are military science fiction. The &lt;em&gt;Merovingen Nights&lt;/em&gt; series is classified as science fantasy, and &lt;em&gt;The Morgaine Cycle&lt;/em&gt; books are set remotely in time and space. &lt;em&gt;Voyager in Night&lt;/em&gt; incorporates elements of horror fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;books-and-reading-order&#34;&gt;Books and Reading Order &lt;a href=&#34;#books-and-reading-order&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides guidance on the order in which to read the books set in the Alliance–Union universe. C. J. Cherryh states that most books can be read in any order, with two exceptions: &lt;em&gt;Heavy Time&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Hellburner&lt;/em&gt; should be read in that order, and &lt;em&gt;Cyteen&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Regenesis&lt;/em&gt; should be read in sequence. The novels in the &lt;em&gt;Faded Sun&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Chanur&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Morgaine&lt;/em&gt; series are also designed to be read in order. The &lt;em&gt;Merovingen Nights&lt;/em&gt; series begins with &lt;em&gt;Angel with the Sword&lt;/em&gt; and continues with the short story anthologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;major-characters&#34;&gt;Major Characters &lt;a href=&#34;#major-characters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists and describes some of the most important characters in the Alliance–Union universe. These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pyanfar Chanur:&lt;/strong&gt; Hani captain and leader of the Compact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sten Duncan:&lt;/strong&gt; Alliance soldier who joins the Mri.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ariane Emory-1 and Ariane Emory-2 PR:&lt;/strong&gt; Scientist and her clone from Cyteen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Damon Konstantin and Elene Quen:&lt;/strong&gt; Leaders of Pell Station and the Merchanter Alliance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conrad Mazian:&lt;/strong&gt; Commander of the Earth Company Fleet and later leader of the Mazianni.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Signy Mallory:&lt;/strong&gt; Captain of the &lt;em&gt;Norway&lt;/em&gt; who defects to the Alliance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elizabeth McGee:&lt;/strong&gt; Union scientist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James Robert Neihart:&lt;/strong&gt; Senior captain of &lt;em&gt;Finity&amp;rsquo;s End&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kurt Morgan:&lt;/strong&gt; Survivor of the &lt;em&gt;Endymion&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raen a Sul hant Meth-maren:&lt;/strong&gt; Human mediator with the Majat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thorn:&lt;/strong&gt; Human raised by the Shonunin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sentient-alien-species&#34;&gt;Sentient Alien Species &lt;a href=&#34;#sentient-alien-species&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides a table listing various sentient alien species encountered in the Alliance–Union universe. The table includes the species name, home system, home planet, the works in which they appear, and brief notes about their characteristics. Some of the species listed are the Amaut, Ahnit, Caliban, Chi, Elee, Hani, Hisa, Iduve, Kallia, Kif, Knnn, Majat, Mahendo&amp;rsquo;sat, Mri, Nemet, Regul, Stsho, Sharrh, Shonunin, and Tc&amp;rsquo;a. The section also mentions the Qual/Khal from the &lt;em&gt;Morgaine&lt;/em&gt; books and the Harilim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;planets&#34;&gt;Planets &lt;a href=&#34;#planets&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section describes several key planets in the Alliance–Union universe:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pell&amp;rsquo;s World (Downbelow):&lt;/strong&gt; A planet orbiting Tau Ceti, notable for its advanced ecosystem, intelligent extraterrestrial life (the Hisa), and its impact on the balance of power.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gehenna:&lt;/strong&gt; A habitable planet in the Zeta Reticuli system, secretly colonized by the Union and home to the calibans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cyteen:&lt;/strong&gt; A planet deep in Union territory, with a toxic atmosphere and native life, known for its rejuvenation drug.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Merovin:&lt;/strong&gt; An isolated planet with backward technology due to poor interstellar relations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;technologies&#34;&gt;Technologies &lt;a href=&#34;#technologies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section outlines the signature futuristic technologies of the Alliance–Union universe:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump Drive:&lt;/strong&gt; Allows faster-than-light travel by shifting ships into a parallel space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rejuv:&lt;/strong&gt; A life-extension drug derived from Cyteen&amp;rsquo;s lifeforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human Cloning:&lt;/strong&gt; Used extensively by the Union to create &lt;em&gt;azi&lt;/em&gt;, genetically tailored laborers and soldiers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tape:&lt;/strong&gt; Subliminal conditioning and information transfer used for various purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Terraforming:&lt;/strong&gt; Technologies used to make areas of Cyteen suitable for Earth-based life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;society&#34;&gt;Society &lt;a href=&#34;#society&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section describes the societal structures and attitudes within the Alliance–Union universe. It highlights the divergence of attitudes between planet-dwellers, space station-dwellers, and starship crews. Space station residents are cautious, while starship crews have an insular worldview due to the effects of jump. In Union, there is a division between unengineered citizens (CITs) and &lt;em&gt;azi&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mazianni&#34;&gt;Mazianni &lt;a href=&#34;#mazianni&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section defines the &lt;em&gt;Mazianni&lt;/em&gt; as the military starships and their crews who remained loyal to Conrad Mazian after he renounced his allegiance to Earth. It describes their origins as the Earth Company Fleet, their role in the Company War, and their subsequent guerrilla warfare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;songs&#34;&gt;Songs &lt;a href=&#34;#songs&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section mentions that C. J. Cherryh wrote a collection of songs about the station trade, which were recorded by filk musician Leslie Fish and released on an album entitled &lt;em&gt;Finity&amp;rsquo;s End&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;critical-reception&#34;&gt;Critical Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section summarizes the critical reception of the Alliance–Union universe. John Clute called it Cherryh&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;central achievement,&amp;rdquo; noting its rough edges but the impression of a larger, yet-to-be-revealed history. M. Keith Booker described it as &amp;ldquo;so far-reaching that its overall outlines remain unclear and continue to develop.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists the references cited in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;works-cited&#34;&gt;Works Cited &lt;a href=&#34;#works-cited&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists the works cited in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further Reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section lists additional resources for further reading about the Alliance–Union universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External Links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external websites related to the Alliance–Union universe, including the author&amp;rsquo;s official site, star maps, and a list of ships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hisa_(fictional_alien_species)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hisa_(fictional_alien_species)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
