<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Magnetism on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/magnetism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Magnetism on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 12:54:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/magnetism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project Magnet (UFO)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_54c2e92fd9a1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 12:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_54c2e92fd9a1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;project-magnet&#34;&gt;Project Magnet &lt;a href=&#34;#project-magnet&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project Magnet was a Canadian government-sponsored study of unidentified flying objects (UFOs) established in December 1950 and led by Wilbert Brockhouse Smith. The project was formally active until mid-1954, but Smith continued research informally until his death in 1962. Smith concluded that UFOs were likely extraterrestrial in origin and operated by manipulating magnetism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project began after Smith requested permission to use Department of Transport facilities to study UFOs. Approved on December 2, 1950, the project aimed to collect data on UFOs and apply it to practical engineering and technology, specifically geomagnetism and the possibility of using Earth&amp;rsquo;s magnetic field for propulsion. The project involved DOT facilities and assistance from the Defence Research Board (DRB) and the National Research Council. In June 1952, Smith issued a preliminary report suggesting UFOs came from intelligent, extraterrestrial sources and manipulated magnetism for flight. A 1953 report reiterated these conclusions. In April 1952, the Canadian government also established Project Second Storey, a parallel UFO research project involving Smith, consisting of scientists and military officers who met to consider the UFO question and recommend government action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith also believed UFOs were linked to psychic phenomena and claimed to be in telepathic contact with extraterrestrial beings. He wrote articles for &lt;em&gt;Topside&lt;/em&gt;, the publication of the Ottawa New Sciences Club, outlining the philosophy of the &amp;ldquo;Space Brothers&amp;rdquo; with whom he claimed to be in contact. These articles were later published posthumously in 1969 as &lt;em&gt;The Boys from Topside&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;shirleys-bay&#34;&gt;Shirley&amp;rsquo;s Bay &lt;a href=&#34;#shirleys-bay&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October 1952, Smith established an observatory at Shirley&amp;rsquo;s Bay outside Ottawa to study UFO sightings, believing they emitted measurable physical characteristics. Project Magnet investigated several sighting reports, but the project was shut down in 1954. Smith continued to use the Shirley&amp;rsquo;s Bay facilities with his own funding until his death in 1962.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_Magnet_(UFO)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_Magnet_(UFO)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
