<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Foo Fighters on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/foo-fighters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Foo Fighters on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/foo-fighters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>List of reported UFO sightings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_583476a95eee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_583476a95eee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-reported-ufo-sightings&#34;&gt;List of Reported UFO Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-reported-ufo-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Wikipedia article provides a compilation of notable reported sightings of Unidentified Flying Objects (UFOs), including claims of close encounters and alien abduction. It clarifies that UFOs encompass any aerial phenomenon that cannot be immediately identified, noting that most are eventually explained as known objects or atmospheric phenomena. The article also mentions the use of the term &amp;ldquo;Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena&amp;rdquo; (UAP) to avoid associations with UFO conspiracy theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;antiquity&#34;&gt;Antiquity &lt;a href=&#34;#antiquity&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details alleged UFO sightings from ancient times, drawing from historical texts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c. 1450 BC:&lt;/strong&gt; The Tulli Papyrus describes an event during Thutmose III&amp;rsquo;s reign in Ancient Egypt, where a &amp;ldquo;star came down&amp;rdquo; and set fire to his adversaries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;218 BC:&lt;/strong&gt; Reports from the Roman Republic in Italia mention &amp;ldquo;phantom navy&amp;rdquo; seen shining in the sky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;76 BC:&lt;/strong&gt; An account from Asia (Roman Republic) describes a &amp;ldquo;spark&amp;rdquo; falling from a star, growing to the size of the Moon, and then transforming into a torch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;73 BC:&lt;/strong&gt; Plutarch recounts a &amp;ldquo;flame-like body&amp;rdquo; resembling a wine-jar (pithos) falling between Roman and Pontic armies in Phrygia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AD 65:&lt;/strong&gt; Flavius Josephus reports chariots &amp;ldquo;hurtling through the clouds&amp;rdquo; in Judaea before the First Jewish–Roman War.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AD 196:&lt;/strong&gt; Cassius Dio describes a &amp;ldquo;fine rain resembling silver&amp;rdquo; falling from a clear sky in Rome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;8th-century&#34;&gt;8th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#8th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a single entry:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c. AD 740:&lt;/strong&gt; The &amp;ldquo;Air ship of Clonmacnoise&amp;rdquo; is recorded in Irish annals, describing &amp;ldquo;ships with their crews were seen in the air&amp;rdquo; over Teltown and Clonmacnoise in Ireland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;16th17th-centuries&#34;&gt;16th–17th Centuries &lt;a href=&#34;#16th17th-centuries&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists reports from the Renaissance and early modern periods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1561:&lt;/strong&gt; A celestial phenomenon over Nuremberg, Bavaria, is described as an aerial battle with spheres, cylinders, and other odd-shaped objects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1566:&lt;/strong&gt; A broadsheet depicts spherical objects appearing out of the sun over Basel, Switzerland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1609:&lt;/strong&gt; Multiple witnesses in Joseon (Korea) describe a Halo or washbowl that was divided in two in the sky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;19th-century&#34;&gt;19th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#19th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers sightings from the 1800s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1883:&lt;/strong&gt; Astronomer José Bonilla photographed hundreds of dark objects crossing the sun at the Zacatecas Observatory in Mexico.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1896-1897:&lt;/strong&gt; Reports of &amp;ldquo;mystery airships&amp;rdquo; with bright lights and cigar-shaped bodies appear in newspapers across California and the Midwest United States.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1897:&lt;/strong&gt; S.E. Hayden reports the crash of an airship piloted by an alien in Aurora, Texas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;20th-century&#34;&gt;20th Century &lt;a href=&#34;#20th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is divided into two sub-sections: 1900-1949 and 1950-1974.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;19001949&#34;&gt;1900–1949 &lt;a href=&#34;#19001949&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the early to mid-20th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1904:&lt;/strong&gt; Crew members aboard the USS &lt;em&gt;Supply&lt;/em&gt; report seeing three &amp;ldquo;bright red&amp;rdquo; objects in geometrical formation flight pattern in the North Pacific.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1907:&lt;/strong&gt; Fighters of Çerçiz Topulli in Albania report seeing a shiny object suspended in the air.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1909:&lt;/strong&gt; Moving lights are reported in the sky around Otago, New Zealand, followed by more sightings across the country.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1917:&lt;/strong&gt; Thousands gather in Fátima, Portugal, and claim to see bizarre solar activity, later interpreted as a mass UFO sighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1926:&lt;/strong&gt; Nicholas Roerich reports an oval object in the sky above his caravan in Tibet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1933:&lt;/strong&gt; Frank Smythe witnesses two spots hovering and pulsating in the sky near Mount Everest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1940s:&lt;/strong&gt; Allied fighter pilots report colorful balls of light following their aircraft during World War II (Foo fighters).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1941:&lt;/strong&gt; A local legend emerges in Cape Girardeau, Missouri, about a crashed flying saucer and its dying crew.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1942:&lt;/strong&gt; Anti-aircraft artillery fires thousands of rounds at an unidentified aerial object over Los Angeles, California (Battle of Los Angeles).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1942:&lt;/strong&gt; Control tower operator near Flying School, Columbus, Missouri observes two reddish colored round objects descend-hover-accelerate away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1944:&lt;/strong&gt; 468th Bomb Group reports an intense red or orange object that throbbed or vibrated constantly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1945:&lt;/strong&gt; Conflicting accounts emerge regarding an avocado-shaped craft piloted by insectoid aliens crashing at the Trinity nuclear test site in New Mexico.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1946:&lt;/strong&gt; Thousands of UFO sightings are reported over Europe (Ghost Rockets), prompting investigations by the Swedish and Greek governments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1946:&lt;/strong&gt; Swedish entrepreneur Gösta Carlsson commemorates a 1946 UFO encounter with a concrete monument in Ängelholm, Sweden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; Private pilot Kenneth Arnold reports seeing a group of reflective craft moving at high speeds near Mount Rainier, Washington, coining the term &amp;ldquo;flying saucers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; Over 800 similar sightings are reported throughout 1947 after the Kenneth Arnold sighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; A United Airlines crew witnesses nine unidentified objects en route from Boise, Idaho, to Pendleton, Oregon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; William Albert Rhodes takes photographs of a silent grey object in Phoenix, Arizona.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; Walter Haut issues a press release announcing the &amp;ldquo;capture&amp;rdquo; of a &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; near Roswell, New Mexico, later retracted as a weather balloon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947:&lt;/strong&gt; Fred Crisman mails an account of flying doughnut-shaped objects and threats from Men in Black to Raymond A. Palmer (Maury Island hoax).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; Reports of green flares streaking across the sky are investigated by the US Air Force (The Green Fireballs).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; Captain Thomas F. Mantell dies in the crash of his P-51 Mustang fighter plane near Franklin, Kentucky, after pursuing an unidentified flying object.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; Conmen Silas Newton and Leo Gebauer sell &amp;ldquo;magnetic oil-detecting machines&amp;rdquo; based on a story about replicated technology from a crashed spaceship (Aztec, New Mexico UFO hoax).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; Clarence Chiles and John Whitted report that their airplane nearly collided with a UFO near Montgomery, Alabama.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1948:&lt;/strong&gt; A US Air Force pilot sights and pursues a UFO for 27 minutes over Fargo, North Dakota (Gorman dogfight).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;19501974&#34;&gt;1950–1974 &lt;a href=&#34;#19501974&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the mid to late 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1950:&lt;/strong&gt; A farmer takes pictures of a purported &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; near McMinnville, Oregon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1950:&lt;/strong&gt; The manager of Great Falls&amp;rsquo; pro baseball team took color film of two UFOs flying over Great Falls, Montana.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1951:&lt;/strong&gt; Two pilots and a military officer passenger aboard a commercial DC-3 reported being buzzed by an unidentified straight-winged plane over Sioux City, Iowa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1951:&lt;/strong&gt; Several lights in V-shaped formations were repeatedly spotted flying over the city of Lubbock, Texas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952:&lt;/strong&gt; Four American military personnel aboard two different B-29 bombers reported seeing an orange globe-shaped light over two different cities in northern Korea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952:&lt;/strong&gt; A series of sightings accompanied radar contacts in the Washington, D.C. area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952:&lt;/strong&gt; William B. Nash and William H. Fortenberry, pilots of a DC-4 airliner of Pan American Airways, radioed the Norfolk civil aviation authority to report eight large, round, glowing red objects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952:&lt;/strong&gt; Three local boys followed a bright object into the forest to what they believed was a UFO landing in Flatwoods, West Virginia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1954:&lt;/strong&gt; French metalworker Marius Dewilde claimed to have become a contactee in Quarouble, France.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1954:&lt;/strong&gt; A football game between Fiorentina and Pistoiese was under way at the Stadio Artemio Franchi in Florence when a group of UFOs traveling at high speed abruptly stopped over the stadium.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1955:&lt;/strong&gt; Eleven people witnessed creatures in the night at a rural farmhouse near Hopkinsville, Kentucky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1956:&lt;/strong&gt; United States Air Force (USAF) and Royal Air Force (RAF) radar operators detected up to 15 objects over Suffolk, England.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1956:&lt;/strong&gt; Elizabeth Klarer claimed detailed adventures with an alien race including having had an alien lover, Akon, who would have fathered her son Ayling in Drakens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO_sightings&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO_sightings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
