<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Disinformation on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/disinformation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Disinformation on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 13:04:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/disinformation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bill Moore (ufologist)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_c8e39d7b02ff/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 13:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_c8e39d7b02ff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;william-l-moore-ufologist&#34;&gt;William L. Moore (Ufologist) &lt;a href=&#34;#william-l-moore-ufologist&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;William Leonard Moore, born October 31, 1943, is an author and former UFO researcher who gained prominence from the late 1970s to the late 1980s. He is best known for co-authoring two books with Charles Berlitz, including &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;career&#34;&gt;Career &lt;a href=&#34;#career&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moore&amp;rsquo;s interest in UFOs began in his teenage years. He graduated from Thiel College in Greenville, Pennsylvania, in 1965. After teaching language and humanities at various high schools, he became the Arizona state section director of the Mutual UFO Network (MUFON). He then transitioned to a career as a freelance writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He co-authored &lt;em&gt;The Philadelphia Experiment - Project Invisibility&lt;/em&gt; with Charles Berlitz in 1979, which explored the alleged naval military experiment aboard the USS &lt;em&gt;Eldridge&lt;/em&gt; in 1943. In 1980, Moore and Berlitz co-wrote &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt;, which claimed that the Roswell UFO incident involved the crash of an extraterrestrial spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May 1987, Moore, along with ufologists Jaime Shandera and Stanton Friedman, circulated the Majestic 12 documents, which purported the existence of a high-level policy-making group overseeing UFOs and extraterrestrials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a 1989 MUFON conference, Moore admitted to engaging in &amp;ldquo;disinformation&amp;rdquo; activities against Paul Bennewitz on behalf of the Air Force Office of Special Investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;critical-reception&#34;&gt;Critical Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Philadelphia Experiment - Project Invisibility&lt;/em&gt; has been largely dismissed as an unsubstantiated urban myth. &lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt; has been criticized as a collection of hearsay and unwarranted speculation. Critics have also pointed fingers at Moore regarding the fraudulent nature of the Majestic 12 documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;books&#34;&gt;Books &lt;a href=&#34;#books&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Philadelphia Experiment Project Invisibility&lt;/em&gt; (1979)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Roswell Incident&lt;/em&gt; (1980)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFO conspiracy theory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bill_Moore_(ufologist)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bill_Moore_(ufologist)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
