<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Creatures on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/creatures/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Creatures on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 02:09:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/creatures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fictional Creatures in a Fictional Universe</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_540f44a89e41/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 02:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_540f44a89e41/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;fictional-creatures-in-a-fictional-universe&#34;&gt;Fictional Creatures in a Fictional Universe &lt;a href=&#34;#fictional-creatures-in-a-fictional-universe&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Wikipedia article provides a comprehensive list of fictional creatures and aliens from the Doctor Who universe, a long-running BBC science fiction television series. It notes the show&amp;rsquo;s initial run from 1963 to 1989, its revival in 2005, and the central character, the Doctor, an extraterrestrial who travels through time and space in the TARDIS. The list excludes specific characters and focuses on alien races and fictional creatures, including those appearing in spin-off series like &lt;em&gt;The Sarah Jane Adventures&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Torchwood&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Class&lt;/em&gt;, but excludes antagonists original to those series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a&#34;&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;#a&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists alien creatures whose names begin with the letter &amp;ldquo;A.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abzorbaloff&#34;&gt;Abzorbaloff &lt;a href=&#34;#abzorbaloff&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Abzorbaloff is an alien creature from the planet Clom, known for absorbing living beings into its body through touch. It appeared in the episode &amp;ldquo;Love &amp;amp; Monsters&amp;rdquo; (2006). In this episode, an Abzorbalovian disguised as &amp;ldquo;Victor Kennedy&amp;rdquo; infiltrated a group called L.I.N.D.A. to gain knowledge from the Doctor. The Abzorbaloff was ultimately defeated when Elton Pope broke its cane, causing the Earth to absorb it. The creature was created by William Grantham, a nine-year-old who won a &lt;em&gt;Blue Peter&lt;/em&gt; contest. Comedian Peter Kay portrayed the Abzorbaloff on-screen. A short sequel, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;The Genuine Article&lt;/em&gt;,&amp;rdquo; features the Abzorbaloff&amp;rsquo;s father seeking revenge, directed and animated by Grantham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;adipose&#34;&gt;Adipose &lt;a href=&#34;#adipose&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Adipose are aliens composed of living fat, featured in the episode &amp;ldquo;Partners in Crime&amp;rdquo; (2008). Originating from the lost breeding world Adipose 3, they rely on a drug formulated by &amp;ldquo;Miss Foster&amp;rdquo; to convert human fat into Adipose children through parthenogenesis. This process, if accelerated, can be fatal to the host. The Adipose abandoned Foster to hide their illegal activities. In an alternate timeline in &amp;ldquo;Turn Left&amp;rdquo; (2008), the Adipose incident in America resulted in over 60 million deaths. The Adipose were inspired by a plush toy owned by writer Russell T Davies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aggedor&#34;&gt;Aggedor &lt;a href=&#34;#aggedor&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aggedor is the Sacred Royal Beast of the planet Peladon, first appearing in &lt;em&gt;The Curse of Peladon&lt;/em&gt; (1972). The creature is a large, hairy beast with a single horn, hunted to near extinction. In the story, Peladon&amp;rsquo;s High Priest, Hepesh, used a captured Aggedor to generate superstition and prevent Peladon from joining the Galactic Federation. Actor Nick Hobbs portrayed Aggedor in both &lt;em&gt;The Curse of Peladon&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Monster of Peladon&lt;/em&gt; (1974). The audio story &lt;em&gt;The Bride of Peladon&lt;/em&gt; reveals Aggedor had a child, which later gave birth to many baby Aggedors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;axons&#34;&gt;Axons &lt;a href=&#34;#axons&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Axons are golden-skinned humanoids who attempt to take over Earth by distributing Axonite, pieces of the single creature Axos, in &lt;em&gt;The Claws of Axos&lt;/em&gt; (1971). They pose as a friendly family but can shapeshift into monstrous forms. The Axons are later trapped in a time loop alongside Axos. Actors Bernard Holley, Patricia Gordino, John Hicks, and Debbie Lee London portrayed the Axons. The Axons reappeared in the 2010 comic strip &amp;ldquo;The Golden Ones,&amp;rdquo; where they attempted to free Axos and rampage across Tokyo until defeated by the Eleventh Doctor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;b&#34;&gt;B &lt;a href=&#34;#b&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists alien creatures whose names begin with the letter &amp;ldquo;B.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bandril&#34;&gt;Bandril &lt;a href=&#34;#bandril&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bandrils are a reptilian species encountered in the serial &lt;em&gt;Timelash&lt;/em&gt; (1985). A villain known as the Borad seeks to start a war between them and the people of Karfel. The Sixth Doctor is able to thwart the plot. Actor Martin Gower portrayed the Bandril Ambassador.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;boneless&#34;&gt;Boneless &lt;a href=&#34;#boneless&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Boneless are creatures from a two-dimensional universe, seen in &amp;ldquo;Flatline&amp;rdquo; (2014). They harness energy from the TARDIS to infiltrate the Doctor&amp;rsquo;s universe. Clara Oswald and Rigsy trick the Boneless into restoring the TARDIS, allowing the Doctor to send them back to their home dimension. The Boneless later appeared in the comic story &lt;em&gt;The Fourth Wall&lt;/em&gt;, where they use comic books to trap readers until the Twelfth Doctor defeats them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;c&#34;&gt;C &lt;a href=&#34;#c&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists alien creatures whose names begin with the letter &amp;ldquo;C.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;carrionite&#34;&gt;Carrionite &lt;a href=&#34;#carrionite&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Carrionites are creatures from &amp;ldquo;The Dark Times,&amp;rdquo; who fought against the Time Lords. They appear in &amp;ldquo;The Shakespeare Code&amp;rdquo; (2007). Three Carrionites, Bloodtide, Doomfinger, and Lilith, attempt to release their species from a prison using the power of words and witchcraft, manipulating William Shakespeare. The Tenth Doctor and Shakespeare reverse the process, trapping the Carrionites back into their prison. They reappeared in the audio drama &lt;em&gt;The Carrionite Curse&lt;/em&gt;, facing the Sixth Doctor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;catkind&#34;&gt;Catkind &lt;a href=&#34;#catkind&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Catkind are felines evolved into humanoids, first seen in &amp;ldquo;New Earth&amp;rdquo; (2006). They have hair-covered bodies, feline facial features, and retractable claws. In &amp;ldquo;New Earth,&amp;rdquo; the Sisters of Plenitude, a group of Catkind, run a hospital where they test on human subjects. The Tenth Doctor develops a cure, and the Sisters are arrested. In &amp;ldquo;Gridlock&amp;rdquo; (2007), a Cat Person, Thomas Kincade Brannigan, has a human wife and kittens. Novice Hame, a surviving Sister of Plentitude, aids the Tenth Doctor. Actress Anna Hope portrayed Hame. A short scene, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;The Secret of Novice Hame&lt;/em&gt;,&amp;rdquo; depicts Hame on her deathbed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chameleons&#34;&gt;Chameleons &lt;a href=&#34;#chameleons&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chameleons are aliens with no features who can take on the appearance of individual humans, seen in &lt;em&gt;The Faceless Ones&lt;/em&gt; (1967). They lost their identities in an explosion and kidnap humans to adopt their identities. The Second Doctor convinces them to seek another solution. The Chameleons later re-appeared in the spin-off book &lt;em&gt;Short Trips and Side Steps&lt;/em&gt;, where they infiltrate the planet Krennos until the Sixth Doctor stops them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cheetah-people&#34;&gt;Cheetah People &lt;a href=&#34;#cheetah-people&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheetah People are feline humanoids resembling cheetahs who enjoy hunting humans, encountered in &lt;em&gt;Survival&lt;/em&gt; (1989). They were once humanoids who mutated after bonding with cat-like creatures known as Kitlings. The Master, stranded on their planet, attempts to use them to escape. The Seventh Doctor stops the Master, leaving him stranded. Writer Rona Munro was disappointed with the final version of the Cheetah People.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chronovores&#34;&gt;Chronovores &lt;a href=&#34;#chronovores&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chronovores are glowing white creatures that live outside time, one of whom, Kronos, is encountered in &lt;em&gt;The Time Monster&lt;/em&gt; (1972). The Master attempts to use Kronos, but the Third Doctor thwarts his plans. The Chronovores re-appeared in the book &lt;em&gt;The Quantum Archangel&lt;/em&gt;, where Kronos sought revenge against the Master and sacrificed itself to stop the Chronovores from feeding on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chuldur&#34;&gt;Chuldur &lt;a href=&#34;#chuldur&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chuldur are a race of shape shifting bird-like aliens who appeared in the Fifteenth Doctor story &amp;ldquo;Rogue&amp;rdquo; (2024). The Chuldur appeared in 1813, where they infiltrated a ball in order to &amp;ldquo;cosplay&amp;rdquo; as those from the nineteenth century. The Fifteenth Doctor is able to trap the Chuldur within a sealing device, which banished them to another dimension, but at the sacrifice of Rogue, a bounty hunter the Doctor had fallen in love with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cryons&#34;&gt;Cryons &lt;a href=&#34;#cryons&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cryons are an all-female species of alien first seen in &lt;em&gt;Attack of the Cybermen&lt;/em&gt; (1985). They cannot exist at temperatures above zero degrees. The Cryons lived on Telos until the Cybermen took control, and allied with the mercenary Lytton to defeat them. The Cryons were later destroyed by an attack by the Cybermen. Director Matthew Robinson elected to make the Cryons an all-female race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cyberman&#34;&gt;Cyberman &lt;a href=&#34;#cyberman&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cybermen are humanoids originating on Earth&amp;rsquo;s twin planet Mondas, first seen in &lt;em&gt;The Tenth Planet&lt;/em&gt; (1966). They replace organic body parts with artificial ones, becoming coldly logical. The Cyberman concept was created by Dr. Kit Pedler and Gerry Davis in 1966. The Cybermen were portrayed by tall actors. In the two-part story &amp;ldquo;Rise of the Cybermen&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;The Age of Steel&amp;rdquo; (2006), the Cybermen originate on a parallel-universe version of Earth, created by John Lumic. The Cybermen have several variants, such as the Cybermat and the Cybershades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;d&#34;&gt;D &lt;a href=&#34;#d&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists alien creatures whose names begin with the letter &amp;ldquo;D.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dæmon&#34;&gt;Dæmon &lt;a href=&#34;#d%c3%a6mon&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A race of humanoids from the planet Dæmos, seen in &lt;em&gt;The Dæmons&lt;/em&gt; (1971). They resemble demons and have great power. The Master attempts to obtain the power of a Dæmon named Azal, but Jo Grant sacrifices herself, confusing Azal and reversing his powers, killing him. Another Dæmon later appeared in the unofficial 2004 BBV film &lt;em&gt;Dæmos Rising&lt;/em&gt;, and the spin-off novel &lt;em&gt;Child of Time&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dalek&#34;&gt;Dalek &lt;a href=&#34;#dalek&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Doctor_Who_universe_creatures_and_aliens&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Doctor_Who_universe_creatures_and_aliens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
