<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Military SF on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/military-sf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Military SF on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 05:10:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/military-sf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alliance–Union universe</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_5a9d367a3d1f/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 05:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_5a9d367a3d1f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;allianceunion-universe&#34;&gt;Alliance–Union Universe &lt;a href=&#34;#allianceunion-universe&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Alliance–Union universe is a fictional setting created by C. J. Cherryh for her science fiction novels. It spans from the 21st century into the far future and focuses on humanity&amp;rsquo;s expansion into space. The universe is dominated by three major powers: Earth Company, the Alliance, and the Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description &lt;a href=&#34;#description&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This universe centers on humanity&amp;rsquo;s exploration and colonization of space, leading to the rise of three economic powers: Earth Company, the Alliance, and the Union. The Earth Company&amp;rsquo;s control is challenged during the Company Wars. The Union, based on the planet Cyteen, expands its territories using cloned humans called &lt;em&gt;azi&lt;/em&gt;, leading to conflicts with the Alliance and Earth Company. Other series, such as &lt;em&gt;The Faded Sun Trilogy&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Chanur&lt;/em&gt; novels, and &lt;em&gt;Merovingen Nights&lt;/em&gt;, are linked within this universe, creating a larger narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humanity&amp;rsquo;s initial expansion into space is facilitated by the Sol Corporation, later renamed the Earth Company, which finances the construction of space stations. These stations, built progressively farther from Earth, foster distinct cultural identities among stationers and merchanters. The discovery of Pell&amp;rsquo;s World in the Tau Ceti system disrupts the existing economic and political order, as it provides a habitable planet and supports alien life, the Hisa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The development of faster-than-light (FTL) travel in 2248 prompts Earth to reassert its authority, leading to unrest and rebellion among the colonists. The Earth Company commissions the Company Fleet under Conrad Mazian to enforce its orders. In 2300, the colonists centered at Cyteen declare independence as the Union, augmenting their forces with genetically engineered clones (&lt;em&gt;azi&lt;/em&gt;). The ensuing Company War sees fierce fighting between the Fleet and Union forces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conflict culminates at Pell&amp;rsquo;s World in 2352-2353. Merchanter families form the Alliance, a neutral power. Mazian refuses peace, leading to Signy Mallory&amp;rsquo;s defection to the Alliance with the ship &lt;em&gt;Norway&lt;/em&gt;. Mazian&amp;rsquo;s coup attempt against Earth fails. The Alliance brokers a peace treaty, gaining a monopoly on interstellar commerce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Mazianni threat diminishes, rivalry between the Alliance and Union intensifies. Tensions rise with the discovery of a secret Union colony on Gehenna. Within Union, political factions vie for power, while Ariane Emory pursues her own agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;genre&#34;&gt;Genre &lt;a href=&#34;#genre&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The works in this universe span various science fiction subgenres. Many stories set in space are considered space opera, while those on planets are planetary romances. Works like &lt;em&gt;Cyteen&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Downbelow Station&lt;/em&gt; are hard science fiction. The &amp;ldquo;Company Wars&amp;rdquo; novels and the &lt;em&gt;Faded Sun&lt;/em&gt; trilogy are military science fiction. The &lt;em&gt;Merovingen Nights&lt;/em&gt; series blends science fantasy with elements of sword and planet. &lt;em&gt;Voyager in Night&lt;/em&gt; incorporates elements of horror fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;books-and-reading-order&#34;&gt;Books and Reading Order &lt;a href=&#34;#books-and-reading-order&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. J. Cherryh has stated that the books can be read in any order, except for &lt;em&gt;Heavy Time&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Hellburner&lt;/em&gt;, which should be read in that order, and &lt;em&gt;Cyteen&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Regenesis&lt;/em&gt;, which are tightly linked. The novels in the &lt;em&gt;Faded Sun&lt;/em&gt; trilogy, the &lt;em&gt;Chanur&lt;/em&gt; series, and the &lt;em&gt;Morgaine&lt;/em&gt; series are designed to be read in sequence. The &lt;em&gt;Merovingen Nights&lt;/em&gt; series begins with &lt;em&gt;Angel with the Sword&lt;/em&gt; and continues with the short story anthologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;major-characters&#34;&gt;Major Characters &lt;a href=&#34;#major-characters&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key figures in the Alliance–Union universe include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pyanfar Chanur:&lt;/strong&gt; Hani captain and leader of the Compact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sten Duncan:&lt;/strong&gt; Alliance soldier who joins the Mri.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ariane Emory-1 and Ariane Emory-2 PR:&lt;/strong&gt; Scientist and her clone in the Union.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Damon Konstantin and Elene Quen:&lt;/strong&gt; Leaders in the Merchanter Alliance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conrad Mazian:&lt;/strong&gt; Commander of the Earth Company Fleet and later leader of the Mazianni.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Signy Mallory:&lt;/strong&gt; Captain of the &lt;em&gt;Norway&lt;/em&gt; who defects to the Alliance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elizabeth McGee:&lt;/strong&gt; Union scientist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James Robert Neihart:&lt;/strong&gt; Captain of &lt;em&gt;Finity&amp;rsquo;s End&lt;/em&gt; and negotiator for the Merchanter Alliance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kurt Morgan:&lt;/strong&gt; Survivor of the &lt;em&gt;Endymion&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raen a Sul hant Meth-maren:&lt;/strong&gt; Human mediator with the Majat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thorn:&lt;/strong&gt; Human raised by the Shonunin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sentient-alien-species&#34;&gt;Sentient Alien Species &lt;a href=&#34;#sentient-alien-species&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Alliance–Union universe features a diverse array of sentient alien species, each with unique cultures and characteristics. Some notable species include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amaut:&lt;/strong&gt; Industrious humanoids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ahnit:&lt;/strong&gt; Species appearing in &lt;em&gt;Wave Without a Shore&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caliban:&lt;/strong&gt; Semi-reptilians on Gehenna.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chi:&lt;/strong&gt; Sticklike methane-breathers linked to the T&amp;rsquo;ca.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elee:&lt;/strong&gt; Humanoid, artistic species akin to the Mri.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hani:&lt;/strong&gt; Bipedal felines with a matriarchal society.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hisa:&lt;/strong&gt; Peaceful mammalians on Pell&amp;rsquo;s World.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iduve:&lt;/strong&gt; Dangerous, psychic humanoids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kallia:&lt;/strong&gt; Thin, hollow-boned pacifists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kif:&lt;/strong&gt; Long-snouted carnivores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knnn:&lt;/strong&gt; Multi-legged methane-breathers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Majat:&lt;/strong&gt; Hive-mind insectoids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mahendo&amp;rsquo;sat:&lt;/strong&gt; Political mammalians.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mri:&lt;/strong&gt; Humanoid, militaristic species.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nemet:&lt;/strong&gt; Humanoid species with a strict honor code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regul:&lt;/strong&gt; Xenophobic species with differentiated juvenile and adult forms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stsho:&lt;/strong&gt; Hermaphroditic, fragile species.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sharrh:&lt;/strong&gt; Advanced, aggressive species.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shonunin:&lt;/strong&gt; Bipedal mammalians with technology equivalent to 20th-century Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tc&amp;rsquo;a:&lt;/strong&gt; Serpentine methane-breathers linked to the Chi.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;planets&#34;&gt;Planets &lt;a href=&#34;#planets&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several planets play significant roles in the Alliance–Union universe:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pells-world&#34;&gt;Pell&amp;rsquo;s World &lt;a href=&#34;#pells-world&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also known as Downbelow, Pell&amp;rsquo;s World orbits Tau Ceti and was discovered in 2093. It is the first planet with an advanced ecosystem and intelligent extraterrestrial life (the Hisa). Pell Station orbits the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gehenna&#34;&gt;Gehenna &lt;a href=&#34;#gehenna&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Located in the Zeta Reticuli system, Gehenna is home to the calibans. It was secretly colonized by the Union and then abandoned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cyteen&#34;&gt;Cyteen &lt;a href=&#34;#cyteen&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyteen is a planet in Union territory with a toxic atmosphere. It required terraforming and the establishment of enclaves. It is the source of the rejuvenation drug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;merovin&#34;&gt;Merovin &lt;a href=&#34;#merovin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merovin is an isolated planet with backward technology due to poor interstellar relations with the Sharrh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;technologies&#34;&gt;Technologies &lt;a href=&#34;#technologies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key technologies in the Alliance–Union universe include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump Drive:&lt;/strong&gt; Allows faster-than-light travel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rejuv:&lt;/strong&gt; A life-extension drug derived from Cyteen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cloning:&lt;/strong&gt; Used extensively in the Union to create &lt;em&gt;azi&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tape:&lt;/strong&gt; Subliminal conditioning and information transfer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Terraforming:&lt;/strong&gt; Used to make areas of Cyteen suitable for Earth-based life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;society&#34;&gt;Society &lt;a href=&#34;#society&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key aspect of the Alliance–Union universe is the divergence of attitudes among planet-dwellers, stationers, and spacers. Planet dwellers have concerns similar to those of 21st-century people. Stationers are cautious due to the fragility of their environment. Spacers have an insular worldview due to the effects of jump. In the Union, there is a division between citizens and &lt;em&gt;azi&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mazianni&#34;&gt;Mazianni &lt;a href=&#34;#mazianni&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mazianni are the military starships and crews loyal to Conrad Mazian after he renounces allegiance to Earth. They engage in guerrilla warfare and prey on merchant ships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;songs&#34;&gt;Songs &lt;a href=&#34;#songs&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. J. Cherryh wrote songs about the station trade, which were recorded by Leslie Fish and released on the album &lt;em&gt;Finity&amp;rsquo;s End&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;critical-reception&#34;&gt;Critical Reception &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Clute called the Alliance–Union universe Cherryh&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;central achievement.&amp;rdquo; M. Keith Booker described it as &amp;ldquo;so far-reaching that its overall outlines remain unclear and continue to develop.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mri_(fictional_alien_species)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mri_(fictional_alien_species)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
