<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Africa on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/africa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Africa on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 22:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/africa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFO sightings in Africa</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_728e44ceaefa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_728e44ceaefa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-africa&#34;&gt;List of Alleged UFO Sightings in Africa &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-alleged-ufo-sightings-in-africa&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a compilation of reported Unidentified Flying Object (UFO) sightings across various countries in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;algeria&#34;&gt;Algeria &lt;a href=&#34;#algeria&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details alleged UFO sightings during the Algerian War (1954–1962) around conflict zones. A specific incident from March 1958 is highlighted, where a soldier reported witnessing a large, elliptical craft with green lights and a beam of light. In March 1975, multiple UFOs were reportedly observed by several people across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;benin&#34;&gt;Benin &lt;a href=&#34;#benin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section simply states that reports were received from Benin, but does not provide any specific details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;botswana&#34;&gt;Botswana &lt;a href=&#34;#botswana&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists two specific UFO sightings in Botswana: one in the Okavango Delta on June 25, 2016, and another in Gaberone on May 14, 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;morocco&#34;&gt;Morocco &lt;a href=&#34;#morocco&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes three UFO sightings in July 1952. The first involved two elongated flying saucers spotted by policemen above Had Kourt. The second involved inhabitants of Fedala spotting a blue-green, ball-shaped object. The third involved a couple observing another flying saucer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;senegal&#34;&gt;Senegal &lt;a href=&#34;#senegal&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details a UFO sighting above Dakar on July 3, 1952. The object was described as a flat, tapered saucer surrounded by flames, moving at high speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;south-africa&#34;&gt;South Africa &lt;a href=&#34;#south-africa&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section refers to a main article dedicated to UFO sightings in South Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sudan&#34;&gt;Sudan &lt;a href=&#34;#sudan&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes a UFO sighting in January 2018 over Khartoum. The Sudanese military identified it as a potential satellite, possibly the failed US satellite Zuma, but admitted they could not clearly identify the object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tunisia&#34;&gt;Tunisia &lt;a href=&#34;#tunisia&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section recounts a UFO sighting in July 1969, where many observers, including US embassy officials, reported a large, two-part green-blue object in the sky of Tunis. The object reportedly exploded, forming a greenish circular cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;zimbabwe&#34;&gt;Zimbabwe &lt;a href=&#34;#zimbabwe&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the Ruwa UFO incident on September 14, 1994, where 62 children from a school in Ruwa witnessed the landing of a large spaceship and smaller ones. The children described the aliens as having large heads, slits for mouths, and dark suits. American psychiatrist John E. Mack interviewed the children and concluded that the incident was likely not mass hysteria, as the children gave consistent accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bibliography&#34;&gt;Bibliography &lt;a href=&#34;#bibliography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists two books related to UFOs in Africa:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;UFOs Over Africa&lt;/em&gt; by Cynthia Hind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ufo issue in Central Africa (Gabon, Congo, Democratic Republic of Congo)&lt;/em&gt; by Jann Halexander&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of citations used as sources for the information presented in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains a link to a YouTube video titled &amp;ldquo;UFO Sightings in Algeria 22/01/2008&amp;rdquo; showing a UFO sighting in Taguercift village, Algeria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Africa&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UFO_sightings_in_Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
