<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ExtraterrestrialLife on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/extraterrestriallife/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ExtraterrestrialLife on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 18:04:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/extraterrestriallife/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contact (1997 film)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_d2406df786af/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 18:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_d2406df786af/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;contact-1997-film&#34;&gt;Contact (1997 film) &lt;a href=&#34;#contact-1997-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is a 1997 American science fiction drama film directed by Robert Zemeckis, based on Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s 1985 novel of the same name. The film stars Jodie Foster as Dr. Eleanor Arroway, a SETI scientist who discovers evidence of extraterrestrial life and is chosen to make first contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Ellie Arroway, driven by the childhood loss of her father and inspired by his encouragement of her amateur radio hobby, dedicates her life to SETI research at the Arecibo Observatory. Facing funding cuts led by President&amp;rsquo;s science advisor David Drumlin, she secures private funding from the reclusive billionaire S.R. Hadden to continue her work at the Very Large Array (VLA) in New Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four years later, Arroway discovers a signal from the star Vega containing a sequence of prime numbers. The discovery leads to a global effort to decode the message, which is complicated by Drumlin and the National Security Council&amp;rsquo;s attempts to control the facility. The signal is found to contain a video of Adolf Hitler&amp;rsquo;s opening address at the 1936 Summer Olympics, the first Earth transmission strong enough to reach Vega.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arroway&amp;rsquo;s team decodes the signal, revealing schematics for a complex machine designed to transport a single person. Multiple nations collaborate to fund the machine&amp;rsquo;s construction at the Kennedy Space Center in Cape Canaveral. An international panel is formed to select a candidate for the journey. Arroway is a leading contender, but her atheism, highlighted by panel member Palmer Joss, jeopardizes her selection. Drumlin is chosen, but a religious terrorist destroys the machine during testing, killing Drumlin and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hadden, now terminally ill and living on the Mir space station, informs Arroway of a second, secretly constructed machine in Hokkaido, Japan. Arroway is selected to use it. Equipped with recording devices, she enters the pod and travels through wormholes, observing alien structures and a celestial event. She finds herself on a beach resembling a childhood drawing of Pensacola, Florida, and encounters an alien taking the form of her deceased father, who explains that the aliens have been monitoring humanity&amp;rsquo;s radio emissions and have deemed them ready for first contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arroway awakens in the pod, which has only fallen a short distance into a safety net. Mission control insists that the experiment achieved nothing, and her recording devices show only static. A Congressional Committee, led by Michael Kitz, investigates the possibility of a hoax orchestrated by Hadden, who has since died. Arroway asks the committee to accept her testimony on faith, emphasizing the profound impact of her experience. Kitz and Rachel Constantine, a White House official, acknowledge that Arroway&amp;rsquo;s device recorded 18 hours of static. Arroway receives continued funding for SETI research at the VLA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cast&#34;&gt;Cast &lt;a href=&#34;#cast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film features a cast of notable actors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jodie Foster as Dr. Eleanor &amp;ldquo;Ellie&amp;rdquo; Ann Arroway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jena Malone as young Ellie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matthew McConaughey as Palmer Joss&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Morse as Theodore Arroway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tom Skerritt as Dr. David Drumlin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Woods as Michael Kitz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John Hurt as S. R. Hadden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;William Fichtner as Kent Clarke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Angela Bassett as Rachel Constantine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jake Busey as Joseph&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rob Lowe as Richard Rank&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geoffrey Blake as Fisher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Max Martini as Willie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steven Ford as Major John Russell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jay Leno as himself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Larry King as himself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ann Druyan as herself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;development&#34;&gt;Development &lt;a href=&#34;#development&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Sagan conceived &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; in 1979 with Lynda Obst and Peter Guber at Casablanca FilmWorks. Sagan and Ann Druyan completed the film treatment in 1980, aiming to depict a realistic first contact scenario. Kip Thorne consulted on wormhole travel. The character of Ellie Arroway was not directly inspired by Jill Tarter, though Foster met her for research. The name Ellie was inspired by Eleanor Roosevelt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project faced numerous rewrites and stalled development. Sagan rewrote &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; as a novel, published in 1985. Roland Joffé and George Miller were initially attached to direct but later departed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;filming&#34;&gt;Filming &lt;a href=&#34;#filming&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Zemeckis took over as director, securing artistic control. Filming began in September 1996 and concluded in February 1997. Key locations included the Very Large Array (VLA) in New Mexico, Warner Hollywood Studios, and Culver Studios. CNN news personalities were scripted into the film to enhance realism. Second unit filming took place at the Arecibo Observatory in Puerto Rico, Fiji, Saint John, US Virgin Islands, and Newfoundland, Canada. Technical consultants from the SETI Institute, Caltech, and a former White House staff member were involved. Sagan participated in the production until his death in December 1996, and the film is dedicated to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;visual-effects&#34;&gt;Visual effects &lt;a href=&#34;#visual-effects&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eight VFX companies, including Sony Pictures Imageworks, Weta Digital, and Industrial Light &amp;amp; Magic, collaborated on the visual effects. Weta Digital designed the wormhole sequence. Digital alterations were made to news footage of Bill Clinton. Digital color correction addressed continuity issues during location shooting. The opening scene is a five-minute CGI sequence depicting a zoom out from Earth to the distant universe. The mirror shot was created through three different plates and manipulated in CGI. The machine was designed by concept artist Steve Burg, reusing a design he created as a &amp;ldquo;time-displacement device&amp;rdquo; for an unused scene in &lt;em&gt;Terminator 2&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;Music &lt;a href=&#34;#music&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alan Silvestri composed and conducted the original score. A soundtrack album was released in August 1997.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes &lt;a href=&#34;#themes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; explores the cultural conflicts between religion and science, particularly concerning the existence of God. The film presents various viewpoints on faith and scientific evidence. It depicts intense public debate about the implications of alien contact, including questions about morality and the role of science. The film raises questions about the authenticity of Arroway&amp;rsquo;s journey, leaving room for doubt. The film suggests that science and religion can coexist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release &lt;a href=&#34;#release&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s release in July 1997 boosted interest in Sagan&amp;rsquo;s novel. The book appeared on &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; Best Seller list. The film premiered on July 1, 1997, and was released in the United States and Canada on July 11, 1997.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;critical-reception&#34;&gt;Critical reception &lt;a href=&#34;#critical-reception&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film received generally positive reviews. Critics praised its exploration of scientific and theological concepts but noted weaknesses in storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;awards&#34;&gt;Awards &lt;a href=&#34;#awards&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; won the Hugo Award for Best Dramatic Presentation and two Saturn Awards. It received nominations for an Academy Award for Best Sound and a Golden Globe Award for Best Lead Actress in a Motion Picture – Drama (Jodie Foster).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reactions&#34;&gt;Reactions &lt;a href=&#34;#reactions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bill-clinton&#34;&gt;Bill Clinton &lt;a href=&#34;#bill-clinton&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film used digitally altered footage of President Bill Clinton, leading to a protest from the White House.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cnn&#34;&gt;CNN &lt;a href=&#34;#cnn&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CNN chairman Tom Johnson expressed regret over allowing CNN staff to appear in the film, citing concerns about blurring the lines between news and entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nasa&#34;&gt;NASA &lt;a href=&#34;#nasa&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scene involving a cyanide pill caused controversy, with conflicting accounts from NASA advisor Gerald D. Griffin and Carl Sagan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;seti&#34;&gt;SETI &lt;a href=&#34;#seti&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SETI.org published a review of the film, highlighting its accuracy in depicting SETI research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lawsuits&#34;&gt;Lawsuits &lt;a href=&#34;#lawsuits&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Director George Miller unsuccessfully sued Warner Bros. over breach of contract policies. Francis Ford Coppola sued Warner Bros. and Sagan, claiming that Sagan&amp;rsquo;s novel was based on a story they had developed together. Coppola&amp;rsquo;s claim was dismissed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contact_(1997_American_film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contact_(1997_American_film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
