<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alderney on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/alderney/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alderney on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 13:38:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/alderney/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2007 Alderney UFO sighting</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_40bc71f5c743/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 13:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_40bc71f5c743/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;2007-alderney-ufo-sighting&#34;&gt;2007 Alderney UFO sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#2007-alderney-ufo-sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the reported UFO sighting that occurred on April 23, 2007, over Alderney in the Channel Islands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;accounts-of-the-sighting&#34;&gt;Accounts of the sighting &lt;a href=&#34;#accounts-of-the-sighting&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section introduces the event, mentioning that a pilot, Ray Bowyer, reported seeing unidentified flying objects. An air traffic controller confirmed that another pilot had reported a similar sighting. Passengers on Bowyer&amp;rsquo;s aircraft also reported seeing unusual lights. Possible explanations for the sighting, such as earthquake lights and sun dogs, are also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bowyers-accounts&#34;&gt;Bowyer&amp;rsquo;s accounts &lt;a href=&#34;#bowyers-accounts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the account of Ray Bowyer, the pilot who initially reported the sighting. It details his description of the object as a &amp;ldquo;cigar-shaped brilliant white light,&amp;rdquo; initially thought to be reflections from greenhouses. Bowyer&amp;rsquo;s estimates of the object&amp;rsquo;s size and distance evolved, eventually describing it as being the size of a Boeing 737, then later as large as five or six battleships or a reasonably large town. The section includes details from a recorded conversation between Bowyer and an air traffic controller, who reported only a faint radar contact. Bowyer&amp;rsquo;s actions, such as using binoculars to observe the light, and his report to the Civil Aviation Authority are also covered. The Ministry of Defence&amp;rsquo;s initial reluctance to investigate and subsequent release of information, including a statement from a second pilot, are mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-witness-accounts&#34;&gt;Other witness accounts &lt;a href=&#34;#other-witness-accounts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section presents accounts from other witnesses to the event. Passengers on Bowyer&amp;rsquo;s aircraft reported seeing the light, with one describing it as &amp;ldquo;sunlight-colored&amp;rdquo; and another as &amp;ldquo;an orange light … like an elongated oval.&amp;rdquo; Patrick Patterson, a pilot from Blue Islands, also reported seeing a similar object in the same general location. The section also mentions an interpretation that the sighting was an atmospheric phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;proposed-explanations&#34;&gt;Proposed explanations &lt;a href=&#34;#proposed-explanations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores potential explanations for the UFO sighting. Bowyer rejected the idea that he saw an alien vessel, but considered the possibility of earthquake lights related to the earthquake in south-eastern England that occurred shortly after the sighting. A local astronomer, Michael Maunder, suggested that the sighting could be attributed to sun dogs, an optical phenomenon caused by the refraction of light through ice crystals. He noted that the weather conditions were favorable for sun dogs and that the reported lights were approximately 22 degrees from the sun, consistent with the appearance of sun dogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2007_Alderney_UFO_sighting&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2007_Alderney_UFO_sighting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
