<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hoax on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/hoax/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hoax on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:07:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/hoax/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1967 British flying saucer hoax</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ca77cd9256e0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ca77cd9256e0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;1967-british-flying-saucer-hoax&#34;&gt;1967 British Flying Saucer Hoax &lt;a href=&#34;#1967-british-flying-saucer-hoax&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1967 British flying saucer hoax involved the supposed landing of six &amp;lsquo;spaceships&amp;rsquo; across Southern England on September 4, 1967. These &amp;lsquo;spacecraft&amp;rsquo; prompted a significant response from the police and army. The objects were described as being 54 inches long, 30 inches wide, and 20 inches deep, weighing 100 pounds, and emitting an electronic noise. The six craft were located along the 51st line of latitude, stretching from the Thames Estuary to the Bristol Channel. Specific locations included Queenborough on the Isle of Sheppey, Bromley golf course in south London, Winkfield village near Ascot, Welford near Newbury, Chippenham in Wiltshire, and Dial Hill in Clevedon, Somerset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;planning-and-building-the-spacecraft&#34;&gt;Planning and Building the &amp;lsquo;Spacecraft&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#planning-and-building-the-spacecraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hoax was conceived in January 1967 by aircraft engineering apprentices from the Royal Aircraft Establishment (RAE) at Farnborough as part of Rag Week. The apprentices constructed the flying saucers from fiberglass halves, covered them in metal, and equipped them with electronic devices to produce eerie sounds when flipped. Each saucer also contained a mixture of flour and water. Teams of two or three transported the saucers to the chosen locations at night, flipped them over to activate the sound, and then left the scene undetected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;response-from-the-authorities&#34;&gt;Response from the Authorities &lt;a href=&#34;#response-from-the-authorities&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discovery of the saucers triggered a large-scale response from authorities. Police cordoned off each site, and the British army&amp;rsquo;s southern command, multiple police forces, army bomb disposal units, and RAF helicopters were mobilized. The Ministry of Defence was notified. The army detonated the saucer found in Chippenham, while the one on the Isle of Sheppey was removed by helicopter. Other saucers were sent to the Atomic Weapons Establishment at Aldermaston and the British Aircraft Corporation&amp;rsquo;s guided weapons division. When one of the saucers was drilled into, the mixture inside exploded, covering police officers in foul-smelling slime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;revealing-the-hoax&#34;&gt;Revealing the Hoax &lt;a href=&#34;#revealing-the-hoax&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christopher Southall and Roger Palmer, both 21 years old, were identified as the pranksters behind the hoax. Their motive was to raise funds during Rag Week. The hoax generated extensive media coverage both in Britain and internationally. The apprentices revealed the hoax on the same day the saucers were found. No legal action was taken against them, and they successfully raised £2,000 for charity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources used in the article, including BBC and The Guardian articles, and a GetSurrey news report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to pictures of the hoax flying saucers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1967_British_flying_saucer_hoax&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1967_British_flying_saucer_hoax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jafr alien invasion</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_d7bf74b1dd15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 10:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_d7bf74b1dd15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;2010-jordanian-newspaper-prank-the-jafr-alien-invasion&#34;&gt;2010 Jordanian Newspaper Prank: The Jafr Alien Invasion &lt;a href=&#34;#2010-jordanian-newspaper-prank-the-jafr-alien-invasion&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article details the events surrounding a prank published by the Jordanian newspaper &lt;em&gt;Al-Ghad&lt;/em&gt; on April 1, 2010. The prank involved a fabricated story about UFOs landing near the town of Jafr, Jordan, and the panic that ensued among the town&amp;rsquo;s residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary &lt;a href=&#34;#summary&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article on the front page of &lt;em&gt;Al-Ghad&lt;/em&gt; claimed that UFOs had landed in the desert near Jafr, and the &amp;ldquo;pilots&amp;rdquo; were described as 3-meter-tall creatures. The story also stated that communications were disrupted by the UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;details-of-the-prank-and-reaction&#34;&gt;Details of the Prank and Reaction &lt;a href=&#34;#details-of-the-prank-and-reaction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story elaborated on the alien landing, describing how the town was illuminated by the flying saucers at night, causing residents to flee into the streets. The hoax caused widespread fear in Jafr, leading parents to keep their children home from school. The mayor of Jafr, Mohammed Mleihan, contacted security authorities and considered ordering an evacuation of the town&amp;rsquo;s 13,000 residents. He also expressed the residents&amp;rsquo; fear of an alien attack and considered suing the newspaper for spreading false information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apology-and-context&#34;&gt;Apology and Context &lt;a href=&#34;#apology-and-context&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The newspaper issued a formal apology for the disruption caused by the prank. The editor did not explain why Jafr was chosen as the target of the joke. However, the BBC noted that the area is known for its military bases, which have been used by American soldiers for joint exercises with the Jordanian military and had allegedly housed al-Qaida militants in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comparison-and-cultural-context&#34;&gt;Comparison and Cultural Context &lt;a href=&#34;#comparison-and-cultural-context&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prank is compared to the 1938 radio broadcast of &lt;em&gt;War of the Worlds&lt;/em&gt;, which caused panic in the United States. The article emphasizes that April Fool&amp;rsquo;s Day jokes are not a common practice in Jordanian newspapers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article cites two sources: a BBC article titled &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;Alien invasion&amp;rsquo; April Fools&amp;rsquo; story angers Jordan mayor&amp;rdquo; and a &lt;em&gt;USA Today&lt;/em&gt; article titled &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;Alien invasion&amp;rsquo; April Fools prank causes public panic.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External Links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article provides an external link to the original article in Arabic on the &lt;em&gt;Al-Ghad&lt;/em&gt; website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jafr_alien_invasion&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jafr_alien_invasion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dundy County UFO hoax</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b31c98c9c76b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 20:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_b31c98c9c76b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;dundy-county-ufo-hoax&#34;&gt;Dundy County UFO Hoax &lt;a href=&#34;#dundy-county-ufo-hoax&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dundy County UFO hoax was a fabricated story published by the &lt;em&gt;Nebraska State Journal&lt;/em&gt; in 1884. The story detailed the discovery of a cylindrical object by cowboys in Dundy County, Nebraska, near Max, following a supposed meteor crash. The newspaper later admitted the story was a hoax in 1927, though some people still believe the sighting was real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;report-and-revelation-of-hoax&#34;&gt;Report and Revelation of Hoax &lt;a href=&#34;#report-and-revelation-of-hoax&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the original report published by the &lt;em&gt;Nebraska State Journal&lt;/em&gt; on June 8, 1884. It describes how cowboys in Dundy County, near Max, Nebraska, found the remains of a large meteor. One of the cowboys, Alf Williamson, suffered blisters, hair loss, and eyesight damage upon approaching the site. The heat was so intense that the cowboys couldn&amp;rsquo;t investigate further until the next day. They returned with other locals to find a long, cylindrical tube, approximately 50-60 feet long and 10-12 feet in diameter. Rancher John Ellis intended to claim the land. Two days later, the newspaper reported that rain had dissolved the remains into congealed pools of machinery, which then washed away, leaving only a faint, sweetish smell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The section also covers the immediate reaction to the story, noting that it was widely considered a hoax or joke soon after publication and was parodied during the 1884 presidential election campaign. The &lt;em&gt;Laramie Boomerang&lt;/em&gt; initially carried the story but later reported it was a political allegory for the temperance movement. The hoax predates the mass reports of mystery airships in the late 1890s, some of which occurred in Nebraska.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the &lt;em&gt;Nebraska State Journal&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s 1927 admission, some people still believe the sighting was legitimate. The &lt;em&gt;McCook Gazette&lt;/em&gt; continues to receive inquiries about the event. In 2013, searches in Red Willow County and the reported discovery of a green material fueled further belief in the story&amp;rsquo;s authenticity. Some modern ufologists consider the report a genuine UFO sighting. A 1997 &lt;em&gt;Lincoln Journal Star&lt;/em&gt; article listed the Dundy County sighting as one of the earliest in the state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the citations used in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;citations&#34;&gt;Citations &lt;a href=&#34;#citations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection lists the specific citations used as footnotes throughout the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bibliography&#34;&gt;Bibliography &lt;a href=&#34;#bibliography&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subsection provides a list of sources used in the article, including newspaper articles, academic papers, and online resources. Key sources include articles from the &lt;em&gt;Daily Nebraskan&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;McCook Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Lincoln Journal Star&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Nebraska History&lt;/em&gt;, and a speech by Dale Bacon from the Nebraska State Historical Society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dundy_County_UFO_hoax&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dundy_County_UFO_hoax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
