<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hoax on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/hoax/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hoax on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/hoax/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Autopsy (1995 television film)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f41f4fadf611/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f41f4fadf611/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-autopsy-1995-television-film&#34;&gt;Alien Autopsy (1995 television film) &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-autopsy-1995-television-film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the 1995 pseudo-documentary &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy: Fact or Fiction&lt;/em&gt;, which featured footage purporting to show an alien autopsy conducted after the Roswell incident. The program, hosted by Jonathan Frakes, aired on Fox and Channel 4, sparking intense debate before being thoroughly debunked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;production&#34;&gt;Production &lt;a href=&#34;#production&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the production of the hoaxed footage. Ray Santilli and Gary Shoefield admitted to creating the film in a 2006 documentary. The autopsy was simulated in a London flat, with artist John Humphreys constructing the alien bodies from plaster casts filled with offal, sheep brains, and raspberry jam. Humphreys also played the role of the chief examiner. Alien artifacts were also fabricated. A homeless man was paid to pose as the original cameraman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture &lt;a href=&#34;#in-popular-culture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section covers the reception and parody of &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; in media. &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt; satirized the footage, and Fox later aired a special debunking it. A fictionalized version of the film&amp;rsquo;s creation was retold in the comedy film &lt;em&gt;Alien Autopsy&lt;/em&gt; (2006).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including books, news articles, and documentaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further reading &lt;a href=&#34;#further-reading&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of additional resources for readers interested in learning more about the topic, including articles from &lt;em&gt;Skeptical Inquirer&lt;/em&gt; and books on the Roswell incident and UFO cover-ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to external resources, including an article by Ray Santilli about his story and links to the film&amp;rsquo;s IMDb page and a YouTube video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Autopsy_(1995_film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_Autopsy_(1995_film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
