<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quarantine on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/quarantine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quarantine on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 22:24:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/quarantine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extra-Terrestrial Exposure Law</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_2c97c62f03e8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 22:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_2c97c62f03e8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extra-terrestrial-exposure-law&#34;&gt;Extra-Terrestrial Exposure Law &lt;a href=&#34;#extra-terrestrial-exposure-law&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document details the Extra-Terrestrial Exposure Law, a set of regulations enacted by NASA in 1969 to protect Earth from potential contamination by extraterrestrial organisms. The law was in effect from 1969 to 1977.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;regulations&#34;&gt;Regulations &lt;a href=&#34;#regulations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section defines the core purpose of the Extra-Terrestrial Exposure Law (14 CFR 1211). It highlights NASA&amp;rsquo;s responsibility and authority to prevent harmful contamination of Earth from returning space missions. The regulations were implemented before the Apollo 11 mission and provided the legal basis for quarantining astronauts. It defines &amp;ldquo;extraterrestrially exposed&amp;rdquo; as anything that has come into contact with or proximity to a celestial body or something that has been in contact with a celestial body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quarantining&#34;&gt;Quarantining &lt;a href=&#34;#quarantining&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the practical application of the Extra-Terrestrial Exposure Law, specifically the quarantine of astronauts returning from lunar missions. It mentions that the quarantines were implemented due to the possibility of unknown lunar organisms endangering life on Earth. The Apollo 11 astronauts were quarantined for 21 days after their return from the Moon. NASA filed notices establishing quarantine periods in the Federal Register for Apollo 11, 12, 13, and 14.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;termination&#34;&gt;Termination &lt;a href=&#34;#termination&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details the end of the Extra-Terrestrial Exposure Law&amp;rsquo;s enforcement and its eventual removal from the Code of Federal Regulations. After the Apollo 14 mission, NASA stopped enforcing the regulation due to analysis concluding there was no hazard to man, animals, or plants in the lunar material. Dr. George M. Low, NASA&amp;rsquo;s acting administrator, announced this decision. The rule was revoked in 1977 and formally removed from the Code of Federal Regulations in 1991.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the &amp;ldquo;Planetary protection&amp;rdquo; article, which is related to the prevention of interplanetary biological contamination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources used in the article, including citations from the Code of Federal Regulations, news articles, and NASA documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the full text of the Extra-Terrestrial Exposure Law as published in the Federal Register.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extra-Terrestrial_Exposure_Law&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extra-Terrestrial_Exposure_Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
