<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MOD on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/mod/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MOD on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 18:11:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/mod/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flying Saucer Working Party</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6d5bc0aa1a71/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 18:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6d5bc0aa1a71/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;flying-saucer-working-party&#34;&gt;Flying Saucer Working Party &lt;a href=&#34;#flying-saucer-working-party&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Flying Saucer Working Party (FSWP) was the United Kingdom Ministry of Defence&amp;rsquo;s (MOD) initial formal investigation into UFOs. It originated from a study commissioned in 1950 by Sir Henry Tizard, the MOD&amp;rsquo;s Chief Scientific Adviser and a radar expert. Tizard insisted that UFO sightings should be scientifically examined, leading to the establishment of the FSWP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;set-up&#34;&gt;Set-up &lt;a href=&#34;#set-up&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Flying Saucer Working Party was established in October 1950 by Sir Henry Tizard. Tizard believed UFO reports warranted serious study. He authorized a small team to investigate the phenomenon. The group&amp;rsquo;s final report was published in June 1951. It was released to UFO researchers Dr. David Clarke and Andy Roberts in 2001 by the MOD, following requests made under the Code of Practice on Access to Government Information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Working Party concluded that all studied reports could be explained by astronomical or meteorological phenomena, misidentification of objects, optical illusions, psychological delusions, or deliberate hoaxes. The report recommended ceasing further investigation of reported mysterious aerial phenomena unless material evidence emerged. A detailed commentary and analysis of this material can be found at the Real UFO Project website, including scans of the report and associated documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flying_Saucer_Working_Party&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flying_Saucer_Working_Party&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
