<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pseudoscience on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/pseudoscience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pseudoscience on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 08:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/pseudoscience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ancient astronauts</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_96b21753a786/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 08:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_96b21753a786/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ancient-astronauts&#34;&gt;Ancient Astronauts &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-astronauts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ancient astronauts, also known as ancient aliens, is a pseudoscientific belief that intelligent extraterrestrial beings visited Earth in ancient times and influenced the development of human civilization. Proponents suggest that these aliens affected cultures, technologies, religions, and even human biology. A common idea is that deities in various religions were actually extraterrestrials, and their advanced technologies were seen as divine powers by early humans. Academics and archaeologists dismiss these claims as pseudoarchaeology and unscientific, lacking credible peer-reviewed evidence. Some argue that these theories have racist undertones, diminishing the achievements of indigenous cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extraterrestrial contact in ancient times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Influence on human civilization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deities as extraterrestrials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dismissal by academics as pseudoscience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potential racist implications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert Charroux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jacques Bergier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jean Sendy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erich von Däniken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alexander Kazantsev&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zecharia Sitchin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert K. G. Temple&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giorgio A. Tsoukalos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Hatcher Childress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peter Kolosimo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mauro Biglino&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various terms are used to describe claims about ancient astronauts, including ancient aliens, ancient ufonauts, ancient space pilots, paleocontact, astronaut- or alien gods, and paleo- or biblical-SETI. Believers often assert that humans are descendants or creations of extraterrestrial intelligence that landed on Earth in the distant past. They propose that human knowledge, religion, and culture originated from these ancient alien visitors, who acted as a &amp;ldquo;mother culture.&amp;rdquo; Additionally, they claim that extraterrestrials built or assisted in building structures like the Egyptian pyramids and the Moai stone heads of Easter Island. Proponents cite documentary gaps in historical and archaeological records and point to archaeological artifacts they consider anachronistic and beyond the technical capabilities of ancient people. These artifacts, sometimes called &amp;ldquo;out-of-place artifacts,&amp;rdquo; include artwork and legends reinterpreted to support extraterrestrial contact or technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alternative terms for ancient astronaut theories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Humans as descendants or creations of extraterrestrials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extraterrestrial origin of human knowledge and culture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extraterrestrial involvement in building ancient structures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use of &amp;ldquo;out-of-place artifacts&amp;rdquo; as evidence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34;&gt;History of Ancient Aliens Beliefs and Their Proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paleocontact narratives first appeared in early science fiction in the late 19th and early 20th centuries. Harold T. Wilkins proposed the idea in earnest in 1954. It gained popularity in the 1960s due to the Space Race and the success of Erich von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s works. Critics emerged in the 1970s, discrediting Von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s claims. By the early 1980s, the idea had little remaining support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Origins in early science fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rise in popularity in the 1960s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Criticism and decline in the 1970s and 1980s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;shklovskii-and-sagan&#34;&gt;Shklovskii and Sagan &lt;a href=&#34;#shklovskii-and-sagan&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Sagan co-authored &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Life in the Universe&lt;/em&gt; with Soviet astrophysicist Iosif Shklovsky in 1966. Sagan later expressed disapproval of writers like von Däniken who treated speculations about ancient astronauts as valid evidence. Sagan acknowledged the possibility of extraterrestrial visits but emphasized that they were unproven and improbable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sagan and Shklovsky&amp;rsquo;s influence on ancient astronaut theories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sagan&amp;rsquo;s disapproval of uncritical writers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emphasis on the lack of evidence for extraterrestrial visits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;erich-von-däniken&#34;&gt;Erich von Däniken &lt;a href=&#34;#erich-von-d%c3%a4niken&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erich von Däniken became a leading proponent of the ancient astronaut hypothesis in the late 1960s and early 1970s with his book &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; He argued that certain artifacts required more advanced technology than was available to ancient cultures, suggesting they were constructed by extraterrestrials or humans who learned from them. These artifacts include Stonehenge, Pumapunku, the Moai of Easter Island, the Great Pyramid of Giza, and the ancient Baghdad electric batteries. Von Däniken interpreted ancient art and iconography as illustrations of air and space vehicles, non-human creatures, and advanced technology. He also suggested that geographically separated cultures shared artistic themes, implying a common extraterrestrial origin. He interpreted the sarcophagus lid of Maya ruler Pacal the Great as depicting an astronaut. He viewed the origins of many religions as reactions to encounters with an alien race, with humans considering alien technology supernatural and the aliens themselves as gods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s role as a leading proponent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Argument that certain artifacts required advanced technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interpretation of ancient art as evidence of extraterrestrial contact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View of religions as reactions to alien encounters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erich von Däniken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Locations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stonehenge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pumapunku&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easter Island&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great Pyramid of Giza&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baghdad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;zecharia-sitchin&#34;&gt;Zecharia Sitchin &lt;a href=&#34;#zecharia-sitchin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zecharia Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Earth Chronicles&lt;/em&gt; series revolves around his interpretation of ancient Sumerian and Middle Eastern texts, megalithic sites, and artifacts. He hypothesized that the gods of ancient Mesopotamia were astronauts from the planet Nibiru, which he claimed the Sumerians believed to be a remote &amp;ldquo;12th planet.&amp;rdquo; Sitchin argued that Sumerian texts tell the story of the Anunnaki, inhabitants of Nibiru, who came to Earth approximately 400,000 years ago to mine raw materials, especially gold. They genetically engineered laborers, creating Homo sapiens sapiens, the Adapa or Adam of later mythology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s interpretation of Sumerian texts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hypothesis of the Anunnaki from Nibiru&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Genetic engineering of humans by the Anunnaki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zecharia Sitchin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Locations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mesopotamia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;robert-temple&#34;&gt;Robert Temple &lt;a href=&#34;#robert-temple&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert K. G. Temple&amp;rsquo;s 1976 book, &lt;em&gt;The Sirius Mystery,&lt;/em&gt; argues that the Dogon people of northwestern Mali preserved an account of extraterrestrial visitation from around 5,000 years ago. He cited advanced astronomical knowledge inherited by the tribe, descriptions, and comparative belief systems with ancient civilizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Temple&amp;rsquo;s argument about the Dogon people&amp;rsquo;s knowledge of extraterrestrial visitation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Citing advanced astronomical knowledge and comparative belief systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert K. G. Temple&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marcel Griaule&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Germaine Dieterlen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Locations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mali&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ufo-religions&#34;&gt;UFO Religions &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-religions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various new religious movements, including some branches of Theosophy, Scientology, Raëlism, Aetherius Society, and Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate, believe in ancient and present-day contact with extraterrestrial intelligence. Many of these faiths see both ancient scriptures and recent revelations as connected with the action of aliens from other planetary systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Belief in ancient and present-day contact with extraterrestrial intelligence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connection between ancient scriptures and alien actions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organizations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theosophy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scientology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raëlism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aetherius Society&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;claims-of-proponents&#34;&gt;Claims of Proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#claims-of-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists generally view the ancient astronaut hypothesis as unjustified and unnecessary, as the &amp;ldquo;mysteries&amp;rdquo; cited as evidence can be explained without invoking ancient astronauts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scientific consensus against the ancient astronaut hypothesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unnecessary nature of the hypothesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ancient-religious-texts&#34;&gt;Ancient Religious Texts &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-religious-texts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proponents cite ancient mythologies, interpreting creation myths of gods descending from the heavens as representations of alien visitors. They draw an analogy to modern cargo cults, where isolated cultures believe Western ships and cargo are sent from the gods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interpretation of ancient creation myths as alien visits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analogy to modern cargo cults&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;ramayana&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ramayana&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#ramayana&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Hindu mythology, gods and their avatars travel in flying vehicles called Vimana. The &lt;em&gt;Ramayana&lt;/em&gt; contains mentions of these flying objects. Erich von Däniken suggests that the &lt;em&gt;vimanas&lt;/em&gt; were &amp;ldquo;space vehicles.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mentions of flying vehicles (Vimana) in the &lt;em&gt;Ramayana&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s interpretation of &lt;em&gt;vimanas&lt;/em&gt; as space vehicles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Locations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ayodhya&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sri Lanka&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-bible&#34;&gt;The Bible &lt;a href=&#34;#the-bible&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;book-of-genesis-and-book-of-enoch&#34;&gt;Book of Genesis and Book of Enoch &lt;a href=&#34;#book-of-genesis-and-book-of-enoch&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Book of Genesis mentions the &amp;ldquo;sons of God&amp;rdquo; marrying human women and the Nephilim. The Book of Enoch expands on this, describing the &amp;ldquo;sons of God&amp;rdquo; as angels who descended to Earth to breed with humans. Some ancient astronaut proponents argue that this is a historical account of extraterrestrials visiting Earth, called Watchers, who made contact with humans, cross-bred with human females, and shared knowledge with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interpretation of Genesis and Enoch as accounts of extraterrestrial contact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watchers as extraterrestrials who cross-bred with humans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nephilim as half-human-half-extraterrestrial hybrids&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;book-of&#34;&gt;Book of &lt;a href=&#34;#book-of&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
