<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pseudoscience on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/pseudoscience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pseudoscience on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 12:27:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/pseudoscience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ufology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_2c01afed379f/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_2c01afed379f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufology&#34;&gt;Ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology is the investigation of unidentified flying objects (UFOs) by individuals who believe they may have extraordinary origins, often extraterrestrial. While governments, private groups, and fringe science have investigated UFOs, ufology is generally considered pseudoscience by skeptics and science educators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;etymology&#34;&gt;Etymology &lt;a href=&#34;#etymology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;ufology&amp;rdquo; is a neologism derived from &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; and the suffix &amp;ldquo;-logy.&amp;rdquo; Edward J. Ruppelt is credited with coining the term UFO. Early uses of &amp;ldquo;ufology&amp;rdquo; appeared in a 1957 &lt;em&gt;Fantastic Universe&lt;/em&gt; article and a 1958 presentation for The Planetary Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-background&#34;&gt;Historical background &lt;a href=&#34;#historical-background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology&amp;rsquo;s roots trace back to various historical phenomena, including the mystery airships of the late 1890s, foo fighters reported during World War II, ghost fliers of the 1930s, ghost rockets of 1946 in Scandinavia, and the Kenneth Arnold sighting in 1947. The Arnold sighting popularized the concept of flying saucers. Increased UFO publicity after World War II coincided with Cold War tensions and concerns about Soviet aircraft. Official government involvement in ufology in the United States ended after the Condon Committee report and the termination of Project Blue Book. France maintains the GEIPAN program for UFO studies. In September 2023, NASA appointed Mark McInerney as the first Director of U.A.P. to study such occurrences scientifically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;as-a-field&#34;&gt;As a field &lt;a href=&#34;#as-a-field&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology is not recognized as a scientific field by academia and is generally considered pseudoscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;status-as-a-pseudoscience&#34;&gt;Status as a pseudoscience &lt;a href=&#34;#status-as-a-pseudoscience&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology is often listed as a pseudoscience due to its lack of adherence to the scientific method, supporting evidence, plausibility, and falsifiability. Social factors contribute to this status, including mistrust between ufology, the sciences, and government bodies. Poor science communication regarding the extraterrestrial intelligence (ETI) hypothesis hinders public understanding and discourages academic inquiry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-interest&#34;&gt;Current interest &lt;a href=&#34;#current-interest&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astronomer Avi Loeb launched The Galileo Project in 2021 to collect scientific evidence of extraterrestrial technology. The University of Würzburg is developing sensors for detecting and analyzing aerial objects. A 2021 Gallup poll indicated increased belief among Americans that some UFOs are extraterrestrial spacecraft. In 2022, NASA announced a study to investigate UAP. In 2023, the RAND Corporation published a study reviewing public reports of UAP sightings in the United States from 1998 to 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;methodological-issues&#34;&gt;Methodological issues &lt;a href=&#34;#methodological-issues&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific UFO research faces challenges due to the unpredictable nature of UFO phenomena, their lack of reproducibility, and tangible physicality. Most UFO sightings have mundane explanations, limiting the interpretive power of extraordinary events. Carl Sagan noted that reliable cases are uninteresting, and interesting cases are unreliable. J. Allen Hynek and Jacques Vallée developed descriptive systems for characterizing UFO sightings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;phenomena-linked-to-ufology&#34;&gt;Phenomena linked to ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#phenomena-linked-to-ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufologists are interested in phenomena related to UFO sightings, including crop circles, cattle mutilations, anomalous materials, alien abductions, and implants. Some ufologists promote UFO conspiracy theories, such as the Roswell Incident and the Majestic 12 documents. Robert Sheaffer has accused ufology of a &amp;ldquo;credulity explosion,&amp;rdquo; and James E. McDonald identified &amp;ldquo;cultism&amp;rdquo; as negatively impacting ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-posadism&#34;&gt;In Posadism &lt;a href=&#34;#in-posadism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the Cold War, ufology was combined with the ideas of the Trotskyist Posadism movement in South America. Juan Posadas, the main theorist, believed humanity should appeal to extraterrestrials to collaborate in suppressing poverty and creating a socialist system on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;governmental-and-private-ufology-studies&#34;&gt;Governmental and private ufology studies &lt;a href=&#34;#governmental-and-private-ufology-studies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the 1940s, governmental agencies and private groups have sponsored UFO investigations, studies, and conferences. These include Project Sign, Project Magnet, Project Blue Book, the Robertson Panel, and the Condon Committee in the United States; the Flying Saucer Working Party and Project Condign in Britain; GEIPAN in France; and Project Hessdalen in Norway. Private studies include those by the RAND Corporation, Harvey Rutledge, and the National Press Club&amp;rsquo;s Disclosure Project. The United Nations sponsored meetings and hearings on UFO sightings from 1977 to 1979. In August 2020, the United States Department of Defense established the Unidentified Aerial Phenomena Task Force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufo-organizations-and-events&#34;&gt;UFO organizations and events &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-organizations-and-events&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerous private organizations worldwide are dedicated to the study and discussion of ufology. Skeptic organizations emphasize the pseudoscientific nature of ufology. During World UFO Day (July 2), ufologists raise public awareness of ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ufologist&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ufologist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ufology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_ca17bd06df71/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_ca17bd06df71/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufology&#34;&gt;Ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology is the investigation of unidentified flying objects (UFOs) by individuals who believe they may have extraordinary origins, often extraterrestrial. While governments, private groups, and fringe science may investigate UFOs, ufology is generally considered pseudoscience by skeptics and science educators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;etymology&#34;&gt;Etymology &lt;a href=&#34;#etymology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;ufology&amp;rdquo; is a neologism derived from &amp;ldquo;UFO&amp;rdquo; and the suffix &amp;ldquo;-logy.&amp;rdquo; Edward J. Ruppelt is credited with coining the term UFO. Early uses of &amp;ldquo;ufology&amp;rdquo; appeared in a 1957 &lt;em&gt;Fantastic Universe&lt;/em&gt; article and a 1958 presentation for The Planetary Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-background&#34;&gt;Historical background &lt;a href=&#34;#historical-background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology&amp;rsquo;s roots can be traced to several historical phenomena: the &amp;ldquo;mystery airships&amp;rdquo; of the late 1890s, &amp;ldquo;foo fighters&amp;rdquo; reported during World War II, &amp;ldquo;ghost fliers&amp;rdquo; of the 1930s, &amp;ldquo;ghost rockets&amp;rdquo; in Scandinavia in 1946, and the Kenneth Arnold &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; sighting in 1947. The Arnold sighting significantly popularized the concept of flying saucers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increased UFO publicity after World War II coincided with the Cold War and concerns about Soviet aircraft. Official government activities related to ufology in the United States ended in the late 1960s after the Condon Committee report and the termination of Project Blue Book. Similar government-sponsored activities in other countries, such as the United Kingdom, Canada, Denmark, Italy, and Sweden, also ended. France is an exception, maintaining the GEIPAN program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In September 2023, NASA appointed Mark McInerney as the Director of U.A.P. to study such occurrences scientifically and transparently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;as-a-field&#34;&gt;As a field &lt;a href=&#34;#as-a-field&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;status-as-a-pseudoscience&#34;&gt;Status as a pseudoscience &lt;a href=&#34;#status-as-a-pseudoscience&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ufology is not recognized as a scientific field by academia and is generally considered a pseudoscience by skeptics and science educators. Pseudoscience lacks adherence to the scientific method, supporting evidence, plausibility, or falsifiability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social factors contribute to ufology&amp;rsquo;s status as a pseudoscience. Some argue that mistrust between ufology, the sciences, and government bodies contributes to this status. Poor science communication regarding the extraterrestrial intelligence (ETI) hypothesis for UFOs hinders public understanding and discourages academic inquiry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-interest&#34;&gt;Current interest &lt;a href=&#34;#current-interest&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2021, Avi Loeb launched The Galileo Project to collect scientific evidence of extraterrestrials or their technology near Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Würzburg in Germany is developing sensors to detect and analyze aerial objects, potentially applicable to UAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2021 Gallup poll indicated an increase in the belief among Americans that some UFOs are extraterrestrial spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022, NASA announced a study to establish a roadmap for investigating UAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2023, the RAND Corporation published a study reviewing public reports of UAP sightings in the United States from 1998 to 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;methodological-issues&#34;&gt;Methodological issues &lt;a href=&#34;#methodological-issues&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific UFO research faces challenges due to the unpredictable nature of the phenomena, lack of reproducibility, and absence of tangible physicality. Most UFO sightings have mundane explanations, limiting the interpretive power of extraordinary events. Carl Sagan noted that reliable cases are uninteresting, and interesting cases are unreliable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. Allen Hynek and Jacques Vallée developed descriptive systems for characterizing UFO sightings and organizing ufology investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;phenomena-linked-to-ufology&#34;&gt;Phenomena linked to ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#phenomena-linked-to-ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain phenomena are of interest to some ufologists, including crop circles, cattle mutilations, anomalous materials, alien abductions, and implants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ufologists promote UFO conspiracy theories, including the Roswell Incident, Majestic 12 documents, and UFO disclosure advocates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Sheaffer has accused ufology of a &amp;ldquo;credulity explosion,&amp;rdquo; where increasingly outlandish stories gain traction. James E. McDonald identified &amp;ldquo;cultism&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;extreme subgroups&amp;rdquo; as negatively impacting ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-posadism&#34;&gt;In Posadism &lt;a href=&#34;#in-posadism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the Cold War, ufology was synthesized with Posadism, a Trotskyist movement in South America. Juan Posadas, the main theorist, believed humanity should appeal to extraterrestrials to collaborate in suppressing poverty and creating a socialist system on Earth. This belief contributed to the decline of Posadism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;governmental-and-private-ufology-studies&#34;&gt;Governmental and private ufology studies &lt;a href=&#34;#governmental-and-private-ufology-studies&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting in the 1940s, governmental agencies and private groups sponsored investigations, studies, and conferences related to ufology. These studies include Project Sign, Project Magnet, Project Blue Book, the Robertson Panel, and the Condon Committee in the United States; the Flying Saucer Working Party and Project Condign in Britain; GEIPAN in France; and Project Hessdalen in Norway. Private studies include those by the RAND Corporation, Harvey Rutledge of the University of Missouri, and the National Press Club&amp;rsquo;s Disclosure Project. The United Nations sponsored meetings and hearings concerning UFO sightings from 1977 to 1979. In August 2020, the United States Department of Defense established the Unidentified Aerial Phenomena Task Force to detect, analyze, and catalog unidentified aerial phenomena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufo-organizations-and-events&#34;&gt;UFO organizations and events &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-organizations-and-events&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerous private organizations worldwide are dedicated to the study, discussion, and publicity of ufology. Skeptic organizations emphasize the pseudoscientific nature of ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During World UFO Day (July 2), ufologists raise public awareness of ufology, including group gatherings to search for and observe UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ufological&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ufological&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planetary objects proposed in religion, astrology, ufology and pseudoscience</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_2684e1d7f984/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_2684e1d7f984/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;non-scientific-hypothetical-objects&#34;&gt;Non-scientific hypothetical objects &lt;a href=&#34;#non-scientific-hypothetical-objects&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses planetary objects proposed in religion, astrology, ufology, and pseudoscience that lack scientific evidence. It distinguishes these from scientifically accepted hypothetical astronomical objects and fictional planets in science fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;kolob&#34;&gt;Kolob &lt;a href=&#34;#kolob&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kolob is a star or planet described in the Book of Abraham, a sacred text in the Latter Day Saint movement. While the Book of Abraham refers to Kolob as a &amp;ldquo;star,&amp;rdquo; it also refers to planets as stars, leading Latter Day Saints to commonly view Kolob as a planet. It is described as the heavenly body closest to the throne of God and is said to have &amp;ldquo;signified&amp;rdquo; the first creation according to Joseph Smith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lilith&#34;&gt;Lilith &lt;a href=&#34;#lilith&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lilith is a fictitious, invisible moon of Earth proposed in 1918 by astrologer Walter Gorn Old (Sepharial). Sepharial claimed Lilith was the same second moon that scientist Georg Waltemath claimed to have discovered twenty years earlier, but which was never confirmed. Sepharial claimed to be the first to observe Waltemath&amp;rsquo;s moon crossing the Sun. The scientific community had already discredited Waltemath&amp;rsquo;s proposed moon. While fringe groups believe in Lilith&amp;rsquo;s existence, astrologers now generally use the name for the position of the Moon&amp;rsquo;s apogee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-modern-astrology&#34;&gt;In modern astrology &lt;a href=&#34;#in-modern-astrology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In modern astrology, &amp;ldquo;Lilith&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Black Moon Lilith&amp;rdquo; refers to a point on the horoscope representing the Moon&amp;rsquo;s apogee. This point is sometimes defined as the second focus of the ellipse described by the Moon&amp;rsquo;s orbit. It takes approximately 8 years and 10 months for this point to complete a circuit through the zodiac, tracking the apsidal precession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;planets-proposed-by-l-ron-hubbard&#34;&gt;Planets proposed by L. Ron Hubbard &lt;a href=&#34;#planets-proposed-by-l-ron-hubbard&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L. Ron Hubbard, the founder of Scientology, proposed a Galactic Confederacy as part of his cosmology. This confederacy consisted of 26 stars and 76 planets, including Earth, then known as &amp;ldquo;Teegeeack.&amp;rdquo; Helatrobus is another planet mentioned in Scientology doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ummo&#34;&gt;Ummo &lt;a href=&#34;#ummo&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ummo is a hypothetical planet believed to be located in the Constellation Virgo. A series of claims describe aliens from Ummo communicating with people on Earth through detailed documents and letters. The Ummo affair gained attention in France and Spain during the 1960s. Ummoism refers to groups interested in studying the ideas presented in the Ummo letters. José Luis Jordán Peña has claimed responsibility for writing the letters and instigating Ummoism, leading many to believe Ummo is a hoax. Jacques Vallée compared the Ummo documents to Borges&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;Tlön, Uqbar, Orbis Tertius.&amp;rdquo; Mike Dash notes that Ummoism began on February 6, 1966, in Madrid, when Jordán Peña claimed to have seen a circular object with a symbol resembling the alchemical sign for Uranus. Fernando Sesma Manzano, a contactee, became involved after receiving documents purportedly from the Ummites. Jean-Pierre Petit claims to have detected signs of superior intelligence in the Ummite writings and that they have inspired his research in cosmology and magnetohydrodynamics. Antonio Ribera compiled 403 Ummo words in 1978, and Jean Pollion listed over a thousand words in 2002.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two theories have been formulated by analysts of Ummite letters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jean Pollion considers each letter (sound or phoneme) in words transcribed in typewritten form to be signifying, calling these sounds &amp;ldquo;soncepts&amp;rdquo; and considering the language to be &amp;ldquo;ideophonemic.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The second theory considers that differences in spelling are of little significance and are due to differences in the understanding of foreign sounds by the typist(s), or to difficulties in alphabetic transcription, considering that language is made up of word-objects and not of &amp;ldquo;soncepts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 1300 pages of letters have been registered, with references to 3850 pages in a 1988 letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dash notes that the photographic evidence was suspect, and the letters, while sophisticated, could have originated on Earth. Jerome Clark notes that Jacques Vallée argued that the scientific content of the Ummo letters was knowledgeable but unremarkable, comparing the scientific references to a well-researched science fiction novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The controversy over an &amp;ldquo;error&amp;rdquo; in the distance from Wolf 424 arose from the first letter, referenced D21 (May 1966), which states that the distance used by terrestrial astronomers is different from the real distance in decadimensional space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;planets-proposed-by-zecharia-sitchin&#34;&gt;Planets proposed by Zecharia Sitchin &lt;a href=&#34;#planets-proposed-by-zecharia-sitchin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zecharia Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s work has gained attention among ufologists, ancient astronaut theorists, and conspiracy theorists. He claimed to have found evidence in Sumerian texts that the human race was visited/created by extraterrestrials from a distant planet in the Solar System. He interpreted the Babylonian creation myth, the &lt;em&gt;Enuma Elish&lt;/em&gt;, by replacing the names of gods with hypothetical planets. Academics consider his work pseudoscience and pseudohistory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s theory proposes the planets Tiamat and Nibiru. Tiamat supposedly existed between Mars and Jupiter, and its orbit was disrupted by the arrival of Nibiru. The collision of Tiamat with one of Nibiru&amp;rsquo;s moons supposedly formed the asteroid belt and Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitchin claimed the Babylonians associated Nibiru with the god Marduk. He hypothesized it as a planet in a highly elliptic orbit around the Sun, with a perihelion passage some 3,600 years ago and an orbital period of about 3,450 years. He also claimed it was the home of the Anunnaki, a technologically advanced alien race who visited Earth in search of gold and created humanity by genetically crossing themselves with primates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Websites such as ZetaTalk have claimed that Nibiru or &amp;ldquo;Planet X&amp;rdquo; is a brown dwarf within our planetary system, soon to pass close to Earth. Sitchin disagreed that it is a star, with the timing and parameters of passage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitchin also postulated that Pluto began life as Gaga, a satellite of Saturn, which was flung into orbit beyond Neptune due to Nibiru&amp;rsquo;s passing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;serpo&#34;&gt;Serpo &lt;a href=&#34;#serpo&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project Serpo is an alleged top-secret exchange program between the United States government and an alien planet called Serpo in the Zeta Reticuli star system. Details of the alleged exchange program have appeared in UFO conspiracy stories, including an incident in 1983 involving Richard C. Doty and Linda Moulton Howe, and emails sent to a UFO discussion group run by Victor Martinez in 2005. Some versions state that Serpo is the nickname of the extrasolar planet, while others claim it is a mispronunciation of Serponia or Seinu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first mention of Project Serpo was in a UFO email list maintained by Victor Martinez. According to the story, an alien survived a crash near Roswell in the late 1940s and was repatriated, leading to a relationship between the American government and the people of its home world in the Zeta Reticuli system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story claims that twelve American military personnel visited the planet between 1965 and 1978 and that all have since died from radiation levels from the two suns. Another version claims that eight team members returned, one died en route, one died on the planet, and two decided to remain on Serpo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Criticism of Project Serpo stems from the lack of veracity of Richard Doty, who has been involved in other UFO-related activities and is considered a discredited source. There is no physical evidence supporting the project&amp;rsquo;s existence. Tim Swartz of &lt;em&gt;Mysteries Magazine&lt;/em&gt; expressed that the details of Project Serpo have varied considerably with different accounts. It has been alleged that the entire series of posts were designed to be viral marketing for a new book by Doty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill Ryan, a proponent of publicizing the Project Serpo claims, stepped down from his role as webmaster for the Serpo material but maintains his belief that an extraterrestrial exchange program did occur, although the Serpo releases contained disinformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planetary_objects_proposed_in_religion,_astrology,_ufology_and_pseudoscience&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planetary_objects_proposed_in_religion,_astrology,_ufology_and_pseudoscience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancient astronauts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_96b21753a786/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 08:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_96b21753a786/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ancient-astronauts&#34;&gt;Ancient Astronauts &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-astronauts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ancient astronauts, also known as ancient aliens, is a pseudoscientific belief that intelligent extraterrestrial beings visited Earth in ancient times and influenced human civilization. Proponents suggest that these aliens affected the development of cultures, technologies, religions, and even human biology. A common idea is that deities in many religions were actually extraterrestrials, and their advanced technologies were seen as divine powers by early humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This idea is rejected by academics and archaeologists, who consider it pseudoarchaeology and unscientific. Claims are often based on distorted or fabricated evidence. Some critics argue that ancient astronaut theories have racist implications, diminishing the achievements of indigenous cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notable proponents in the late 20th century include Robert Charroux, Jacques Bergier, Jean Sendy, Erich von Däniken, Alexander Kazantsev, Zecharia Sitchin, Robert K. G. Temple, Giorgio A. Tsoukalos, David Hatcher Childress, Peter Kolosimo, and Mauro Biglino.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various terms are used to describe claims about ancient astronauts, including ancient aliens, ancient ufonauts, ancient space pilots, paleocontact, astronaut- or alien gods, and paleo- or biblical-SETI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believers often claim that humans are descendants or creations of extraterrestrial intelligence that landed on Earth in the past. They suggest that human knowledge, religion, and culture originated from these ancient alien visitors, who acted as a &amp;ldquo;mother culture.&amp;rdquo; Proponents also claim that extraterrestrials built or helped humans build structures like the Egyptian pyramids and the Moai stone heads of Easter Island. Evidence is said to come from gaps in historical and archaeological records, as well as artifacts that are considered anachronistic and beyond the technical capabilities of ancient people. These &amp;ldquo;out-of-place artifacts&amp;rdquo; include artwork and legends reinterpreted to support extraterrestrial contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is featured in fringe media, such as the History Channel series &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;. The show mixes fact with fiction to promote theories of an alternate past, often incorporating white supremacist, nativist, imperialist, settler-colonial, and Christian Identity beliefs. Proponents portray themselves as an oppressed minority of academics challenging mainstream archaeology, despite lacking credentials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like past archaeological endeavors, the focus is on monumental structures, suggesting that indigenous people could not have built them without alien help. However, some indigenous voices argue that ancient alien theory supports their stories of extraterrestrial origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common theme is the portrayal of aliens as light-skinned or Aryan, as claimed by Erich von Däniken. Some proponents are associated with white supremacism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainstream archaeologists have largely ignored these claims, while popular science explainers and skeptics have criticized them. Carl Sagan noted that cases of apparent interest have reasonable alternative explanations, misreporting, or are hoaxes and distortions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34;&gt;History of Ancient Aliens Beliefs and Their Proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paleocontact narratives appeared in early science fiction of the late 19th and early 20th centuries, including &lt;em&gt;Edison&amp;rsquo;s Conquest of Mars&lt;/em&gt; (1898) and the works of H.P. Lovecraft. Harold T. Wilkins proposed the idea in earnest in 1954. It gained popularity in the 1960s due to the Space Race and Erich von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s works. Critics emerged in the 1970s, discrediting Von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s claims. By the early 1980s, support dwindled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;shklovskii-and-sagan&#34;&gt;Shklovskii and Sagan &lt;a href=&#34;#shklovskii-and-sagan&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Sagan co-authored &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Life in the Universe&lt;/em&gt; (1966) with Soviet astrophysicist Iosif Shklovsky. In &lt;em&gt;Broca&amp;rsquo;s Brain&lt;/em&gt; (1979), Sagan expressed disapproval of writers like von Däniken who treated speculations as valid evidence of extraterrestrial contact. Sagan noted that many legends, artifacts, and out-of-place artifacts cited in support of ancient astronaut hypotheses could be explained with conventional hypotheses. He reiterated that extraterrestrial visits were possible but unproven and improbable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;erich-von-däniken&#34;&gt;Erich von Däniken &lt;a href=&#34;#erich-von-d%c3%a4niken&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erich von Däniken became a leading proponent in the late 1960s and early 1970s with his book &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; (1968) and its sequels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Von Däniken argued that certain artifacts required more advanced technology than was available to ancient cultures. He claimed that these artifacts were constructed by extraterrestrial visitors or humans who learned from them. Examples include Stonehenge, Pumapunku, the Moai of Easter Island, the Great Pyramid of Giza, and the ancient Baghdad electric batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He wrote that ancient art and iconography depict air and space vehicles, intelligent non-human creatures, ancient astronauts, and advanced technology. He also stated that geographically separated cultures share artistic themes, implying a common origin. One example is his interpretation of the sarcophagus lid from the tomb of Pacal the Great in Palenque, which he saw as a seated astronaut, while Maya texts identify it as a portrait of the ruler with the World Tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Von Däniken interpreted the origins of many religions as reactions to encounters with an alien race, whose technology was seen as supernatural. He stated that religious traditions contain references to alien visitors, such as Ezekiel&amp;rsquo;s revelation, which he interpreted as a landing spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His hypotheses became popularized in the U.S. through the NBC-TV documentary &lt;em&gt;In Search of Ancient Astronauts&lt;/em&gt; and the film &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critics argue that von Däniken misrepresented data, made unfounded claims, and failed to validate his core claims. Christian creationists also criticized his work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the Nazca Lines, von Däniken stated that they resembled an airfield when seen from the air. Kenneth L. Feder argues that readers seeing the Nazca Lines in a book about aliens would be more likely to associate them with extraterrestrial origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1970, von Däniken admitted that the Nazca markings could have been laid out using a system of coordinates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;zecharia-sitchin&#34;&gt;Zecharia Sitchin &lt;a href=&#34;#zecharia-sitchin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zecharia Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Earth Chronicles&lt;/em&gt; series revolves around his interpretation of ancient Sumerian and Middle Eastern texts, megalithic sites, and artifacts. He hypothesized that the gods of Mesopotamia were astronauts from the planet Nibiru, which the Sumerians believed to be a remote &amp;ldquo;12th planet&amp;rdquo; associated with the god Marduk. According to Sitchin, Nibiru orbits the Sun on a 3,600-year elongated orbit. Modern astronomy has found no evidence to support these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitchin argued that Sumerian texts tell the story of 50 Anunnaki from Nibiru who came to Earth approximately 400,000 years ago to mine raw materials, especially gold. They genetically engineered laborers, creating &lt;em&gt;Homo sapiens sapiens&lt;/em&gt;: the &amp;ldquo;Adapa&amp;rdquo; or Adam of later mythology. Sitchin contended that the Anunnaki were active in human affairs until their culture was destroyed by global catastrophes caused by the end of the last ice age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His work has not received mainstream scholarly support and has been criticized by professionals. Semitic languages scholar Michael S. Heiser says that many of Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s translations are inconsistent with Mesopotamian cuneiform dictionaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alan F. Alford, author of &lt;em&gt;Gods of the New Millennium&lt;/em&gt;, initially adhered to Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s hypotheses but later found fault, stating that the gods personified the falling sky and that the descent of the gods was a poetic rendition of the cataclysm myth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;robert-temple&#34;&gt;Robert Temple &lt;a href=&#34;#robert-temple&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert K. G. Temple&amp;rsquo;s 1976 book, &lt;em&gt;The Sirius Mystery,&lt;/em&gt; argues that the Dogon people of northwestern Mali preserved an account of extraterrestrial visitation from around 5,000 years ago. He cites advanced astronomical knowledge, descriptions, and comparative belief systems with ancient civilizations. His work draws on the studies of cultural anthropologists Marcel Griaule and Germaine Dieterlen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His conclusions have been criticized by scientists, who point out discrepancies and suggest that the Dogon may have received their astronomical information recently from European sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ufo-religions&#34;&gt;UFO Religions &lt;a href=&#34;#ufo-religions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various new religious movements, including some branches of Theosophy, Scientology, Raëlism, Aetherius Society, and Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate, believe in ancient and present-day contact with extraterrestrial intelligence. Many see ancient scriptures and recent revelations as connected with the action of aliens. Psychologists have found that UFO religions have similarities suggesting that members associate enchantment with science fiction memes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;claims-of-proponents&#34;&gt;Claims of Proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#claims-of-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientific consensus is that the ancient astronaut hypothesis is not impossible, but unjustified and unnecessary. The &amp;ldquo;mysteries&amp;rdquo; cited as evidence can be explained without invoking ancient astronauts. Since ancient astronauts are unnecessary, Occam&amp;rsquo;s razor should be applied and the hypothesis rejected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ancient-religious-texts&#34;&gt;Ancient Religious Texts &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-religious-texts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proponents cite ancient mythologies, suggesting that creation myths of gods descending from the heavens to create or instruct humanity are representations of alien visitors. They draw an analogy to cargo cults, where isolated cultures believed Western ships and cargo were sent from the gods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ancient Sumerian myth of &lt;em&gt;Enûma Eliš&lt;/em&gt; says humankind was created to serve gods called the &amp;ldquo;Annunaki.&amp;rdquo; Proponents believe that the Annunaki were aliens who came to Earth to mine gold and created the human race as slaves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;ramayana&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ramayana&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#ramayana&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Hindu mythology, the gods and their avatars travel in flying vehicles called Vimana. The &lt;em&gt;Ramayana&lt;/em&gt; mentions these flying objects, used by the Lankan king Ravana from Sri Lanka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples from the &lt;em&gt;Ramayana&lt;/em&gt; include descriptions of the Pushpak chariot, a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Search of Aliens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_78bbf70c1c9e/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 19:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_78bbf70c1c9e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;in-search-of-aliens&#34;&gt;In Search of Aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#in-search-of-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In Search of Aliens&lt;/em&gt; is a 2014 American television series that aired on the H2 channel. The show is presented by Giorgio A. Tsoukalos, a prominent figure from &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;, and explores topics related to pseudoscience, ufology, and conspiracy theories, particularly the ancient astronaut theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;episodes&#34;&gt;Episodes &lt;a href=&#34;#episodes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the titles of all ten episodes of the single season of &lt;em&gt;In Search of Aliens&lt;/em&gt;. The episodes cover a range of topics, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Hunt for Atlantis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nazi Time Travelers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Mystery of Loch Ness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Roswell Rock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searching for Bigfoot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Mystery of the Cyclops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Mystery of Puma Punku&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Founding of America&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Mystery of Nazca&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Alien Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;criticism&#34;&gt;Criticism &lt;a href=&#34;#criticism&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show has faced criticism from reviewers and organizations. Jason Colavito criticized the show for lacking a clear thesis and for Tsoukalos&amp;rsquo; apparent skepticism towards his interviewees&amp;rsquo; claims. The Southern Poverty Law Center (SPLC), through Alexander Zaitchik&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Hatewatch&lt;/em&gt; blog, has criticized shows like &lt;em&gt;In Search of Aliens&lt;/em&gt; for promoting &amp;ldquo;racist pseudo-scholarship&amp;rdquo; and raising the profile of figures like Jan Udo Holey, whose antisemitic works have been banned in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of related topics and television programs, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of topics characterized as pseudoscience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pseudoarchaeology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unsealed Alien Files&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;In Search of&amp;hellip; (TV series)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists the sources cited in the article, including links to History.com, Jason Colavito&amp;rsquo;s website, and the Southern Poverty Law Center&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Hatewatch&lt;/em&gt; blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;external-links&#34;&gt;External links &lt;a href=&#34;#external-links&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a link to the show&amp;rsquo;s page on IMDb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/In_Search_of_Aliens&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/In_Search_of_Aliens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
