<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pseudoscience on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/pseudoscience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pseudoscience on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 08:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/pseudoscience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ancient astronauts</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_96b21753a786/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 08:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_96b21753a786/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ancient-astronauts&#34;&gt;Ancient Astronauts &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-astronauts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ancient astronauts, also known as ancient aliens, is a pseudoscientific belief that intelligent extraterrestrial beings visited Earth in ancient times and influenced the development of human civilization. Proponents suggest that these aliens affected modern cultures, technologies, religions, and human biology. A common idea is that deities from religions are extraterrestrial in origin, and advanced technologies were seen as divine by early humans. Academics and archaeologists dismiss these claims as pseudoarchaeological or unscientific, lacking credible peer-reviewed studies. Some argue that these theories have racist undertones, diminishing the accomplishments of indigenous cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Various terms are used to describe claims about ancient astronauts, including ancient aliens, ancient ufonauts, ancient space pilots, paleocontact, astronaut- or alien gods, and paleo- or biblical-SETI. Believers often claim that humans are descendants or creations of extraterrestrial intelligence who landed on Earth in the past. They suggest that human knowledge, religion, and culture originated from these visitors, who acted as a &amp;ldquo;mother culture.&amp;rdquo; Proponents also claim that aliens built structures like the Egyptian pyramids and the Moai stone heads of Easter Island or aided humans in their construction. Evidence is said to come from gaps in historical and archaeological records and artifacts that are considered anachronistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a pseudoarcheology, the idea is featured in fringe media, such as the History Channel series &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aliens&lt;/em&gt;. The show mixes fact with fiction to spread theories of an alternate past with tropes that follow white supremacist, nativist, imperialist, settler-colonial, and Christian Identity beliefs. Proponents claim to be an oppressed minority of academics that &amp;lsquo;big archaeology&amp;rsquo; is conspiring to disenfranchise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like archaeological endeavors of the criticized past, these proponents focus primarily on monumental archaeological structures claiming they could have only been constructed with extraterrestrial intervention. The implication is that the non-white Indigenous people in the regions in which these monuments appear could not have built them on their own. However, Dakota/Lakota Sioux writer Ruth H. Burns counters that ancient alien theory and the idea of extraterrestrials in general supports the viewpoints of indigenous, non-European peoples. She believes the denial of extraterrestrial encounters and indigenous peoples’ stories tracing their origins to extraterrestrials is part of “Indigenous erasure,” as it minimizes or completely discounts the viewpoints of indigenous peoples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common feature in the stories portray the aliens as light-skinned or Aryan in complexion, as prominent alien astronaut proponent Erich von Däniken claims in his foundational work &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; Some ancient astronaut proponents are thus associated with white supremacism, although their theories are sometimes applied to European cultures as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These claims are so outlandish that up until recently, mainstream archaeologists essentially ignored them as absurdities. The few dedicated popular science explainers and skeptics who did offer opinions on the ideas universally panned them. Carl Sagan noted that cases of interest have reasonable alternative explanations or are misreported, fabricated, or distorted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34;&gt;History of ancient aliens beliefs and their proponents &lt;a href=&#34;#history-of-ancient-aliens-beliefs-and-their-proponents&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paleocontact narratives first appeared in early science fiction of the late 19th and early 20th centuries, including &lt;em&gt;Edison&amp;rsquo;s Conquest of Mars&lt;/em&gt; (1898) and the works of H.P. Lovecraft. Harold T. Wilkins proposed the idea in earnest in 1954. It grew in popularity in the 1960s due to the Space Race and the success of Erich von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s works. Critics emerged throughout the 1970s, discrediting Von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s claims. Ufologists separated the idea from the UFO controversy. By the early 1980s little remaining support could be found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;shklovskii-and-sagan&#34;&gt;Shklovskii and Sagan &lt;a href=&#34;#shklovskii-and-sagan&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Carl Sagan co-authored &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Life in the Universe&lt;/em&gt; with Soviet astrophysicist Iosif Shklovsky in 1966. In &lt;em&gt;Broca&amp;rsquo;s Brain&lt;/em&gt; (1979), Sagan suggested that he and Shklovsky might have inspired the wave of 1970s ancient astronaut books, expressing disapproval of &amp;ldquo;von Däniken and other uncritical writers&amp;rdquo; who seemingly built on these ideas not as guarded speculations but as &amp;ldquo;valid evidence of extraterrestrial contact.&amp;rdquo; Sagan pointed out that many legends, artifacts, and purported out-of-place artifacts were cited in support of ancient astronaut hypotheses, &amp;ldquo;very few require more than passing mention&amp;rdquo; and could be easily explained with more conventional hypotheses. Sagan also reiterated his earlier conclusion that extraterrestrial visits to Earth were possible but unproven and improbable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;erich-von-däniken&#34;&gt;Erich von Däniken &lt;a href=&#34;#erich-von-d%c3%a4niken&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Erich von Däniken was a leading proponent of the ancient astronaut hypothesis in the late 1960s and early 1970s, gaining a large audience through the 1968 publication of his best-selling book &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; and its sequels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to von Däniken, certain artifacts require more sophisticated technological ability in their construction than that which was available to the ancient cultures who constructed them. Von Däniken maintains that these artifacts were constructed either directly by extraterrestrial visitors or by humans who learned the necessary knowledge from said visitors. These include Stonehenge, Pumapunku, the Moai of Easter Island, the Great Pyramid of Giza, and the ancient Baghdad electric batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Von Däniken writes that ancient art and iconography throughout the world illustrates air and space vehicles, non-human but intelligent creatures, ancient astronauts, and artifacts of an anachronistically advanced technology. Von Däniken also states that geographically separated historical cultures share artistic themes, which he argues imply a common origin. One such example is von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s interpretation of the sarcophagus lid recovered from the tomb of the Classic-era Maya ruler of Palenque, Pacal the Great. Von Däniken writes that the design represented a seated astronaut. The iconography and accompanying Maya text, however, identifies it as a portrait of the ruler himself with the World Tree of Maya mythology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The origins of many religions are interpreted by von Däniken as reactions to encounters with an alien race. According to his view, humans considered the technology of the aliens to be supernatural and the aliens themselves to be gods. Von Däniken states that the oral and written traditions of most religions contain references to alien visitors in the way of descriptions of stars and vehicular objects traveling through air and space. One such is Ezekiel&amp;rsquo;s revelation, which Däniken interprets as a detailed description of a landing spacecraft (&lt;em&gt;The Spaceships of Ezekiel&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s hypotheses became popularized in the U.S. after the NBC-TV documentary &lt;em&gt;In Search of Ancient Astronauts&lt;/em&gt; hosted by Rod Serling, and the film &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critics argue that von Däniken misrepresented data, that many of his claims were unfounded, and that none of his core claims have been validated. In particular the Christian creationist community is highly critical of most of von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s work. Young Earth creationist author Clifford A. Wilson published &lt;em&gt;Crash Go the Chariots&lt;/em&gt; in 1972 in which he attempted to discredit all the claims made in &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt;, regarding the Nazca Lines, von Däniken states that &amp;ldquo;Seen from the air, the clear-cut impression that the 60 km [37-mile] long plain of Nazca made on me was that of an airfield.&amp;rdquo; Considering he was in the process of seeking evidence of ancient aliens, von Däniken exhibits confirmation bias, as he does not consider the Nazca Lines to be man-made until after the publication of &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; This etic perspective that he presents could be easily accepted by a reader familiar with air travel, and an undeveloped knowledge of the nature of the geoglyphs. Furthermore, since the majority of readers of &lt;em&gt;Chariots of the Gods?&lt;/em&gt; are not educated in viewing artifacts from ancient civilizations, their interpretations are highly subject to von Däniken&amp;rsquo;s opinions of the artifacts. Kenneth L. Feder argues a reader seeing the Nazca Lines for the first time in a book about aliens would be much more likely to associate those features with extraterrestrial origins, rather than from a civilization that existed on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1970, von Däniken admitted that the Nazca markings &amp;ldquo;could have been laid out on their gigantic scale by working from a model using a system of coordinates.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;zecharia-sitchin&#34;&gt;Zecharia Sitchin &lt;a href=&#34;#zecharia-sitchin&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zecharia Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s series &lt;em&gt;The Earth Chronicles&lt;/em&gt;, beginning with &lt;em&gt;The 12th Planet&lt;/em&gt;, revolves around Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s unique interpretation of ancient Sumerian and Middle Eastern texts, megalithic sites, and artifacts from around the world. He hypothesizes that the gods of old Mesopotamia were astronauts from the planet &amp;ldquo;Nibiru&amp;rdquo;, which Sitchin states the Sumerians believed to be a remote &amp;ldquo;12th planet&amp;rdquo; (counting the Sun, Moon, and Pluto as planets) associated with the god Marduk. According to Sitchin, Nibiru continues to orbit the Sun on a 3,600-year elongated orbit. Modern astronomy has found no evidence to support Sitchin&amp;rsquo;s ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitchin argues that there are Sumerian texts that tell the story that 50 Anunnaki, inhabitants of a planet named Nibiru, came to Earth approximately 400,000 years ago with the intent of mining raw materials, especially gold, for transport back to Nibiru. With their small numbers they soon grew tired of the task and set out to genetically engineer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_astronauts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
