<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aliens on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/aliens/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aliens on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 14:49:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/aliens/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>List of humanoid aliens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_889911f31664/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_889911f31664/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-humanoid-aliens&#34;&gt;List of Humanoid Aliens &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-humanoid-aliens&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Wikipedia entry is a compilation of fictional extraterrestrial humanoid characters from various media. It emphasizes that these aliens possess human-like traits such as upright posture, bipedalism, opposable thumbs, and facial features. The list is organized by medium: Animation, Comics, Film, Literature, Television, and Video Games. Each entry includes the character&amp;rsquo;s name, origin (the work in which they appear), and brief notes about their role or characteristics. The article is flagged as needing additional citations for verification and may not be complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;animation&#34;&gt;Animation &lt;a href=&#34;#animation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists humanoid aliens featured in animated works. Key characters include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Great Gazoo&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Flintstones&lt;/em&gt;): A tiny alien exiled to Earth who can only be seen by Fred, Barney, children, and animals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cure Princess/Hime Shirayuki&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;HappinessCharge PreCure!&lt;/em&gt;): A princess from the Blue Sky Kingdom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mikitaka Hazekura&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;JoJo&amp;rsquo;s Bizarre Adventure&lt;/em&gt;): An alien who appears as a teenage boy with pointed ears.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interplanet Janet&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Schoolhouse Rock&lt;/em&gt;): A cyborg girl from another galaxy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jet Propulsion&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Ready Jet Go!&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from Bortron 7 studying Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cure Milky/Lala Hagoromo&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Star Twinkle PreCure&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from the planet Samaan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Little Twelvetoes&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Schoolhouse Rock&lt;/em&gt;): A jovial alien with green skin and six fingers and toes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marvin the Martian&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Looney Tunes&lt;/em&gt;): A Martian often accompanied by his dog K-9.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ozmodiar&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Simpsons&lt;/em&gt;): A parody of The Great Gazoo, only visible to Homer Simpson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roger&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;American Dad!&lt;/em&gt;): An alien living in Stan&amp;rsquo;s attic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sailor Starlights&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Sailor Moon&lt;/em&gt;): Sailor Guardians from Planet Kinmoku.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shadow Galactica&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Sailor Moon&lt;/em&gt;): Antagonists from various planets in the Milky Way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Son Goku&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Dragon Ball&lt;/em&gt;): A Saiyan from Planet Vegeta.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cure Cosmo/Yuni&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Star Twinkle PreCure&lt;/em&gt;): A shapeshifting catgirl from Planet Rainbow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zim&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Invader Zim&lt;/em&gt;): An Irken invader sent to conquer Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upgrade&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Ben 10&lt;/em&gt;): A Galvanic Mechamorph from Galvan B.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atomix&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Ben 10&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from an unknown planet who can create nuclear energy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comics&#34;&gt;Comics &lt;a href=&#34;#comics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details humanoid aliens from comic books. Notable entries include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Annihilus&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Fantastic Four&lt;/em&gt;): A villain from the Marvel Universe. Created by Stan Lee and Jack Kirby.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cosmo&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Cosmo the Merry Martian&lt;/em&gt;): A Martian who visits Earth. Created by Bob White.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Darna&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Darna&lt;/em&gt;): An extraterrestrial warrior who manifests in a human girl. Created by Mars Ravelo and Nestor Redondo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Khâny&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Yoko Tsuno&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from the planet Vinea. Created by Roger Leloup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plunk&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Plunk&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from the planet Smurk. Created by Luc Cromheecke and Laurent Letzer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Scrameustache&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Scrameustache&lt;/em&gt;): An alien with a cat-like face. Created by Roland Goossens (Gos).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr. Skygack&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Mr. Skygack, from Mars&lt;/em&gt;): A Martian studying human behavior. Created by A.D. Condo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Superman/Clark Kent&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Action Comics #1&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from Krypton with superhuman powers. Created by Jerry Siegel and Joe Shuster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xal-Kor&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Xal-Kor the Human Cat&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from Felis who can transform between cat, hybrid, and human forms. Created by Grass Green.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zook&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Zook&lt;/em&gt;): A Martian who visits Earth. Created by Jack Miller and Joe Certa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;film&#34;&gt;Film &lt;a href=&#34;#film&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists humanoid aliens appearing in movies. Key examples include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E.T.&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial&lt;/em&gt;): An alien who befriends a human boy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Various&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/em&gt;): Includes Asgardians, members of the Guardians of the Galaxy, and Eternals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Klaatu&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Day the Earth Stood Still&lt;/em&gt;): An alien who delivers a peaceful message to Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Various&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;): Includes Chewbacca, Yoda, Darth Maul, and Ahsoka Tano.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zaphod Beeblebrox&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from near Betelgeuse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mork&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Mork and Mindy&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from Ork who studies humanity on Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Alien Girl&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Super Deluxe&lt;/em&gt;): An alien living on Earth, mingling with humans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;literature&#34;&gt;Literature &lt;a href=&#34;#literature&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section compiles humanoid aliens from literary works. Notable characters include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Little Prince&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Little Prince&lt;/em&gt;): A prince from an asteroid who visits Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Curtis&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;One Door Away from Heaven&lt;/em&gt;): A shape-shifting alien on the run.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ras Thavas&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Master Mind of Mars&lt;/em&gt;): A Martian mad scientist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Thing&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Who Goes There?&lt;/em&gt;): A shapeshifting alien that takes a human form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;television&#34;&gt;Television &lt;a href=&#34;#television&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists humanoid aliens featured in television shows. Key characters include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adric&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Doctor Who&lt;/em&gt;): A young native of Alzarius in E-Space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ALF/Gordon Shumway&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;ALF&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from Melmac who crash lands on Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beldar, Prymaat, and Connie&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Coneheads&lt;/em&gt;): An alien family from Remulak with conical heads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big Giant Head&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;3rd Rock from the Sun&lt;/em&gt;): The alien leader of the Solomons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Doctor&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Doctor Who&lt;/em&gt;): An adventurer and scientist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fofão&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Balão Mágico&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;TV Fofão&lt;/em&gt;): An extraterrestrial child character.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gonzo&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Muppet Show&lt;/em&gt;): A puppet revealed to be of extraterrestrial origin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mork&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Mork &amp;amp; Mindy&lt;/em&gt;): An alien from Ork who befriends a human woman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martin O&amp;rsquo;Hara&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;My Favorite Martian&lt;/em&gt;): A Martian anthropologist stranded on Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dick Solomon&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;3rd Rock from the Sun&lt;/em&gt;): An alien in human guise on Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry Solomon&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;3rd Rock from the Sun&lt;/em&gt;): An alien in human guise on Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sally Solomon&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;3rd Rock from the Sun&lt;/em&gt;): An alien in human guise on Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tommy Solomon&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;3rd Rock from the Sun&lt;/em&gt;): An alien in human guise on Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spock&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;): A Vulcan science officer on the Enterprise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ultraman&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Ultraman&lt;/em&gt;): A race of aliens who protect the universe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ultronians&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;My Hero&lt;/em&gt;): A species from the planet Ultron with superpowers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-games&#34;&gt;Video Games &lt;a href=&#34;#video-games&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists humanoid aliens appearing in video games. Key examples include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abe&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Oddworld&lt;/em&gt;): The central character of the &lt;em&gt;Oddworld&lt;/em&gt; series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artanis&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt;): A Protoss commander and protagonist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forerunner&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;): Ancient Humanoid Aliens that created the Halo rings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_humanoid_aliens&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_humanoid_aliens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
