<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Extraterrestrial on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/extraterrestrial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Extraterrestrial on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 13:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/extraterrestrial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien abduction</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_85a477e6d898/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_85a477e6d898/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-abduction&#34;&gt;Alien Abduction &lt;a href=&#34;#alien-abduction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alien abduction, also known as abduction phenomenon, alien abduction syndrome, or UFO abduction, is the subjective experience of individuals reporting being kidnapped by extraterrestrial beings and subjected to physical and psychological experimentation. These individuals are often referred to as &amp;ldquo;abductees&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;experiencers.&amp;rdquo; While most scientists and mental health professionals attribute these experiences to factors like suggestibility, sleep paralysis, deception, and psychopathology, some researchers give credence to the claims. Typical claims involve forced medical examinations, often focusing on reproductive systems, warnings about environmental abuses and nuclear weapons, or interspecies breeding. The content of these narratives often varies with the abductee&amp;rsquo;s cultural background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview &lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainstream scientists generally reject the literal interpretation of alien abduction claims. However, some, like psychiatrist John E. Mack, argue that many abductees are sane individuals, with psychopathology only present in some cases. Detailed abduction reports have led to the development of a subculture with support groups and a complex mythos explaining the roles, origins, and motivations of various alien types, such as Greys, Reptilians, and Nordics. Some abductees engage in independent research and attribute the lack of wider awareness to extraterrestrial or governmental cover-ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;paleo-abductions&#34;&gt;Paleo-abductions &lt;a href=&#34;#paleo-abductions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the widespread attention to alien abduction in the 1960s, some older stories have been reinterpreted as possible early cases, termed &amp;ldquo;paleo-abductions&amp;rdquo; by UFO researcher Jerome Clark. One example is Colonel H. G. Shaw&amp;rsquo;s 1896 claim of being harassed by tall, slender humanoids. An article from 1953 asked if flying saucers were kidnapping humans for zoological specimens or vivisection. The 1955 publication of Harold T. Wilkins&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Flying Saucers Uncensored&lt;/em&gt; reported speculation that Karl Hunrath and Wilbur Wilkinson, who claimed alien contact, disappeared due to abduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;two-landmark-cases&#34;&gt;Two landmark cases &lt;a href=&#34;#two-landmark-cases&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Antônio Vilas-Boas case in Brazil during the mid-1950s was an early claim but received limited attention initially. The Betty and Barney Hill abduction in 1961 gained widespread publicity, including a 1975 television film. The Hill incident is considered a prototypical abduction case, possibly the first to describe beings later known as the Greys and explicitly identify an extraterrestrial origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;later-developments&#34;&gt;Later developments &lt;a href=&#34;#later-developments&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R. Leo Sprinkle, a psychologist at the University of Wyoming, became interested in the phenomenon in the 1960s and linked abductions to cattle mutilation. Budd Hopkins became a key figure in the abductee subculture in the 1970s, using hypnosis to uncover details of remembered events. The 1980s saw increased mainstream attention, with works by Hopkins, Whitley Strieber, David M. Jacobs, and John E. Mack presenting alien abduction as a plausible experience. Thomas E. Bullard&amp;rsquo;s comparative analysis of nearly 300 alleged abductees was also published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jacobs and Hopkins argued that alien abduction was more common than previously thought, estimating tens of thousands of North Americans had been abducted. They also proposed an alien effort to create human-alien hybrids. While anecdotal reports of phantom pregnancies related to UFO encounters existed earlier, Hopkins and Jacobs popularized the idea of widespread interbreeding efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Boston Globe&lt;/em&gt; writer Linda Rodriguez McRobbie, alien abduction stories have declined in mainstream media. Michael Shermer suggests that the ubiquity of camera phones has increased the burden of evidence, contributing to the decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;john-e-mack&#34;&gt;John E. Mack &lt;a href=&#34;#john-e-mack&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harvard psychiatry professor John E. Mack believed in the credibility of alien abduction claims. Niall Boyce, writing in &lt;em&gt;The Lancet&lt;/em&gt;, suggested that Mack&amp;rsquo;s work in hypnotic regression helped spread the Grey aliens meme. Mack interviewed over 800 people and wrote two books on the subject. His professional reputation suffered due to his belief and promotion of abduction claims, leading to a Harvard review in 1994.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abductees&#34;&gt;Abductees &lt;a href=&#34;#abductees&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The precise number of alleged abductees is uncertain. Early studies found 1,700 claimants, while contested surveys suggested 5–6 percent of the general population claim to have been abducted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;demographics&#34;&gt;Demographics &lt;a href=&#34;#demographics&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While abduction reports are usually made by adults, children sometimes report similar experiences. These reports often share specific details with adult reports, including circumstances, narrative, entities, and aftermaths. Young abductees often have family members who have reported abduction experiences, and family involvement in the military or residence near a military base is also common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mental-health&#34;&gt;Mental health &lt;a href=&#34;#mental-health&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some studies suggest that abductees have psychological characteristics that render their testimony suspect, while others show that abductees are not different from the general population in terms of psychopathology prevalence. Elizabeth Slater&amp;rsquo;s blind study found abductees prone to &amp;ldquo;mildly paranoid thinking,&amp;rdquo; nightmares, and weak sexual identity, while Richard McNally&amp;rsquo;s study concluded that none of the abductees suffered from psychiatric illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;political-conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;Political conspiracy theories &lt;a href=&#34;#political-conspiracy-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Political scientist Michael Barkun highlights links between radical politics and conspiracy theories involving UFOs, alien visitation, environmental pollution, hidden groups, and government takeover. He observed the rise of &amp;ldquo;improvisional millenarism.&amp;rdquo; UFO and abduction stories can be part of stigmatized knowledge narratives. UFO and alien-related conspiracy theories emerged in far-right politics from the 1980s onwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Barkun, TV shows like &lt;em&gt;The X-Files&lt;/em&gt; included aliens as part of coverup conspiracies, with militias and black helicopters, and demonized FEMA. Political scientist Jodi Dean noted that the stigma of alien abduction stories is seductive to dismiss &amp;ldquo;consensus reality&amp;rdquo; in favor of deviant alternative realities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-described abduction victims often join self-help communities and may resort to questionable regression therapy. Some espouse conspiracy theories of technological mind control, including implants, to force them to serve a New World Order or for the purposes of the antichrist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abduction-narrative&#34;&gt;Abduction narrative &lt;a href=&#34;#abduction-narrative&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various researchers have noted common points in report narratives. CUFOS defines an abductee as someone taken against their will by non-human beings to an extraterrestrial place or spaceship, subjected to examination or communication, with memories that may be conscious or recovered through hypnosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although cases vary, some UFO researchers argue that there is a fairly consistent sequence and description of events that make up the typical &amp;ldquo;close encounter of the fourth kind.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bullard argues most abduction accounts feature the following events:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capture&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductee is rendered incapable of resisting and taken to an alien spacecraft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Examination and Procedures&lt;/strong&gt;: Invasive physiological and psychological procedures, and on occasion simulated behavioral situations, training &amp;amp; testing, or sexual liaisons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conference&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductors communicate with the abductee or direct them to interact with specific individuals for some purpose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tour&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductees are given a tour of their captors&amp;rsquo; vessel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loss of Time&lt;/strong&gt;: Abductees often rapidly forget the majority of their experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Return&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductees are returned to earth, occasionally in a different location or with new injuries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theophany&lt;/strong&gt;: Abductees may have a profound sense of love, a &amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo; similar to those induced by certain drugs, or a &amp;ldquo;mystical experience&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aftermath&lt;/strong&gt;: The abductee must cope with the psychological, physical, and social effects of the experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David M. Jacobs says that the entire abduction event is precisely orchestrated, with predetermined procedures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;capture&#34;&gt;Capture &lt;a href=&#34;#capture&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abduction claimants report unusual feelings preceding the onset of an abduction experience, such as a compulsive desire to be at a certain place or expectations that something &amp;ldquo;familiar yet unknown&amp;rdquo; will occur. They also report feeling severe anxiety. Eventually, the experiencer will undergo an apparent &amp;ldquo;shift&amp;rdquo; into an altered state of consciousness. External sounds cease to have any significance, and they report feeling introspective and unusually calm. As consciousness shifts, lights are alleged to appear, occasionally accompanied by a strange mist. As the alleged abduction proceeds, claimants say they will walk or be levitated into an alien craft, often through solid objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;examination&#34;&gt;Examination &lt;a href=&#34;#examination&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The examination phase is characterized by medical procedures and examinations by alien beings against the will of the experiencer. Such procedures often focus on sex and reproductive biology. The entity in charge of the operation is often taller than the others and may appear to be of a different species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miller notes different areas of emphasis between human medicine and what is reported as being practiced by the abductors. The abductors&amp;rsquo; areas of interest appear to be the cranium, nervous system, skin, reproductive system, and joints. Systems given less attention include the cardiovascular system, the respiratory system below the pharynx, and the lymphatic system. The abductors also appear to ignore the upper region of the abdomen in favor of the lower one. The abductors do not appear to wear gloves during the &amp;ldquo;examination.&amp;rdquo; Other constants of terrestrial medicine like pills and tablets are missing from abduction narratives, although sometimes abductees are asked to drink liquids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;subsequent-procedures&#34;&gt;Subsequent procedures &lt;a href=&#34;#subsequent-procedures&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the medical exam, the alleged abductees often report other procedures being performed with the entities. Common among these post-examination procedures are imaging, envisioning, staging, and testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Imaging&amp;rdquo; procedures consist of an abductee being made to view screens displaying images and scenes that appear to be specially chosen with the intent to provoke certain emotional responses in the abductee. &amp;ldquo;Envisioning&amp;rdquo; is a similar procedure, with the primary difference being that the images being viewed, rather than being on a screen, actually seem to be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_abduction&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_abduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History of the extraterrestrial life debate</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a9b9b3e228d3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 20:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_a9b9b3e228d3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;historical-views-about-extraterrestrial-life&#34;&gt;Historical Views about Extraterrestrial Life &lt;a href=&#34;#historical-views-about-extraterrestrial-life&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article explores the historical debate surrounding the existence of extraterrestrial life, tracing its evolution from ancient philosophical speculations to modern scientific inquiry. It highlights key figures, pivotal moments, and shifting perspectives that have shaped our understanding of this enduring question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ancient-greece&#34;&gt;Ancient Greece &lt;a href=&#34;#ancient-greece&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section delves into the earliest recorded discussions about extraterrestrial life, focusing on Ancient Greece. It contrasts the views of atomists, who believed in the possibility of multiple worlds with life, and Aristotelians, who argued for the uniqueness of Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt; The section highlights the shift from mythological explanations of celestial objects to philosophical inquiries about the nature of the universe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important People:&lt;/strong&gt; Thales of Miletus, Anaximander, Pythagoras, Aristarchus of Samos, Plato, Aristotle, Leucippus, Democritus, Epicurus, Lucretius, Alexander the Great.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Locations:&lt;/strong&gt; Ancient Greece, Alexandria, Baghdad, Roman Empire, Byzantine Empire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Major Events:&lt;/strong&gt; The development of geometry, the proposal of heliocentric and geocentric models, the spread of Greek ideas through the Macedonian Empire and the Islamic Golden Age, and the eventual return of this knowledge to Europe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;christianity&#34;&gt;Christianity &lt;a href=&#34;#christianity&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section examines the influence of Christianity on the debate about extraterrestrial life during the Middle Ages. It discusses how the concept of multiple worlds was largely viewed as heretical, with a few exceptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt; The section focuses on the conflict between religious doctrine and the idea of extraterrestrial life, particularly concerning the uniqueness of creation and the role of Christ&amp;rsquo;s redemption.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important People:&lt;/strong&gt; Origen, Augustine of Hippo, Thomas Aquinas, William Vorilong, John.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Major Events:&lt;/strong&gt; The rise of Christianity, the Condemnation of 1277, and the discussions surrounding the implications of extraterrestrial life for Christian theology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;copernican-revolution&#34;&gt;Copernican Revolution &lt;a href=&#34;#copernican-revolution&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores how the Copernican Revolution, which shifted the Earth from the center of the universe, significantly impacted the plausibility of extraterrestrial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt; The section highlights the transition from a geocentric to a heliocentric worldview and the scientific advancements that supported this shift.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important People:&lt;/strong&gt; Nicolaus Copernicus, Tycho Brahe, Johannes Kepler, Galileo Galilei, Isaac Newton, Giordano Bruno.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Major Events:&lt;/strong&gt; The publication of &lt;em&gt;De revolutionibus orbium coelestium&lt;/em&gt;, Kepler&amp;rsquo;s discovery of elliptical orbits, Galileo&amp;rsquo;s telescopic observations, and Newton&amp;rsquo;s formulation of the laws of motion and universal gravitation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modern-times&#34;&gt;Modern Times &lt;a href=&#34;#modern-times&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the modern scientific approach to the question of extraterrestrial life, encompassing fields like biology, chemistry, biochemistry, physics, and planetary science, all under the umbrella of astrobiology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt; The section emphasizes the vastness and age of the universe, the abundance of elements necessary for life, and the universality of physical laws, which together suggest that life on other worlds is plausible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Major Events:&lt;/strong&gt; The development of astrobiology as a multidisciplinary field, and the ongoing search for extraterrestrial life through scientific exploration and research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_the_extraterrestrial_life_debate&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_the_extraterrestrial_life_debate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Harder</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ed1204981fce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 16:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_ed1204981fce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;james-a-harder&#34;&gt;James A. Harder &lt;a href=&#34;#james-a-harder&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James Albert Harder was a professor of civil and hydraulic engineering at the University of California, Berkeley, and later a professor emeritus. He also had a notable interest in ufology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;engineering&#34;&gt;Engineering &lt;a href=&#34;#engineering&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harder taught civil engineering at various levels, emphasizing practical aspects like lab experiments and model testing. While he didn&amp;rsquo;t publish extensively, his work was recognized for its quality. He made significant contributions to flow simulations before computers were widely used. A paper he co-authored, &lt;em&gt;Sea Water Intrusion in California&lt;/em&gt;, received an award in 1957. His work was applied in Suisun Bay and the Mekong Delta, and he also studied fish protection facilities. Later in his career, he studied fluid mechanics in a medical context, working on artificial hearts, endoscopes, and colostomy equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufology&#34;&gt;Ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harder believed that unidentified flying objects were extraterrestrial beings. He testified before the House of Representatives Committee on Science and Astronautics and was involved with the Aerial Phenomena Research Organization (APRO).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education &lt;a href=&#34;#education&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harder&amp;rsquo;s education included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;B.S. from the California Institute of Technology in 1948.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M.S. in Civil Engineering from UC Berkeley in 1952.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ph.D. in Fluid Mechanics from UC Berkeley in 1957.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;career&#34;&gt;Career &lt;a href=&#34;#career&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harder&amp;rsquo;s career included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;U.S. Navy as an electronics technician (1944-45).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design Engineer for the soil conservation service, U.S. Department of Agriculture (1948–50).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resident engineer at UC Berkeley (1952–57).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assistant professor of hydraulic engineering at UC Berkeley (1957–62).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Associate professor of civil engineering at UC Berkeley (1962–70).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professor of civil engineering at UC Berkeley (1970–91).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professor emeritus at UC Berkeley (1991).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;organizations&#34;&gt;Organizations &lt;a href=&#34;#organizations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harder was a Fellow of the American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS) and the American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE). He was also a founding member of the Society for Scientific Exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Harder_(ufologist)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Harder_(ufologist)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
