<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Black Triangles on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/black-triangles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Black Triangles on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 02:48:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/black-triangles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Black triangle (UFO)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/content_7c3b758d8d9d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 02:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/content_7c3b758d8d9d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;black-triangles&#34;&gt;Black Triangles &lt;a href=&#34;#black-triangles&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Black triangles are a type of unidentified flying object (UFO) characterized by their triangular shape and dark color. These objects are typically observed at night and are often described as large, silent, hovering, moving slowly, and displaying pulsating, colored lights that can be turned off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;british-sightings-and-uk-ministry-of-defence-report&#34;&gt;British Sightings and UK Ministry of Defence Report &lt;a href=&#34;#british-sightings-and-uk-ministry-of-defence-report&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the analysis of black triangle sightings by the UK Ministry of Defence in a declassified report called Project Condign. The report suggests that many unexplained UAP reports could be attributed to atmospheric gaseous electrically charged buoyant plasmas. It also mentions that some observations might be due to meteor entry into the atmosphere. The report proposes that a field with undetermined characteristics can exist between charged buoyant objects in loose formation, creating a triangular shape where light reflection doesn&amp;rsquo;t occur. A recommendation from the report advises aircraft to avoid intercepting these objects and instead position them astern to reduce collision risks. The report also speculates that plasma formations could induce vivid but incorrect perceptions in observers. Mark Stenhoff and Adrian James are mentioned as authors who doubt the scientific veracity of the Project Condign report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-sightings&#34;&gt;Other Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#other-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section details various black triangle UFO sightings reported across different locations and time periods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1980s-hudson-valley-sightings&#34;&gt;1980s Hudson Valley Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#1980s-hudson-valley-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the early 1980s, hundreds of people reported seeing UFOs over or near the Hudson River in New York state. These objects were described as hovering or slowly flying V-shaped objects with colorful lights. Some pilots claimed responsibility for these sightings, stating that the objects were ultralight aircraft flown in formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;19891992-belgian-wave&#34;&gt;1989–1992 Belgian Wave &lt;a href=&#34;#19891992-belgian-wave&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Belgian UFO wave began in November 1989. On November 29, over thirty groups of witnesses and three police groups documented a large, flat, triangular object with lights underneath flying at low altitude without making any sound. A report titled &lt;em&gt;The Belgian UFO Wave of 1989–1992 – A Neglected Hypothesis&lt;/em&gt; suggests that some sightings could be explained by helicopters, with the lack of noise attributed to engine noise in witnesses&amp;rsquo; automobiles or strong winds. The Belgian Air Force attempted to intercept an object detected by radar during this wave, but the pilots did not visually confirm the object. Brian Dunning is mentioned as a skeptic who disputes the entire Belgian UFO wave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1997-phoenix-lights-incident&#34;&gt;1997 Phoenix Lights Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#1997-phoenix-lights-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section focuses on the widely reported &amp;ldquo;Phoenix Lights&amp;rdquo; events, where multiple unidentified objects were observed near Phoenix, Arizona, beginning on March 13, 1997. Some objects appeared in a large &amp;ldquo;V&amp;rdquo; formation and lingered for several minutes. Residents reported that one of the black triangles was over a mile wide and drifted slowly over their houses. The US Air Force concluded that the military had been testing aircraft-launched flares during that period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2000-southern-illinois-incident&#34;&gt;2000 Southern Illinois Incident &lt;a href=&#34;#2000-southern-illinois-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;St. Clair Triangle&amp;rdquo; sighting occurred on January 5, 2000, over several towns in Southern Illinois. The incident was featured in television shows, and Sufjan Stevens included it in his song &amp;ldquo;Concerning the UFO Sighting Near Highland, Illinois.&amp;rdquo; The FAA suggested that the sightings might have been due to an advertising blimp operated by the American Blimp Company. William Stage is mentioned as a source, and Eric Mack is cited for debunking his own UFO sighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;20042006-tinley-park-lights&#34;&gt;2004–2006 Tinley Park Lights &lt;a href=&#34;#20042006-tinley-park-lights&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple witnesses in Tinley Park and Oak Forest, Illinois, reported seeing three red lights hovering in a triangular formation on several occasions between 2004 and 2006. Some witnesses captured the lights in photographs and videos. The incident was examined in a &lt;em&gt;Dateline NBC&lt;/em&gt; episode and in an episode of the television series &lt;em&gt;UFO Hunters&lt;/em&gt;. Julie Dekker is mentioned in connection with remembering the &amp;ldquo;Tinley Park lights.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2008-stephenville-texas&#34;&gt;2008 Stephenville, Texas &lt;a href=&#34;#2008-stephenville-texas&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mass sighting occurred in Stephenville, Texas, around January 8, 2008. The Netflix documentary series &lt;em&gt;Encounters&lt;/em&gt; claims that the black triangles seen had what looked like insects or a praying mantis inside. Angelia Joiner is mentioned as reporting on the possible UFO sighting in the &lt;em&gt;Stephenville Empire-Tribune&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;military-aircraft&#34;&gt;Military Aircraft &lt;a href=&#34;#military-aircraft&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explores the possibility that classified military aircraft could be responsible for many black triangle UFO reports. Sightings have been reported over Antelope Valley in southern California, near military research and testing areas like Edwards Air Force Base and United States Air Force Plant 42. The National Institute for Discovery Science suggested that black triangles might be U.S. Air Force craft. The Northrop TR-3A Black Manta, a speculative surveillance aircraft, is mentioned, but its existence is not confirmed. Gregory T. Pope is cited regarding America&amp;rsquo;s new secret aircraft, and Global Security is referenced for information on the TR-3A. Geoscientist Ben McGee is identified as suggesting that border patrol drones with infrared lights could explain some black triangles. Natalie Wolchover is cited in relation to McGee&amp;rsquo;s explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_triangle_(UFO)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_triangle_(UFO)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
