<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Government Investigations on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/government-investigations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Government Investigations on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 13:36:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/government-investigations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>List of UFO organizations</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6fed819364a2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 13:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_6fed819364a2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufos-and-ufology&#34;&gt;UFOs and Ufology &lt;a href=&#34;#ufos-and-ufology&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a general overview of the topic, linking to the main articles on Unidentified Flying Objects (UFOs) and Ufology, the study of UFOs. It includes an image of a &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; from the National Archives and Records Administration. It also links to a list of notable UFO sightings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;notable-sightings&#34;&gt;Notable Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#notable-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists various notable UFO sightings and incidents, categorized chronologically and geographically. Some key events include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947 Wave:&lt;/strong&gt; The surge of UFO sightings in 1947, marking the beginning of the modern UFO era.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1952 Flap:&lt;/strong&gt; A series of UFO sightings over Washington, D.C.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barney and Betty Hill Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; A famous alleged alien abduction case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Belgian Wave:&lt;/strong&gt; A series of UFO sightings over Belgium in the late 1980s and early 1990s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calvine Photo:&lt;/strong&gt; A controversial UFO photograph from Scotland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chiles-Whitted Encounter:&lt;/strong&gt; A 1948 sighting by commercial pilots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flatwoods Monster:&lt;/strong&gt; A West Virginia sighting of a strange creature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gorman Dogfight:&lt;/strong&gt; A 1948 encounter between a pilot and a UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenneth Arnold Sighting:&lt;/strong&gt; The event that popularized the term &amp;ldquo;flying saucer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mantell Crash:&lt;/strong&gt; The death of a pilot while pursuing a UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mariana Film:&lt;/strong&gt; A 1950 UFO sighting filmed in Montana.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;McMinnville Photos:&lt;/strong&gt; A set of photographs purportedly showing a UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rendlesham Forest Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; A series of reported sightings near a US military base in the UK.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roswell Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; The alleged crash of a UFO in Roswell, New Mexico.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sightings in Outer Space:&lt;/strong&gt; UFO sightings reported by astronauts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Swamp Gas&amp;rdquo; Reports:&lt;/strong&gt; UFO reports attributed to natural phenomena.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pentagon UFO Videos:&lt;/strong&gt; Declassified videos of UFOs recorded by US Navy pilots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phoenix Lights:&lt;/strong&gt; A mass sighting of lights over Phoenix, Arizona.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;hoaxes&#34;&gt;Hoaxes &lt;a href=&#34;#hoaxes&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists notable UFO-related hoaxes, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alien Autopsy Hoax:&lt;/strong&gt; A purported film of an alien autopsy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travis Walton Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; A controversial alleged alien abduction case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;government-investigations&#34;&gt;Government Investigations &lt;a href=&#34;#government-investigations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists various government investigations into UFOs from different countries, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operação Prato (Brazil):&lt;/strong&gt; A Brazilian military investigation into UFO sightings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Magnet (Canada):&lt;/strong&gt; A Canadian government UFO study.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GEIPAN (France):&lt;/strong&gt; A French government UFO investigation unit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institute 22 (Soviet Union):&lt;/strong&gt; A Soviet military research program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flying Saucer Working Party (UK):&lt;/strong&gt; An early British government investigation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Condign (UK):&lt;/strong&gt; A later British government study.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;History of Government Investigations (US):&lt;/strong&gt; A general overview of US government involvement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All-domain Anomaly Resolution Office (US):&lt;/strong&gt; A current US government office for investigating UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NASA&amp;rsquo;s UAP Independent Study Team (US):&lt;/strong&gt; A NASA team studying UAPs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Condon Committee (US):&lt;/strong&gt; A controversial US government study that concluded UFOs posed no threat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Blue Book (US):&lt;/strong&gt; A long-running US Air Force investigation into UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena Disclosure Act (US):&lt;/strong&gt; A US law aimed at disclosing information about UAPs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;Conspiracy Theories &lt;a href=&#34;#conspiracy-theories&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists popular UFO-related conspiracy theories, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Area 51:&lt;/strong&gt; A secret US military base rumored to house alien technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bob Lazar:&lt;/strong&gt; A man who claims to have worked on alien technology at Area 51.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Majestic 12:&lt;/strong&gt; An alleged secret group of government officials tasked with managing UFO information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Men in Black:&lt;/strong&gt; Mysterious figures who allegedly harass UFO witnesses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Serpo:&lt;/strong&gt; A purported exchange program between the US and aliens from the planet Serpo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;religions&#34;&gt;Religions &lt;a href=&#34;#religions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists religions that incorporate UFOs and extraterrestrial beings into their belief systems, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aetherius Society:&lt;/strong&gt; A religious group that believes in communication with extraterrestrial beings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Church of the SubGenius:&lt;/strong&gt; A parody religion that incorporates UFOs and conspiracy theories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gate:&lt;/strong&gt; A religious group that committed mass suicide in the belief that they would ascend to a spaceship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nation of Islam:&lt;/strong&gt; An Islamic religious movement that believes in a &amp;ldquo;Mother Plane&amp;rdquo; or UFO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raëlism:&lt;/strong&gt; A religion that believes extraterrestrials created humanity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scientology:&lt;/strong&gt; A religion that incorporates extraterrestrial beings and events into its cosmology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unarius Academy of Science:&lt;/strong&gt; A religious group that believes in communication with advanced extraterrestrial civilizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;lists-of-organizations-sightings-studies-etc&#34;&gt;Lists of Organizations, Sightings, Studies, etc. &lt;a href=&#34;#lists-of-organizations-sightings-studies-etc&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to various lists related to UFOs, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFO organizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reported UFO sightings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sightings by country&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigations of UFOs by governments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification studies of UFOs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ufologists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alleged extraterrestrial beings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;list-of-ufo-organizations&#34;&gt;List of UFO Organizations &lt;a href=&#34;#list-of-ufo-organizations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a list of notable non-governmental UFO organizations located around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;belarus&#34;&gt;Belarus &lt;a href=&#34;#belarus&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UfoCom:&lt;/strong&gt; A UFO research organization in Belarus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;estonia&#34;&gt;Estonia &lt;a href=&#34;#estonia&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AKRAK:&lt;/strong&gt; An inactive UFO research organization in Estonia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;france&#34;&gt;France &lt;a href=&#34;#france&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COMETA:&lt;/strong&gt; A French association that published a report on UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sweden&#34;&gt;Sweden &lt;a href=&#34;#sweden&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Archives for the Unexplained (AFU):&lt;/strong&gt; A Swedish archive dedicated to UFO research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;russia&#34;&gt;Russia &lt;a href=&#34;#russia&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kosmopoisk:&lt;/strong&gt; A Russian research group that investigates anomalous phenomena, including UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;united-kingdom&#34;&gt;United Kingdom &lt;a href=&#34;#united-kingdom&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;British UFO Research Association (BUFORA):&lt;/strong&gt; A UK-based UFO research organization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;united-states&#34;&gt;United States &lt;a href=&#34;#united-states&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;active&#34;&gt;Active &lt;a href=&#34;#active&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All-domain Anomaly Resolution Office (AARO):&lt;/strong&gt; A US government office for investigating UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Center for the Study of Extraterrestrial Intelligence (CSETI):&lt;/strong&gt; An organization that seeks to establish contact with extraterrestrial civilizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Center for UFO Studies (CUFOS or JAHCUFOS):&lt;/strong&gt; A UFO research organization founded by J. Allen Hynek.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;International UFO Congress (IUFOC):&lt;/strong&gt; An annual conference on UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mutual UFO Network (MUFON):&lt;/strong&gt; A large international UFO research organization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National UFO Reporting Center (NUFORC):&lt;/strong&gt; A US-based organization that collects and disseminates UFO sighting reports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To the Stars (TTS):&lt;/strong&gt; A company that researches and disseminates information about UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;inactivedefunct&#34;&gt;Inactive/Defunct &lt;a href=&#34;#inactivedefunct&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced Aerospace Threat Identification Program (AATIP):&lt;/strong&gt; A former US Department of Defense program that studied UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aerial Phenomena Research Organization (APRO):&lt;/strong&gt; A former UFO research organization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citizens Against UFO Secrecy (CAUS):&lt;/strong&gt; A former organization that advocated for government transparency on UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Civilian Saucer Investigation (CSI-LA):&lt;/strong&gt; A former UFO research group in Los Angeles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Civilian Saucer Intelligence (CSI-NY):&lt;/strong&gt; A former UFO research group in New York.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fund for UFO Research (FUFOR):&lt;/strong&gt; A former organization that provided funding for UFO research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National Institute for Discovery Science (NIDSci):&lt;/strong&gt; A former privately funded research institute that investigated UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National Investigations Committee On Aerial Phenomena (NICAP):&lt;/strong&gt; A former prominent UFO research organization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UFO Investigators League (UFOIL):&lt;/strong&gt; A former UFO research group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified Aerial Phenomena Task Force (UAPTF):&lt;/strong&gt; A former US Navy task force that investigated UFOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;see-also&#34;&gt;See Also &lt;a href=&#34;#see-also&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides links to related articles, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of investigations of UFOs by governments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification studies of UFOs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ufology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;ufos&#34;&gt;UFOs &lt;a href=&#34;#ufos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides a comprehensive overview of the topic, linking to the main articles on Unidentified Flying Objects (UFOs) and Ufology, the study of UFOs. It includes an image of a &amp;ldquo;flying saucer&amp;rdquo; from the National Archives and Records Administration. It also links to a list of notable UFO sightings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;claimed-sightings&#34;&gt;Claimed Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;#claimed-sightings&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section lists various notable UFO sightings and incidents, categorized chronologically and geographically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;general&#34;&gt;General &lt;a href=&#34;#general&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List of reported UFO sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; A comprehensive list of UFO sightings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sightings in outer space:&lt;/strong&gt; UFO sightings reported by astronauts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sightings near atomic sites:&lt;/strong&gt; UFO sightings reported near atomic sites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pre-20th-century&#34;&gt;Pre-20th century &lt;a href=&#34;#pre-20th-century&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ezekiel&amp;rsquo;s Wheel (circa 622–570 BC):&lt;/strong&gt; An ancient biblical vision interpreted by some as a UFO sighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Airship of Clon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO_organizations&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_UFO_organizations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
