<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Extraterrestrial Water on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/extraterrestrial-water/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Extraterrestrial Water on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 22:47:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/tags/extraterrestrial-water/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial liquid water</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_77e58d4d298b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 22:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_77e58d4d298b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterrestrial-liquid-water&#34;&gt;Extraterrestrial Liquid Water &lt;a href=&#34;#extraterrestrial-liquid-water&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extraterrestrial liquid water refers to water in its liquid state that occurs naturally outside of Earth. Its presence is considered a key prerequisite for life as we know it, making it a central focus in the search for extraterrestrial life. While many celestial bodies in the Solar System have a hydrosphere, Earth is the only one known to have stable bodies of liquid water on its surface. Confirmation of liquid water relies on absorption spectroscopy and geochemistry, which are effective for detecting water vapor and ice. However, detecting liquid water, especially subsurface water, is more challenging. Scientists use habitable zone theory, gravitational and tidal theory, planetary differentiation models, and radiometry to assess the potential for liquid water. Volcanic activity, fluvial features, and the presence of antifreeze agents also provide indirect evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;significance&#34;&gt;Significance &lt;a href=&#34;#significance&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Water is essential for the biochemistry of all known life forms. While lifeforms on Earth have adapted to varying levels of water scarcity, no known lifeform can survive entirely without it. Water is a simple molecule, consisting of oxygen and hydrogen, found throughout the solar system. However, it is only useful for life in its liquid state, which is less common than water vapor or ice. Because the first life forms on Earth originated in liquid water, the search for extraterrestrial liquid water is closely linked to the search for extraterrestrial life. Liquid water&amp;rsquo;s unique properties, such as becoming less dense when solidifying, are also beneficial for life, as they allow aquatic ecosystems to survive in cold environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;liquid-water-in-the-solar-system&#34;&gt;Liquid Water in the Solar System &lt;a href=&#34;#liquid-water-in-the-solar-system&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of December 2015, the confirmed liquid water outside Earth in the Solar System is estimated to be 25-50 times the volume of Earth&amp;rsquo;s water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mars&#34;&gt;Mars &lt;a href=&#34;#mars&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mars ocean theory suggests that nearly a third of the surface of Mars was once covered by water. Today, water on Mars exists primarily as ice and underground, with a small amount present as vapor in the atmosphere. Liquid water may occur transiently under specific conditions. The low atmospheric pressure and temperature prevent large bodies of standing liquid water from existing. Recurring slope lineae are thought to be caused by flows of brine. In July 2018, scientists from the Italian Space Agency detected a subglacial lake 1.5 kilometers below the southern polar ice cap, providing the first evidence of a stable body of liquid water on Mars. The water is thought to remain liquid due to the presence of magnesium and calcium perchlorates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;europa&#34;&gt;Europa &lt;a href=&#34;#europa&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists generally agree that a layer of liquid water exists beneath the surface of Europa, a moon of Jupiter. Heat from tidal flexing allows the subsurface ocean to remain liquid. The outer crust of solid ice is estimated to be 10-30 km thick, while the liquid ocean underneath may be about 100 km deep, resulting in a volume slightly more than twice that of Earth&amp;rsquo;s oceans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;enceladus&#34;&gt;Enceladus &lt;a href=&#34;#enceladus&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enceladus, a moon of Saturn, has geysers of water, confirmed by the &lt;em&gt;Cassini&lt;/em&gt; spacecraft. Gravimetric data confirmed a subsurface ocean. Evidence suggests the subsurface ocean is global in nature. The geysers also contain small amounts of salt, nitrogen, carbon dioxide, and volatile hydrocarbons. The melting of the ocean water and the geysers appear to be driven by tidal flux from Saturn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mimas&#34;&gt;Mimas &lt;a href=&#34;#mimas&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mimas, another moon of Saturn, was found by &lt;em&gt;Cassini&lt;/em&gt; to have a &amp;ldquo;rocking&amp;rdquo; motion whose amplitude could only be explained by a large subsurface ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ganymede&#34;&gt;Ganymede &lt;a href=&#34;#ganymede&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A subsurface saline ocean is theorized to exist on Ganymede, a moon of Jupiter, following observation by the Hubble Space Telescope in 2015. Patterns in auroral belts and rocking of the magnetic field suggest the presence of an ocean. It is estimated to be 100 km deep with the surface lying below a crust of 150 km of ice. The precise quantity of liquid water on Ganymede is highly uncertain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ceres&#34;&gt;Ceres &lt;a href=&#34;#ceres&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ceres appears to be differentiated into a rocky core and icy mantle, and may have a remnant internal ocean of liquid water under the layer of ice. The surface is probably a mixture of water ice and hydrated minerals. Emissions of water vapor have been detected from several regions of Ceres. Ceres also features a mountain called Ahuna Mons that is thought to be a cryovolcanic dome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ice-giants&#34;&gt;Ice Giants &lt;a href=&#34;#ice-giants&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ice giant planets Uranus and Neptune are thought to have a supercritical water ocean beneath their clouds, which accounts for about two-thirds of their total mass, most likely surrounding small rocky cores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pluto&#34;&gt;Pluto &lt;a href=&#34;#pluto&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June 2020, astronomers reported evidence that the dwarf planet Pluto may have had a subsurface ocean, and consequently may have been habitable, when it was first formed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;indicators-methods-of-detection-and-confirmation&#34;&gt;Indicators, Methods of Detection and Confirmation &lt;a href=&#34;#indicators-methods-of-detection-and-confirmation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most known extrasolar planetary systems appear to have very different compositions to the Solar System.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;spectroscopy&#34;&gt;Spectroscopy &lt;a href=&#34;#spectroscopy&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liquid water has a distinct absorption spectroscopy signature compared to other states of water due to the state of its hydrogen bonds. Despite the confirmation of extraterrestrial water vapor and ice, the spectral signature of liquid water is yet to be confirmed outside of Earth. Seasonal flows on warm Martian slopes, though strongly suggestive of briny liquid water, have yet to indicate this in spectroscopic analysis. Water vapor has been confirmed in numerous objects via spectroscopy, though it does not by itself confirm the presence of liquid water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;magnetic-fields&#34;&gt;Magnetic Fields &lt;a href=&#34;#magnetic-fields&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Jovian moons Ganymede and Europa, the existence of a sub-ice ocean is inferred from the measurements of the magnetic field of Jupiter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;geological-indicators&#34;&gt;Geological Indicators &lt;a href=&#34;#geological-indicators&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas Gold posited that many Solar System bodies could potentially hold groundwater below the surface. Liquid water may exist in the Martian subsurface. Research suggests that in the past there was liquid water flowing on the surface, creating large areas similar to Earth&amp;rsquo;s oceans. &amp;ldquo;Chaos terrain&amp;rdquo;, a common feature on Europa&amp;rsquo;s surface, is interpreted as regions where the subsurface ocean has melted through the icy crust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;volcanic-observation&#34;&gt;Volcanic Observation &lt;a href=&#34;#volcanic-observation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geysers have been found on Enceladus, a moon of Saturn, and Europa, moon of Jupiter. These contain water vapour and could be indicators of liquid water deeper down. In June 2009, researchers noticed that Enceladus wobbled in a certain way as it orbited Saturn, indicating that the moon&amp;rsquo;s icy crust didn&amp;rsquo;t extend all the way to its core — instead, it rested on a global ocean. On 3 April 2014, NASA reported that evidence for a large underground ocean of liquid water on Enceladus had been found by the &lt;em&gt;Cassini&lt;/em&gt; spacecraft. Emissions of water vapor have been detected from several regions of the dwarf planet Ceres, combined with evidence of ongoing cryovalcanic activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gravitational-evidence&#34;&gt;Gravitational Evidence &lt;a href=&#34;#gravitational-evidence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists used gravitational measurements from the &lt;em&gt;Cassini&lt;/em&gt; spacecraft to confirm a water ocean under the crust of Enceladus. Such tidal models have been used as theories for water layers in other Solar System moons. Anomalies in the orbital libration of Saturn&amp;rsquo;s moon Mimas combined with models of tidal mechanics led scientists in 2022 to propose that it harbours an internal ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ground-penetrating-radio&#34;&gt;Ground Penetrating Radio &lt;a href=&#34;#ground-penetrating-radio&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists have detected liquid water using radio signals. The radio detection and ranging (RADAR) instrument of the &lt;em&gt;Cassini&lt;/em&gt; probe was used to detect the existence of a layer of liquid water and ammonia beneath the surface of Saturn&amp;rsquo;s moon Titan. Ground penetrating radar and dielectric permittivity data from the MARSIS instrument on Mars Express indicates a 20-kilometer-wide stable body of briny liquid water in the Planum Australe region of planet Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;density-calculation&#34;&gt;Density Calculation &lt;a href=&#34;#density-calculation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planetary scientists can use calculations of density to determine the composition of planets and their potential to possess liquid water. Models of Saturn&amp;rsquo;s moon Titan density indicate the presence of a subsurface ocean layer. Similar density estimations are strong indicators of an subsurface ocean on Enceladus. GJ 1214 b was the second exoplanet to have an established mass and radius less than those of the giant Solar System planets. Its low density indicated that it is likely a mix of rock and water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;models-of-radioactive-decay&#34;&gt;Models of Radioactive Decay &lt;a href=&#34;#models-of-radioactive-decay&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Models of heat retention and heating via radioactive decay in smaller icy Solar System bodies suggest that Rhea, Titania, Oberon, Triton, Pluto, Eris, Sedna, and Orcus may have oceans underneath solid icy crusts approximately 100 km thick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;internal-differentiation-models&#34;&gt;Internal Differentiation Models &lt;a href=&#34;#internal-differentiation-models&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Models of Solar System objects indicate the presence of liquid water in their internal differentiation. Some models of the dwarf planet Ceres indicate the possibility of a wet interior layer. A global layer of liquid water thick enough to decouple the crust from the mantle is thought to be present on Titan, Europa and, with less certainty, Callisto, Ganymede and Triton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;habitable-zone&#34;&gt;Habitable Zone &lt;a href=&#34;#habitable-zone&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A planet&amp;rsquo;s orbit in the circumstellar habitable zone is a popular method used to predict its potential for surface water at its surface. Habitable zone theory has put forward several extrasolar candidates for liquid water. The Gliese 581 planetary system contains multiple planets that may be candidates for surface water, including Gliese 581c, Gliese 581d, and Gliese 581e. Gliese 667 C has three of them are in the habitable zone including Gliese 667 Cc is estimated to have surface temperatures similar to Earth and a strong chance of liquid water. Kepler-22b one of the first 54 candidates found by the Kepler telescope and reported is 2.4 times the size of the Earth, with an estimated temperature of 22 °C. It is described as having the potential for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_liquid_water&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_liquid_water&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
