<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UFO Religion on Alien Truth Social</title>
    <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/ufo-religion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UFO Religion on Alien Truth Social</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 11:32:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alien-truth-social.github.io/categories/ufo-religion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ashtar (extraterrestrial being)</title>
      <link>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f573308dd64c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 11:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alien-truth-social.github.io/content/content_f573308dd64c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ashtar-extraterrestrial-being&#34;&gt;Ashtar (Extraterrestrial Being) &lt;a href=&#34;#ashtar-extraterrestrial-being&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ashtar, sometimes referred to as Ashtar Sheran, is the name attributed to an alleged extraterrestrial being or group of beings that some individuals claim to have channeled. The first claim of receiving an Ashtar message came from UFO contactee George Van Tassel in 1952. Following Van Tassel&amp;rsquo;s claims, numerous other mediums also asserted contact, presenting conflicting messages. Ashtar is often depicted as a humanoid with blond hair and European features, leading to associations with Nordic aliens. The Ashtar movement is studied as a prominent form of UFO religion. The Czech Universe People, for example, venerate Ashtar alongside figures like Jesus and Krishna.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;#history&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section provides background information and details the development of the Ashtar phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background &lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The concept of Ascended Masters from esoteric teachings reappearing in spacesuits is discussed in the context of UFO religions. Theosophy, particularly Helena Blavatsky&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Secret Doctrine&lt;/em&gt;, is mentioned as containing references to extraterrestrial masters. The term &amp;ldquo;ashtar&amp;rdquo; itself appears in Blavatsky&amp;rsquo;s work, referring to the Sanskrit term ashtar-vidya, meaning advanced warfare technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;purported-contact-with-van-tassel&#34;&gt;Purported contact with Van Tassel &lt;a href=&#34;#purported-contact-with-van-tassel&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;George Van Tassel&amp;rsquo;s claim of telepathic communication with Ashtar in 1952 is detailed. Van Tassel interpreted the Bible in terms of extraterrestrial intervention and claimed Jesus was a being from space. He asserted that humans could tap into the &amp;ldquo;Universal Mind of God&amp;rdquo; and receive messages from Ashtar and deceased individuals like Nikola Tesla. From Tesla, he claimed to receive instructions to build the Integratron, a machine to extend lifespan and access knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van Tassel&amp;rsquo;s early messages from Ashtar focused on apocalyptic concerns regarding the hydrogen bomb. It was claimed that Ashtar, as Commander in Chief of the Ashtar Galactic Command, entered the Solar System to warn humanity about the dangers of nuclear detonation. The messages stated the space command was determined to prevent Earth&amp;rsquo;s destruction and was assisting the human race. Van Tassel claimed to have been tasked with delivering specific messages to the U.S. federal government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van Tassel claimed his communication method involved a new form of telepathy utilizing both human abilities and advanced alien technology, rather than traditional spiritual mediumship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;giant-rock-space-conventions&#34;&gt;Giant Rock Space Conventions &lt;a href=&#34;#giant-rock-space-conventions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Van Tassel held weekly channeling sessions at Giant Rock, California, where people could ask questions and channel answers from extraterrestrials. These gatherings helped coalesce the contactee subculture. The annual Giant Rock Spacecraft Convention, organized by Van Tassel, began in 1953 and continued for at least 24 years. These conventions attracted thousands of attendees and featured channeled messages from space. Many well-known UFO contactees attended as speakers and channelers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ashtar-command&#34;&gt;Ashtar Command &lt;a href=&#34;#ashtar-command&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The concept of an &amp;ldquo;Ashtar Command&amp;rdquo; was appropriated by various contactees and channelers, based on Van Tassel&amp;rsquo;s Ashtar figure. Robert Short, editor of &lt;em&gt;Interplanetary News Digest&lt;/em&gt;, popularized the messages but later formed his own group called &amp;ldquo;Ashtar Command&amp;rdquo; due to disagreements with Van Tassel. By the mid-1950s, the idea of Ashtar and a galactic law enforcement agency preparing to rescue humanity was established. Elouise Moeller and Adelaide J. Brown made predictions about space fleets and flourishing civilizations on other planets. The failure of these predictions negatively impacted the movement due to a lack of central authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;development-into-spiritual-religion-1990s-onward&#34;&gt;Development into spiritual religion (1990s onward) &lt;a href=&#34;#development-into-spiritual-religion-1990s-onward&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Ashtar message evolved from a technological communication to a more spiritual message, with Ashtar taking on the role of an Ascended Master. The Ashtar Command became a diffuse New Age Spiritualist movement with varied teachings. Tuella founded Guardian Action International. Andreas Grunschloss describes much of the Ashtar channeling as akin to cargo cults, blending spiritual ascension with alien technologies. Millenarian concepts involved a transformation of humans via these technologies, who would then return to Earth to enjoy a golden millennium. Later, teachings were modified to include a less material and more spiritual emphasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1970s-broadcasts&#34;&gt;1970s broadcasts &lt;a href=&#34;#1970s-broadcasts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1971, a British radio talk show received a call-in claiming to originate from outer space. This was followed by the 1977 Southern Television broadcast interruption, when a voice calling itself &amp;ldquo;Vrillon&amp;rdquo; of the Ashtar Galactic Command temporarily took over a television transmitter in southern England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1986-prediction-of-1994-apocalypse&#34;&gt;1986 prediction of 1994 apocalypse &lt;a href=&#34;#1986-prediction-of-1994-apocalypse&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yvonne Cole, who claimed to channel Ashtar messages from 1986, predicted the destruction of Earth civilizations and the arrival of alien cultures in 1994. Cole claimed governments were working with extraterrestrials to prepare for contact. The landing would be broadcast globally and include a message from the Ashtar Command. These prophecies furthered the fracturing and disappointment within the movement when they failed to occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-1994-pioneer-voyage-meditations&#34;&gt;The 1994 Pioneer Voyage meditations &lt;a href=&#34;#the-1994-pioneer-voyage-meditations&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1994, a group of Ashtar Command members claimed to have experienced &amp;ldquo;the lift-off experience,&amp;rdquo; being placed aboard &amp;ldquo;ships of Light&amp;rdquo; circling the planet. A second event was predicted for December 1994, involving over 250 people, which was declared to have &amp;ldquo;opened a portal to the AC (Ashtar Command) ships for ever.&amp;rdquo; Participants were said to have their vibrations raised through a contemplative procedure, and the Pioneer Voyage would occur during meditation. This evoked &amp;ldquo;memory recall&amp;rdquo; from members who began providing accounts of their &amp;ldquo;time aboard the ships.&amp;rdquo; The group claims the purpose of the lift-off is for the ascension of the human race, aided by electronic grids deployed around the planet by guardian ships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;developments-after-the-mid-1990s&#34;&gt;Developments after the mid-1990s &lt;a href=&#34;#developments-after-the-mid-1990s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the mid-1990s, channeling groups began using the Internet to unify the movement and establish an authoritative source for Ashtar messages. This addressed the problem of conflicting prophecies and enabled the Ashtar Command to produce a single Ashtar worldview. Channelers espousing messages focusing on destruction, conspiracies, and fear-mongering were declared invalid, claiming they had been deceived by negative space beings. The movement declared that future channels would only be accepted if they operated on the &amp;ldquo;level of the soul.&amp;rdquo; Channeled messages would be accepted if they complied with a set of twelve guidelines. The new framework claimed that spaceships would not interfere on Earth unless there was a serious problem. The emergent group was more spiritually focused and less concerned with spaceships. The Pioneer Voyage was incorporated into the Ashtar worldview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;credibility&#34;&gt;Credibility &lt;a href=&#34;#credibility&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section discusses the credibility of the Ashtar claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The failure of the July 1952 prediction that life on Earth would be destroyed by the hydrogen atom is noted. However, the message also stated that Ashtar was intervening to stop the destruction. After the explosion, messages claimed that Ashtar&amp;rsquo;s space fleet took actions to repair damage. The Ashtar belief system is based on faith in an extraterrestrial celebrity, and shifts in content seem due to failed prophecy, moving the emphasis from a physical space fleet to the concept of an Ascended Master aiding spiritual advancement. The Ashtar beliefs are seen as a syncretism between the I AM movements and the UFO experience. Though followers believe in Ashtar&amp;rsquo;s divine right and knowledge, he and others have yet to provide any physical evidence of their existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ashtar_(extraterrestrial_being)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ashtar_(extraterrestrial_being)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
